At the Fieri house,
we always love
cooking up family meals.
But lately, you know what
we've been doing?
We've been getting
some takeout.
Yeah. "Triple-D" style.
Exactly.
But you know what, Hunter?
I thought we'd kind of
bump things up a notch.
How about we reach out
to some of our favorite
celebrity chefs
from all over the country
and we ask them to send us
some of their best dishes
from their restaurants
And we cook them here?
Who are you thinking?
Oh, I'm telling you,
the biggest and the best.
Boom.
Maneet Chauhan's got tandoori
chicken poutine,
plus a bonus bite
coming from Nashville.
I've completely left
the building now, folks.
I have lost my mind.
There is off-the-hook
arancini and empanadas
from Antonia Lofaso
in Los Angeles.
Well, those weren't good,
evidently.
And we've got Maryland
crab cakes
from Michael Voltaggio's
joint in D.C.
You did it right.
Christian Petroni
in New York
is shipping us
his signature polenta
with all kinds
of over-the-top flavor.
Every bite
is a different bite.
And also, out of NYC,
Marcus Samuelsson
is sending us
a fried chicken collard
comfort food feast.
That is the way to my heart.
You guys ready?
This is "Triple-D Takeout"
celebrity style.
Oh, this is great
'cause I am hungry.
Exactly.
♪♪
Well, look at this
cast of characters.
Chefs, welcome.
Hunter, this is a very
special gathering
of "Triple-D Takeout."
None of these chefs
have the restaurants
that fall
in the "Triple-D" category.
They're celebrities
for one.
And, two, they have these big,
monster restaurants
that don't look like funky,
little, mom-and-pop shops.
But I thought, "We're doing
'Triple-D Takeout.'
What a perfect time
to invite
some of our favorite chefs
that we've had as guests
on 'Triple-D'
and have, of course, competed
and judged on 'Triple-G'
or 'T.O.C.,'
'Tournament of Champions.'"
So here we are,
ladies and gentlemen.
"Triple-D Takeout,"
celebrity-chef edition.
You ready?
[ All cheering ]
Which restaurant you at,
Christian?
We're at our location
in the beautiful
Hudson Valley,
New York, in Yonkers.
Beautiful.
And Maneet,
where are you today?
I am at Chaatable, which is
our street-Indian restaurant.
And right behind me,
those are 40,000 bangles.
The bands, the gold --
Wow.
Chef Marcus.
So Red Rooster's across
the street.
This is our office.
Today, we're coming
from the Streetbird.
Streetbird
is a pop-up restaurant.
Boomboxes, retro,
old-school hip-hop,
fried chicken --
It all works.
And Voltaggio,
the way you have this set up
with the backlighting
that we should have
a gray screen over your face
and a voice changer
doing some witness protection
program explanation.
[ Voice distorted ]
[ Laughter ]
I just moved into a new house
yesterday. I'm in Los Angeles.
This is also now the R&D
headquarters
for both Voltaggio Brothers
Steak House
and Estuary in Washington, D.C.
It's all of the furniture
I've managed to unpack so far.
That's it.
So the rest of the house
that way has boxes everywhere.
Alright, Antonia,
I can tell
from that picturesque
backdrop
you've got to be
downtown L.A.
Where are you today,
chef?
I'm at my house.
I'm home.
I know that if I'm in the
restaurant and talking to you,
I'm gonna be highly distracted.
I know that
everybody loves you
as a competitor
on "Triple-G"
and as a warrior on "T.O.C."
and as a judge.
Yes!
But we asked you to go
and give us a little tour
of the restaurant.
So let's take a look
at Scopa and DAMA.
Hey, everyone.
I'm Chef Antonia Lofaso.
I'm the executive chef and owner
of three restaurants
in Los Angeles --
Black Market Liquor Bar
in Studio City,
DAMA in downtown's
fashion district,
and Scopa Italian Roots
in Venice.
So the food
at Scopa Italian Roots
is an inspiration from my
American-Italian background
growing up in Long Island,
New York.
And DAMA's inspiration
came from love of Latin food
growing up here
in Los Angeles, California.
[ Laughing ]
I hope everything
made it okay.
Well, I don't know,
because the box...
Were you able to just
take the box
right off the streets
of L.A.?
Your box looks like it took
the subway to get there, bro.
That's a garbage bag
in case you need a garbage bag.
We're still digging here.
Did you know the new future
of cooking
is not to have
90,000 ingredients?
No, I have two dishes
for you, Guy.
Making us look bad.
Alright.
So run me through this,
what we're gonna make.
The empanadas are from DAMA,
which is my Latin-inspired
concept,
which is downtown Los Angeles.
Then we can make the rice balls.
Some people say arancini.
I say rice ball because
they're like giant tennis balls.
They're not like little,
dainty arancini
that you find in a really, like,
refined Italian restaurant.
These are Christian Petroni
like...
[ New York accent ]
Yo, we're having rice balls.
You want to come over
today or what, huh?
I would probably start
with the empanada filling.
So you're gonna go raw
empanada meat
into a hot sauté pan.
[ Normal voice ] Okay.
What is this, ground beef?
Ground sirloin and 1%
dry-aged as well.
So what my meat purveyor does,
he takes all of the dry-aged
scraps from all of the meat
they dry age, and then grind
that and add it to the sirloin,
about 10%, to give it
a little bit more funk
and a little bit
more aggressive meat flavor.
Okay.
You're gonna brown it.
Salt. Pepper.
There should be
two Yukons there.
Just do like a 1-inch
dice to those.
Let that meat just brown up
and then
you can add the potatoes to it.
Alright. And how long does this
need to cook down, Chef?
20 minutes.
While that's working,
Chef,
let's talk about
making these rice balls.
So you should have some cooked
risotto rice that's there
for you already.
Tada!
Stick it in a bowl.
There should be some microplaned
Parmesan cheese.
The cheese melts
differently in to the rice
when it's microplane
versus when it's grated.
Unless you eat it all right now.
Oh, it wasn't
tasting time?
Whisk up three eggs,
and then you're gonna
whisk those eggs into
that cheese-risotto mixture.
Guy, like this.
Look at me.
Huh?
It should be tacky.
It's not as tacky
as some people's
outfits today,
but it's --
it's on there.
I do a cupping texture
like this.
Look, I cup it.
Yeah.
Okay.
Yes.
Scoop meat, peas,
two types of cheese --
ricotta, mozzarella.
Take rice on the other hand,
pat it here
so it makes it like this,
and then on top.
I've made enough
arancini in my day.
But the key is
to make sure
that that top
really seals that bottom.
Yes.
So we don't have
the bleed-out.
You're gonna dredge it
in the panko-parsley mixture.
Oh, this is gorgeous,
by the way.
We're gonna let these set up
in the fridge ahead of time.
So when they go
into the fryer,
we don't have
the big ba-bosh!
Right? That's how you'd say it,
right, Christian?
The ba-bosh-ya-kay!
Badaboom!
[ Laughter ]
What do you want me to do
with this beef and potatoes?
I want you to add chopped
oregano to that,
garlic as well.
Garlic's already chopped
for you, Hunter.
You're welcome.
Thank you very much.
Smoked paprika,
about a tablespoon,
and 2 tablespoons
of the tomato paste.
Hit it with a little bit
of water.
Once it's cooked,
fold in those green onions.
Hunter, that piri piri sauce
is in that plastic bag
if you want to put it
in a ramekin,
because those empanadas
are gonna fry.
And then that sauce is
right there for it.
Perfect. Right here?
That's perfect.
Just a little chopped parsley
to garnish
that piri piri vinegar.
Just throw it
right in there, huh?
Yeah, just a little...
I got it.
A little dab will do you.
Alright, so, Chef.
Let me get the rundown here.
The arancini --
those are all done
and formed it in the fridge.
And we have to
cool those off
before we drop them
in the fire.
Otherwise
they're gonna explode.
Hunter's finished
the picadillo,
but we got
to let that cool
as I'm also cooling
the empanada dough
and we'll put
those together.
And when you guys
come back to this
"Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives Takeout,"
celebrity edition.
We'll start cooking all this
because, Lord knows,
we are starving.
We'll see a little bit.
Alright.
Finish that. Let it cool.
Don't go anywhere.
You guys better come back.
♪♪
Welcome back.
Hunter and Guy,
and I got my number-one
new camera guy right there.
My nephew, Jules,
is running the show.
Ryder's off --
We don't know
where Ryder is.
Hanging out
in the backyard.
It is a hot day here
in Northern California
and even hotter because I've got
five of the hottest chefs
in the country that have
joined us
for "Triple-D Takeout,"
the Celebrity Edition.
Maneet Chauhan,
Marcus Samuelsson,
of course,
Michael Voltaggio,
the one and only,
Antonia Lofaso.
And then
this really crazy dude
named Christian Petroni.
Anyhow, chefs,
thank you very much.
You've sent us
some fantastic ingredients,
and we are trying to make
the best of what you sent us.
First dish,
Antonia Lofaso,
almost done.
Beautiful arancini with smoked
mozzarella, ricotta,
Italian beef.
Then hit into
a Parmesan-panko breading
on the outside
of this rice.
And you said 350,
drop them?
Yep. Throw 'em in.
Nice.
I didn't want
to kerplunk 'em.
Don't kerplunk.
And we've got some empanada
dough, Argentinian style.
This is coming from
the DAMA restaurant.
Yes.
Scopa is in the fryer.
DAMA is being prepared now.
We've got in this picadillo --
aged sirloin,
Yukon potatoes,
oregano, garlic,
salt, pepper,
smoked paprika.
You have your dough ready.
You're gonna break it off
into about 2 ounces.
What's in the dough,
Chef?
Flour, salt, cold butter
pulsed in,
a little bit
of white vinegar and ice water.
Those bubbles,
when you fry empanada,
the vinegar does that.
Got it.
We have a little bit
of egg wash
and give us
the rundown, Chef.
You're just gonna brush
a little bit of egg
and then a nice filling
of the picadillo in the center.
Yes.
Do we have
a special fold style?
I'm just a pincher.
I just like to pinch the edges.
I just like to pinch.
Nice, little,
gentle float.
Let me see yours, Hunter.
Don't judge me,
alright?
I need to see it, Hunter.
Hunter, that's more
dumpling-like, but I like it.
Okay. Hold on.
How would you like it?
Shall I go crescent moon?
No, you're good. You're good.
You're good.
HUNTER: I just said,
"Don't judge me."
And the first thing
she said it was,
"That's more
dumpling-like."
Don't listen. You're good.
You're good.
Look at these arancini.
Nice crust on them.
That's perfect, huh?
[ New York accent ]
The rice balls are coming up.
You're gonna put
the rice ball on the plate.
Where's the gabagool?
Rice ball on the plate!
You're gonna
microplane more cheese
than should be allowed
in the world.
It should look like snow.
Yeah.
[ Normal voice ] Okay?
Little chopped parsley
and get in there.
There you go, Hunter.
Why do I get the spoon?
I don't want you
to get hurt.
Yes.
Mmm!
Well, those were good,
evidently.
We didn't like that one.
It's all the balance
in that.
It's the right amount
of cheese in the rice
and it's the rice cooked
exactly the right way.
And the breading
wasn't heavy.
The peas, boom, boom, boom,
boom, boom,
fresh mozz, everything,
and the ricotta.
Fluffy and just light
and it was...
It wasn't
a big, heavy arancini.
That was a delicious,
light rice ball.
Empanadas.
Plate piri piri.
Look at these, huh?
Whoa.
Jules, look at these,
look at the three.
You could tell the three
that Hunter made...
[ Laughter ]
...in the empanadas.
Don't make fun of me.
Welcome to the dumpling
and empanada hour.
I'm Guy,
this is Chef Hunter.
And enjoy.
This is what I would do --
cut it in half
and pour the piri piri vinegar
into the halves
so it's, like, into the meat.
Yes. Yes. Oh, my God.
You're my favorite person
to eat with.
Excuse me.
Oh, my God.
It's the vinegar.
I would put the vinegar
on everything.
Now, that's just
the vinegar?
That's vinegar
and tomato sauce?
The piri piri bottle
that you have there,
we use that vinegar.
When that vinegar is empty,
we take the piri piri pickles,
pour more vinegar.
Stick it in the blender
and then put it
through a strainer.
Hunter, can you swing
the dumpling cart around
if it comes --
If you see it,
can you stop them?
[ Laughter ]
That's a cold move there.
I thought
we were friends.
Hunter, you did a very good job.
Oh, my gosh.
That is so good.
Delicious.
That vinegar
on everything.
If you can see --
Here, Jules,
get a shot of that.
Super tender
but holds together.
It's not leaking out.
And the filling --
this picadillo is just --
It's tangy, meaty.
You've got a nice
silkiness in there.
I think from that Yukon being
broken down inside of it.
Love the smoked paprika.
Touch of the garlic.
But I got to tell you something,
across the board,
it is just...
Insane.
If somebody calls you up,
you can freeze these
and ship them?
Absolutely.
Oh, my gosh.
Fantastic.
Well done. Chef.
Thank you.
None of our forcefields
were able to pull us back
from overheating,
so we're gonna take a little
break, do some cleanup.
My brother,
Chef Michael Voltaggio,
when we come back.
♪♪
So welcome back.
"Triple-D Takeout,"
celebrity edition,
some great celebrity chefs
from around the country.
Christian Petroni,
Antonia Lofaso,
Maneet Chauhan,
Marcus Samuelsson,
and the one and only
Chef Michael Voltaggio,
who I've had more crazy
adventures with.
Voltaggio working
with purpose today.
And beverages already.
Ready to roll.
Take it away, Chef.
Hey, guys.
It's Chef Michael Voltaggio,
and I'm at my house here in L.A.
doing some research
and development
for our restaurant Estuary
in Washington, D.C.,
which is a restaurant
that Bryan, my brother, and I
are partners on
in the Conrad Hotel.
I'm excited to be doing this
with my Food Network fam.
We've all done work together
on "Guy's Grocery Games."
We've cooked
at the ranch together,
also "Tournament of Champions."
And now we've figured out a way
to cook together for all of you.
And here comes Hunter
with a box of goods.
Oh, yeah.
I brought you guys
a little wardrobe design.
That one is from
my first collection.
And then the white one
is a one-of-a-kind piece
that I feel like only you
can really pull off.
Give him a little high five.
You are awesome.
Alright.
Voltaggio wins best dish.
Let's go home.
Yeah!
[ Laughter ]
[ Laughs ]
That is cool.
Well done, brother.
What are we making?
Estuary is focused
on the Chesapeake watershed.
So basically the idea is that
this is a Maryland crab cake,
but we're serving it
with crepes.
Fold it like a tortilla,
eat it with some
dill-pickle tartar sauce.
You can make the perfect bite
every single time
without having to share
the entire dish.
I also threw in
a little luxury ingredient
in there for you as well --
a little caviar.
Wow.
What hasn't this guy
thought of?
GUY: So I see that you made us
buttermilk pancake batter.
Since Antonia already took up
half the episode,
we can probably just use
the crepe batter that's there.
[ Laughter ]
Antonia, are you having a snack
right now as we talk?
I'm having a snack.
Just take that parsley
crepe batter,
which is made out of buttermilk,
milk, parsley, eggs, flour,
and just make it into crepes.
And the idea is that
these effectively are
little wrappers
or, like, little tortillas.
So tartar sauce.
I chopped the pickles
for you ahead of time.
You're just such a giver.
It was really nice.
Really nice to you.
Gifts, crabs, caviar,
custom-made,
one-off shirts.
Boy, I'm telling you what.
Unless Christian Petroni
jumps out
of the box himself,
he might not be even contending
in this competition.
'Cause you understand,
ladies and gentlemen,
everybody at home,
these are some
of my closest friends
and some of
the highest-regarded chefs
in the country.
And, yes, we are down
to the nitty-gritty
of who's gonna get
best dish.
It will not involve
any cash or prizes,
simply just
bragging rights.
And amongst these five,
that's a lot.
Dijon mustard, capers,
mayo and chives?
Little bit of chopped dill.
Got it.
Let's see them
crepe skills.
I think
I went a little big.
Oh, no, that's perfect.
Because you can actually
shape the crab cakes
and cut the crepes with the
biscuit cutters that I sent you.
Almost had it.
It's probably
just his recipe.
Stop it.
I think there's
a user error going on.
The fact that you're out
in the heat,
that might be messing it up
a little bit, too.
Michael, how can
I start this crab cake?
So I like to make the sauce
separately in another bowl
and then fold it
into the crab meat.
One egg, a little bit of mayo,
a little bit of mustard,
some Old Bay.
Scallions in the sauce?
Yeah.
Right into the sauce.
We're making
the [indistinct] for it,
so we're not gonna
break up all that crap meat.
This is one pound of crab meat
with, I think, maybe not even
1/4 cup of panko.
And that's it.
This is all thriller,
no filler.
So let's mix all the dressing
into the crab meat
until everything's nice
and, like, homogenous.
Wait, do we get that flip
in slow motion over there?
Yeah, can I see that flip
in slo-mo?
♪♪
Yes. Yes.
Put in about 1/4 cup panko.
And just barely fold that
into it as well.
Hunter, you look like you're
from Maryland right now, man.
This is actually my first time
making crab cakes.
Finally.
There we go.
There it is.
So you have the oven
preheated at 350, 375.
That is correct.
Hunter's doing
a very nice job by the way.
So you're gonna press
that into the mold
and push your -- push it
with your fingers in there
so that it takes the shape,
but don't smash it too hard
that it becomes
like a hockey puck.
And this is the Maryland
Blue Crab?
This is Maryland blue crab.
Fantastic.
They'll go in the oven
for about 14 minutes.
What I like to do
is cook them on one side
for half the time,
take them out,
flip it and let it cook
the rest of the time.
So we bust these out.
I'm gonna get back
to doing the crepes.
We're hanging out with
some of our favorite chefs
from around the country.
They've just sent us
amazing meals.
We're doing our best
to put them together
under some severe temperatures
here in Northern California.
But don't go anywhere.
Crab cakes go to the oven
and we'll see you
in a little bit.
Oh, my goodness.
I'm gonna go in the house.
Get back to work.
It's air-conditioning.
Come on. Get back to work.
Get those in the oven.
"14 minutes," he said.
Stick with it.
♪♪
Welcome back. Hanging out
at the Fieri house.
It is "Triple-D Takeout"
with some great celebrity chefs
from around the country.
Michael Voltaggio,
Antonia Lofaso,
Marcus Samuelsson,
Maneet Chauhan,
the one and only
Christian Petroni.
Chef Voltaggio, crab cakes
in the oven.
We are starving.
Alright, Chef.
I've got this
little fennel salad here.
You want me to do
anything with it?
A little olive oil, little bit
of salt, that's it.
And then I'll add, like,
a nice little slaw
kind of crunch to the dish.
Take the pancake,
open it up,
put the crab meat inside,
a little bit
of the fennel salad,
tartar sauce,
and then caviar.
That's at your discretion, Chef.
Caviar?
Is that not cheating?
Yep.
It's bribery.
Alright.
Moment of truth.
Guys, is he happy or what?
I can't see anything.
My screen is not there.
He looks
very disappointed.
Did he just thrown it
in the trash?
Antonia is so mean.
Love you, Voltaggio.
Thank you.
I love you, too.
You get this delicious,
tender,
fall-apart-in-your-mouth
crab cake
with very
little binder,
great crab flavor,
enough acid, enough fat,
brininess
from the caviar.
Just a little kiss
from Maryland.
You did it right.
When you're gonna take
the almighty crab cake
and completely mess
with it,
break the rules,
you better break it
like that.
Dynamite. Okay.
Who wants to go next?
Marcus? Chef Marcus?
One of the first times
we got to work together
was on "T.O.C.,"
"Tournament of the Champions,"
and he was our lead judge.
That method --
I've never seen before.
I don't think
any one of us have.
Marcus, you have really
spent a lot of time
helping a lot
of other people
and things are not easy
in Harlem.
Have a good day.
And I like to see
that smile on your face.
What's up, everybody?
My name is
Chef Marcus Samuelsson.
I was born in Ethiopia.
Then I grew up in Sweden.
So really what you see
in my food is a combination.
Roasted cauliflower steak
with eggplant puree
and summer succotash.
For me, cooking
is a way of expression.
So when it's all about
super-fine dining,
I do that at Marcus.
When it's all about
my neighborhood and community,
it's Red Rooster.
When it's about picnic
and block party,
and be able to deliver
to your house,
it's all about Streetbird.
Right now,
we're in downtown Newark,
which we're getting ready
to do our Streetbird
pop-up restaurant.
It's fun. It's funky.
It's to go, you know,
it's just a good time.
Alright. So, Chef Marcus,
what have you sent me?
Chicken and waffle
from Streetbird
with a cornbread waffle.
It's all about party in a box.
Let me turn
the waffle maker on.
Get your oil ready.
So let's put a big, whole bulb
of garlic in the oil
and a sprig of rosemary.
What temperature
you want that oil at, Chef?
320.
We have it at 321.
We'll lower it.
[ Laughs ]
Collard greens?!
Cooked, done,
ready for you.
That is the way
to my heart.
What was in
the collard greens?
Sliced onions, sliced garlic,
white wine vinegar.
And there's already
turmeric, Chef?
Because I've got this nice,
beautiful color in there.
I sent you some
really good spiced butter.
What's in
the spiced butter, Chef?
Turmeric, ginger, garlic.
-Oh!
-That sounds amazing.
Why can't I have that
on my popcorn?
-Yeah, seriously.
-Oh. Nice.
I sent you some brined chicken,
so it's been brined overnight.
Put the chicken
in the buttermilk,
so it's gonna be nice and sour.
And you got my favorite.
You got drumsticks
and thighs.
That is where
the real flavor is.
In this dredge,
you have panko, cornstarch,
and regular flour.
And I sent you
a bunch of spices.
Flour spice.
Little garlic,
little onion,
little cayenne...
And turmeric.
So throw that in.
You know, I didn't grow up
with fried chicken.
Before we opened
the restaurant,
I was so nervous
about getting it right.
So actually, the first person
that the fried chicken for me
was John Legend.
The singer?
Yeah.
John came up,
fried the chicken.
This is how
you're supposed to fry it.
Well, the first time I had
made waffles was with Elvis.
And he told me, "Guy,
you got to make sure..."
You know what?
I forgot to mention, Guy.
The empanada recipe
actually came
from Chrissy Teigen.
[ Laughter ]
Antonia, at one time,
me and Donna Summer
were making meatballs,
and she was showing me
her trick.
Take the fried chicken
out of the buttermilk,
put in the dredge,
and we can start frying.
This is gonna be
a double fry, right?
The first fry is really
just to cook it through
and then you want
to let it rest.
And then the second fry
is really to make it nice
and crispy.
Sweet.
GUY: You want to do anything
with these waffles yet, Chef?
Yeah.
This is a cornbread mix.
It already
smells fantastic.
Delish.
It tastes more like cookie
dough with cornmeal.
It does. It does.
It's really
a cornbread batter
with waffle batter into it.
Gosh.
If you look at the honey
that we sent to you,
pour the honey into a bowl
and then you pour
this smoked paprika.
It's called berbere.
It's from my wife's village
in Ethiopia.
Berbere is like the salt
and pepper of Ethiopia.
It's not super spicy.
It's got a little kick
on the back.
And we're gonna take
about 2 tablespoons
from the chicken oil
into this hot honey.
That's how we gonna get
the nice flavor.
Oh, I'm excited.
So Hunter, with the hot honey,
just take maybe
a tablespoon of soy
and squeeze a lemon
into that as well.
So just to brighten up
a little bit.
It's making my mouth water
right now by the way.
MARCUS: Finish off with that
fried rosemary that we had.
And that garlic that we fried,
chop it up
and put into
that hot honey as well.
Apple cider vinegar
in the collard greens.
Perfect. Finish it
with fish sauce.
An old traditional
Scandinavian, Ethiopian,
Academy Award-winning
singer sauce.
You know, in Scandinavia,
we have a shrimp sauce
that is very similar
to the fish sauce.
So every country has it.
Chicken's coming out.
We got to let it rest.
Is that everything?
There's supposed to be
another box.
Hunter has another big box
of goods.
[ Whistling ]
I know that the food's
already been sent.
What is that?
Is that a boombox?
That is a boombox.
Going back.
Going back to, you know,
I didn't know Hunter knew
what a boombox was.
I'm like, "You have to teach
these kids today."
Yeah.
There you go.
When you deal with people like
Antonia that does two dishes,
you got to come back strong.
Christian,
what do you say?
Should we just throw
in the towel?
I'm outta here, guys.
[ Mumbles ]
[ Laughter ]
Alright.
We're back to the bird.
I got waffle.
I got collard greens.
We're just gonna drizzle
that brown butter
on top of the waffle
because there's not enough
butter in this recipe, right?
There's never
enough butter ever.
Chop up that rosemary
a little bit.
Put the chicken in the bowl.
This the way John
did it?
Exactly.
Take that honey,
you drizzle it on top.
You can hear that
crunchy chicken,
like, hit against
the side of that bowl.
Beautiful.
Throw those pickles in there.
Hunter, you want to take a spoon
and just drizzle the hot honey
on top of all of this.
Get that spoon.
If you want, Guy, just powder
a little of that berbere on top.
Yeah. Yeah.
There you go.
Can we get a picture
of that first?
Hang on a second.
♪♪
There you go, Hunter.
That's the way to eat it.
It's a ton of textures
and flavors.
You get
this candied waffle,
but then
you get the acidity
from the apple cider vinegar
and the fish sauce.
But then you get this fantastic
cornmeal crunch in it.
And then you get these
little gems
of the house-made pickle
splashing up
and the smokiness
to the berbere.
It says chicken
and waffles,
but it eats
like last meal.
Booyah.
This has been
outstanding.
And the thing that's
even more outstanding,
we've got two more chefs
coming up.
Hunter and I are gonna
take a nap,
and we'll see you
a little bit.
Alright.
I am going to go
lay down.
Do not hold on to me.
Welcome back. "Triple-D
Takeout," celebrity edition.
Three heavy hitters
have already gone --
Antonia Lofaso,
Michael Voltaggio,
Marcus Samuelsson.
We have two
more fantastic chefs.
So here we go with our boy,
Christian Petroni.
He loves food.
He really loves his family.
He loves his customers.
He really loves his team.
My name is Christian Petroni.
You might have seen me here
and there on the Food Network.
"Guy's Grocery Games."
Listen, he can't get rid
of me at this point,
but my baby is Fortina.
We have five restaurants.
We make pizzas
in wood-burning ovens.
We cook vegetables.
We really are here to embrace
the food of the Bronx,
the red-sauce joints
that I grew up with.
And I am so happy to be here
to show you what we do.
♪♪
[ New York accent ]
Yo. So when I tell you,
we're gonna make
some polentas
and put it in the thing.
I've been waiting
for this.
[ Normal voice ] Chef, do we
have food in here?
Yeah, there's a box in there
that's ready to go.
I know where we're going
because you are
the polenta king
at Fortina.
-Nice.
-Yeah.
WOMAN: Nice.
Can somebody
make some noise, guys?
[ Cheers and applause ]
♪♪
I'm starving.
You got a pot of water
boiling over there, Guy?
[ New York accent ] Yeah.
I've got some
boiling water over here.
You're gonna pretend
like you're making grits.
Turn the water into like a
whirlpool and add some sea salt.
And listen, I'm more of
a method guy than a recipe guy.
You're gonna kind of eyeball
the right amount of polenta
going in there.
And then Hunter's gonna hang
back and just keep stirring.
While Uncle Guy
gets everything else ready,
that polenta is gonna keep
going in the background.
Let me get
this bone marrow going.
Just do a little bit of salt
and pepper over the top
and put it in your pizza oven.
That polenta is okay?
It's doing good.
So, as you see it
getting kind of thick,
feel free to add a little bit
of water in there.
Keep in mind that
you're gonna be adding
a copious amount of butter
and the "triumvirant"
of cheeses.
Triumvirant.
[ Laughs ]
Well,
that is a big word.
I'm Googling "triumvent."
I don't think
you're saying it right.
-Probably not.
-Alright, Chef.
What do you want
in next?
Oh, actually, yeah.
You know, the sausage
is a bonus, Guy.
You can definitely throw that
in the oven
with the bone marrow.
The marinara and brasciole
can all go together, Guy,
and you can start
to let that simmer.
The marinara's already
cooked for a few hours.
The brasciole --
we take the pork butt
and we cut them into,
like, 4-ounce medallions.
We pound them thin.
We make a paste with parsley,
Pecorino, garlic confit,
and then we rub
the inside of that pork butt.
We then roll it
and tie it with string
and we roast it up
in our wood oven.
It comes out,
goes in the swimming pool,
Jacuzzi of marinara sauce.
So it's really tender
and beautiful and sweet.
Alright, Chef.
Next up?
What we can do
is talk meatballs.
I do beef meatballs.
It's got to have
the bread soaked in milk,
the parsley,
the cheese, the garlic.
What kind of cheese?
What I like to do,
believe it or not,
is cut my Pecorino
with Parmigiano-Reggiano.
Pecorino -- that sheep's milk --
really gives that funk.
The Parmesan is
a little mellower,
and it works really great.
So those meatballs,
they're steamed and ready to go.
I would go right into the oil
and get them nice and crispy.
Sausage looks great.
♪♪
Hey...[indistinct]
[ Laughter ]
So, we ready to get down
with some Pecorino
and some Parmesan?
I thought you'd never be ready
to go.
Reserve some of that Parmesan
for garnish later.
So at least four
to seven handfuls.
You've got to have four
or five extra handfuls
on hand.
At all times.
And then I'm gonna
give you the secret.
My favorite trick
is high-quality,
low-moisture mozzarella
towards the end.
It's gonna give you that, like,
ooey-gooey cheese pull
that everyone's
looking for.
For our polenta,
you're gonna want to throw
a couple of knobs
of butter in that polenta.
And I even like
to put a cup of glugs
of that really high-quality,
green, grassy,
artichoky olive oil.
You're gonna want
to be able to pour that polenta
where it's not going
to be too loose.
But it's not gonna be
so thick that it won't pour.
What are we plating
this up on?
Did you say plates?
Where we're going, we won't need
plates, my friend.
The way I do this
in the restaurant
is based off
a very old tradition,
predominantly in northern Italy,
where they make this polenta
and they spread it out
on a table.
Let's talk here for a second,
goombah, okay?
You know Loretta.
Oh, my God.
I pour this on the table
in that house,
I'm gonna be moving
to the Bronx
to live with you.
So what else could I do?
You could take your
favorite cutting board.
You can put wax paper
down on your table.
There really are no rules.
I've done this on the hood
of a car, my friend.
Really?
Yeah, that'll work.
Beautiful.
And that's some
black truffle, Guy,
that we puree
with champignon mushrooms,
extra virgin olive oil.
Oh!
And it's way better than that
tiny, little jar of caviar
you got in the --
in the kid pack.
Voltag, I love you, bro.
Oh, my gosh.
Yeah.
So, Guy, when you're ready,
we can go, babe.
I am so excited
for them right now.
But you got to do this
with fanfare.
Let's get weird.
Alright. Here we go.
-Oh,
-Nice.
-Higher!
-Nice!
You got this!
-Oh!
-Yes!
Yes!
Yes! Nice.
Get some of that hot ragu
that's been warming up
the brasciole
and kind of just throw it
around that polenta
like a Jackson Pollock,
you know.
There you go.
Yes.
Next stop is crispy meatballs.
Then I like to take
a couple of marrow bones
and just kind of cross them
somewhere off to the side.
And then the sausage
can go all about.
Take a lot of that basil, Guy,
and just rip it
and spread it around.
Now, Chef, take a tablespoon
and splash that black truffle
and that salsa verde.
Yo, that is ridiculous.
That is amazing.
Now, just to finish,
people like
to sprinkle Parmesan.
I like to throw it
with some vigor in one spot.
Ready?
Parmesan explosion.
Boom!
Yes!
I'm impressed, Chef.
If I start driving
from Nashville,
how long do you think it will
take me to get to you?
Oh, but here's
the beautiful thing.
I'm shipping these
all over the country now.
GUY:
This is crazy on a board,
but the flavors,
the meatball, so tender,
that little bit of fry
on the outside.
The brasciole --
Every bite
is a different bite,
be it a big piece of basil
coming through.
The truffle
just peaks in there.
Then you get just that
little nugget
of the truffle pesto combo
meatball sauce
on top of the 19-different-
cheese polenta.
This is the most exciting dish
I've ever seen you make.
I've heard about it forever,
but kudos.
-Well done, dude.
-Love you guys.
-Amazing.
-That's awesome.
But I got to be honest
with you, folks.
You have no idea
what's coming
out of the big town
of Nashville.
Watch out for the one
and only Chef Maneet Chauhan.
Whoo-hoo.
Okay, guys,
get away from me.
I'm going to my room
with this.
We'll be right back.
Welcome back.
We have slept off
the polenta coma
on "Triple-D Takeout,"
celebrity edition.
Five of my favorite
celebrity chefs.
Christian Petroni,
Antonia Lofaso,
Marcus Samuelsson,
and the one and only
Michael Voltaggio
have all delivered.
It's like seeing
all your favorite music groups
play at the same time,
like John Legend.
[ Laughter ]
Without further ado,
ladies and gentlemen,
big energy,
incredible food.
Everybody loves her.
And I did not know
how big the sword was
that this one swings.
My name is Maneet Chauhan,
and I am a chef/restaurateur
here in Nashville.
I've got four restaurants --
Chauhan Ale and Masala House,
Chaatale, Tánsuo,
and Mockingbird.
You might have also
seen me as a judge
on Food Network's "Chopped."
So what I've known for,
or my style of cooking,
is more fusion-based.
Hot chicken pakora.
Being situated in the South,
I love to embrace
the local ingredients
and serve it
with an Indian twist.
Thank you.
I'm so excited to be here.
I almost feel like, you know,
the backstage
of getting on the "Tournament
of Championship,"
my heart feels
that way right now.
I got taken out
on "T.O.C." by...
GUY: Maneet Chauhan!
Chauhan, show off!
This is very organized,
very organized.
"Dear Guy, each and every
household in India
has a masala dabba,
or a spice box.
It has the spices most loved
by the household.
I'm sending you a masala
dabba for your household."
This is gorgeous.
Chef,
what did you send us?
Tandoori chicken poutine.
We are taking
the tikka masala to Canada.
[ Laughs ]
I have
the marinated chicken.
The marinade has our house blend
tandoori spice mix --
yogurt, ginger, garlic.
We usually marinate it
for at least 24 hours.
I also send you
a couple of pieces
which I cooked
in the tandoor.
So it has that
lovely charred effect to it.
I have the wood fired up,
and I could throw it
in there.
That's perfect.
We just need to get
a little bit of char.
Maneet, how can
I start the sauce?
In a cast-iron pan,
just put in all the butter.
This is about the sauce,
so it's going to be rich.
At what point does he add
the handful of Parmesan?
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
Alright, Chef,
what do you think
of my little tandoor move
that I did here?
I love it.
In the wood-fired oven.
It's awesome.
So you have
some whole spices --
green cardamom,
black peppercorn,
bay leaf, cinnamon stick.
Lightly crush it
and throw it in the butter.
Once they stop dancing,
you go ahead
and put in the onions.
Got it.
Okay.
Go ahead and put
the ginger-garlic paste in it.
Let the onions
caramelize slightly.
And then we put the green chili
along with the tomato
and the tomato paste.
Fantastic.
What is this called?
Kasuri methi --
dried fenugreek leaves.
Tandoori masala in.
Yes.
Roasted cumin,
that was nice.
Red chili powder,
turmeric.
Salt to taste.
And you have sent me
something here
that says gold bouillon cubes
or whatever it is.
I don't understand
what this is.
[ Laughs ]
That is golgappa.
And what we have to do
is take those disks
and put it in the fryer.
Yes.
They're gonna bloom.
They will stop looking like
ping-pong balls like this.
Okay.
Oh, look at that.
Who makes the disks?
We make it in-house.
It's a combination
of whole-wheat flour,
rice flour, semolina flour,
and AP flour,
and then very little water.
I have completely left
the building now, folks.
I have lost my mind.
Let those cool down,
I take it?
So right now what we can
also do is the fries.
We've cut it into small pieces.
Put it in cold water
for 30 minutes.
Then take it out.
Put some cornstarch.
Let it sit for a little bit
and then deep-fry it.
325 degrees
for 4 or 5 minutes.
And then we're supposed
to fry them at 375?
Yes. Absolutely.
Is the sauce simmering?
Yes.
Remove the bay leaf,
and we need to blend
that sauce.
Once we blend it,
we'll put it back
and put the honey
and the heavy cream.
And then we taste for salt.
Got it.
That looks amazing.
Okay, so let's do this.
You will need a spoon to make
a hole in the ping-pong balls.
[ Laughter ]
And if you go ahead
and crack the top,
you'll get a hole like this.
Got it.
And then you take a little bit
of the garbanzo filling in it.
So the filling has potatoes,
black garbanzo, cumin,
chaat masala, red chili powder,
cilantro.
And then put
the tamarind chutney,
and then make a mint cilantro
water, which we pour it in it.
There is an old Indian custom
of taking some tequila
and putting it in it.
Your Indian custom must have
missed the Santo in there.
One bite.
Just put the whole thing
in your mouth.
Oh, yeah.
That is one of
the weirdest things
I've ever had,
and I want another one.
Yeah. This is Indian
Street food at its best.
So just to clarify,
you and Antonia
both made
two dishes then.
Yeah.
♪♪
What do you think
of that, huh?
JULES: That was amazing.
So it's kind of like
a profiterole.
GUY: The whole thing.
Yeah.
An Indian
crunchy profiterole.
That is crazy.
Whoa.
Hey.
So look at this.
That was my makeshift --
hey, makeshift tandoor.
Oh.
[ Whistles ]
That is awesome.
Fantastic.
Nice.
Chop this chicken up?
We can just slice it.
So, Guy, when we take
the fries out,
there is a chaat masala,
which is...
I saw it.
...a dried raw mango powder.
So that's going to be
the finishing salt on the fries.
Beautiful.
And then we can start
assembling the poutine.
Whoo-hoo!
Alright. How do you want us
to build it, Chef?
So first the fries
go into the cast iron.
That's a good fry.
Go ahead and put
the chicken on top.
Oh, my gosh.
Put the sauce on top.
Beautiful.
Put the mozzarella on top.
Into the oven?
To the oven.
Yes.
To the oven, I go!
So all we are trying to do is
look for the cheese to be melty.
Shout-out
to cuz Jules, though.
Gets all the perks
and all the benes.
Doesn't have to be on TV,
and he gets to eat.
JULES: It's a great job.
You stand right next
to the hot oil
in the 100-degree
weather. It's great.
[ Laughter ]
I think the poutine
should be ready.
Okay. Coming over hot.
Oh, my God.
Look at that.
Beautiful.
Cilantro as a garnish
on top?
Look at that
cheesiness.
-Oh.
-Ooh.
That makes me so happy.
Looks so good.
The masala sauce...
Yeah. Who made that?
They did a really good job
on there or something.
Outstanding.
The tandoor chicken,
had I done it in the oven
was gonna be equally
as delicious
because the marinade
was so spot-on.
The crunch of the fries
and the creaminess
of the chicken.
Although we like
a little bit of cream
in the tikka masala,
the cheese is, like,
the extra thing,
like, why doesn't it
always have cheese?
I mean,
this is outrageous.
These all were just
rock-star dishes.
-Whoo!
-Give me one moment.
You guys
are absolutely nuts.
I'm gonna have to work
with my constituents...
Julesy.
...to decide
who's gonna
get best dish.
Oh. Love you guys.
Love you, Maneet.
♪♪
Uh-oh.
Moment of truth, guys.
Round two is tomorrow.
It's not agreed upon.
It's not mutual,
but there could
only be one winner.
Remember, this is
for no cash or prizes,
simply bragging rights,
folks.
And the winner is...
winner, winner,
polenta dinner!
I never win anything!
Yes!
Good job.
I tell you what,
everybody did
a fantastic job.
And the beautiful part
about this, folks, is
you can reach out
to all of our chefs.
They've got delivery.
Hope you had a great time.
We are stuffed.
Say good night
for "Triple-D Takeout,"
celebrity edition.
Awesome job.
-I love you all.
-Thank you.
It looks okay.
It looks alright.
I can't see.
I can't see anything.
My screen is not there.
That means you're out.
It means you lost, bro.
It means...
Guys, is he happy or what?
I can't see anything.
No, I see him
shaking his head.
Come on!
I saw that move.
Oh, no, no, no.
He's good. He's good.