You know, people are asking me
all the time,
"hey, Guy, that one joint you
checked out that one city
when you were doing 'Triple D'
-- how they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous,
dude,
But it turns out
it was only the beginning,
because "Triple D"
have been blown up,
and we're going back to see
what's cooking.
Like on this trip...
Let's get it on!
...right from the farm
to the table...
Mmm!
[ Laughs ]
...a Portland, Oregon place
flipping the script,
going for pork...
That's one of the best
pork dishes I've ever had.
...to plant based.
Is there a mask
behind...
Is this going to be
a "Scooby-Doo" moment?
...a cafe in Cleveland creating
culinary masterpieces...
I feel like I'm taking a bite
of the Mona Lisa right now.
...straight from the garden.
Mmm.
[ Laughs ]
I don't have
anything to say.
Plus, a brunch spot
in Virginia Beach....
Throw the supercharger
on that thing, man.
...where the food matches
their attitude.
Potato pancakes.
The colors...
The colors,
the brightness.
...the brightness.
Sunny,
it's welcoming.
Huge.
Familiar faces,
new places,
and more off the hook flavors.
This is "Triple-D Nation".
♪♪
Out of all the joints
we've shot
on
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives",
believe it or not,
a few have closed.
Oh, for various reasons.
They've lost the lease,
the partnership broke up,
people move, they got out
of the business, you name it.
So I'm here in Portland, Oregon,
where one of my favorites,
a joint called Country Cat,
has closed.
The husband and wife,
they lost the lease.
They said, "We're done.
We're going to start
a new joint.
A little more fitting
for our lifestyle now."
This is Harlow's Cafe
and Juice Bar.
WOMAN:
Walnut chorizo quesadilla.
MAN: Country Cat
was super familiar food,
the food that's close
to my heart.
Like Jackie and Adam,
I've moved towards
healthful cuisine.
I went to Country Cat. I thought
it was a good restaurant.
I really enjoyed the food.
I'm sure that they had to
think real hard and long
about wanting to go
from one style of restaurant
to a different style.
But if you're a chef and you
know food, you know food, right?
FIERI: Right.
And Adam and Jackie Sappington,
they definitely know food.
Mmm.
Meat candy.
You're killing me.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
So let me do
the timeline here,
or let me help you
help me do the timeline.
Yes.
When did we shoot
Country Cat?
2013.
2013?
Yeah.
And everybody
falls in love with the joint.
You're breaking down
whole hog.
Oh, yeah.
When you say
whole hog,
you are getting a portion
of the whole hog.
Of each pig, yeah.
Let's get it on!
Get it on!
Straight across.
Ah.
Full nelson.
♪♪
Get it!
Hai, hai!
Make it your dinner.
Here we are with
this big monster chop,
the rest of the loin.
And what are we creating
out of this now?
The porketta
for the plate.
Okay, so, now we're
gonna take this and brine this?
Cure it.
We're gonna cure it like bacon
for five days.
Kosher salt.
Pink salt, brown sugar,
white sugar.
Ginger.
Chili flake, Cayenne,
a little combo.
Black pepper, parsley,
thyme, a little sage.
Good to go.
I kind of
massage it in.
Just push it down.
Let it go five days?
And then roll it.
♪♪
And then roast it 2 1/2,
3 hours, 300 degrees.
[ Whistles ]
Check it out.
So, there's our beautiful
porketta.
It's like opening up a present
at Christmastime.
From Pig Santa.
Yeah, baby.
Now what are we gonna do
with it?
We're gonna put it in the pan
and sear it up.
Braised shoulder.
Porketta.
Mmm.
Brined,
cured pork chop.
These are Willamette Valley
prune plums.
It's keep-on-moving sauce.
It is.
And...
The cornmeal-crusted
fried headcheese.
That's correct,
my man.
That is gorgeous,
huh?
Now I'm gonna get a little bit
of this porketta.
Amazing flavor,
incredible texture,
all coming
from the same animal.
This is one of the best
pork dishes I've ever had.
Thank you so much.
Before Guy came,
we were butchering
one to maybe two pigs
a week.
After Guy came,
it was like four to five.
And I came here
for the fried chicken.
[ Laughs ]
I learned
how to fry chicken
from my great-grandmother
Maude Marie Murphy.
The three "M."
Give me the rundown.
Real simple brine -- salt
and water for 24 hours.
And I debone
the chicken.
So, now we're gonna take them
and hit them in the brine?
Plop, plop,
fizz, fizz.
24 hours, and another 24 hours
in the buttermilk?
Yes.
Ready? Dredge.
Flour first
in the paper bag, salt,
lemon pepper,
and then onion powder.
Got it.
Granulated garlic,
then celery seed.
Then I give it
the old shaky.
Throw some music to this,
please.
[ Up-tempo music plays ]
[ Laughs ]
Let it set up
for about three hours?
Then we'll fry it
in the beef and pork fat.
[ Whistles ]
Look at that.
Ready for your life
to be changed?
Let's go, buddy.
Thigh.
None of that
fork-and-knife stuff.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
It's more complex
than the average fried chicken.
That's some damn
good fried chicken, son.
Thanks, brother.
Give me the rundown.
What happened?
Yeah.
We lost the lease
on Country Cat.
Country Cat
was open for 12 years.
It had a great run.
We had already focused
on this restaurant
for about a year
and figured,
"You know what? We're just
going to keep rolling."
So...
[ Exhales sharply ]
But Country Cat is still
in the airport?
Absolutely.
And what is Harlow?
Harlow is a plant
based cafe, juice bar.
Gluten free,
dairy free.
From fried chicken
to healthy juice bar?
FIERI:
It's a complete 180.
How long
did this ridic--
I mean, how long has
this fantastic transition been?
And I'm headed to the kitchen
to see it with my own eyes.
That doesn't taste like
your average stroganoff.
It tastes way better.
[ Laughs ]
Welcome back. Hanging out
in Portland at the Country Cat
with the crazy
butcher, Chef Adam.
Watch out for this chef.
He's nose to tail,
farm to table,
and his menu
is off the hook.
That should be
illegal right there.
FIERI:
That was back in 2013.
These days, they're not
so much nose to tail,
but they're still rocking
farm to table
at their new place, Harlow.
It has just all vegetarian
and vegan options,
which is sometimes
kind of difficult
to find in some places.
I like that it's
gluten and dairy free
and there's a lot of options
for me here.
I actually eat meat,
I eat gluten,
and I love this place because
you're not really missing out
on anything.
It's all delicious.
So flashback
to 2013.
Yes.
We're in a kitchen.
There was maybe
a little more of you.
Yeah. [ Laughs ]
A little less of me.
Copacabana, man.
You can do it.
I don't know if you can
handle it, though, bro.
And now we are plant-based
menu completely.
Plant-based, gluten-free,
dairy-free.
[ Exhales sharply ]
How long
did this ridic--
I mean, how long has
this fantastic transition been?
About two years.
Really?
Yeah.
What are you
gonna make us?
Okay, we're going to make
a little
wild mushroom
beef stroganoff.
Wild mushroom
See, I still can't
get past it.
I can't get past it.
Wild mushroom beef stroganoff
is what we're making.
[ Laughs ]
So we're going to start with
a little bit of vegetable oil
right here,
little rice oil.
We like to use that because
the smoke point, you know?
And that way, we can get
some nice caramelization
on this tempeh here.
Tempeh is basically
just a fermented soybean.
But not fermented funky.
No, not fermented
funky at all.
So I get a little bit
of caramelization on it.
Then I like to add onion,
a little bit of salt,
the garlic, pepper,
chili flake, fresh thyme.
So this is vegan
Worcestershire sauce.
Okay, because typically
Worcestershire
has a bit of anchovy
in it.
That's correct.
I get it to wear
it coats,
and then I immediately add
balsamic vinegar, white wine,
lemon zest, rehydrated wild
mushrooms, vegan sour cream,
so cashews, lemon juice, salt,
pepper, a little bit of lime.
Got it.
Red lentil pasta.
Let that reduced down.
That's gorgeous.
♪♪
The bad news is
that doesn't taste
like your average stroganoff.
It tastes way better.
[ Laughs ]
The mushrooms carry it
with that really nice meatiness.
The Worcestershire's
outstanding.
It's super
rich and delicious.
Oh, thank you.
MAN: This is fabulous.
The big chunks of mushrooms
are almost like chunks of meat.
They have the same texture.
It really, really is
a complete meal,
and I'm not missing a thing.
It's tangy. It's earthy.
It's creamy. It's just awesome.
You know, we really do focus
on comfort food, plant-based.
Lots of kale,
lots of vegetables.
I don't even believe
I'm speaking to the same guy.
Let me pull --
Is there a mask behind...
Is this going to be
a "Scooby-Doo" moment,
that I'm really --
"Ha-ha! We got you"?
MAN: A lot of people,
when they come here,
don't really realize
that it is vegetarian.
And it's guilt free.
-One Urban Bowl.
-the Little Dragon Bowl.
The Hawthorne Mac --
gluten-free and dairy-free.
Jackfruit wrap in the window,
table seven.
Oh, my God. The quesadilla --
it's so good.
We're making the walnut chorizo
for the quesadilla.
We have some crushed walnuts.
Coriander, paprika, cumin,
black pepper,
onion powder, tamari,
and a little bit of salt.
We like the coriander
in the cumin
because to me those really speak
to the Latin spice.
This is a gluten-free tortilla.
Non-dairy cheddar cheese.
So now I'm going to add
the vegetables.
Squash, onions,
Anaheim peppers, red peppers,
salt, chili powder, garlic.
Now I'm going to add
the walnut chorizo.
I'm going to flip it over
and let a toast
for about a minute.
Slice it into thirds like this.
This is our cashew
jalapeño cream.
And then a little bit
more of the walnut chorizo.
A little cilantro garnish.
And this is the walnut
chorizo quesadilla.
I can't even tell
that it was walnuts.
It was just like a meat
almost.
All the vegetables
were really nice and tender.
I really love the quesadilla.
There's a little kick of spice,
which is really nice and
enjoyable.
The world of vegetarian, vegan
food is wide open.
Oh, yeah.
And to know that this
is what your next step was
is very fitting
and you're doing it
in truly your chef style.
I don't think there's anything
that comes out of this kitchen
that isn't just up there
in the
Flavortown.
Hall of Fame.
Oh, thanks.
-Dairy-free, gluten-free.
-Dairy-flee, gluten-free.
You can't even say it.
I can't. Do you hear me?
Dairy -- Dairy --
[ Babbles ]
[ Laughs ]
What he said.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up,
a cafe in Cleveland...
Wow.
...making almost everything
from scratch.
Reuben,
table 20.
Mmm!
[ Laughs ]
I don't know that you should
accept money for these.
Bring us
your first born.
FIERI:
Not every joint I hit up falls
neatly into one of the three Ds,
and back in 2009, I found myself
at one of those spots.
What it's really about
is real people making real food,
kind of like this joint
here in Cleveland,
where it's all about farm
to table at Lucky's Cafe.
And lucky for us,
nothing's changed.
People that know
Lucky's love Lucky's
and we're so excited to have
Guy here to have it recognized.
And the reason we call
it Lucky's
is because we're lucky to have
Heather.
FIERI:
That's owner Heather Haviland,
who's spotlighting local
farmers and plucking ingredients
right from her garden.
Mint...
Yes.
...tarragon, oregano.
I love the message
that you're sending here.
People love to see
our cooks go out
and harvest things
out of the garden
and then walk back into
the kitchen because they know
that it's going to eventually
end up on their plate.
What are we making?
We're going to make the brine
actually for the brisket
for the Reuben.
Two gallons of water.
Kosher salt?
Kosher salt.
Then we got sugar,
garlic cloves.
Curing salt.
There you go.
You got to have a little
pink nitrate.
Peppercorn,
fresh ginger, bay leaves,
cinnamon sticks,
ground mace,
whole cloves, allspice,
red pepper flakes, coriander
actually
from our garden.
Oh, look at that.
Mustard seed.
And then we bring it
to a boil
and then let it
cool completely.
So we've got this big monster
piece of brisket.
Yep.
And then we're going to
pour our beautiful brine
onto there.
Mmm!
FIERI: How long will
we let this brine?
Seven days.
And then we're going to
pull it up
and move it out of here.
Into the pot.
Gosh, this is going to be
melt in your mouth.
Or melt in my mouth.
Some first thyme.
Which was out
in the garden?
Yes.
Carrots, onions, celery
and then fresh water.
So, you'll bring it
to a boil?
And then cover it
and simmer it for three hours.
Dig it, and then I'll eat
all of it.
You'll eat
the whole thing
with some rye bread
on the outside.
We make
our own rye bread.
Of course we make our own
rye bread,
as we harvest our rye.
Come back later, folks,
where we will get
the pottery wheel out
and she will start to spin
plates for you.
Don't challenge me.
FIERI: You make the bread,
you make the corned beef,
you make the sauerkraut.
Yep.
If we could make
the Swiss cheese, we would.
There's just not enough space.
Look at that.
I don't have
anything to say.
Mmm!
[ Laughs ]
I don't know that you should
accept money for these.
Bring us
your first born.
He was super appreciative
of the efforts that we make.
Oh.
She's so passionate
about making amazing food,
And this is all comfort food,
really.
The Reuben,
the biscuits with gravy,
the lamb burger.
It's terrific.
I recommend it for everyone.
Best lamb burger I've ever had.
We put ground pork
with the ground lamb,
garlic, shallots,
lemon zest, and orange zest,
and we bake them off.
We put the patty
on the flat top
drizzle it
with Mongolian barbecue sauce.
It's got tamari, hoisin,
sugar, sherry vinegar,
rice vinegar, fresh ginger,
sesame oil.
It just complements the lamb
so well.
We put a little bit
of our tzatziki sauce,
feta cheese,
toasted sesame seeds,
and scallions.
MAN: Table four!
MAN #2: The sauce
is really flavorful.
A little bit of a kick,
but not too much.
Like everything Heather does,
they're just amazing.
Absolutely amazing.
Now, what's amazing
is you.
[ Giggles ]
After the show,
like, we went
from being
a struggling restaurant,
now people are
opening businesses near Lucky's.
They named the park after us.
Things just built up around her,
and just now it's a warm,
glowing spot in a neighborhood
that is really built up
and supported.
That spotlight helped us
continue to do what we love.
The whole point
behind the granola
was to focus
on one of our favorite farmers.
We use a fifth-generation
Amish grain farmer.
To showcase all our products,
I developed granola in house.
Ta-da.
I feel like I'm taking a bite
of the Mona Lisa right now.
Mmm. Wow.
And we do griddle cakes
with their cornmeal.
It's a pretty standard
pancake recipe.
Sugar, melted butter,
buttermilk, leavening,
local cornmeal,
all-purpose flour.
We top it with some warm
blueberry compote
that has fresh
lemon juice and sugar.
On top of that, we put
a honey whipped cream
and drizzle it with lemon
verbena crema glazed.
MAN: Sweet corn
griddle cakes up.
WOMAN: It's like the perfect
crunch and sweetness,
but a little bit savory.
Just perfect for the morning.
Pretty much everything
on the menu is awesome.
It's a home run.
When it's all done, you'll have
the most delicious meal
you probably will have
in your whole life.
I love it.
Thank you.
Nice job.
Thanks, sweetie.
FIERI: Next, we're headed
to Virginia Beach...
Oh! See?
Nice!
...for some farm-
and ocean-fresh flavors.
All of our seafood
comes straight from the dock.
Mmm.
Just dynamite.
♪♪
I'm about two blocks
from the Chesapeake Bay
here in Virginia Beach
to check out a local favorite
that people walk to, drive to,
bike to, even boat to.
And when I was there in 2011,
they were dishing fresh
and local breakfast and lunch.
Whoa!
These days,
they've bought the whole farm
and are serving their fans
in two spots.
This is Citrus.
♪♪
We were just having breakfast
and "Triple D" came in.
And how's your
Bloody Mary?
Excellent.
Wonderful.
It was very exciting
to see a place
that we absolutely love
being recognized.
It is delicious.
MAN: Come on. Get it out,
guys. Let's go.
WOMAN:
I love this place.
It's the best breakfast in town
by far.
It's all fresh.
It's all local.
FIERI:
And for owners Lance and Cheri
Shores, it's all in the name.
Tell me about the name --
Citrus.
It all was the concept
of the colors.
Isn't that how
we always think?
The colors...
The colors,
the brightness.
...brightness.
Sunny,
it's welcoming and fresh.
And there's nothing fresher than
getting it from your own farm.
We're growing a lot of
our own produce now.
We're very fortunate to
work with our local fishermen.
All of our seafood
comes straight from the dock.
Beautiful lunch special.
You don't hear "breakfast lunch
joint" and say "oysters"
very often,
or soft-shell crab.
Guy had our
soft-shell Benedicts.
What are we into?
We're making
fresh hollandaise.
First,
with our egg yolks,
lemon juice,
hot sauce,
salt, water.
Got it.
Now butter.
Throw the supercharger
on that thing, man.
Lance wasn't going
fast enough.
Okay, tap out.
Go.
Here we go.
[ As Arnold Schwarzenegger ]
Yeah, you can hear it now.
It's like
a motorboat engine.
Now on low heat.
[ Normal voice ]Does he think
I'm going to keep doing this?
Man, you're on a roll.
Why stop?
So, emulsified
all the butter.
And the key is we stir
for about 15, 20 minutes
to get this stuff
thickening up on us.
Without cooking into
a big old nasty batch of eggs.
Yeah.
Now we're making
the batter for the soft-shell?
We're going to start off
with flour, pepper, garlic.
Lowry seasoning.
Our seafood
seasoning,
baking soda.
I batter
the crab first.
We dredge it in
our egg wash.
And then back it
one more time.
Then you can see
it's getting ready to pop,
so be careful.
Oh!
Oh! See?
Nice!
Popped him in the neck.
Give me a little
replay on that.
[ Slow motion ]
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Right to the neck.
The crab.
♪♪
Mmm.
Little tomato.
That soft-shell is
just dynamite.
Knocked it out.
Awesome.
After the show aired,
it doubled
our wait time.
Hi, welcome to Citrus.
We're on a nine hour wait.
Did you
bring a sleeping bag?
We were fortunate to open
a second location
on the same road.
You can get the same
quality food and each one.
MAN: They're constantly
mixing up the menu.
It's always changing.
Their potato pancakes --
they're unique.
They aren't the traditional
what people think
of a potato pancake.
Fresh shredded potatoes
and our homemade pancake batter.
This is
the pancake batter.
We're going to start with eggs,
buttermilk, salt,
baking powder, and sugar.
Okay.
Come on.
[ Grunting ]
Work it.
Work the muscle. There you go.
Alright. And we're going
to start it.
[ Laughs ]
Flour.
Mix that up.
And the oil.
And you're done.
And this will make
the famous pancakes?
This will make
the famous pancakes.
Then you combine that with
beaten eggs, parsley and onions,
salt, pepper,
shredded hash browns.
Cook them on the grill for about
four minutes each side.
Potato pancakes.
WOMAN:
They're excellent.
They're not like
your typical potato pancake.
You have that sweetness
of the pancake batter,
but you also get, like,
the potato-y feel to it.
WOMAN #2: You've got the savory
with the onions inside of it
and sweet with applesauce.
It's, like, delicious.
There's always something
fresh and new,
breakfast, lunch, or dinner.
Fantastic.
Do you need a job here.
I want to.
Please hire me, Lance.
I said it.
I still stand by.
It's just that good. Best
breakfast on the East Coast.
♪♪
Waffle, biscuit,
grape on the side.
FIERI:
But these aren't the only spots
serving up garden-grown
and farm fresh foods.
Griddle cakes
right there for you, sir.
We got plenty more places to hit
next time on "Triple D Nation".
[ Southern accent ] You know,
with a pocketful of pork,
just going to the river.
I don't know
where this all came from.
And I don't know why I just
start talking like George Bush.
I don't know what happened
there, either.