You know, people are asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint
don't you checked out
in that one city
when you were doing "Triple-D,"
How they do it?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
♪♪
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out
it was only the beginning
because "Triple D" joints
have been
blowing up and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip.
We're packing it in.
Oh, look at that.
From pork...
-Are you kidding me?
...to po' boys.
Good night.
A German joint outside Denver
scoring big with their
sauerkraut and sausage.
That's killer kraut.
A place in the Midwest
known for making Mod Mex...
Pork chop hitting the window.
Pick up.
When you come in,
ask for thunder pork.
...and in Los Angeles...
There's a real deal
po' boy, man.
....French Quarter classics
meet the Far East.
Boudin and Cajun egg rolls,
order up.
Familiar faces,
new places
and more off the hook flavors.
This is "Triple-D Nation."
♪♪
I'm about 20 miles north
of Denver, Colorado
in a little farming community
called Brighton
to check out a joint
that serving up
fourth generation
German family recipes
and something called
a kraut burger.
And since I was there in 2010,
they've started rolling
their recipes all over town.
This is Lauer-Krauts.
I was at Lauer-Krauts
when "Triple-D" came.
There is nothing better
than a Lauer-Krauts burger.
It's the same, best food ever.
When "Triple-D" was here
the first time,
I actually eat desserts.
I've tried all the desserts.
My favorite is the Kouga.
We've known them
for a really long time.
I was here the first time
when Guy came in.
-What makes it so good?
-The sauerkraut.
It's always yummy.
FIERI: Guess I'm not the only
customer
coming back for
Robin Trujillo's family recipes.
My dad's always made
his homemade sauerkraut.
Aunties'
bean and noodle soup.
Aunt Shirl's
chicken noodle soup.
You got recipes
from your mom's side,
recipes from your dad's side
four generations back.
-Correct.
-Thank you.
I talk about Lauer-Krauts
all the time.
I've never come across anybody
doing what you were doing
because everybody wants
to think about sauerkraut,
that stuff that comes
in a can.
And I say wait till you have
real deal, homemade,
handmade sauerkraut.
FIERI: You're going to hand
slice all this cabbage.
We are.
No, you are.
[ Laughs ]
I don't know where you got this,
but I'm getting one. Awesome.
That's my Grandpa Lauer's,
actually.
And what's it called?
[ Speaks native language ],
a cabbage shredder.
We gave Guy a --
This is like mandolin
gone wild.
[ Chuckles ]
I still have my --.
I still have it in my kitchen.
-Awesome.
-Still sits up on a shelf.
Great.
So, we shred all the cabbage.
We start adding it
to the crock,
then we salt it
and we start mashing it by hand.
It starts to juice,
and then we just keep adding
more cabbage, adding more salt
and you just keep frothing
until we have a full crock.
And how long
does sauerkraut ferment?
28 days,
and it's really mild.
Mmm, that's killer kraut.
It's not that harsh,
acidic, tough flavor.
It's really kind of sweet.
We make a lot of Kraut lovers
out of people
who don't like sauerkraut.
How do you explain to someone
what a kraut burger?
Homemade bread dough,
and we fill it
with ground chuck, cabbage
and our homemade sauerkraut.
Oh.
Oh, look at that.
Mmm. That's
like a meat pretzel.
Oh, yeah.
Where has these
been all my life.
-I'm glad you like it.
-Nice job.
Caramel apple bread pudding.
Pie up!
So, tell me
what's new on the menu.
This is our Perry special.
I'm Perry.
It's our German
sausage wrap,
Chili, sauerkraut
and onions and German sausage.
It's just like a wonderful mix.
We're going to take
our German sausage
and wrap them
in our homemade bread dough
We do the dough.
Flour, salt,
and in goes my shortening.
Whose recipe?
This is My mom's.
Got a cooking family,
you do.
We do.
Add our eggs.
Dry milk, then the yeast.
You're gonna knead this?
We knead it right
in the bowl.
You do this by hand
all the time.
Yep.
I got to get you
a mixer now.
[ Laughs ]
We do have a mixer now,
and it's amazing.
I'm going to roll it out
slightly bigger
than my sausage link
and wrap that little baby up
with a little seal.
And we bake them
for 10 to 15 minutes.
I'm going to smother
in Auntie's five-bean chili,
which is ground chuck,
onions, brown gravy mix
chili beans,
chopped tomatoes, branch beans,
seasoned tomatoes, white beans,
black beans,
light red kidney beans,
taco seasoning.
And we simmer it for an hour,
and it has sauerkraut,
grated cheddar
cheese and onions.
Okay.
Delicious.
That's dynamite.
Perry special
Perry special is comfort food.
The chili is just enough spice,
it's filling,
It's delicious.
I love their chili,
so adding that
to the German sausage wrap
is wonderful.
And then the sauerkraut
with all the flavors together,
it's just -- it's amazing.
It's on the menu
every Thursday,
Just on Thursday?
Thursday's chili.
That's gonna change Perry,
just so you know.
[ Laughter ]
What else you bring me?
Our green bean soup
is not new,
but it's hands down
our favorite soup.
We start with our ham starter.
TRUJILLO: Green beans, its's got
potatoes, a little water,
ham base, house seasoning.
It's salt, pepper,
garlic powder.
What are the little
nuggets?
They're egg dumplings.
Adding our flour.
Okay.
Put the lid on this.
Start it running,
stream in the eggs,
and I have to shake it.
Might be on
it's last pasta batch.
Little bit
of water till I see it forming.
There you go.
You can hear it.
That's it.
Okay.
Then I dump to the table and
form a ball.
And it rests
for a minimum 30 minutes.
Follow the ball,
follow the ball.
Okay, pick it.
[ Gasps ] Magic.
[ Laughs ]
And then we'll roll it
and cut one direction first,
and then the other way,
rough them up a little bit,
make them look more
like a dumpling.
And once our soup is boiling,
they're ready
to go into the pot.
We're going to let those boil
for about five minutes,
and we can add
our cream mixture,
There's cream in those?
Sour cream, heavy cream
and evaporated milk.
This is really strange.
I've had green beans
for a lot of things.
I don't know that
I've had it soup.
It's great.
Thank you.
Where's the recipe from?
Our grandma.
Excellent.
MAN: The green beans,
have a really nice crispiness.
The ham is almost like
a bacon flavor.
The cream really adds
a great element to it.
It almost makes it
like a chowder.
Auntie's green bean soup
is fabulous.
Dumplings, potato, cream,
vegetables.
What else do you need?
Nothing.
Then the show airs,
and then what happened?
Then we blew up,
just like you said it would.
Now we have a food truck.
You have a food truck now.
Yeah.
Awesome.
Where's the baby?
And you're prego?
I'm due next week from today,
actually.
Seriously?
Yeah.
ROBIN: he just turned nine.
Are you kidding me?
Yes.
The Kraut baby is now nine.
I'm so glad
I don't live in this town.
I'd be here
three times a week.
Nine years later,
we still get the same.
Well, I talk about you
all the time.
You're the real deal.
Thank you.
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up...
I gotta go back in.
...a Cleveland spot
serving
south of the border
staples...
-Whoa.
-With a twist.
Two pork chops al carbon.
Because one Guacamole
is not enough.
It just wouldn't be enough.
♪♪
As I travel the country,
one of the things
I learned on "Triple-D"
is there is great
Mexican food everywhere.
And in 2009,
I found it in Cleveland, Ohio.
Modern Mexican.
It's awesome.
FIERI:
And a place doing something
they called Mod Mex.
Three pork chops
hitting the grill.
Oh, yeah. This is Momocho.
Pick up, please.
I was here when "Triple-D"
filmed it the last time.
It is the most delicious
guacamole.
I mean, it's amazing.
Everything has been
consistently as good,
if not better
than it was 10 years ago.
Salsa trio pick up, please.
We had no idea what it would
mean for the restaurant.
Nothing compares to this.
Every time that airs,
there are a whole new set
of people who come in here.
WOMAN:
The first time that I came in
was because I saw
the "Triple-D" episode.
Everything tastes even better
than you can imagine.
I'd say owner Eric Williams
has a pretty
loyal fan base.
fundido in the window.
I need a runner, please.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
I'm eating with a spoon
it's so good.
FIERI:
And they're flocking in for his
take on Mexican classics.
So the inspiration behind this,
where did yours come from?
Always been a Latin lover.
♪ Mmm ♪
Fifteen years and --
I was was talking
about the food.
I got ya.
[ Laughs ]
I always really dug
the Latin flavors.
Modern Mexican is classic
regional dishes with a twist.
For instance,
we're taking guacamole
and putting a twist on it.
Blue crab, chipotle,
pickled corn.
That's got
to be a nice one.
Goat cheese
and roasted tomato.
Because one.
guacamole is not enough.
It just wouldn't be enough.
And the one we're making today,
smoked trout and bacon.
Mmm.
Avocados.
We're going to add kosher salt,
chopped garlic, lime juice.
Then we're going to
mash it, creamy, no chunks.
Next, we're going to add
our onions, jalapeno,
fresh chopped cilantro.
You say how jalapeno
or jalapeno
Jalapeno.
I'm from Erie.
[ Laughs ]
Chopped bacon, roasted
and diced poblano chilies.
Now we're adding the trout.
Flake it all by hand.
And mix it into guacamole,
right.
Fresh lime on top,
then our Cuban chips.
That's the way
to go with this.
[ Chuckles ] Whoa.
As soon as you put it
in your mouth,
boom,
there's the smoke.
Mmm.
That's great, man.
I'd write a book
about guacamole
if I was you
and just put that in there.
Just one page, open up.
Bop, there you go.
I'm done.
Everything here
is just top of the heap.
One beef brisket taco up.
I love the taquitos.
It's delicious.
I love this chorizo fundido.
It has a really
great flavor profile.
That pork chap.
I mean, are you kidding me?
Dude, that is righteous.
Thanks.
I mean, dude, this is...
It gotta go back in.
We're going to make the recipe
for pork chop al carbon with
smoke gouda tamala dumplings.
This is our smoked gouda
tamala dough,
butter, water and salt,
Dijon mustard.
Let this simmer
and then we're going to go ahead
and add cornmeal, flour,
grated smoked gouda cheese
and we're going to add six eggs.
Take a little scoop,
form them into dumplings.
We're going to get
a skillet hot,
then we're gonna saute 'em.
Add the pickled corn,
some chili --.
Tamale dumplings are ready now.
Now we're going to start
the pork chop.
We want to make
our own adobo marinade.
We're going to start by adding
chipotle, guajillo, ancho,
some cinnamon and toasted cumin,
salt and sugar.
And then for the liquid,
cider vinegar.
And then we're just going to put
these pork chops in the marinade
right before
they go on the grill.
Then we're going to top the pork
chop with our mole sauce.
Then We're going to start
with some onions, carrots,
bananas and raisins,
ancho chilies, some ground
cinnamon, guajillo chili,
ground cumin, oregano and thyme,
salts, toasted corn tortillas,
flour tortillas,
sesame, pecan and pumpkin seeds.
Canned green tomatillos,
tomato juice, water.
Now, we're going
to let it simmer
for about 45 minutes
to an hour.
Once this is finished,
we're going to go to the blender
and add some Mexican chocolate.
Garnished with a little sour
cream, a little micro greens.
It's ready to go, pork chop
al carbon Mod Mex style.
Dude, this is thunder pork.
When you come in,
ask for thunder pork.
SERVER: Pork chop al carbon.
Its's juicy, it's flavorful,
it's delicious.
It's rich, it's hearty.
The mole really adds
something special to the dish.
All I'm going to tell you,
Mr. Mocho,
you better put on the mask
and the cape
because what's going
to come through that door,
"Triple-D" is on you like
a title match.
[ Bell dings ]
WILLIAMS:
Once we were on "Triple-D,"
there was a line
at the door
before we opened.
Thanks to Guy, we had to add
another restaurant.
MAN: I love El Carnicero.
It's a great atmosphere,
just like it is here.
It's sort Mocho's
little brother.
You really can't go wrong
going to either place.
When you guys get a chance
to come,
where the stretch pants
and the muumuus.
Two pork chops, please.
Good luck, man.
Thanks.
Very happy for you.
Great guy.
You're gonna love it.
FIERI: Up next
in Los Angeles...
Wow.
...big Easy bites
in the heart of Chinatown.
Cochon de lait po' boy.
Come and get it.
You should really think
about opening a Cajun joint.
Cray mac and cheese up.
Po' Boy,
there you go.
FIERI: Back at 2015,
I heard about
this crazy spot in L.A.'s
old Chinatown neighborhood,
but it wasn't
a Chinese restaurant.
People that have never been
to Chinatown are flocking.
Cochon de lait po' boy.
Come and get it.
FIERI: And these days,
the name still fits.
This is the Little Jewel
of New Orleans.
Two hush puppies all day.
My family actually
discovered it on "Triple-D."
I'd just love the food here.
Coming here is like going
to New Orleans.
FIERI: Makes sense
because that's where owner
Marcus Christiana-Beniger
is from.
Whoo!
It really is a little jewel,
a little gem
in the middle of Chinatown.
[ Gong bangs ]
Specifically,
Old Chinatown.
-This is Old Chinatown.
-Old Chinatown.
You just figured
you'd come to Chinatown
and open up
a New Orleans joint.
We were looking
for a large kitchen,
which the older
Chinese restaurants have.
A large kitchen.
Yes.
Can, can, can, you,
you, you hear me, me, me?
MAN: No, no, no
[ Laughter ]
I brought a lot of crazy energy.
It's like party.
Camera one, camera two.
I need you to do that.
Camera one!
Camera two.
Camera one, camera two.
He wins.
We made Cochon de Lait.
First up, we're going to get
our rub going.
Our house
Creole seasoning,
dark chili powder,
some light chili powder,
cayenne with some salt.
We're going to take the pork,
make about 12 to 15 incisions
in slide whole
cloves of garlic.
This is going to get a chance
to break down a really perfume
all the way through.
Now green Tabasco pepper.
Oh, there you go.
Chicken stock.
And then we're going to
finish it off with our rub.
Nice, big fat coating
up on top.
You should really think about
opening a Cajun joint.
Cook it for eight
and a half to 12 hours.
What's up next?
Creole slaw.
We got cabbage, shredded carrots
some shredded white onions.
I'm going to finish that off
with some sliced green onions,
lightly toss
and then we'll add our dressing.
♪♪
Then we put our slaw directly
right on there.
So, a small sandwich.
And we're going to tong over
copious amounts of our pork.
And that's all she wrote.
And that's it.
♪♪
We're talking about a tremendous
amount of tradition,
and there's
a lot going on here.
It's a real deal
po' boy, man.
Real deal, delicious.
The Cochon de Lait
is still on the menu.
It's a best seller.
-What?
-The nose.
-You're good.
-Alright?
Po' boy.
Here you go.
The po' boy is to die for.
Creole hot sausage po' boy.
It's incredible to see
all the po' boys
Marcus came up with.
Orders up.
Flavors is what
he concerned about.
Soft shell crab supreme po' boy.
The two ingredients
are soft shell crab
and New Orleans style
barbecue shrimp.
Now, I personally like to season
them a little
with just a little Cajun
or Creole seasoning,
and it's sauteed in butter,
Worcestershire sauce, water,
lemon, minced garlic,
black pepper, beer.
What we're going to do now
is fry up a soft shell crab
for a couple of minutes.
We want a nice cheese base,
pickles.
Then we're going to put a little
bacon bits, sauteed Gulf shrimp.
Then I'm going to crown
the sandwich with my two crabs.
I come back with the Ramano
and do a little top garnish.
Hot sauce, red onions
and then finally
a signature remoulade sauce.
It's mainly a mayonnaise-based
sauce, Creole mustard,
dark chili powder, salt, pepper,
fresh brown garlic,
green onion,
chopped celery,
sliced kalamata olives,
olive oil, fresh lemon juice,
a Louisiana hot sauce,
Worcestershire sauce
and then Sriracha.
Mix this all together,
chill it for about 30 minutes.
Ready to serve.
Everyone asks for extra,
so you might as well
do it again now
Voila.
We've got your soft shell crab
supreme po' boy right here.
The crab is magnificent.
It's got a nice crunch to it.
The bread is not soggy.
I love it.
MAN: Delicious. All of the
flavors playing into one another
from the crab and the shrimp.
Very traditional Cajun flavor.
♪♪
What is Cajun Creole
food to you?
Cajun Creole food to me
is a balance.
You go on the Creole
side of things,
it's not as spicy,
there is more of a subtlety.
whereas Cajun food
is definitely spicy.
FIERI: Coming up...
it's outstanding.
We're not just cooking
the Bayou basics...
Cajun egg rolls.
...he's also throwing in a nod
to the neighborhood.
If that's all you served,
beeline down Chinatown.
♪♪
So, I got one for you.
Why would a dude
from New Orleans
that's been living
in Los Angeles
for the last 18 years,
decided to open
a Cajun Creole joint
in old Chinatown?
The answer, for the big kitchen.
This is bigger than
most restaurants on "Triple-D."
But the neighborhood's gotten
used to Marcus'
French Quarter flavors.
Order up.
It is like
I'm in New Orleans.
I mean, it has that feeling.
You've got everything.
I've loaded the majority
of my trunk with ingredients.
Oh, that's good.
That'll be fine.
Just as long as I
can write it off.
Alright, brother,
now we're into it.
Crawfish mac and cheese.
Mac and cheese.
So we're going to go ahead now
with our crawfish.
We're going to puree.
It sounds like
going to the dentist.
Yeah.
We're going to caramelize
some onions here.
We're going to add our house
Creole,
Cayenne.
Chili powder, salt.
We're going to take
our white wine,
we're gonna add it this
till it hits
a little bubble.
Cream, crawfish puree.
Word.
Gonna add
some Parmesan cheese.
[ Whistles ]
And then throwing in
some mozzarella and provolone.
Is this a normal portion,
or are we feeding
a bunch of people outside?
This is a normal portion.
There you go.
♪♪
It's not good.
It's outstanding.
If that's all you served,
be a line down Chinatown.
They say it's a favorite,
and it's probably
going to get more so.
Oh, you think?
After that, I mean,
it was crazy.
We had to have
a larger seating area,
and the dishes that Guy
tried in particular,
it just went crazy.
I'm sitting here with this
Alice Wong,
who was Miss Chinatown.
How do the folks in Chinatown
feel about this crazy Cajun
opening up this joint in
a little Chinese restaurant?
It's awesome.
It's definitely welcome.
And now he's using the hood
as an inspiration
for his latest Creole creation.
What could be better
than a boudin egg roll
Boudin-stuffed egg rolls.
These are extremely popular.
The egg rolls were
a complete surprise to me.
We're gonna start with beer.
Pork shoulder butt,
add our onions,
whole garlic cloves
and then finally some valiance.
Once that's good and brown,
we're going to add our liver.
This is going to cook for about
an hour and 20 minutes.
And then we grind the meat.
Next, take our ground meat,
mix it in the mixing bowl
with green onions, bell peppers,
chopped parsley,
cooked rice and salt and pepper.
Ad cheddar cheese
and jalapenos to our mix.
But then going to scoop the
filling onto an egg roll skin,
tuck in the two short sides,
roll it across like a burrito.
Deep fry the egg rolls
until golden brown.
And that is served
with our remillard,
a little Sriracha.
There you have it.
Deep fried boudin egg rolls,
the flavor of the meat
on the inside,
the crispiness of the shell.
It's delicious.
I think that it was cool
that they sourced from Chinatown
and then they mixed it with
their original Cajun flavors.
The sauce
that they paired with it
really brought out
the different flavors.
Wow.
Oh, outstanding.
I mean, really, dude
out of bounds. Good night.
♪♪
Guac pico in the window.
I need a runner, please.
FIERI:
But these aren't the only places
I can't get enough of.
Po' boy.
So we'll check in on more
next time
on "Triple-D Nation."
You get that?
You just see Guy double dip?
Oh, you think that's
interesting?
Watch this.
[ Laughter ]
Let me try it.
Bro.