Hey, everybody, I'm Guy Fieri
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives!
FIERI: This trip...
That's my kind of portion.
...we're going from authentic...
Talk about making it
traditional.
...to inventive.
That's not
what I was expecting.
We've got true Philly
cheesesteaks with a twist...
I'll take 10 to go.
Thank you.
...an Oklahoma City spot
going funky all the way...
This is getting weirder
as we go.
...and a Portland landmark...
This is when you're
going to show me the magic.
...putting out
Chinese specialties...
Outstanding.
...about as real as it gets.
Everybody's sitting here
watching
with their mouth
like this.
That's all right here,
right now
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
So I'm here in Portland, Oregon,
in the Hollywood district to
check out a Chinese restaurant.
Not just any Chinese restaurant.
No, this one opened
in 1949.
Now they've had several owners,
but most recently
they're delivering real-deal
Northeastern Chinese.
This is Chin's Kitchen.
♪♪
There's something very special
about this restaurant.
It's fresh, it's delicious.
And this is the di san xian.
It's not the Americanized
Chinese food.
This is right up there
with my mom's food.
FIERI: And they're Wendy Li's
mom's recipes,
which she started serving
when she took over this
more than 70-year-old
Portland icon.
This is Northeastern
Chinese food
from my hometown,
Dongbei cuisine.
What is the most popular
Chinese food from Dongbei?
The dumplings.
The dumplings
I would call "plumplings"
because they're so plump --
just delicious.
WOMAN: The seafood
and pork dumplings
have, like, a whole shrimp
in them.
I could just eat a whole plate
of them, they're so good.
We're going to make dumplings.
We're going to make the dough
for the dumpling.
Okay.
High-gluten flour.
And the water.
You just kind of mix until you
see it the way you like it.
Yes.
We knead it?
Yeah.
Let it rest.
Three times we're gonna
knead it?
Yeah.
So now we're gonna make
the filling. Pork butt.
Talk about
making it traditional.
I bet you it's going to taste
awesome.
You want to try?
You want me to --
Oh, I -- I --
Come on! So fast.
[ Sighs ]
[ Laughs ]
Little bit of water.
Shh.
Soy sauce?
Chicken base and salt.
Seasoned. So it does have
the Szechuan peppercorn.
Yes.
'Cause I get a little bit
of that tingle on my tongue.
I can see how smooth
and creamy that is.
And then a lot of leeks.
There you go.
This is when you're gonna
show me the magic.
[ Laughs ]
One, two, three,
four, five.
That's just ridiculous
how fast she does it.
I'm gonna screw this up.
One, two, three, four, five.
Good.
Not bad for a rookie.
One shrimp.
And pressed with both hands.
How are we going to cook them?
Six minutes.
This just in --
They're gonna be hot.
Oh, that's my kind of portion.
Come on!
Do you know
how to use chopsticks?
Of course I know
how to use them.
Oh, my --
I thought it was
dumpling on a stick. No?
[ Laughs ]
And what is in the sauce?
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
Are you okay?
You don't understand, this is
like my Kryptonite.
It's so good. Juicy.
You get the tenderness
of the shrimp.
Still get a little crunch
of the leek.
The noodle that wraps
the dumpling is the key.
It's that pillowy, soft,
but not too thick dough
combined with all of the
fantastic ingredients
inside of it and this
delicious dipping sauce.
Outstanding.
♪♪
Seafood and pork dumplings.
The dumplings are just like
little pillows of heaven.
And every time I come,
I'm like, "Okay,
today I'm going to get
the one kind of dumpling."
"And I'm not going
to eat them all."
Yeah, but I get the three kinds.
It's 15, and I do eat them all.
Yeah, I just had
that problem today.
So good.
MAN: She's got some dishes
on the menu
that nobody else in town makes.
Beef noodle soup is ready.
The beef noodle soup
is outstanding.
The noodles are handmade
and absolutely delicious.
FIERI:
Now what are we gonna do?
We are going to make
the noodles
for the beef noodle soup.
We made the dough.
Very similar to the dough
that we made for the dumplings,
except we used egg in it.
Yeah.
She does not need to go
to the gym.
And keeping it traditional.
You have got to be
kidding me.
♪♪
Beautiful.
I mean, it's like...
Oh, thank you.
You're putting on a lesson.
Everybody's sitting here
watching
with their mouth like this.
Now we make the broth.
Yeah.
Beef shoulder?
So we cook it in the hot water
there for a bit.
The impurities came out, and
then we drop it in here.
Can I see?
Kind of like
a Chinese 5 spice.
You're right.
[ Laughs ]
So this is going to cook
for how long?
Two hours.
And now we're going to make
the braised beef?
So this looks like
a cardamom pod of some sort.
But what do you call it
in Chinese?
[ Speaks Chinese ]
Real cinnamon.
Chilies.
Szechuan peppercorn?
Yeah.
And star anise.
A little bit of oil.
Ginger.
Green onions.
And the beef.
Top round.
Oyster sauce.
A little sugar.
Smells fantastic.
Chicken base
and a little water.
Let it glaze up.
Throw the basket in.
And how long
will this simmer?
The noodles -- beautiful.
The baby bok choy goes in.
Ridiculous.
♪♪
It's outstanding.
All those spices
really perfume
all the way through.
You get the nice, rich,
luxurious beef flavor.
The noodles are amazing.
Wow, wow, wow.
Unbelievable.
[ Laughing ]
Ah!
Beef noodle soup.
How is it?
Delicious.
The noodles have
a really nice texture to them.
The broth I think makes a soup.
It has a nice soy taste to it.
Something like this,
it's a treat.
Di san xian.
I lived in China
for eight years,
and when I moved back
to the U.S.,
I went out on a search
to find the best in Portland
and it brought me here.
This is like a temple.
You're doing it right.
Well done, my friend.
Thank you.
You're a sweetheart.
This is how it's
going to end, folks,
just right here like this.
Me and an all-you-can-eat
dumpling bar.
"Whatever happened
to Guy Fieri?"
"I don't know, but I know
he was up in Portland."
Up next, a jamming joint
in Oklahoma City...
I'm expecting to get something
really funky
and wicked and weird.
...getting groovy with chicken
and biscuits...
Delicious.
...and beating their own drum
with their signature dish.
You guys are really crazy.
♪♪
So on "Triple D," you know,
there are some funky joints
with some funky names.
Let's see -- Gorilla Barbecue,
Pies 'n' Thighs,
Naked City Pizza, Pinky G's,
I mean,
the list goes on and on.
But the truth is, folks,
it's not just the name.
These funky joints have got
to have fantastic food.
I'm here in OKC, Oklahoma City,
to check out a joint.
I hear the food is fantastic.
You know, when it's got Guy
in the name,
you know I got to check it out.
This is Guyutes.
Alright. We got a ring of fire
in the window.
Guyutes is this awesome,
like, Phish-themed bar.
FIERI: Phish, meaning,
you know, the jam band.
It's a weird little oasis
of cool here
in the middle of Oklahoma City.
Alright.
We got a pip in the window.
The food is absolutely
immaculate.
It's very creative.
FIERI: And it's all coming from
a couple of high school buddies,
Jarrod Friedel
and Wayne Perotka.
Guyutes --
What does it mean?
It's the name
of a Phish song.
And you're both big fans
of Phish?
We are.
Phishheads.
What's the food like?
Basically, we tried
to take normal things
and put a huge twist on it
where somebody would not be able
to recognize
what it was beforehand.
For instance?
The Guyute, which is our
signature dish.
And the Guyute for you.
It is a braised pork belly
on top of their mashed potatoes
with sautéed spinach on top.
MAN #2: And then this beautiful
basil whipped cream.
It's something
completely different
than what you get
at any other restaurant.
FIERI: Alright,
let's get into it.
The namesake
of the entire joint.
Yes, sir. We are making
the pork belly marinade
for the Guyute.
White wine, soy sauce,
lemon juice,
shallots, green onion,
a little bit of ginger,
garlic,
"galapeños."
"Galapeños."
Listen, these guys
listen to Phish,
they can call it
whatever they want.
And some lime.
That's a pretty big mix
there, pal.
We throw the marinade
on the pork belly.
That is a power marinade.
And we hit it
with orange juice.
And how long is this
gonna marinate?
Could be a day.
Could be two days.
We're gonna cover this
with some plastic wrap and foil.
Stick it in the oven,
five hours.
Then we're gonna braise it
in this actual liquid.
Yes, sir.
Bring it out.
Let it cool.
Let it congeal.
Yes, sir.
Alright.
Let's talk about basil creme.
This is getting weirder
as we go.
We came up
with these recipes,
then we lost
our recipe book twice.
So we had to completely
rewrite the recipe.
Time-out.
The whole recipe book.
I'm not sure
if somebody stole it,
if it got dumped in the laundry
or the trash twice.
Seriously?
So first we got our basil,
throw our milk in
and some salt.
Get that going.
Strain it.
Pour some heavy cream
over that.
Mash that basil.
And we'll take
our whipped cream gun,
give it a little shake.
And we've got
our basil whip.
A savory whipped cream.
Delicious.
Good basil
and a nice little move
on the salt.
You guys are really crazy.
Pork belly's done.
Gorgeous.
Next, we slice it up,
and that'll be
our pork belly pieces.
What's the final step?
We're gonna make
the spicy honey butter.
Show me the magic.
So we're gonna take
our honey,
dump all that butter
in there.
And a little cayenne.
Whoa!
Little bit of cayenne.
Heat up the honey
until it's all melted together.
Drizzle on the pork belly
and finish in the pizza oven.
Yes, chef.
Got it.
Alright. So we're gonna take
our mashed potatoes,
make three little piles,
sautéed spinach, pork belly.
That's a lot of pork
for a little bit of mash.
Spicy honey butter.
That's just to glue
our wonton chip on.
And we'll take
our basil whip.
This is a lot more refined
than I was expecting.
That's our Guyute.
Booyah.
♪♪
Every bite I'm getting is
a little bit different.
The pork belly's dynamite,
it's tender, it's unctuous.
The mashed potatoes
are creamy.
I love the honey butter
with a little bit of the heat,
but the wonton
with the basil whipped cream,
that's not
what I was expecting.
It is
definitely delicious.
Alright. We've got a Guyute
in the window.
Pork belly tastes like a big
chunk of bacon. It's delicious.
These little chips on top
with basil whipped cream,
I like to save till the end
as a dessert.
They knock it out of the park.
-All day long.
MAN #2:
The unique environment
and the different take
on the food, I think,
is what brings me back
every time.
I got Tequila
Sunfryz in the window.
Now, what else you do?
Because, I mean, I'm expecting
to get something really funky
and wicked and weird.
You know, we are,
We're Guyutes.
You know we are.
And the Disco Biscuit.
The Disco Biscuit captures
the true taste
of what it means to be
in the south.
It's candy in your mouth.
We'll see you in a bit.
You know we are.
What is this,
a prison fork, dude?
Absolutely.
That is...
I mean, you know, whoo.
Only the best.
Only the best for you.
Welcome back.
Hanging out at Guy Fieri's --
Oh, no, I'm sorry.
Guyutes in OKC.
See, I almost
got it right.
We have part
of the "Guy" right.
So these two dudes
named this restaurant
after one of their favorite
Phish songs,
Phish the band.
They have put together
a funky jam joint.
FRIEDEL: Plating our
catfish wontons.
It's very open and eclectic,
has food for any flair.
Roll the dice and see
what you have today.
You're gonna be happy
every single time.
You got the Disco Biscuit
in the window.
The Disco Biscuit's fried
chicken on a cheddar biscuit
with honey glaze and everything.
It's absolutely
out of this world.
Alright,
what are we into next?
We're gonna make our Disco
marinade for our Disco Biscuit.
First up
is our "galapeños" again.
They have their own language
evidentally
and their own style.
Got to have
culinary goggles.
Absolutely.
Okay, next up?
We've got our buttermilk.
So we'll throw our salt in
and pepper.
Blend that up.
So next, we're going
to take our chicken,
cut them
right down the middle.
Throw those into our bag,
pound these bad boys out.
So we're gonna brine
this chicken breast
in the buttermilk.
How long will this marinate?
At least one day.
What are we dredging them
in to fry?
Disco flour, of course.
Disco flour.
It's basically just flour,
salt, pepper,
paprika and garlic.
Then fry it up
until it's golden brown.
Alright, Chef.
So we're gonna make our
cheddar biscuits.
Let's see it.
Flour, butter,
and then we're gonna mix
that up
until it gets
a little bit grainy.
Do you take into account
how much may be thrown
out of the bowl?
Is that part of the recipe
development process?
It was on recipe number two,
but then on three,
we didn't do it so...
Well, because we don't
remember one.
Two is a distant memory.
Three, we're pretty
hard core on.
Absolutely, Chef.
Got salt, baking powder,
sugar, little brown sugar,
some cheddar cheese,
regular milk,
buttermilk.
Hang on a second.
Let me check.
Let's see if there's anything
else in the kitchen
we didn't put in.
We got some heavy cream.
Oh, heavy cream.
That's what else we needed.
I'm really surprised there's
no beer in that or something.
Maybe next time.
Yeah, think about it.
Put that
in the menu revision.
Mix this up how long?
Three to five minutes.
And then it's ready
to make biscuits.
Portion it in a ball,
then drop it
in a greased-up
muffin pan.
Then I'm gonna
stick them in the oven
at 350 for 45 minutes.
We're gonna take a little bit
of honey butter
and we're gonna make a
nice little design on the plate.
Put our biscuit down,
a little bit more honey butter
on there.
Wow. It's a big piece
of chicken. More honey butter.
Absolutely.
Drench that thing.
To top it off,
just a little bit
of green onion.
That's it, Chef.
There's more fried chicken
there
than there is
anything else.
The chicken eclipsed
the biscuit.
Great crunch,
not super spicy
but you get a little bit
of the "jalopano,"
a little bit
of the buttermilk.
Look at that.
Just soaking up
that honey butter.
Little sweet,
a lot of silkiness
from the butter,
delicious biscuit, light.
It's rich. It's tangy.
Well done.
SERVER:
Here's your Disco Biscuit.
WOMAN #2:
The chicken is really juicy.
And then the glaze
just kind of sets it off.
And the cheddar biscuits
are amazing.
It just all comes
together flawlessly.
Dragon sauce going,
finishing
the Franklins Tower.
Anybody I meet out of town,
this is the first place
I tell them to come to.
Really?
Absolutely.
Out of all the joints?
All the joints.
You can't top it.
FIERI:
You're just two dudes
doing the restaurant
the way you like to go
and enjoy a restaurant.
But it's your style.
It's your way and just
as funky as Phish is.
I think the band
should be proud.
Well done, brother.
Thank you, Chef.
This guy.
FIERI: Coming up,
a true Philly sandwich spot...
That's legit.
...buzzing up their brisket...
It doesn't get
much more scratch made
and handmade than that
right there, brother.
...and putting their own spin
on a classic.
It takes cheesesteak
to another level.
♪♪
I don't think that there is
a city in the country
or city in the world
that has a more
connected, iconic food type
than cheesesteaks
in Philadelphia.
And every time
somebody's coming here
or I'm showing up in Philly,
people say, "Where's
your favorite cheesesteak?"
That's like me saying,
"Who's your favorite kid?"
I mean, there's so many amazing
places with so much history
and their own style that when
I hear about a joint in Philly
that's doing cheesesteaks
with their own new spin
and attitude,
you know I got to check it out.
This is Woodrow's Sandwich Shop.
Walking in,
I need a shrimp po' boy.
This sandwich place
does its own thing.
It follows its own rules.
Woodrow's pork up
for order 12.
You're here
for Kevin's creations.
I get whatever he tells me
to get.
FIERI: And all that giving
and taking orders
isn't something new for chef
and owner Kevin Kramer.
So you served our country.
Thank you, by the way.
I really appreciate that.
You were in the Navy.
Yes, I got in and I said,
you know,
"I just want to be a cook.
That's all I want to do."
People want to fly planes.
People want to run
the artillery.
And you want to come in
and you want to cook.
Yeah.
Okay.
MAN #3: Kevin comes up with a
lot of cool, different dishes.
The cheesesteaks here
are my go-to.
Two whiz wits
in the window.
The Woodrow's whiz wit is the
best cheesesteak in Philly.
Does a truffle whiz along
with the cherry pepper relish.
It's that little bit of extra
that kind of brings
it really modern
and really fresh.
FIERI: Now, I'm
a cheesesteak junkie.
Anybody that knows
the hunch on "Triple D"
knows that it came
from Philly,
from eating
the cheesesteak.
You're elevating it
a little bit.
We're gonna be making
the Woodrow's whiz wit.
Start with our heavy cream.
You're making your own
whiz versus a lot of people
that buy it out of the can.
That's right.
Yellow cheddar,
sliced American.
This is another American.
It's Cooper.
You're trying
to get that nice meltiness.
That's a Philly term --
meltiness.
Aged provolone,
sliced truffle, salt, pepper.
Let that melt down.
What's up next?
Cherry pepper mayo.
Alright, let's go.
Mayo, garlic,
cherry peppers,
pickles, salt and pepper.
Blend this up.
Finally we build
the sandwich?
Yep.
We start with
our beef fat, steak,
onions, a little salt and
pepper, granulated garlic.
It comes this way.
This way or no way.
Pretty hard core.
Cherry pepper mayo.
The truffle whiz,
meat in the roll.
One more swipe
with the the truffle whiz.
That's all she wrote.
That's it.
Got to get
that hunch right.
♪♪
Oh, are you waiting for me
to tell you about this?
Oh, I'm sorry,
I was just in the moment
of enjoying
this delicious sandwich.
Onions are great.
The meat's not overcooked.
The cherry pepper mayo
brush,
that little bit of acidity
is really key and essential.
And when
we get to the whiz,
it takes cheesesteak
to another level.
Delicious.
I'll take 10 to go.
Thank you.
Woodrow's whiz wit.
This truffle whiz,
I could basically drink.
If there was a truffle
whiz trough, you'd be at it.
Yeah, I would.
And the bread
is always super soft.
It's amazing.
My buddy Jay here wrote for
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"
for nine centuries.
You know great cheesesteaks,
living here in Philly.
So give me the hunch.
Let me see
your best impression.
I've seen you do this
many a time.
Little neck roll there.
There you go.
Well done.
Got to go in
for a second bite.
You got to go in
You cram it all in your face.
He knows.
Spiced pork going down
for Cubano.
MAN #3:
The food is delicious here.
There's always something
new and different to try.
The coffee brisket sandwich,
it doesn't get much better.
Coffee, barbecue brisket.
Brisket -- good,
crispy oniony-potatoy
thingies -- good.
What's not to like?
Now what are we gonna do?
Our coffee barbecue
brisket sandwich.
Got it.
We're just gonna save
some of this fat.
This is a secret. I don't like
telling people this.
Okay, well, let's just keep it
between you and me.
Nobody will know.
Nobody's gonna know.
You're not gonna render
this down
and cook fries
in it, are you?
Not fries.
But we do cook onions
that we use for this sandwich.
Now we'll dry-rub it.
Salt, black pepper,
granulated garlic,
chili powder,
smoked paprika, brown sugar.
We're gonna rub
the brisket with oil,
put the rub on
and then more oil.
How are we gonna cook it?
Char the outside
and then it's gonna go
in the oven.
200 overnight.
Where's your coffee
coming in?
With the barbecue sauce.
Let's see it.
Butter here.
Shallots,
some garlic, coffee,
basic barbecue sauce.
You can use whatever you got.
Turned into a cooking show
just now
telling us
how we can do it at home.
Salt, black pepper,
bay leaf.
How long is this
gonna simmer, Chef?
It's gonna go
for about an hour.
Pull out the bay leaf,
run it through the blender.
Get rid of all the chunks
of garlic and everything.
Chunks.
Get rid of the chunks.
What do we have left?
We're just going
to make the sandwich.
Okay, that's the part
I came for.
Brisket's out of the oven.
We just slice this down,
put some coffee barbecue sauce
in here,
toasted brioche bread here,
yellow cheddar.
So with the brisket,
we almost burn this.
Right, because somebody
wants to clean that pan.
Yes. Onions cooked
in the beef fat.
The new shoestring fries.
We're gonna top it off.
That's it.
It doesn't get
much more scratch made,
handmade than that
right there, brother.
Do I have anything
on my face?
No, no, you're good.
No? I'm good?
Yeah.
Want to go out?
Yeah, let's go.
The brisket is super,
super tender,
really absorbs that sauce.
Coffee kind of imparts
a little bit
of that smokiness to it.
And the onions cooked
in the beef tallow,
that's legit.
Thank you.
I have
a coffee barbecue brisket.
WOMAN #3:
You get the sweetness,
you get the bitterness
from the coffee,
and then you have the delicious
saltiness from the onions.
It just, like, melts
in your mouth.
The house-roasted turkey.
It's just good food and that's
what brings people here.
I would come here
every day if I could.
FIERI: You're making each one
of your sandwiches
the way it should be made
and you're putting a lot
of your culinary discipline
into it.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
So was this a great road trip
or what?
But don't you worry.
I got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
Break it down
in Guy style.
What do you think
of the sandwich?
The shaved rib eye
is great.
It's a lot harder
than it looks.
It's easier to be
behind the camera, guys.
I'm having a blast with this
right now.