Alright, Hunter,
here's the game plan.
Months ago, you sent out a video
saying to people
you wanted to know
their favorite
"Triple-D" location.
That's right.
Remember that?
I do.
We want to know what
is your
favorite "Triple-D" joint?
People submit their video.
-My favorite...
-Our favorite...
-Favorite...
-Favorite Triple-D joint.
[ Munches ]
They had to describe
why they like it.
They're favorite dish.
They can be funny.
They could be sad.
They can sing a song,
whatever they want to do
to draw attention
to why this "Triple-D" location
should be on
America's favorite list.
People were very excited
about this.
Thousands of submissions.
You and I sat, you and I watched
and we picked...
I think,
some of the best.
Just look at how
delicious this stuff is.
[ Laughs ]
Those winners, Hunter,
each are going to get
a 1,000 bucks
and they're going
to get featured
on their own special edition
of "Diners,
Drive-Ins and Dives."
On top of that, we're not only
going to show you their video...
Hi, Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out.
...we're going to show America
that "Triple-D" location again
so they can understand
why they're on the list
of America's favorite
"Triple-D" joints.
We're on the same page?
Yes.
Oh, yeah.
FIERI:
Like on this trip,
for beef,
Mmm, that's killer.
...a poppin' treat...
That's ridiculous
...and sandwiches
that really stack up.
That's good eats
right there, man.
All served up with a soundtrack.
♪ They make pastrami pizza too ♪
♪ Incredible desserts
all for us and you ♪
[ Laughing ]
♪♪
Okay, we have whittled down
to the finalists.
I want you to remember we are
looking for the creativity,
the delivery.
We want to see
can they convince us
that it is one
of the best "Triple-D"
1,500 that we've done
in the last 13 years
and how much
do they love it.
Definitely.
Roll the type.
♪♪
Hi, I'm Caili.
I'm from Omaha, Nebraska,
otherwise known as
the of backbone
of Flavortown.
Beesneez of the Midwest
Festival of the funk.
The place everybody
is talking about.
The home of California Tacos.
That was awesome.
That's so awesome.
♪♪
These tacos are not something
you want to miss,
so you better make your way
back to Omaha.
Just ask Guy Fieri.
[ Laughs ]
MAN AS GUY: That is gangster.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and I approve
this message.
Oh, my gosh.
That is funny.
Priceless.
That was awesome.
That was great.
The deal is, Hunter,
a few of these folks
we're going to actually
give a Zoom call to.
You have to.
That was so good.
Alright,
from California Tacos,
we've got the owner, Brad,
and our winner, Cailin.
-Oh, no.
-What?
Cailin, how are you?
Hi.
-Sit up straight.
Her eyes got so big.
Cailin,
I got to tell you,
you and your buddies
did the best job.
Your video is outstanding.
The cardboard cutout
was hysterical.
[ Laughing ] Thank you.
I got to know, where did you get
the cardboard cutout?
My sister got me that
for my 21st birthday.
That is awesome.
We literally have it
sitting up always.
So, I'm always
at the party with you.
You're always
at the party with us.
What's your favorite thing
at the restaurant?
They have the [indistinct].
That's their specialty.
And any of them.
Now we can stuff it
with whatever we want.
Steak, chicken, beef.
The steak one's probably
my favorite,
but you can't go wrong.
In 1914, a Belgian immigrant
put up this building
and opened up a pharmacy.
He later passed it on
to his son.
Well, decades later,
his son retires and it looks
like the Bogard family legacy
is going to end on this corner.
Well, that is until the grandson
stepped up and said,
"I'll take a shot,"
move backed from Miami
and reopened the place
his way
as a taqueria.
Two beef [indistinct]
Serving all the classic.
Chicken chimichangas is great.
-[Indistinct]
-Great food.
FIERI: But the heavy hitter...
-One more beef.
...is something Brad Bogard
calls the California Taco...
There we go.
...Even though he discovered it
on a trip to the Caribbean,
It's a puffy shell taco.
-...that he brought to Omaha...
-Oh, lettuce.
...when he decided to
settle down and open this joint
in the old family building.
Beef taco coming up.
Just one hitch.
Never worked at a restaurant
before in my life.
Never worked at one.
Went down to Mexican
grocery store,
pollo, chicken.
They started giving you...
Yeah, they would point
at what to do.
Oh, there's
the tortilla recipe.
And that's how you start
making tortillas?
-Yeah.
-Give me the rundown here.
Start with wheat flour,
sea salt, baking soda.
So that's gonna give it
some of the leavening.
Vegetable shortening,
then some hot water.
Crank this baby up.
So once the dough works...
You gotta knead the dough.
Now, who taught you
how to do this?
Nobody. Me.
Throw my dough down
and put it
in the bun divider.
Look at that.
What is that?
Circa 1840?
Patented 1931.
Wow.
Into the slot.
Confinement ring.
Because you will
stay in there.
Pull it down,
then we hit the button.
Nice drop down,
activate.
-Really?
-Pull it up.
Wow. Look at those
little biscuits of friendship.
Now you go ahead
and roll these out by hand.
Exactly. Power it up.
And we don't do it
till we get your order.
So that's it. Now, this is what
we're going to use
to make the carne asada?
Steak.
Exactly.
Take it over the slicer,
put the spices together,
a little black pepper,
sea salt,
onion, salt cayenne pepper,
the oregano.
I like the seasoning
mix on that.
And then we grill it?
-Open flame.
Medium rare on both sides
so it doesn't dry out.
You got it. And after it cools,
then we slice.
If you slice it right away...
-Lose all the juice.
Exactly.
That's some
pretty good carne.
These get put inside here?
Yes.
That's a healthy little portion,
and that's it.
Bye-bye, let's fry.
-Let's do it again.
After it's done cooking,
you let it drain
a little bit of the oil.
You see what
she looks like.
That takes
a little something.
Look at that.
Lettuce,
we shred our own cheese here.
Queso.
Look at that.
That's outstanding.
Meat's got great flavor,
crunchy.
Look at all
the juice in there.
Mmm, that's killer.
Do I look like I just took
a bath in that or what?
Wow, that's good.
Nice job, man.
-I appreciate that.
-Good texture.
It's got a great taste to it.
Tasted homemade.
My mom didn't make them
this good.
That's kind of like
the seal of approval.
We've got to make
that tunk, tunk sound.
Tunk, tunk.
It's quick, it's easy
and it's great food.
It tastes really fresh
I want everything.
cook that day.
-This sauce is great
-Two kinds. The red...
Taste like somebody just shot it
with a tomato
and put it in the bottle.
FIERI: ...and the green made
with fresh opinions.
Look at that.
-That's good.
That's mine.
-That's money.
-All the way down.
-And Brad keeps serving up
all the favorites.
Beef hard shell tacos.
There we go. Burrito.
We got Nacho Supreme.
Really good.
FIERI: And when he heads back
to the fryer...
BRAD: Chicken chimi.
Love to make chimichanga,
a big deep fried burrito.
Exactly.
Maybe 20 ground beef.
Add the seasonings right after
we get the meat in there.
-Ancho.
-Ancho chili pepper.
-The chipotle.
-Sea salt.
-Okay.
-And onion salt.
Add a little water.
Everybody's in the pool.
You're going to let it sit here
and cook for what? Two hours.
So, that's cook down.
I mean that is like beef sauce.
[ Whistles ]
And this is the method, huh?
The spices help separate
that oil from the meat.
That's precise.
So let these cool down then.
Then what goes down?
Pinto beans. We stored
everyone by hand
looking for rocks.
The thing I love is that
when you were hanging down
at the Mexican market,
you've got some
really particular information.
Something like shorting beans,
which is quite an art,
very seldom done.
And then you cook the beans.
Mix the beans
into the ground beef.
Just a few flour.
Flour tortilla.
Put a little steam on it
so it's pliable.
Exactly.
Make it pliable.
So it doesn't crack.
A little refined beans,
a good amount of meat,
onions.
You know how I like cheese?
-Cheesy.
-Like that.
We gonna wedge
that in there again?
Then over the fryer.
-You've got it.
-There we go.
Plate it real quick.
Lettuce on there,
cheese, couple olives.
Let's take a gander
at that bad boy.
Crispy outside, creamy,
cheesy on the inside.
Mmm.
That's awesome, Brad.
Know what my favorite part?
A little bit of onion
you put in there.
Nice crunch,
enough cheese.
Well done, brother.
-Thanks for that.
Look at that.
He's got homemade flavors
you don't find
just anywhere else.
All the meat and cheese,
it's just good.
I don't know how they do it,
but it's amazing.
-You have a lot of choices.
-There's nothing else like it.
It's always, always good.
What is the future
of California Taco?
There's to be said
for staying small.
You're doing something right,
brother.
Here you go.
You win a thousand bucks.
And you're now on the show.
-Nice.
-Oh, my God.
-Thank you so much.
-Nice.
Thanks, Guy.
Good seeing you.
Awesome job.
See you guys.
-Alright, guys.
-Alright. More to come.
Who's America's
favorite diners,
drive-ins and dives?
We'll find out.
Don't go anywhere.
Oh, no. He's doing it.
Bring Flavortown
back to Charm City.
Peace.
Those girls
get free onion rings
next time they come in,
okay?
I think forever.
I think forever, yeah.
Holy!
Welcome back,
Hunter and Guy.
We're going through some
of the most outrageous videos
you've ever seen.
[ Screams ]
[ Rapid whistle ]
So yummy.
Because this was really
the best meat, boys.
I want the chicken taco.
Big time.
FIERI: These are people that
are trying to convince us
that their favorite "Triple-D"
location
is one
of America's favorites.
This is Copper Penny.
This is the place that we pulled
up in North Carolina
and there was a massive crowd.
Okay, roll it.
[ Rapping ]
♪ Philly cheesesteak's
how we eat it, babe ♪
[ Rapping ] ♪ Give me hand-cut
fries any day♪
♪ From Copper Penny
any day ♪
♪ Say the word
and I'm on the way out ♪
♪ That hot roasted pork sandwich
really slays ♪
♪ Yeah, we've got that
yummy-yum ♪
♪ The yummy-yum ♪
Copper Penny's got that
yummy-yum.
The yummy-yum.
♪ The yummy-yum ♪
♪ Copper Penny ♪
Peace out.
Oh, my God.
Oh, this is so creative,
I love it.
Oh, that was dynamite.
And I got to tell you
that those two get a call.
Alright, Hunter.
So there's our winners --
Callie and Lexi and Brian
from Copper Penny.
-Hello there.
-Oh, wow.
How are you,
Callie, Lexi?
I got to tell you girls,
impressive.
Brian, did you get a chance
to see the video?
Yeah, I sure did.
It was awesome to see.
Yeah, very good.
Such a great place.
You know,
we have such great memories
of coming to Copper Penny.
Girls, what's your favorite
thing at the restaurant?
I like
the Philly cheesesteak.
You like Philly cheesesteak?
People gonna love that.
And I really
like the grilled cheese.
The bread's so good.
The bread is fantastic.
We go to our local baker
every day.
He makes it special
for us.
Those girls
get free onion rings
next time they come in,
okay?
I think forever.
I think forever, yeah.
Nice.
♪ Copper Penny, love the way
you cook it, babe ♪
♪♪
So, I'm here in Wilmington,
North Carolina.
A lot of people know
this is the port city
because of the Cape Fear River
and all the history of pirates
in the Civil War.
And a lot of the folks they know
for all the great beaches
and the vacation spot.
But I'll tell you what,
it's going to get known for --
a funky little joint
that's serving up
simple but real deal food.
This is The Copper Penny.
♪♪
Drop a crab cake sandwich
and one steak
and bacon sandwich, please.
The food's amazing.
Large buffalo wings.
It's pub food,
but it's inventive.
Courtesy of Brian
and Christine Cadwallader,
a husband and wife duo
bringing some brotherly love
to this southern spot.
I heard that you guys
lived in Philly,
then you came back here because
you wanted to be warm again,
and then you thought you'd
open up your own
Philly-esque joint.
BRAD:
We needed a place where my wife
could go and get some good food
that I could watch the game,
have some wings.
So you designed your own place
that you wanted to go to.
Absolutely.
FIERI: And while their
signature sandwich
pays homage
to their Philadelphia roots,
it's name for the street
where it served up.
Got the 109
chestnut chicken sandwich,
The 109 chestnut chicken
is one of my favorites here.
Got Mushrooms and cheese
and chicken.
It's delicious.
We're going to take
some chicken breast,
thin,
little oil on there.
We're going to throw
a little dried oregano,
dry basil, black pepper,
granulated garlic
and some kosher salt.
And then we're going to
cook them off in the oven,
350 for about
20 minutes or so.
-Okay.
-Soon as they cool off,
we slice them thin on a slicer,
finish them on the flat top.
Alright. Let's hear about
the famous onion rings.
Oh,
these babies are amazing.
-Give me a rundown.
-Some all purpose flour,
granulated garlic,
black pepper, kosher salt
and some cayenne pepper as well.
-Got it.
And then we're going to make
our milk wash for the onions.
Half a gallon of milk,
half a gallon of buttermilk.
And my favorite part,
a pint of beer.
Keeping the batter
nice and cold. Great technique.
To double dip,
we're going to go in the onions,
milk wash, onions,
milk wash twice.
Onions, milk wash, onions,
I got it.
-So we've got some jumbo onions.
Soak them in this beer batter
for a second.
Going into our flour mixture,
right back into the milk wash.
Onions, milk wash.
Twice.
Then it goes directly
to 350-degree fryer
for approximately
three minutes.
Oh, that is great
onion ring.
Alright,
got a chicken,
caramelized onions,
sauteed mushrooms.
-Little provolone.
-Yes, sir.
Steam that for a second.
Toasted the bread,
add our chipotle mayo.
Little Philly cheesesteak
move going right there.
-Yes, sir.
-Huh?
♪♪
The bread is fantastic.
We go to our local baker
every day.
He makes it special
for us.
Thin crust, great texture,
mushroom, onions,
all tied together, very simple,
but done very right
and delicious.
Keep this onions rings
away from me.
I never want
to see them again.
The onion rings are the bomb.
Big, juicy, tasty.
In terms
of a chicken cheesesteak,
how do you think
this does?
I think it stacks up
to the ones
in Philly for sure.
-Seriously?
-Yeah.
FIERI: And they're making sure
this sandwich
keeps getting long
after it's gone.
MAN: When you buy the 109
chestnut chicken,
they donate $1.09
and you get it on Tuesday.
So basically you give
all the profit
from the sandwich
and give it away.
Yeah, we live
in a great community,
so it's our way
of giving back.
FIERI: Well, they're giving back
with the chicken.
They're paying the flavor
forward with the pork.
The hot roast pork sandwich
with hand-cut fries.
Thinly sliced pork
with crispy onions,
and it all just melts
in your mouth.
We're going to take a whole pork
loin, add some kosher salt,
black pepper,
granulated garlic,
FIERI: Sear it off,
give a little caramelization.
Finish in the oven.
350 for about an hour.
-Okay.
As soon as she cools,
sliced nice and thin.
Alright.
So, now what are we making?
We are doing
our sauteed spinach.
Got it.
Going to start us off
with a little olive oil
in a pan,
lots of garlic.
Sauté this down
for a second.
Drop the spinach,
crushed red pepper.
I knew why I liked this.
-Black pepper.
Very similar to a handmade
sauteed spinach at the house.
Kosher salt.
If that's a little
white wine...
That's it. Chef.
We eat this spinach three times
a week at my house.
Then we're going
to finish it off
with a little grated parm.
I'd just order
a side of that.
Hand-cut fries.
Cut, soaked, double fried.
Hot as can be.
See that fry? Mmm.
We got our shaved pork,
some spinach.
-A little provolone?
-Absolutely.
We got our bread-roasted
garlic aioli,
and then we kick it off
with a Oju we just made.
Oh.
Man, you can get that garlic and
spinach in there big time, huh?
Yeah, buddy.
Bread's dynamite,
pork's not dry,
the spinach
has got a ton of garlic in it,
which is perfect.
Don't come in and say,
"I don't want any spinach on it.
Just give me
a pork sandwich."
So far, spinach is leading
by a bunch.
A bunch of spinach.
[ Chuckles ]
♪♪
I can.
It's my show.
Hand-cut fries,
homemade slaw.
If I lived here, minimum,
once a week, I come here.
I appreciate that.
You like
a Philly cheesesteak,
you're gonna love that.
That is outstanding.
I appreciate it.
Thank you.
Girls, you did a great job.
So congratulations
on winning.
Congratulations on 1,000 bucks.
Well done, ladies.
-Nice.
Exquisitely delicious.
-Next up...
-Because it's good as heck.
[ Laughing ]
Just like all the levels
of righteousness.
I'll take three
of those to go.
Yee-haw!
[ Laughs ]
HUNTER: Alright,
welcome back.
My dad and I asked,
we want to know,
what is your favorite
"Triple-D" joint?
HUNTER: And you answered.
Food is just phenomenal.
It is the "Triple-D" spot
to visit.
HUNTER: We're diving into
more of America's favorites.
Okay, next up,
Pieous, Austin, Texas.
Let's see
what these guys got.
We nominate Pieous as your
favorite "Triple-D"
joint of all time.
Why?
Because it's good as heck,
good as heck our version.
Good as heck.
♪ They make pastrami,
pizza too ♪
♪ Incredible desserts
all for us and you ♪
♪ Pastries,
scratch-made bread ♪
♪ Hand-pulled... ♪
He's boxing
from the back.
♪ There's so much more to it,
really great owners ♪
♪ And amazing staff too ♪
♪ They work so hard,
it's what they do ♪
♪ To find the community,
me and you ♪
♪ They pay it forward
in trying times ♪
♪ We love them so much
we made a rhyme ♪
♪ We love our Pieous,
yes we do ♪
♪ Ask anyone around,
they will tell you too ♪
Oh boy.
♪ Ring a bell,
"Triple-D" fan favorite ♪
♪ Because it's good as heck ♪
-Nice.
-[ Laughing, stuttering ]
Ring the bell
because it's good as heck.
[ Laughs ]
I just got to watch it
one more time.
Ring a bell,
"Triple-D" fan favorite
♪ Because it's good as heck ♪
[ Laughs ]
I want a T-shirt, Pieous.
♪♪
So, here on the southwest side
of Austin, Texas.
Now a "Triple-D" statement
that we always make
is don't judge a book
by its cover.
But what happens
when you go to a place
and the name it says pizza,
but they're known
for awesome pastries,
amazing bread
and killer pastrami?
We're about to find out
because this is Pieous.
House on fire
and a margarita.
MAN: You would think it's
a pizza place or maybe a bakery,
but it's so much more.
One pastrami
chili fixings on the side.
I just feel like it's a gem.
Megan is a producer for us
on "Guy's Grocery Game."
One of my favorite chefs,
You really know
a ton about food.
MEGAN:
I think what's going on here is
high-end chef-driven food.
From two people who didn't
actually start out as chefs.
We worked in the music business,
but we didn't like what we did.
Did you become lawyers
and accountants?
-Yes.
-Okay.
we talked about
doing a restaurant forever.
FIERI: Finally,
Josh and Paige Kaner went for it
and started serving up
the food they love.
You make the pizza,
you're baking bread,
you're doing pastrami.
JOSH: Juicy pastrami sandwich,
table 20.
They're pastrami is in a world
of their own.
The sourdough bread is awesome.
It's art in itself.
The pastrami
that I hear is to die,
give me the rundown,
brother.
We have to cure it for 20 days
before we smoke it.
Most people are happy
with seven.
♪ Overachiever ♪
We're going to build
our brine.
Kosher salt, curing salt,
a little bit of hot water.
We're going to dump a bunch
of water to cool it down,
cover this, pureed garlic.
That much garlic...
-Onion.
-...for one brisket?
Yeah.
Black peppercorn.
Put it in the deep cooler.
20 days later, we're going
to make our rub.
Black pepper,
paprika, garlic, coriander.
This is going to get rubbed
on here liberally.
Let it sit for about a half hour
for the juices
to kind of come out
and grab the seasoning.
How long on the smoker?
10 to 13 hours.
depending on the size.
Depending on the size.
You do the feel.
Yeah. We're going to make
a pastrami sandwich.
I like it juicy.
Make it nice.
Hoo-hoo!
Look at the bark on that.
Sourdough,
whole grain mustard.
Oh. So you're going full
on -- Deli with this.
You be the judge.
Couple of kosher
pickles,
house pickled onions.
That onions has
a nice little kiss.
♪♪
Delicious bark,
it's got the right pepper,
got a touch of coriander,
not over salty,
which is always the curse.
You got this thin bread
and it's not coming apart.
You shove it in
your face hole.
The piece de resistance
is without question
the pickled onion,
which cleanses the palate.
That's as a badge of honor
right there, buddy.
I'll take three
of those to go.
The pastrami will knock
your socks off.
MAN:
Reminds me in New York where
there's more meat than bread.
And the mustard just adds
enough that tang.
When my friends
come in from out of town,
I told tell them, "Hey,
I'm going to take you
to get some
life changing pastrami
and some good pizza."
JOSH:
I got the fat queen going in.
They got this incredible oven
imported from Italy.
I got a margarita.
You just come for the pizza.
Sometimes we come
just for the desserts
because the desserts
are amazing.
JOSH: Caramel roll going to 10.
The caramel roll's delicious.
That croissant-like crisp
outside, gooey inside.
It's like genius-level pastry.
We're now making
croissant dough.
81 layers.
Start with
a sourdough starter,
high gluten flour, sugar, milk,
diastolic malt powder.
This is going to give
a good flavor and good color.
Butter and water.
My mouth to starting
to water.
Let it relax,
add the salt.
We're going to run it
for about five minutes.
-Okay, where we are?
-Caramel sauce.
We're going to start
with butter, brown sugar,
little water, a little bit
of corn syrup, heavy cream,
pinch of salt,
vanilla bean paste.
Okay, so we're going to
let this cook down.
We're going to start
with cinnamon, brown sugar,
Texas pecans,
roll this into a log.
Were you this good
of have an accountant?
-No.
-[ Laughs ]
Welcome to
the Flavortown Zoo.
Today,
the cinnamon roll anaconda.
Then we're going to market
so we know where to cut it.
Next up,
we have the caramel.
Oh, great caramel.
add some more pecans
to the bottom
and stick them in.
This exceeds
what I've seen before.
This is not even close
to being done.
-Of course.
-We have to proof this now.
He's not for real,
ladies and gentlemen.
I'm being punked.
So, now they're
out of the oven.
-Got it.
-Do a flip.
You want to get a good release.
That's sugar napalm.
It's going to hurt.
Mmm! Aww!
[ Laughs ]
Wow.
Delicious, nice little bit
of salt, great vanilla,
sugar to cinnamon balance
fantastic,
flakiness of the dough.
I mean, just like all the levels
of righteousness.
One of the most unique,
delicate pastries
that I've had.
That right there is
what every
cinnamon roll wants to be.
That's crazy.
Here are the caramel roll.
WOMAN:
I dig right to the middle.
You got to have
that crunchy part of it,
And it's so good,
it's so sweet.
The nuts on the top
just really set it off.
Pastrami chili.
MAN: I never leave here with
food because we wind up
eating it all.
That's how good it is.
I'm really impressed
that you took
that discipline
and responsibility
of being an accountant, whether
you can taste it,
everything that I'm seeing you
do is of the next level.
Well, done. It's delicious.
-Thank you, Guy.
Wrap up my cinnamon roll and get
me my pastrami
because I'm out of here.
♪♪
FIERI: Up next.
If you're
in Charleston area,
you got to check this place out.
The best "Diners, "Drive-ins
and Dives" restaurant ever.
I can't stop eating a banana.
Don't tell Kelly and Craig,
but if I win this,
I'm giving the money
right back to them.
Ah.
That's awesome.
"Triple-D" fans
love their restaurants.
This guys got it.
Roll 'em.
Hey, Guy and Hunter.
Yeah!
[ Laughing ]
Welcome back.
Hunter and I are here.
We've got fantastic submissions
from "Triple-D" fans
that are voting for
their favorite
"Triple-D" restaurant
to be America's favorite.
♪ Yeah ♪
Okay, roll it.
CINDY: I'm Guy Fieri.
I don't have a convertible yet.
I know who you are.
Do you know who I am?
I'm Cindy, and I
was on the episode
where you came out
to Wilma and Frieda.
Wilma and Frieda,
right smack in the middle
of the Coachella Valley
in the beautiful city
of Palm Desert...
-I remember this.
-...one of my very,
very favorite places.
There's literally nobody else
that I would take
a bite of something on TV.
But their meatloaf is that good.
The proof is
in the meatloaf.
Guy Fieri,
I know you didn't forget
these housemaid pop tarts.
Besides their amazing food,
what really...
It's a great place.
Really nice folks.
-...and their culture
-In a mall.
[In a mall?
-On the second story/.
Don't tell Kelly and Craig,
but if I win this,
I'm giving
the money right back to them
to help them
during this tough time.
That's, yeah, nice.
This has been a terrible time
for the restaurant industry,
and you're such a fan.
You're going to donate
the money if you win.
Classy. Love it.
And that's what "Triple-D"
fans are.
They love their restaurants.
♪♪
Can you tell me
where Wilma and Frieda's is?
That way?
Thank you.
Well, I guess the '68
can't pull right up to this one.
I'm here at the gardens
on El Paseo
in Palm Desert, California.
And I'm looking for
this funky joint
where a brother and sister
have teamed up
to give you
an eclectic breakfast
and lunch experience
you won't forget.
This is Wilma Frieda.
[Indistinct] French toast.
You like to think of it
as the rising star
of the Coachella Valley
when it comes to restaurants.
Meat loaf and eggs, over easy.
comfort food,
but with a delectable twist.
FIERI: The kind of food the made
Kelly McFall
ditch her corporate life
and recruited brother
Craig Alexander
opened a joint named
after their grandmothers.
And now they're dishing
down home to a high end crowd.
El Paseo's kind of known
as the Rodeo Drive.
Oh, this is that
the kind of place.
We were kind of
the casual place for me.
That meat loaf ready, sir.
-Who am I cooking with?
-Chad's our chef.
He is amazing.
And we have Camilla's
our pastry chef.
So, I get
to cook both of them?
SERVER:
Short rib melt on sourdough.
The short rib melt
is incredible.
MAN: You can't get it
anywhere else.
Definitely an experience
in itself.
Well, what are we making?
We're going to braise the short
rib for the short rib melt.
So we start out
with the bone-in short rib,
black peppercorn,
garlic cloves, bay leaf.
A lot of bay leaves.
Ground thyme,
kosher salt,
a whole gallon
of burgundy red wine.
Burgundy. Is it because
it's out of the box?
[ Laughs ]
Now you're going to get
all splashy, splashy chef,
All your blue shirts
get splashed.
Are you a fan of it?
Yeah, I'm a fan
of all of your blue shirts.
You've got some issues, son.
This is a strong beef base,
and we braise it overnight
at 250 degrees.
I like the way this is going.
Alright, boss,
what are we into now?
We are making pickled
red onions.
Red wine vinegar.
-Water.
A whole bunch
of coriander.
Black pepper, crushed
red pepper flakes, bay leaf.
You and your bay leaf.
It's like me and blue shirt.
Kosher salt.
I let it come to a boil.
Onions go in,
steep for an hour and a half.
Short ribs are finished
braising.
That is pull apart short rib
all day long.
-Right.
-Strain the [indistinct]
We'll mix the whole pot.
That is music to my ears.
And I reincorporate it
back into the meat.
[ Sighs ]
Now we start
to make this melt.
I put oil down,
typically sourdough bread.
-Alright
-Monterey jack cheese,
six-ounce portion
of short ribs,
pickled red onions,
sauteed arugula
right behind it.
-Got it.
Cook it all up,
added it together.
♪♪
Nice move.
That's like Fonzie, dude.
This is a Fonz move.
You, Cunningham.
Short rib's tender.
arugula's really nice touch,
but the kicker that makes you
want to take another bite
of the sandwich
each time is what?
[Indistinct]
This guy's got it.
Well played, my friend,
give me one more Fonzie.
Hey.
It's got
a lot of flavor.
You really taste, like,
the wine in there.
And so moist
and the meat is just amazing.
-You don't hear moist enough.
-You don't.
I'm from more moist.
The hand says he is.
We'll save room for dessert.
WOMAN: The pastry selection
is amazing.
I grabbed cookies and cake pops
and things for my kids.
I've had several breakfast
tarts here.
They're all delicious.
Tell me if I get sugar
on my face.
It's got really great
fruity feeling.
Very nostalgic.
So, today we're making the Wilma
and Frieda breakfast tart.
OK, let's get into it.
We're going to start
with the blueberry compo.
I got fresh blueberries,
some lemon juice
and granulated sugar.
We're going to let
that cook down.
In the meantime,
we're going to make a slurry,
so this is cornstarch
and water.
There we go.
It's going to get thick
and then it's going
to cool down
and we're going to use
that in our breakfast tart.
We're going to make
the dough now?
-Yes.
-Awesome.
You notice my blue shirt?
-Yes, I did.
Thank you.
Great shirt.
All-purpose flour,
sugar, kosher salt, nutmeg,
some vanilla extract,
shortening and butter.
-So we're making grabble.
-Yes.
And we have ice water.
So this is all going
to pull together
and we're going
to roll it out.
Don't get any of it
on my blue shirt.
Don't you start.
I won't, I won't.
Alright.
Down to about a centimeter,
And then we're going to use
a pastry cutter.
Time to party.
No we go the other way.
And this is where the blueberry
compote comes in,
and we take one more piece
and some egg wash.
We paint it like Picasso.
-Okay.
-And use pastry crumper here.
We got to make sure we seal it.
That's going to glue it shut.
-Yes.
-What are we baking these at?
-350.
-For how long?
10 minutes, and we're going
to pull it out,
put milk on it and put it
back in for 10 minutes.
-And that creates the glaze?
-Yes.
Dig it.
Learning something today.
Pick a card, any card.
This one.
You're playing lead dog
on this?
You're in my house.
Ooh. Alright.
That's what do you think I want.
This is our frosting here.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What happened?
This is a sprinkles.
We finish it with powdered sugar
and some fresh blueberries.
-Good seller?
-Yes.
♪♪
You won't like these.
Never come here.
[ Laughs ]
That's ridiculous.
It's shortbread
meets awesome pie crust
meets a morning
breakfast tart.
Wow. The compote in the middle
is really great.
That's the key to it.
Just delicious.
Nice job, chef.
-Thank you.
WOMAN: It's the perfect
amount of sweetness
with a little bit
of salty crust there.
-Like grandma's homemade pie.
-Amazing.
Come on, come on.
Blackberry custard
French toast.
Wilma and Frieda's is one
of my favorite breakfast spots.
Tops your day off
in a great way.
I'm always a fan of seeing
brothers and sisters
work together, and to see
that you honor family.
Your grandma
still with you?
No, they passed away.
Did they know
about the naming?
Wilma did.
That's why it's Wilma
and Frieda's.
Yes.
We added Wilma first.
-They're really good.
-Wonderful, delicious.
FIERI: Up next...
That's how big it is?
[ Horror chord plays ]
Jimmy's.
That's ridiculous.
♪ Yummy, chef ♪
Favorite!
So, this is what
we're doing.
we're hanging out here
in the kitchen
at the Fieri house
watching some
of the greatest
videos we've ever seen,
The food here
is absolutely killer.
Who's America's favorite?
Role it.
Honey, I'm hungry.
Well, then what
do you want to eat?
I don't know.
You want to order
a pizza?
No.
Tacos?
Well, then we could order
some Chinese.
No.
Well, then how about
Jimmy's famous seafood?
[ Horror chord plays ]
Jimmy's.
Where'd you go?
[ Laughs ]
-Nicely done.
-So good.
Well, that was quick.
Jimmy's famous burger
and the crab cake
all on the same bun?
Yum.
Oh, my gosh.
That was awesome.
[ Horror chord strikes]
Jimmy's.
♪♪
I'm here in Baltimore, Maryland,
about 10 minutes from downtown
to check out a joint
where a family lives
on the second floor --
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm getting confused.
That was 40 years ago.
Now they've turned it into
a super-successful
seafood restaurant
that seats over 500 people,
and the crab cakes are the bomb!
This is Jimmy's Famous Seafood.
Seafood Ecstasy up!
Their seafood
has always been top-notch.
It's a family business.
The recipes have
been carried on for
a number of years.
FIERI: Those recipes
come from Jimmy Minidakis,
who opened this place in 1974,
raising his family
on the second floor.
And since his passing,
his sons and wife, Foula,
are carrying on his legacy.
Got mussels up!
It's a blessing
to carry one man's dream
that started with nothing.
-You're the chef?
-Yes.
You're the manager,
front of the house,
and you're the boss.
-Backbone.
I know who the boss is.
Crab cake up!
MAN: It's always worth a trip
to come down to East Baltimore
and have a Jimmy's crab cake.
The crab cake is literally
the size of a baseball.
All lump, no filling.
Now, whose recipe is this?
Father's.
So we're gonna take about 30
eggs, give them a little whisk.
Next up -- mayonnaise.
I'll mix that up.
We're gonna go with
our Worcestershire Sauce.
Worcestershire.
Okay.
Black pepper.
Rock salt.
Okay.
House seasoning.
Not too much.
Dry mustard.
Wet mustard.
And next up?
Now we're ready to start making
the crab cakes.
The crab is local from
the eastern shore of Maryland.
So what goes first?
First, couple ladles
of the sauce.
Chopped bread crumbs.
Parsley.
Crabmeat.
By weight, this is 95% crab,
5% binding ingredient.
That's outrageous.
Now we're gonna make the crab
cakes into 8-ounce portions.
That's how big it is?
What is it, like crab meatloaf?
Pretty much.
Put our house seasoning on top
and a little bit of butter.
How we gonna cook it?
350 degrees,
about 15 minutes.
Here's our crab cake.
How many come with an order?
One or two.
Let's just do one.
I've got to watch this
petite dancer's figure.
We're gonna serve it with
our house-made crackers.
Tartar sauce.
Our cocktail sauce.
That's ridiculous.
Look at the size of that lump?
It doesn't need to be
dipped in anything.
Here's the deal, bro.
[ Crunches ]
There's places
that you go to
'cause they've been around
forever.
This is
that kind of place.
I come to Maryland, I want the
bomb crab cakes, you deliver.
Thanks, bro.
Nice job.
The outside
is absolutely crispy,
and then you prick into it,
and it's nothing but crabmeat.
Crab cake up!
MAN: I'm just spoiled by
the crab cake here.
I cannot get a crab cake
anywhere else.
So let's talk about Jimmy
for a second.
How proud is your dad?
I hope he's very proud.
Very proud.
Is this the dream
he told you about
when you guys
were married?
Oh, he was definitely
ahead of his time.
That gives me goose bumps.
MAN:
It's a family environment, man.
When you come here,
you just feel welcome.
The food's unbelievable.
There's nothing
that you can order on the menu
that you'll be displeased with.
Soft Crab Po'Boy up!
Absolutely delicious.
It's worth its weight in gold.
[ Chuckles ]
Jimmy's -- It's a legacy.
They've gone down in history
in Baltimore.
A lot of family love,
a lot of family respect.
You guys are doing
a phenomenal job.
It's been
an awesome experience.
Grazie.
Thank you.
Dear, Guy Fieri.
-Possibility.
FIERI: Up next...
Hi, Guy Fieri,
we're and rolling out.
It's the yin
and the yang of pizza.
It really works.
The food is delicious.
I'm here to tell you about one
of my favorite places on
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives."
-Baby.
-Don't miss out on this.
Welcome back.
Hunter and I are here
watching
some of the greatest videos.
These are people that are trying
to convince us
that their favorite
"Triple-D" location
is one
of America's favorites.
So we asked them to submit
some one minute videos
explaining the type of food,
what they love
about the restaurant
and make it entertaining
and creative.
And I got to tell you,
we've been having a blast.
The "Triple-D" fans
blow it up.
They're crazy.
They are -- They are crazy.
Okay, roll the tape.
Hi, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking America's
greatest diners,
drive-Ins and dives.
I decided
to drive to Kansas City today
to just eat at one
of my favorite restaurants.
I got nothing going on today.
I'm going to go to my favorite
restaurant called Grinder's.
So I opened up MapQuest.
I type in Grinder's, KC.
It's three hours and 15 minutes
from my house
in St. Louis, Missouri.
But that's okay because you got
to drive around the country
in order to hit
some of the best spots.
This menu is packed.
It has Philly cheesesteak pizza,
so on and so forth.
But I got the pastrami, and just
like Guy Fieri would say,
"Call my mommy.
That's some killer pastrami,
Am I right, Guy?
Me and my dad --
Look at this cute pick.
Me and my dad made
a three-hour drive.
We drove back at 2:00
in the morning
just to eat good food
and make lifetime memories.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple-D."
Oh, I love it,
I'm not kidding, you guys,
I am so blown away
at the creativity
and the enthusiasm,
and it was the pull up in front
of Grinder's by the way.
Check your attitude
at the door is what we say.
Best wings.
Holding down.
FIERI: His name is Stretch...
A very big man.
He owns the place.
I'm the guy that colors
outside the lines.
British army helmet,
circa 1943.
He's different.
And he's got an off-the-hook way
of doin' just about everything.
-You did that backwards.
-No, it's however I wanna do it.
The beer tower.
-It's a breathing tank
for oxygen, yeah,
Stretchified.
Yeah. The food is
Stretchalicious.
-There you go.
-The pizza is just my favorite.
It's so good.
-With all kinds
of homemade kind.
-I love this pie.
From classic to tater-tot.
Man, this is like being
in grade school again.
Cheesesteak Stretch
and Sister
are better than the ones
he grew up with.
I'm from Philly area.
I think I can make
a cheesesteak wherever
I go in the world.
Hot wings that'll put you
down for the count.
Your eyeballs are sweatin'.
-[Laughs]
In a 100-year-old building
with food in the front
-Love it.
And monster metal sculptures
in the back.
It's about 24 feet tall,
weighs about 9,000 pounds.
That's crazy.
No crazier than Stretch deciding
it makes perfect sense
for a sculptor
to open a restaurant.
Art, like food,
like music,
crosses all
cultural boundaries.
It does.
-And this place is just
all that put together,
just mished and mashed.
And tossed, and baked.
That's our pie
right there.
Starting entirely
from scratch.
Just working
fingers into it,
get all the air
bubbles out.
I gotta tell ya, he's putting
more time into one skin
than I see most people
put into their whole pizza.
Let me see this thing.
I can almost see through it.
Ah, I can't wait
to have this.
I say we make our famous
Bengal Tiger.
Why'd you call it
Bengal Tiger?
You know, we got
this chicken in there
and the tandoori sauce,
it's got curry in it,
and stuff like that.
Little pesto goes down.
-That's a little pesto.
We sprinkle on
our tandoori chicken.
Curry.
-Little curry on there.
Now, how does this go
over here
in the heart
of the beef land?
This is one
of our favorite pizzas.
People love it.
It's even got a little crab
on it, and hearts of palm.
'Cause I often,
when I'm thinkin' pizza,
I'm thinkin'
hearts of palm.
And we sprinkle a little
of our cheese on top.
And that's about it
right there.
What do you think?
-That is gorgeous!
So cilantro.
-Cilantro.
Just drip it in there
a little bit like that.
Bengal Tiger.
Rawr!
[chuckle] Wow.
That's like an all-Calypso,
jazz-band-festival
funkalicious.
I hear it's good.
Delicious.
You get like these gems.
Little hearts of palm,
little bit of the chicken,
some crab.
It's the yin
and the yang of pizza.
It really works.
Stretch'll make anything work.
I love it because you can
kinda specially order it.
Like you get your own slice
and you decide what's on it.
In any combination.
So we're gonna put
some salmon on here now.
Like smoked salmon
and cream cheese on pesto.
Wow.
That's no joke.
There's one with spinach,
peppers, artichokes, olives,
and almonds.
Four kinds together,
with the pepperoni
next to the pineapple.
And this baby,
that makes you wonder
why no one ever did it before.
The chili and the onions,
fresh cut onions.
The surprise is
the tater tot.
So this pie
actually has a hole
out of the center of it
and we put tater tots
in the middle,
put chili on top of it.
cheese whiz on top of that.
and then, we put some green
onions on top of that.
Look at that!
Tasty chili. Mmm.
And you know what?
Nothin' goes better than a tot.
The food
is always just great.
And, while Stretch started this
as an artist, not a chef --
Is this like your own
little mini art gallery?
And that changes,
people bring us stuff.
And that's what I like
about it.
When it comes to the food,
he got real serious, real quick.
Look at that.
-I had a friend
who went to New York, the
culinary institute up there.
He came back and helped me
open the restaurant.
So a lot of the recipes
are derived from his,
you know, participation.
-Nice. Okay,
so that's why you've really got
some true culinary foundation.
Yeah.
But there's also the stuff that
Stretch brought to the party.
I used to live in Philadelphia,
and this is the first place
that's exactly the same
as I remember from back home.
The secret is definitely
seasoning the grill beforehand.
And we've thrown bacon on there
all day long and cheesesteak,
so it's going to be fine.
Nice, lean roast beef we use.
Chop it up.
The other secret
is slicing the bun.
You don't want to go
all the way through.
That bird's first,
put a little onions
on there.
I mix it in there,
put my cheese whiz on here.
That's a Philly cheesesteak
in Kansas City.
-Cheers.
-Bon appetit.
That's tasty. That's good eats
right there, man.
Grinders is just an artistic
and usual friendly place
where you can get
a really great piece of pizza.
Very eclectic atmosphere.
We came from the other side,
not from the culinary
background.
We don't know what's right
and what's wrong,
but we know what we like
and we try
and put it into into action
in a place
that we all want to go
and hang out.
[ Applause ]
They love you here.
MAN: Love that money
Hi, thank you
for being in my lap.
Smokey's helping me.
Hey.
Okay, can I do my work?
Thank you.