All right, all right,
here's the game plan --
Months ago, you sent out
a video saying to people
you wanted to know their
favorite "Triple-D" location.
That's right.
Remember that?
I do.
We want to know, what is
your favorite "Triple-D" joint?
People submit
their video.
-My favorite...
-Our favorite...
Favorite --
Favorite "Triple-D" joint.
[ Growls ]
They had to describe
why they like it.
HUNTER: Mm-hmm.
Their favorite dish.
They could be funny.
They could be sad.
They could sing a song --
whatever they wanted to do
to draw attention to why
this "Triple-D" location
should be on America's
favorite list.
Hi, everyone!
Hi, everyone!      Hi, everyone!
People were very
excited about this.
Thousands
of submissions.
You and I sat,
you and I watched,
and we picked --
I think some
of the best.
Just look at how
delicious this stuff is.
[ Laughs ]
Those winners, Hunter,
each are gonna get
1,000 bucks,
and they're gonna
get featured
on their own special edition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives."
On top of that, we're not only
gonna show you their video...
Hi, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rollin' out!
...We're gonna show America
that "Triple-D" location again
so they can understand
why they're on the list
of America's favorite
"Triple-D" joints.
We're on the same page.
Yes.
Oh, yeah.
GUY:
Like on this trip!
Incredible Italian...
This is the wicked?
Winner, winner,
wicked chicken dinner.
...creative Korean...
That is one of the
most unique dishes
I've ever tried
in a food truck.
...and ridiculous ramen
the whole family
can fill up on.
Who needs a sister when you
have Spicy Hot Tomato Oil?
[ Laughing ]
♪♪
Welcome to another episode
of "Guess That Favorite
'Triple-D' Joint"!
GUY: All right, Hunter,
let's get things started.
We're going through
some of the most
outrageous videos
you've ever seen.
These bad boys
were pretty bomb.
We saw the good ones...
-So good.
-Really, really tasty.
...and we saw some
amazing ones.
Out of bounds!
MAN: I'm Guy Fieri,
and I approve this message.
Definitely.
All right.
Next up, V's Cellar Door,
Juneau, Alaska.
Cody, role it.
Cody looks serious.
[ Dishes clinking ]
I am so hungry
right now.
This is the worst time
to watch this.
What's going on?
[ Sighs ]
[ Laughing ]
This is why Guy Fieri came
to V's Cellar Door
in Juneau, Alaska.
These just aren't
the same as at home.
He just dropped it
right in the chips!
Oh, my gosh!
That was --
[ Laughing ]
I gotta be honest,
if it didn't have
a big splash,
it wasn't going
very good.
Oh, but that was
the perfect setup
to make it drop
like that.
Just so --
Oh, my gosh.
I love that.
That was --
That was money.
We gotta call that dude.
Let's see, Hunter.
We've got our winner,
Cody, the Cabbage Man,
and we've got V
from V's Cellar Door.
What's up, guys?
Oh, hi!
Hey!
V, I gotta
tell you something.
You have a big
fan following --
as we know when we were
up there to shoot.
And, Cody, my brother,
I gotta be honest with you,
we're watching it.
Here it goes,
and I'm like,
"This guy is really not
giving it much."
And you dropped
the cabbage, bro.
We lost it,
and we played it again,
and we played --
And, hey, by the way,
you deadpanned it so great.
So good.
And I do agree with you
on the nachos.
They're great.
That's Crazy Town
right there.
You got acid,
umami, creamy, salty,
meaty, cheesy, beany.
That's a lot.
That's a lot of "Y's."
What was the
inspiration, though?
I mean, you just thought, "Hey,
I'm gonna go and do this"?
CODY: The idea sort of
came to my head
of that picture of the exploding
chips off the plate
and sort of my distress
of not having nachos at home,
and all the work
that goes into it.
And I told my wife about it,
and she just about died.
They showed it to me,
and I couldn't stop laughing.
And then, other customers
in the restaurant
came over and looked, and they
couldn't stop laughing.
I gotta tell you, Cody,
you crushed it, bro,
and when you guys get
a chance to go there,
if you haven't
been up to Juneau
and you haven't come
to V's Cellar,
it's restaurant,
it show, it's energy,
and a lot of
really excited fans.
Okay, Korean short ribs.
Bowl of pozole.
Let's go!
When you first hear
"Mexican-Korean fusion,"
you're like,
"Oh, like, I don't know."
And then,
my mind was blown.
Tinga fusion burrito.
WOMAN: Everything here
is really fresh.
The flavors go
really well together.
It's always enjoyable.
GUY: The good times
come courtesy
of Chef Venietia Santana...
Order up!
GUY:
...a Sicilian Irish chef
who ended up tackling
Asian-Mexican flavor.
My ex-husband is
from Mexico City,
and we would go there,
and the food was amazing.
It's just a really good
feeling being around V.
She's got so much energy,
so much attitude,
and it really shines through
each dish that she makes.
What's your favorite
thing on the menu?
WOMAN: It would have to be
the fusion nachos.
Korean chicken
fusion nacho.
WOMAN: There's melted cheddar
cheese and Korean chicken,
and there's her
fusion sauce.
Everything in a nacho
that you could want
but never knew you wanted.
GUY: Let's get into it, V.
What are we making?
Korean chicken that's
gonna go on top
of our Korean chicken
fusion nachos.
Chop up our
chicken thighs.
Next up, marinade.
Ginger, green onions,
pear, sesame seeds,
garlic, soy sauce.
Sesame oil.
Good job, Dad.
Thank you.
Brown sugar,
sweet onions.
And gochujang --
my favorite Korean ketchup.
How long's this chicken
gonna marinade?
15, 20 minutes.
Next up, V.
What do we got?
Our fusion sauce.
Soy and brown sugar,
gochujang.
Sesame oil,
rice wine vinegar.
Hunter.
♪♪
Oh, yeah, I'd have that
on cold cereal.
I would take a cup of that
with a straw,
Let's build
these nachos.
We're gonna
saute the chicken.
Little bit of salt
and pepper.
Chips, beans,
and then cheese.
Do that again.
What happens when the rest
of the people are ordering food
and we're spending
all day making
Magic Nacho Mountain?
Well, I'm a woman,
so I can multitask.
Got it.
Ooh.
We're gonna put this
in the oven.
Cilantro-onion relish,
tomatoes,
Korean chicken.
I'm gonna go with the idea
that the plate might
be a bit small.
Guacamole, sour cream,
fusion sauce.
So, if you want to get this,
order on a Thursday for Sunday.
Sesame seeds.
This is the salsa
that's served with it.
And?
And a partridge
in a pear tree.
Would you like a fork?
Can't eat nachos
with a fork.
You can't eat nachos
You were putting
so many flavors together,
I was a bit worried...
Say good.
...they were
gonna compete.
They're playing
well together.
This is like a
multicultural playground,
and there's a lot of
different games going on.
That right there was
dodgeball-hopscotch.
[ Laughs ]
Mmm.
When you look up
Mexican-Korean fusion
in the Flavortown library,
that's the picture
you'll see.
Four minutes
on the chicken!
We get nachos
about once a week,
so all the goodness
that goes with it.
Nachos with a fork?
Is that legal in Juneau?
I don't know,
but the problem is that
I want to put more
of this in my mouth
than I can
with my hands.
Okay, okay.
SANTANA: Nice and neat.
We eat with our eyes
way before we eat
with our mouths.
Everything is made
with love,
and that's one of the things
I love about the food here.
If I had my way, I would
simply order one of each,
put it on the table, and eat
off of everybody's plate.
Congratulations on winning!
Congratulations on
1,000 bucks!
V, congratulations
on being recognized
as one of America's favorite
"Triple-D" joints.
Thanks so much,
you guys!
All right, more to come.
Don't go anywhere.
[ Speaking foreign language ]
All right, yeah.
-Amazing.
-We love this place.
One of the best spots.
WOMAN: Look at that.
That's crazy.
Who needs cleaning supplies
when they have
Spicy Hot Tomato Oil?
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
Watching some "Triple-D".
-Yeah!
-Mmm!
So good.
GUY: Here we go!
More of America's
favorite videos.
-I love it.
-Flavortown favorite.
Definitely the top notch
on "Triple-D".
Pastabilities
in Syracuse, New York.
I remember this joint.
Pastabilities.
All right,
this is gonna be --
This is gonna be good.
Hey, guys.
We live in
Syracuse, New York.
And one of the best things
about living in Syracuse
is a restaurant --
our favorite --
called Pastabilities.
And my favorite thing to get is
spaghetti and meatballs.
My favorite thing to get
is fettuccini Alfredo.
But you know what
my family all loves?
Spicy hot tomato oil.
Who needs
this red sauce
when you have
Spicy Hot Tomato Oil?
Who needs their favorite
sports drink...
when you have
Spicy Hot Tomato Oil?
Who needs salsa when you
have Spicy Hot Tomato Oil?
Who needs milk
for their cereal
when they have
Spicy Hot Tomato Oil?
Who needs cleaning supplies
when they have
Spicy Hot Tomato Oil?
Who needs this shampoo
when you have
Spicy Hot Tomato Oil?
This is outstanding.
Who needs a sister when you have
Spicy Hot Tomato Oil?
Sister's face.
BOTH:
We love Pastabilities!
I'm gonna tell you
right now, girls --
right now,
that was one of the best,
without question.
Hysterical.
Who needs
cleaning supplies --
No, who needs
a little sister?
[ Laughing ] And her
sister looks at her!
And that Spicy Hot Tomato Oil,
I'm telling you, is the bomb.
I need to
get some of that.
That is funny.
All right, Hunter,
there you go.
Our sisters -- the winners --
Lilia and Caraline.
And then, there's Karyn
from Pastabilities.
Hi!
Ladies!
Yo!
Oh, my gosh!
How are you?
We're good --
definitely, now.
Hunter and I
wanted to call you
and tell you
how proud we were of you.
Your video
was outstanding...
So funny.
...and we are still
laughing about it.
And, Karyn, I haven't
seen you in --
how many years has it been since
we shot Pastabilities?
I'd have to say
eight years.
Seems like 20, 'cause I ran out
of my Hot Spicy Oil
about nine years ago.
Spicy Hot Tomato Oil.
Karyn, what'd you
think of that?
And you've never met
the girls before?
I've never met them before.
I just met them now.
I was like, "Where are
they going with this?
Oh, my God,
this is so funny."
Priceless.
Who needs a little sister when
you have Spicy Hot Tomato Oil?
Who needs ketchup when you have
Hot Spicy Tomato Oil?
So, tell me about this.
Tell me about Pastabilities.
What do you love
so much about it?
I like the environment
and how you get the food.
I like how they make
their food so creatively.
Mmm.
Oh!
Winner, winner,
wicked chicken dinner.
♪♪
[ Laughter ]
Ladies and gentlemen,
without further ado,
because of their outstanding,
hilarious, well-produced,
well-written,
and well-acted presentation,
this is Pastabilities.
♪♪
The pasta is homemade.
You can just taste
that fresh difference.
They have recipes that
you can't get anywhere else.
GUY: Thanks to owner
Karyn Korteling...
Flatbread up!
...who's been perfecting
the menu since '82.
You can ask almost
anybody in this town,
have they been
to Pastabilities,
and their response
would be?
"I love that place.
This is home."
GUY: I mean,
this joint's so popular,
locals just call it
by its first name.
You call it "Pasta's"?
Oh, all the locals do.
"Oh, I'm going
to Pasta's."
I can't believe
you didn't know that.
Well, now I do.
Here's another
insider tip --
never -- and I
mean never --
pass on Karyn's
famous appetizer.
The Hot Tomato Oil,
it's a way of life here.
♪♪
All right, so, the first thing
we're gonna start off with?
Spicy Hot Tomato Oil.
Let's fire it up.
♪♪
Tomato purée.
Just regular old tomatoes?
They're California tomatoes.
As they should be.
Salt, little bit
of honey.
Got it.
Chili mixture.
Next, the reserved oil.
♪♪
We gotta get out
the big guns.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, who, whoa.
Going in.
[ Mixer whirring ]
That's it.
[ Laughing ]
We gotta stir
our garlic back in.
'Cause you want to
see the chunks.
That's right.
And now, we're ready
to taste it?
Now we're ready
to taste it.
So, if someone
comes in here,
this is what they get
to kick off their meal?
That's right.
This is what
we're famous for.
And this is
some of your bread?
That's our stretch bread.
♪♪
That's crazy.
Oh!
I can't come back and
hang out with you anymore.
Those are ridiculous.
Hot Oil up.
It's like nothing else.
MAN:
It's absolutely amazing.
The first time I had it
years ago, I was addicted.
Just, like, begging the waitress
to give that to you.
GUY: And Karyn's ability
to attract a crowd
isn't just limited
to food...
The restaurant is
pretty much the genesis
of downtown Syracuse.
Just a great place
to come and hang out.
...and she's turning up the heat
on a regional dish
that drives locals crazy!
I've got the wicked chicken
riggies right here.
WOMAN: It's spicy,
but with a great flavor.
It can't be replicated.
It's delicious.
♪♪
KORTELING: It's a central
New York dish.
They're wicked
chicken riggies.
All right, time out.
It's called "riggies"?
Riggies or rigatoni.
These parts,
chicken riggies rule.
Okay, let's start
the riggies.
First, we're gonna start
with olive oil.
Garlic, sweet onion.
We'll just let that
simmer for a moment.
Then we go
to our peppers.
Yellow peppers,
sweet red, green.
A little jalapeño.
So this has got
some spice to it?
Well, we call it "wicked"
for a reason, you know?
Oregano.
Red chili flake.
Cayenne.
The pepper to everything-else
ratio is starting to go up.
Salt, dried basil,
and black pepper.
And next up, this
beautiful tomato sauce?
Yep, this is our
house tomato sauce.
What's this little --
Oh, that's the wicked.
This is the wicked?
That's the wicked.
How hot is that?
I'd say it's hot.
All right, cream.
Let it simmer
for 45 minutes,
just to get all the
pepper goodness in there.
And the sugar,
Romano cheese.
Whoa.
So, we let it
simmer down...
Yep.
And next,
we'll work on what?
We gotta chicken it.
We're gonna chicken it?
We're gonna chicken it.
Sliced chicken breast,
little salt and pepper.
So, the chicken's
browned up nicely.
Yep.
Few ladles of cream
chicky-riggie sauce,
then I pour
my riggies in.
Coat it all.
There you go.
Nice, and she's done.
Garnish with
Locatelli cheese
and green onion.
And that's riggies.
Chicken riggies.
Wicked chicken riggies.
♪♪
Mmm.
Oh!
[ Laughs ]
That's an awesome dish.
I'm so glad.
Pasta's nice,
not too much sauce.
♪♪
Not overly spicy.
A real simple dish,
but quality ingredients
made the right way,
and it's a staple here
at Pastabilities.
That's right.
Love it.
♪♪
Lilia, Caraline,
your video was outstanding.
Not only did we
enjoy it, you won.
You get the money, and you
get to be on "Triple-D."
What do you think of that?
That's awesome.
Crazy.   Crazy.
A lot of people are
gonna see your video.
[ Giggles ]
A lot.
I mean, get ready to
start taking pictures
and signing
autographs, ladies.
[ Laughter ]
Bye!
[ Bell jingles ]
What would you like
to eat today?
Bolognese with
fresh pappardelle.
The duck bacon pizza.
Is it another shwarma fry
kind of day?
Who's America's favorite
"Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives"?
We'll find out.
Don't go anywhere.
Not something
you want to miss.
[ Deep, slowed-down voice ]
Thanks for having dinner
with me, Guy Fieri.
[ Laughing ]
♪♪
It's the middle
of the night.
You're dreaming
of Flavortown.
Looks like I'm
eating out tonight.
Hello, "Triple-D"!
GUY: We're going through
some of the most
outrageous videos
you've ever seen.
[ Creature roaring ]
These are people that are
trying to convince us
that their favorite
"Triple-D" location
is one of
America's favorites.
Thanks, everybody.
All right, up next,
Yakitori Jinbei.
Oh, this should be good.
Dear Guy Fieri,
I went to Yakitori Jinbei
just last Friday,
and it was so good,
if it were a person,
I would [Bleep].
I had the Korean
fried chicken,
one of the sushis --
I forget which --
and the spicy
nappa ramen.
I was at work
earlier that week,
and I was looking for the top
ramen places in Atlanta.
There was an article in "The
"Atlanta Journal-Constitution,"
and Yakitori Jinbei
was number one.
And lo and behold,
I got there,
and Guy Fieri's
handsome face
was on several spots
on the walls.
It was like I was having
dinner with Guy Fieri.
[ Deep, slowed-down voice ]
Thanks for having dinner
with me, Guy Fieri.
What was going on there?
Oh, my gosh.
What did I just watch?
Well, I gotta tell you
something, brother,
you crushed that.
That is, um --
All the bleeps.
The bleeping --
No one's bleeped yet.
That was --
Wow, that was enthusiastic.
Guy Fieri's handsome face
was on several spots
on the wall.
♪♪
So, I'm right outside
of Atlanta, Georgia...
Dude, you're gonna
love this place.
It's got the
amazing sushi...
...with my buddy,
G. Garvin.
...fresh stuff.
It's got ramen --
all different types of ramen,
The broth is amazing.
It's the Asian chicken wings.
You gotta see what
this guy's doing here.
Guy, come on, man!
What are you doing?
It better be good!
This is Yakitori Jinbei.
Come on, my man!
Baby, let's go!
♪♪
Gyoza.
MAN: When you come here
and you're inviting someone,
they're like,
"Oh, my gosh, that's it."
This is the best ramen
in the city.
Dude, I can't stop
talking about this place.
He has been ranting
like this in the car.
Da-da-da-da-da-da,
on and on and on.
Thank you,
thank you.
Oh, Jae himself,
he's a character.
He's just like one of
these dishes here.
Little fusion
of everything.
GUY:
Which includes Jae Choi --
growing up a Chicago kid
in a Korean household
and having a totally
different career.
He was my optometrist
until he decided
to open a restaurant instead.
Since high school, I wanted
to go to culinary school.
As any immigrant parents
would be, they said,
"we didn't come to America
so you can cook."
Bulgogi beef bowl.
So, you bought out
a restaurant?
I inherited the name.
Why didn't you change
the name on the sign?
This was first
the test kitchen,
and then it kind of
grew into this.
You hadn't really
committed yet,
and by the time
you realized
that you were
doing good with it,
you couldn't change
the name.
Exactly.
He's just doing
what he really loves.
This is my style.
Oh, my gosh.
Spicy wing bowl!
MAN: The food is
just excellent,
whether it's the
spicy fried chicken
or it's a nice
curry ramen.
Katsu curry ramen.
Today, I'm having
the katsu curry ramen.
MAN: Basically fried pork
over ramen noodles
with a pork
and chicken broth.
Delicious.
Some of the best
I've ever had.
So, what are we
making first?
We're making a broth
for the katsu curry ramen.
Ramen, man, is all
about the broth.
This is gonna be
interesting.
So, we got pork
and chicken bones,
pre-boiled, washed.
Is that a traditional method
that you learned as a kid,
or is this just you putting
your doctor thing to it?
It's my scientific doctor
trying to make sure
that the broth comes out
nice and white.
Next up?
We're gonna bag
the kombu.
Dried anchovies,
bonito flakes.
We're gonna take it out
after a little bit of time.
So, you want to temper that
flavoring a little bit?
Yes.
So, we got pulverized
shiitake mushrooms.
Tying your shoes not ever been
a big thing, has it?
[ Laughter ]
That's why they do
the Velcro shoes.
Oh, my gosh, help us.
Roasted leeks,
roasted onions,
roasted garlic,
some roasted ginger.
How long?
18 hours.
Hoh!
We add salt, sugar,
and fish powder,
and then let it go
for another six.
What's the next step?
The pork katsu.
Start off with a whole
loin of pork loin.
A whole loin of pork loin.
[ Laughing ]
I-I see-see what you're
saying-saying.
Thank you,
thank you.
Take this
and tenderize it.
He's got good little
tricks of the trade.
♪♪
Salt it a little bit.
Dredge it in AP flour.
Put it into the egg wash.
GARVIN: What do you
have in there?
Tempura flour
and water.
Dredge it in panko.
And this will fry.
350°.
The broth is ready.
GUY: Okay.
GARVIN: Smells good.
Add the noodles.
There we go.
Take the pork.
Boy, that sounds
crunchy.
Top this with
some cabbage sautéed
and some oil and salt,
and we will
add that.
Carrots and corn.
I've never had corn
in ramen.
Green onions.
You and G. Garvin have been
friends for all these years,
and yet, you've chosen to make
just me a bowl of ramen.
G., I'll tell you
how it is.
Tell me.
Mmm.
I can't say that I've ever
had curry ramen broth.
It is a spin on a Japanese
dish called katsu curry.
It takes ramen
another step.
You know, the flavor
in that broth is insane,
and I love the little --
Carrots and corn.
It's good.
It's not traditional.
It's unique,
and it's funky.
Noodles are tender,
broth is rich,
and the creativity
is an "A."
Nice job.
MAN: The broth is
really smooth --
like, a really
silky texture.
The crunch of the corn on top
is just perfect.
Outside of Japan,
this is the best.
GUY:
How did you find it?
He's friend of ours.
We are eye doctors.
You're eye doctors?
What is this, where all the
eye doctors hang out?
[ Laughter ]
We practiced together.
Are you still practicing,
or did you start a pizza place?
No, he's more courageous
than I am.
Just between you and me,
is he a better
optometrist or a chef?
WOMAN:
The food is amazing.
I think he should just stay
in the restaurant business.
[ Laughter ]
Gyoza, bulgogi beef bowl.
It's definitely a dive,
and there's nothing like it.
It's just good food,
and everybody's happy.
It's like when
I called you -- I said...
"You gotta see
the passion."
It's definitely what we
look for on "Triple-D."
G. knew exactly
where to send me.
You're doing food
the way you like to eat.
That's the beauty of it.
Keep making food like this,
and I'll be back.
All right.
GUY: Coming up...
Look how good we look.
You asked what my favorite
restaurant around here is.
The Dirty Buffalo.
The Smoking Swine.
-The Meatball Stop.
-Panini Pete's.
♪♪
That's me and you!
Exquisitely delicious.
You really have to ask?
GUY: Welcome back,
everybody.
Hunter and I are still
checking out the top contenders
for America's favorite
"Triple-D" joints.
My favorite dish
of all time.
The food is
just phenomenal.
The whole idea behind this
was for you to tell us
how much you loved your favorite
"Triple-D" location,
and I gotta tell you
something -- outstanding.
Now, that's what
I'm talking about.
Up next, tahini
in San Diego.
Roll it.
I'm in San Diego,
California,
and I'm on a mission to find
the best pita and hummus.
BOTH: And this is Tahini!
Excellent.
I love tahini
because it's healthy,
and I also love
their food there --
like chicken and rice,
fries, pita, and hummus.
But now you know
who eats hummus.
I do, but only
from Tahini.
I like tahini 'cause
the flavor is good,
and all of the employees
treat me like family,
and I love Osama
and Moody.
And I have a secret.
Have the fries
with the pita.
♪♪
I also have another reason
why I love tahini.
'Cause when I eat tahini,
it makes me want to dance.
♪♪
That's me and you!
We love you, Tahini.
Oh, my gosh!
That was cool.
You gotta be kidding me!
The dance was the best.
[ Cash register dings ]
[ Humming ]
Love it,
love it, love it.
♪♪
I got a snake charmer
rice bowl!
WOMAN: Real, authentic
Middle Eastern food.
I've been hooked.
I could come here
every day.
Cumato salad,
six-piece falafel!
And I love Mahmoud and Osama
and all the crew here.
GUY:
That's high school buddies,
Osama Shabaik
and Mahmoud Barkawi,
who started out as a lawyer
and aspiring cop
but couldn't resist
the pull of their families'
Egyptian and Syrian cuisine.
So they started a side hustle
that exploded into this.
In San Diego, you find taco
shops all the time, right?
You don't find shawarma.
GUY: So, this is a
Middle Eastern taco shop.
Pretty much, yeah.
We stole the recipes
from our mothers.
We'll stack the
shawarmas in-house.
I got a chicken shawarma
sandwich, fries inside!
Chicken shawarma
is definitely one of
the dishes that
I order often.
And all the flavors
just drizzling down,
marinating as they cook it.
MAN: They shave off the meat
right in front of you.
It's delicious.
All right, what are we
make first?
Marinade for the
chicken shawarma.
First thing we have
is yogurt.
Fresh blended oranges
and lemon.
Seeds, pith,
everything.
The whole nine.
Haven't seen
this one yet.
Tomato paste,
red pepper paste,
soybean oil,
white vinegar,
lemon juice,
black pepper.
Turmeric?
Good call.
You know your way
around the kitchen.
I've dabbled.
Paprika.
You got it.
Cumin.
Curry powder.
Garlic powder, salt,
onion powder.
Little cayenne.
Yeah.
And some ground ginger.
Got it.
Now, is it all
chicken thigh?
Yes.
Now we'll throw
the marinade in here.
It'll help break it down
with that yogurt.
And then, we'll start to
build the rotisserie.
Watch me now.
[ Imitating The Count ]
Two pieces of chicken.
Ah-ah-ah.
And three pieces
of chicken now.
We're actually gonna
sneak in some lamb fat.
[ Normal voice ]
Hold, please?
It's definitely
a secret from back home.
It actually melts off
as the vertical boiler
is cooking the chicken.
A couple more
pieces on top,
and then the onion
and the tomato.
And then, this will go
to the vertical rotisserie.
First layer takes roughly
about 45 minutes.
So, now we're gonna build
the chicken shawarma.
I can have it in a bowl,
I can have it as a salad,
or I can have it
as a wrap.
We make our own
pita bread.
I'll have it
as a wrap.
You got it.
It's, like, raining
chicken in Flavortown
right there, buddy.
Make sure I have
extra lamb fat.
Stuff these chicken.
Oh.
French fries.
Garlic sauce,
sriracha tahini,
parsley mix.
[ Whistles ]
Tomatoes,
pickled cucumbers.
Sriracha tahini on top.
That's all she wrote.
♪♪
Silence is killing me.
What's the word?
We'll be back
after these messages.
[ Laughs ]
The chicken,
it's tender.
The garlic and the sriracha
tahini together --
great acidity,
touch of heat.
The vegetable crunch
and the freshness of that.
Little salt and crunch
from the French fry.
I mean, just everywhere
you turn inside this --
It's killer.
Got your chicken
shawarma pita.
MAN: It's amazing.
There's a lot going on
in this thing.
It's extremely,
extremely delicious.
I really love
the chicken.
It has so much
flavor in it.
♪♪
I love
Middle Eastern food.
Do we know what true
Middle Eastern is
out here
on the West Coast?
There's not a lot.
Yeah, not that much.
Order up!
What do you think?
I think it's delicious.
Falafel's on point,
for sure.
I got a falafel
salad ready!
This falafel is crispy
from outside,
but when you bite in it,
it's green and fluffy.
Oh, it's so good.
What's the next dish?
Now we'll be making the falafel
more of the Egyptian way,
where we use fava beans
instead of garbanzo beans.
A little higher
in protein.
Huh?
We'll go ahead and
throw the dill first.
That's a big "dill."
Parsley, chives, cilantro,
Little bit of red onions,
fresh garlic,
salt, black pepper, cumin,
ground coriander.
Don't tell anybody.
I won't.
It's between us.
[ Laughs ]
Cayenne pepper.
Fava beans that have
been soaked.
One grind?
We do it twice.
Little baking soda?
Just a pinch.
It helps create
a little pillowy-ness.
This is my little
falafel scooper.
[ Whistles ]
Another one of
mom's secrets is,
just give it that
little pinkie poke,
'cause it helps the cook
in the middle.
Donut falafel.
Fry this off 350°.
Soybean oil?
Yeah.
And then, we'll
build the salad.
Exactly.
Tomatoes on there,
red onions,
some bell peppers,
olives,
the sriracha tahini,
pepperoncini,
turnips, feta cheese.
GUY: All right,
we're down to three.
[ Laughs ]
Well, I'm sorry!
I was waiting
for the salad.
This is such
a righteous falafel.
So much flavor,
so much texture,
so much going on.
That's how I want
my falafel from now on.
That's no joke
right there, folks.
Outstanding.
Thank you, sir.
Falafel salad.
The falafel is rich,
and the sauces bring out
all the flavors
of the vegetable.
WOMAN: I'm a vegetarian
and gluten free,
so often, we turn
to falafel.
And usually, it's the
traditional chickpeas,
and this has, like,
a new spin to it.
It's incredible.
I have nothing to add.
[ Laughter ]
GUY: Up next...
Go check it out.
It's been on "Triple-D."
-"Triple-D."
-"Triple-D" favorite.
Yum.
Mrs. Potato
changed my life.
That's probably
the most perfect example
and explanation
of why that should be
in America's favorites.
Ooooh.
Ahhhh.
♪♪
They're really good.
It's what I keep
coming back for.
Fantastic.
HUNTER: All right,
welcome back.
My dad and I asked,
and well, you answered.
We're diving into more
of America's favorites.
Guy, I love you
so much.
Mrs. Potato,
Orlando, Florida.
Hey, guys, my name
is Rafaela,
and I'm the owner
of Mrs. Potato.
I didn't see it anywhere
where it says that
a owner cannot make a video
indicating its own restaurant.
Exactly.
But I have a very good
reason to do that.
In my opinion, for me,
Mrs. Potato is the best
restaurant in "Triple-D."
Why?
Because Mrs. Potato
changed my life.
Because of Mrs. Potato
and we being featured
on "Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives,"
I was able to send my
20-year-old daughter to college.
Nice.
I was able to offer
my six-year-old
a secure, happy,
and stable childhood.
It changed my life.
It changed my family's life.
It changed my perspective
for the future.
I now can do what I most like
in life, which is cook.
Thank you.
Thank you, Mrs. Potato.
Thank you, "Triple-D."
Thank you, Guy Fieri.
Thank you, Food Network.
That's awesome.
You got teary-eyed
on that.
I did.
I did, too.
That's a big hit.
Great job.
And I'm so happy --
You know what, Hunter?
That's probably the
most perfect example
and explanation
of why that should be
in America's favorites --
because it is
life-changing.
100%. I agree.
It changed my life.
It changed my family's life.
♪♪
So, I'm here in wonderful
Orlando, Florida,
with good friends Joey Fatone
and Robert Earl.
Robert's the founder
of Planet Hollywood,
and, well, you know,
Joey from TV, movies,
and, well, a little group
called NSYNC.
Are you gonna
let him out?
No.
We're here to check out
a joint --
Joey, please let me out!
We're here
to check out a joint
where a Brazilian chef is
serving up nothing but potatoes.
This is Mrs. Potato.
Joey, let him out.
All right, all right.
♪♪
I love the food there.
Carne seca roasting!
Seven more minutes!
Potatoes are a very
traditional food in Brazil.
It brings us a little bit
back to our root.
GUY: Which is
exactly the reason
behind Rafaela Cabede's
potato palace.
She moved to the U.S.
from Brazil as a kid,
and when she decided
to open a restaurant,
she had one question.
"What do I miss from home
that I can get here?"
And then, it clicked --
my potatoes.
So, you're Mrs. Potato.
We're the three amigos.
We're the
triple threat.
And none of us
like to eat.
GUY: Luckily,
her signature specialty
comes in "XL."
Carne seca rosti up!
Let me tell you,
it's the biggest
hash brown you've ever seen.
And you can add whatever
filling you want to it.
So, what are we
gonna start with?
Carne seca.
GUY:
Which is dried beef.
Pig in Brazil.
This is top butt...
Okay.
...and we salt it.
Pull a lot of
moisture out.
Do you've put enough
salt in there?
I think it's snowing
in that pot.
It goes into the fridge
for three days.
So, we're gonna eat
in about four days.
Cool, I love it.
[ Laughing ]
So, now we're gonna rinse it
four or five times.
Then it goes into
the pressure cooker.
45 minutes to an hour.
We just pull the meat shred it,
and that's the beginning.
Yes.
We are gonna do
the seasoning.
We've got onion,
garlic.
Tomatoes.
Look at that.
So, if that doesn't
smell fantastic,
you have got
serious problems.
Now we're gonna
add the cilantro.
♪ Cilantro ♪
I love that song!
Now we are
making the rosti.
So, shredded potato...
Seasoned with salt
and pepper.
Then, we add the filling,
then we top it with
some more potatoes.
It goes to the stove.
We get some oil.
So, how long
does it go?
Six minutes
on each side.
So, now we're flipping it.
Ooooh.
Ahhhh.
Looking great.
[ British accent ]
Roasty-toasty, I do say.
So, this is Catupiry.
That's a Brazilian
cream cheese.
Dried parsley.
And these are
pimienta pequeño.
It's a pepper
from Brazil.
It actually has
no heat at all,
but it has
a lot of flavor.
[ Inhales ]
[ Laughter ]
Tasty.
Here is our
carne seca rosti.
Gentlemen.
Here it is.
The moment is here.
It's quiet
all of a sudden.
♪♪
It's really good.
I want like ten
of these to go.
I want to have
a house party.
I can see why people
can eat the whole thing.
It is moist.
The cheese seems to
really entwine
with the potato
and with the meat.
It's excellent.
I was worried.
There's just not enough
phenomenal ingredients
for it to get all
the reputation it's got...
but you just made music
with a string-drum tin can.
I mean, it's
a rock concert.
It's delicious.
Carne seca,
two minutes!
It's crispy
and also very smooth.
You can't stop eating.
It's terrific.
Start working
on pastel!
Rafaela is an
amazing person.
She worked hard to be
where she is now.
Come on.
GUY:
But if this is work,
boy, does she make it
look like play.
All in the hips.
Well, I got
a lot of hip.
GUY: [ Laughs ]
♪♪
I love it.
Can't ask for
anything better.
♪♪
Sister, this is
really fantastic.
To have a restaurant
that has dishes
that no one else has...
No one else has.
...this is special.
Give me a hug.
Ah, now, we're talking!
See, it's so beautiful.
I'm okay, I'm okay.
♪♪
GUY: Coming up...
What's up, everybody?
I'm here on-site of my favorite
"Triple-D" restaurant.
I'm outside of my favorite
"Triple-D" joint.
It's like no place
I've ever been before.
BOY: I, um...
[ Smacks lips ] Mmmm!
If there was a "cute baby
video," they just won.
Yeah, for sure.
♪♪
Roll 'em.
Big time,
Don't miss out on this.
I would absolutely eat that
on a flip-flop.
The first time I went,
I ate everything on the menu.
It was so delicious.
"Triple-D" fans love
their restaurants.
So yummy.
All right, next up,
Maui Fresh Streatery.
Okay, roll it.
MAN:
Hey, Guy and Hunter.
Guy and Kimi here with our
favorite "Triple-D" spot,
Maui Fresh Streatery.
Not only the does Chef Kyle
make amazing food
from different cuisines,
but he and his family
do so much
for our community.
They've been providing
free meals for the elderly
during the
COVID-19 pandemic,
holding fundraisers
for families in need,
running a "pay it forward"
meal campaign,
feeding our
first responders,
and donating his
Aloha Tip Jar
to local organizations
and people in need.
KIMI: Our son, Cade,
who was born in January, 2018,
had his first
Maui Fresh Streatery meal
at 10 months of age,
and continues to love
"Uncle Big Truck's" food.
That face.
Cade's eaten
so many cuisines
that Kyle has debuted
at his food truck
and has been featured
on his social media accounts
loving his food.
In fact, recently,
one video of Cade
that Kyle posted on Facebook
got over 5,000 views.
There's no other food truck
that Cade enjoys eating at more
than Maui Fresh Streatery.
[ Cade babbling ]
[ Giggles, babbling ]
Mmmm!
I, um...
[ Smacks lips ]
If there was a "cute baby"
video, they just won.
Yeah, for sure.
God, that kid can eat.
Those guys are awesome,
and I love to see this.
I mean, especially
during the pandemic,
you know this is how
they handle things,
and he's got that --
It's not a
little food truck.
It's a great
food truck, but --
I love those stories.
That's awesome.
Great job.
That kid is so cute.
CADE: [ Babbles ]
Mmmm!
♪♪
KAWAKAMI: Short rib
loco moco with sous vide.
Everything that comes
out that window is amazing.
Saké mahi.
Shiitake ponzu
cream sauce.
Always really unique
combinations.
Firing eggplant
caponata quesadilla.
Every other week,
we get a new,
innovative,
exciting menu.
You basically just say,
"Where I show up
and when you show up, it's
what we have to offer."
Exactly.
So, we have 20 menus that we
go through throughout the year.
GUY: And Chef Kyle Kawakami
bases each of those menus
on a different
global cuisine.
Shelly,
okonomiyaki.
Okonomiyaki is a traditional
Japanese street pancake.
And this is better
than the one I had in Japan.
Really?
It has lots of elements
included in it --
shrimp and pork.
All right, so,
let's do this, Chef.
KAWAKAMI: So, we got
our pork butt,
and we're gonna make
our marinade really quick.
Miso paste, soy, saké.
Got two of them on.
[ Laughs ]
Sugar...
and a little bit
of ginger.
Okay, so, the
marinade goes on.
Give it a
quick massage.
Wrap this, put this in
to chill overnight.
Goes into the oven --
350° three hours.
Then we'll pull it out
and shred it.
Beautiful.
Next step?
The batter for
the okonomiyaki.
What is this?
Yamaimo.
This is a Japanese
mountain yam.
Like a daikon with
the texture of jicama,
but the slime of okra.
Mmm.
Because it has
so much starch in it,
it adds the "crisp-mas"
to the batter.
So it's adding
Christmas to it.
Christmas?
"Crisp-ness."
"Crisp-mas."
[ Laughs ]
Let's peel this.
So, I'm gonna go ahead
and cut that.
Those go straight
to the blender.
Little water.
That's it.
That's nuts, bro.
In our mixing bowl --
AP flour.
Eggs, dashi -- which is
water and some stock.
Salt, and our
yamaimo purée.
All right, Chef,
batter's made.
Now we're gonna go ahead
and make our pancake.
Shredded local cabbage,
little bit of bay shrimp.
Some of the roasted,
shredded pork,
a nice ladle
of our batter.
Stirry-stirry.
Onto the flat top.
Beautiful.
Cook this on one side,
flip it.
Takes about eight
to ten minutes.
We'll put that right
in our plate there.
Okay.
Two sauces.
Little bit of
a red beni shoga,
which is pickled ginger.
Beautiful.
Some scallions.
Is that bonito flakes we're
getting ready to go for?
We are.
You're an animal.
And some nori.
Can't "ig-nori" that.
You cannot.
Here we go.
♪♪
That is one of the
most unique dishes
I've ever tried
in a food truck.
That has got such
a gourmet flair to it.
One minute,
it's all pork.
Next minute, it's all
veggie and creamy.
Then it's the sour coming
from the pickled ginger.
Then you're over
into the crunchiness --
the texture on the outside
of the pancake.
Then, you have the creaminess
in the inside of the pancake.
Oh, dude,
it's so good.
Okonomiyakis,
Tickets 1 and 2.
It's hard to describe,
but it's such
a unique experience.
Beautiful sauce on top,
and it's just
really tasty dish.
GUY: They can
always get this?
No.
Oh, that's good.
[ Snorts ]
Because we change
our menu so often.
If they want to find
where you're at
and what you're serving,
they go online.
Yep, it's always changing.
GUY:
'Cause everything depends
on what he's picking out
fresh at the farm.
MAN: He even has
a board on his truck
that shows
what came from where.
Plating up some
braised octopus.
He gives so much back
to the community.
MAN: All the tips usually go
to a local charity.
Every week, he picks
a different charity ticket.
Number three,
crispy calamari salad.
You got any other
"wow" factors?
Pohole fern
lafette puck salad
with braised octopus.
Didn't The Beatles have
a song with that?
I don't know.
I like everything
about this dish.
The flavor and the texture
is so amazing and so unique.
Let's get started.
Hawaiian octopus.
First, we're
gonna clean it.
So, a little
Hawaiian sea salt,
'cause that just
takes off the slime.
Just give them a rinse
with some fresh water.
How long are we
gonna simmer?
One hour with one
can of local beer.
Really?
Yes.
All right, Chef.
Fiddlehead ferns.
Hawaiian
fiddlehead ferns.
Got some nice
salted boiling water,
and they cook
really quickly.
And then,
into an ice bath.
Yep, right into
an ice bath,
and they're ready to go.
The octopus is cooled.
Add that right into
our mixing bowl.
This is called Limu kohu.
Local seaweed.
Little sesame oil.
And give that
a quick stir.
Okay.
So, we're gonna go ahead
and build our salad now.
Our blanched and shocked
Pohole ferns --
Hawaiian fiddleheads --
some local Kula onions,
which is a sweet onion.
Some cherry tomatoes,
toasted sesame seeds,
a little chopped roasted
macadamia nuts.
This is what we call inamona --
a roasted candle nut.
The old candlenut.
Little bit
of fried garlic.
It's a food truck, sir.
It's not a space shuttle.
We're almost ready
for takeoff.
Dried chopped shrimp,
toasted coconut,
our marinated octopus,
our vinaigrette,
which is roasted garlic oil,
fresh lime juice,
and fish sauce.
And, finally,
some fresh jalapeños.
And that's
all she wrote.
Mixy-mixy,
stirry-stirry.
All those textures
and those flavors,
you want to really
blend that together.
♪♪
Bro...
it's ridiculously good.
Thank you.
It's just like
a symphony of flavor.
You're such a
talented chef
with such a phenomenal
imagination.
It's overwhelming
just how cool you are.
Thank you.
[ Scoffs ]
Come meet this cat.
Oh, and the
food's great, too.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
You know that her
parents forced her.
She was probably
sitting in her room
and they go, "Honey,
we're making a video,
and you have to
be in it."
And she is
chewing her gum.
And then, the dog.
They love puppies!