People are asking
me all the time.
"Hey, Guy, that one joint
you checked out that one city
when you were doing 'Triple D,'
how they doin'?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out
it was only the beginning
because "Triple D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back to see
what's cooking...
like on this trip.
You know what I always say?
Winner, winner.
-Winner, winner.
Winner, winner,
chicken dinner.
So we've got a sandwich shop
outside of Boston
with a once-a-month masterpiece.
Outstanding!
-Fried chicken sandwich.
Just come on down.
There's stuffed-to-the-gills
grilled cheese in Cleveland.
-Bursting with flavor.
-Thank you.
-It's bursting.
-Bursting.
And in Los Angeles...
You got to eat that
as a kid?
...a plate full
of Filipino flavors.
Mother. Father.
That's good.
Familiar faces, new places
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple-D Nation."
♪♪
You know, a sandwich shop's
got to bring something
to the table to stand out
in the "Triple D" world.
And this place outside of Boston
I found back in 2012
definitely brought it.
A lot of flavor on a chew.
Lot of bite.
Always, always great food.
Love it.
And now they've expanded
their footprint and their menu.
This is Cutty's.
♪♪
Two O.G.
Fried chicken sandwiches.
You know, it's great
that my little sandwich shop
is a star on the Food Network
with Guy.
It deserves it.
"Triple D" really showed
what Cutty's is about.
They are making really
delicious sandwiches.
FIERI: Which is something owners
Charles and Rachel Kelsey
were on the hunt for when they
opened this place back in 2010.
We love sandwiches.
We could never find
exactly what
we were looking for.
There are great sandwiches
in Boston --
But just none
that we wanted to eat.
Yeah, that's --
that's sly.
There's a lot of sandwich
places for other people.
You're not the real people
because if you were,
you'd have the hat on.
That's more like it.
Bandero.
[ Laughs ]
You always wear the hat,
or just on special occasions?
Just on
special occasions.
-Yes.
-On rainy days.
I mean, that's what it's like
to be a business owner.
You know, wear
a lot of different hats.
I mean, your own businesses,
is you know what it's like.
Yeah, yeah. I've never had
that went on, though.
You know, I wore the hat
for a few weeks afterwards,
and people asked me
to take it off constantly.
Why?
That was my question constantly.
It got in the way
in the kitchen.
Yeah.
Oh! Team members
asked to take it off.
-Not the guests.
-Exactly.
Is this sombrero
still in the restaurant?
It's hanging on the wall.
And people take their pictures
in front of it. It's awesome.
So, we do this show.
How many years ago?
-Five years.
-Five years ago?
I was pregnant
and our son is gonna be 7.
No!
Yeah.
Roast Beef 1000.
You still doing
the same greatest hits?
What is the story here?
We're going to make
our Roast Beef 1000.
Why'd you call it
the Roast Beef 1000?
Because
it's from the future.
So now let's trim
the beef chuck roll.
Enormous. This is like
the brontosaurus.
Just gonna take off
just a little bit of the fat.
Flip it over
and we'll tie it.
-Yes!
Rub it down.
Okay.
In the fridge, 24 hours,
cook it evenly, and what
temperature and how long?
We start on 500.
After about an hour,
we drop down 300.
And it goes 2, 3 hours
after that.
We got a black pepper
brioche bun.
Got a little toast
in the...press.
Look at that.
So Thousand Island,
we make in-house.
Copious amounts of beef.
Sharp cheddar cheese
and some shallots.
♪♪
Look at that!
Outstanding.
It should be
the Roast Beef 1 Million.
We didn't change the name,
but we probably sold over
a million since "Triple D."
I was on the front cover
of Boston magazine
a few years back.
It's written into history here.
Has the menu changed?
We didn't have
breakfast before.
Now we have this
whole breakfast sandwich menu.
I know how much you love eggs.
Right.
Eggs is my favorite.
Thanks for sharing that.
That'll make the show.
MAN: They're serving breakfast,
and I live in the neighborhood
and I love coming here
to get the Thai breakfast
sausage sandwich.
This has Thai flavors based
on a traditional Thai sausage.
We're going to start
with the brown pork.
This is cooked, cooled
jasmine rice,
water and fish sauce.
We give that a mix.
This is green curry paste.
Dark brown sugar.
We're going to scoop out
generous three ounce portions
and then flatten them out.
Go in a convection oven at 475.
They get nice
and crispy and brown.
Now we're going to make the
dressing for the papaya salad.
Start with lime juice.
Dark brown sugar.
Fish sauce.
Ginger, garlic. Blend that up.
Pour over the papaya.
We're also going to add some
chopped cilantro and mix it up.
We're ready to build
our sandwich.
We're gonna take our pickled
Thai chili mayo.
It's lime juice,
pickled Thai chilies,
granulated garlic,
salt, brown sugar.
Mayonnaise.
A little bit that
on the bottom.
Now we're going to add
two of these patties.
We're going to put
a little bit more mayo.
Papaya salad,
roasted peanuts, fried shallots.
I'm Guy Fieri
and I approve those shallots.
Yes.
♪♪
This is our Thai
sausage sandwich.
Got a Thai sausage up.
They make their own homemade
sausage here.
It has like enough spice,
gives it a kick,
but also a sweetness.
It's delicious.
They add a papaya salad
that really pulls
the whole thing together.
Makes it really unique
and delicious.
Have you lost
the weird?
But the food's not the only
thing unique about this joint.
How now, brown cow?
Plus a Sunday special...
It's like a thing.
...worth every day of the week.
I mean, I'm just starting
the petition now.
Next.
FIERI: Back in 2012,
I was outside of Boston,
in Brookline, Massachusetts.
It's home to the birthplace
of JFK,
a cool magazine called
Cook's Illustrated,
and a rockin' little sandwich
joint known as Cutty's.
There was a great experience,
a great visit,
you guys were so much fun.
You're such a character.
-BFF.
-Have you lost the weird?
It's gotten weirder. I mean,
I'm getting older.
Is that what it is?
How now, brown cow?
The arsonist had
oddly shaped feet.
Yes.
We got so busy afterwards.
We actually had to knock
the wall down.
Out of anger? Was there a family
fight? Or did something happen?
-We needed More space.
-Really?
So how far
did you expand?
Double the size.
Double.
Yeah, double the size.
I still gets crazy.
But, you know,
we have two doors now.
There's a flow,
more comfortable.
They've expanded,
but they're still a line
down the road on Sunday
for chicken.
CHARLES: One Sunday a month,
we do Super Cluckin' Sunday.
We sell like 600-700 sandwiches,
there's a line down the block.
It's like a thing. Yeah.
-Yeah.
WOMAN: The line is out
the door around the corner.
So come early.
[ Chuckles ]
And how are you doing
this fried chicken.
So we do a light buttermilk
brine overnight.
It's got salt, sugar, and 12
secret herbs and spices.
-Uh, somebody already has that.
-No, we have one more.
Oh, they're 11?
You out did
the colonel by one?
You animal.
CHARLES: That's going to go
in the fridge overnight.
We do a double dredge.
Throw it into
our seasoned flour.
They're going gonna go into
the buttermilk egg mixture
and then back into the flour
and we're gonna get them frying.
♪♪
When they're golden brown,
ready to go.
And we do the sandwich
two different ways --
honey mustard
and then barbecue ranch.
And you make
everything yourself.
Yeah.
When we first started,
we only did one sandwich.
It was the
OG honey mustard.
And we use really strong
French Dijon mustard
and really good honey.
We make this in-house.
Chicken more, honey mustard,
and then Vermont sharp cheddar
cheese shaved Vidalia onions,
shredded iceberg lettuce,
and then mayonnaise.
This is our Super Cluckin'
Sunday OG honey mustard.
I got two OG honey mustard fried
chicken sandwiches.
The chicken is crispy and moist.
Honey mustard is the perfect
balance of sweet and tangy.
It's a little sweet, salty,
crunchy. Perfect.
So how do we get
Cluckin' Sunday to every Sunday?
Because that's what's
going to happen.
People are going to
watch this and go,
how do we get
Cluckin' Sunday?
-Yeah.
-Um.
I mean, I'm just starting
the petition now.
CHARLES: Yeah.
You guys just go --
you see the thing
at the bottom of the screen?
Oh, there's no thing?
Just start the petition, please.
They just come on down.
It takes a lot to be
just a sandwich joint
and be on "Triple-D."
I mean, you got to be
like a sandwich plus.
This is sandwich plus, plus.
I'm happy. I'm happy for you.
-Yeah.
This is a great little visit
down memory lane with you two.
Muchos gracias.
Yeah. De nada.
Mañana.
Explosive.
♪♪
Coming up, a neighborhood joint
in Los Angeles.
It's almost like
the all star lineup.
FIERI: Feeding Filipino
favorites to all their fans.
I mean, the thing
is addicting. Mm!
FIERI:
In 2013, I was in the Echo Park
neighborhood of Los Angels,
checking out a catering company
with some roots.
I came here for the food and I'm
getting a bunch of the culture.
And years later,
we're still rocketing.
This is The Park's Finest.
I was actually born
in the Philippines.
I still have memories of how
the food tasted back home.
And this is very comparable
to that.
The place is worthy
of all the hype
that "Triple-D"
created for them.
It's from the community
and it's for the community.
FIERI: Started by
Johneric Concordia and his crew.
Everybody had a crew back
in the '90s.
I mean, you probably ran
a dance crew yourself.
Yeah, big, big. You probably
could see in my moves.
Chris, Mike, Ann
were a crew of people
who love taking care of people.
FIERI: Just like
their moms did for 'em.
This is Mama Leah's
coconut beef.
Mama Leah's my mother who took
care of 13 people
in a three bedroom apartment
and fed them this over rice.
Bring it.
So we're gonna use top round.
This is how much your mother
would cook in a apartment
with three bedrooms?
Maybe a little bit more.
Pink salt.
Pepper blend.
Copious amounts of the dried
onion and the garlic powder.
[ Whistles ]
Mama Leah's coconut beef
is the most
traditionally Filipino dish bed
you're gonna have.
Now is it going
in this smoker?
It's going to go into the rig.
It was our original smoker,
when we started off
as a catering company.
So...
So for the big work,
you put it in the rig?
But in the rig.
It looks like
it's hooked up to my Camaro.
If it's missing,
don't you blame me.
We let this run anywhere
between six to 16 hours.
After dark, I think
I'm moving the car.
I would, too.
[ Laughs ]
Let's get into this.
We've taken
the top round that we cook.
We heat up the wok.
We start to roast it.
This is what you ate
as a kid?
This is what we ate.
Thirteen people --
At least.
Three bedroom house.
Apartment.
You've moved since then.
No, I'm still there.
Where's your mom live?
She lives with us.
We still live together.
We're not leaving
that apartment.
We're going to then add
fish sauce, the yellow chilies.
This is all roasted garlic?
It's garlic with olive oil,
pink Himalayan salt,
our pepper blend.
This is Chaokoh coconut cream,
crushed out in Thailand --
Some of the best coconut milk
out there.
Water.
Now, how long we're going
to let this cooked down?
Another hour and a half
before we add sugar cane vinegar
from the Philippines.
There was Cocoa Puffs
in the '80s
and now there's coco beef.
We'll put it in the smoker,
and that's kind of like
our crock pot.
So you'll hold it in there,
pull it out,
give a scoop on rice.
There you go.
Crazy.
Wow.
Lot of flavors in this.
Oh, my gosh.
Thing is, this is addicting.
♪♪
You got to eat
that as a kid?
Yeah, every day.
No wonder you didn't
move out of that apartment.
He'd be crazy!
-Coconut beef stew.
We know it as Guy Fieri's
number 1 seller.
The beef is so tender,
there's a little bit of spice,
it's just food that's made
with a lot of love.
JOHNERIC:
And we want to continue
to represent Filipino food.
It is food that's welcoming
that you can share
and enjoy with your family.
The Worker Wednesday
combo plate.
We decided to make
a Worker Wednesday plate,
which consists of nearly
60 percent of our menu.
Has a little bit of everything,
kind of it's almost like
the all star lineup.
So we start with
Candy-Coated Chicken.
So we have our split chicken
seasoned with salt,
pepper, garlic, onion blend.
Put it in the oven for about
an hour, slice them into pieces,
and coat it with
our signature barbecue sauce.
We start off
with pineapple chunks,
tomatoes, soy sauce, water.
♪♪
Minced garlic,
California yellow chilies,
tomato paste,
more water.
Brown sugar, coconut powder,
more of our garlic-onion blend.
And we're gonna add a little bit
more of our pepper blend.
And once it's boiled,
we're going to add it
to our roasted chicken to create
a candy coated chicken.
This is our 16-hour
pulled pork,
a fifteen pound pork butt.
And we season it
with our general seasoning
of pink Himalayan salt.
White, black, cayenne powder
and chili flake blend
as well as our garlic
and onion blend.
We cook it for one hundred
and eighty degrees for 16 hours
and it develops a nice bark.
We give you two scoops
of white rice,
16-hour pulled pork,
our hot link medley,
which consists of spicy Polish,
a red hot,
and a Filipino sweet longanisa,
roasted veggie medley,
Candy-Coated Chicken,
Mama Leah's Coconut Beef Stew,
and a slice of
Ann's Cornbread Bibingka.
We are definitely going
kulinary gangster.
Going to go ahead and add
the cream-style corn.
Go for it.
♪♪
Hold onto her, Scottie!
We've roasted some
banana leaves.
We're going to
stay Filipino on this.
Stay Filipino on it
and use this to
naturally moisten
the cornbread bibingka.
Bibingka?
Bibingka, so it's phonetic.
B-I-N-G --
[ Chuckles ]
[ Buzzer ]
[ Ding ]
Butter it.
Hit with some sugar.
To get it nice and crispy
on the top.
We just put it back into
the convection
for another five minutes.
That's about some
of the most tender,
light, fluffy,
flavored cornbread I've had.
Worker Wednesday combo plate.
I like the chicken.
Crispy on the outside
Tender on the inside.
Pulled pork is my favorite,
full in flavor. It's very good.
WOMAN: The flavors are
definitely Filipino.
It tastes like
what I grew up with.
Wish they had it on Monday,
Tuesday, Thursday, and Friday.
"Triple-D" came here and you can
really see the effect of that.
We had no money,
we had no experience.
But somebody on television
decided to show
the world that we were special.
Mother, father.
That's good.
We call it the Guy Fieri effect,
and it's real.
♪♪
FIERI:
Coming up in Cleveland...
You got an
attitude problem, son!
Grilled cheese
never looked so good.
Mm!
Dude. Out of bounds.
FIERI: When we find crazy joints
on "Triple-D,"
lots of times it's 'cause people
send me in the right direction.
You know what's funky?
You know what's out there.
And back in 2009,
I got a hot tip from none
other than my Aunt Polly.
The creativeness
is just awesome.
These days,
they've got 10 locations.
So here I am in Cleveland,
going to another
one of your favorites.
Melt bar and grilled.
it was cool to see Guy visit
a restaurant
that I had been to before.
Made me want
to keep coming back.
It's not your regular
grilled cheese.
MAN:
It's got a neighborhood feel,
but it's also got
that rock and roll vibe.
FIERI: That's thanks to owner
Matt Fish, a musician and chef
who rocks out 30 different types
of grilled cheese.
I think we can stick anything
inside of it
and it's still considered
a grilled cheese sandwich.
FIERI:
But he doesn't take requests.
Everyone comes up and grabs me
and says,
please put this sandwich
on the menu.
I need this sandwich.
Apparently, I grabbed Guy
by the collar.
I think I was trying
to make a point.
FIERI: Look at this!
What am I?
Am I in some G.I. movie?
You got
an attitude problem, son.
So what are we
going to make?
The world-famous
Parmageddon sandwich.
Why does it get
called Parmageddon?
Parma is the Polish hotbed
in Cleveland
and pierogies is
a main staple.
Okay.
We're gonna start with
our grilled bread every time.
Turn our sauté pan on.
We're going to add
our vegetable oil.
We're going to brown
our pierogies.
They're just fresh potatoes,
a good, hearty
cheddar cheese in there.
We brown 'em
real nice on both sides.
And our grilled onions. Get
those bad boys in there, nice.
Flambé, grilled sandwiches,
you never see that.
Look out, girls.
Nice soft cabbage
for it.
Crowd spice, vodka.
Ooh!
Cider vinegar.
And that's it.
All we got to do is just let
this get happy, happy, happy.
Sharp cheddar cheese
goes on both sides of the bread.
Pierogies down first,
all that good, good
caramelization
that goes on top.
This is --
Oh-aah!
Aah! A hot onion, went between
my toes, in my foot flop.
Aah.
I had something
on my tongs.
And I just kind of
flicked it this way.
-Right in between the toes.
-I thought I was in trouble.
Whoo!
I just injured
the star of the show.
Sorry.
I wore the flip flops.
We carried on.
Boom.
That's crazy.
♪♪
Mm, dude.
Out of bounds.
That is one of the best
grilled cheese I've ever had.
It's over the top
and around again, over the top.
Well, thank you.
You know who I have to
bring in here?
Aunt Polly!
Tell me what you think of this.
Is that crazy?
That's the bomb.
Bursting with flavor.
Well, thank you.
It's bursting.
Bursting!
It's bursting!
The "Triple-D" episode really
kind of helped us
catch wildfire.
Melt Bar and Grilled.
Just like...
And that's really what has
helped us to expand
to 10 locations now.
They have tons of locations.
But the food is still amazing.
The Big Popper sandwich.
That tastes like
a jalapeño popper.
Tokyo tuna melt, man.
[ Whistles ]
Making some magic, dude.
Thanks, man.
Killer.
WOMAN: Matt likes to take
the craziest things
you can think of and fit them
between two pieces of bread.
Who else would think of putting
pierogies in a sandwich?
Or the Korean War thing.
Never expected chicken fingers
and mashed potatoes
to be in a sandwich.
I have the winner winner
chicken dinner.
One of Guy's favorite catch
phrases is,
"Winner, winner chicken dinner."
You know...
-Winner, winner.
-Winner, winner chicken dinner.
You got it.
-Alright. So we're making
the Winner, Winner
Chicken Dinner today.
The sandwich essentially
is mom's chicken dinner
on a sandwich.
We're starting by making
the crispy fried chicken
tenders all purpose flour.
Corn meal goes in here,
black pepper, paprika,
onion powder, kosher salt,
baking powder.
I'm just going to mix
all this stuff up.
And then I start to
add some water.
Alright. So we're ready
to dredge our chicken.
We use two chicken tenders
into our crispy batter mix.
Nice and coated, perfect,
right into the fryer.
Put a little oil
on my flat top here.
Put my potaters on there.
Crispin' them up on both sides.
Four slices
of sharp cheddar cheese.
Take our sweet corn purée,
vegan margarine, diced onions,
all-purpose flour,
corn, kosher salt,
sugar, Hungarian paprika,
black pepper,
heavy cream going in next.
Bring this up to a small boil,
thickening it up.
So the sweet corn purée
is going to get
put on both sides of the bread.
Chicken tenders from before,
our mashed potatoes,
garlic greens, everything's
going into the salamander.
The Winner, Winner
Chicken Dinner. Oh, my.
MAN: Winner, Winner was like
super unique.
Never had anything like it.
Excellent.
They Kind of melt the cheese
on each side of the bread
that way you still get
the grilled cheese factor
and they stuff all the filling
in between.
It's just like the best dinner
your grandma ever cooked for you
thrown onto
a grilled cheese sandwich.
♪♪
You're going to trip out
when you come to this place.
Well, thank you for
the recommendation Aunt Polly.
Vern, pick up the check.
Okay, wait here for me.
It's in the mail.
-I got a proper sausage to go.
-But these aren't
the only joints folks like you
have sent me to.
-Mighty macaroni.
-There are plenty more
"Triple-D" fan favorite
out there for me to check out.
Plus, we'll be bopping
into more places.
Next time
on "Triple-D Nation."
Seriously, I'd like to put that
on the back of like an 18.
♪♪
Oh, can you feel the magic?
CHARLES: Just gonna do it
one more time.
Seriously I don't have
anything else to say out loud.