Alright, Hunter,
here's the game plan.
Months ago, you sent out
a video saying to people,
you wanted to know their
favorite "Triple-D" location.
Remember that?
I do.
We want to know, what is your
favorite "Triple-D" joint?
People submit their video.
-My favorite --
-Our favorite --
-Favorite--
-Favorite "Triple-D" joint--
Mmm!
They had to describe
why they like it...
Mm-hmm. Their
favorite dish.
They could be funny.
They could be sad.
They could sing a song,
whatever they wanted to do
to draw attention to why
this "Triple-D" location
should be on
America's "favorite" list.
Mm!
People were very
excited about this.
Thousands of submissions.
You and I sat,
you and I watched,
and we picked --
I think, some of the best.
Just look at how
delicious this stuff is.
[ Laughs ]
Those winners, Hunter,
each are gonna
get 1,000 bucks,
[ Cash register dings ]
and they're gonna
get featured on
their own, special edition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives."
On top of that, we're not only
gonna show you their video...
Hi, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out!
we're gonna show America that
"Triple-D" location again,
so they can understand
why they're on the list
of America's Favorite
"Triple-D" joints.
We're on the same page?
Yes.
Oh, yeah.
Like on this trip --
monster meatballs...
Who doesn't love meatballs?
...top-notch tostadas...
There you go.
...and barbecue that'll
make you bust a rhyme.
♪ Great food, great vibes,
Slab BBQ ♪
That was money.
Bro.
♪♪
ALL: Hi, everyone!
[ Laughs ]
[ Both laugh ]
So, the deal is, Hunter,
we're going through
some of the most outrageous
videos you've ever seen,
and these are people that
are trying to convince us
their favorite
"Triple-D" location
is one of
America's favorites.
Get down here.
So we asked him to submit
some 1-minute videos
explaining
the type of food,
what they love
about the restaurant
and make it entertaining
and creative.
Yee-haw!
It's not based upon how
many videos per location.
It's just what video
is gonna get
what location voted in to
America's Favorite
Diners, Drive-Ins Dives.
Let's see what we
got. Roll it.
♪ Saw a guy standing there
at Chap's Pit Beef ♪
♪ Sandwich in his hand
they call the Triple-D ♪
♪ Pit beef first goes on, then
sausage, corned beef, bun ♪
[ Laughs ]
This is awesome.
♪ ...me, yeah me ♪
♪ With a pit beef of my
own in my belly ♪
♪ Belly ♪
Oh, that was classic.
That was awesome.
Just so you know, I think
that's gonna be coming out
on the 'Flavortown" album.
That was really --
That was so cool.
We should call over to
Bob and Donna and get some --
They need to see that.
I want to find out
how crazy this guy is.
Alright, so we've got our
winner, the rock star Michael,
and our buddy Bob,
from Chap's Pit Beef.
What's up, guys?
Hey!
Hey, hey!
Your song rocked, man.
I mean, you crushed it.
What was the inspiration,
though?
I just love these guys.
I love Chap's.
I love Bob and Donna,
and I know they're
huge fans of yours.
I said, "Well, we
got to represent."
I'm glad that the Triple-D
is one of your favorites.
You got a Guy Triple-D coming?
MAN: Sure do.
This, I got to have.
Look at this.
♪♪
Ridiculous.
The words are right,
the tempo was right,
the enthusiasm was right.
And I laughed
and laughed.
I was dancing around,
singing that song all morning.
I thought it was awesome.
That's awesome.
Well, I'll tell you,
this is Chap's Pit Beef.
On "Triple-D," when we hit an
historic place like Baltimore,
well, we got to use the inside
track of a buddy who lives here.
So, regardless of the weather
or how busy this dude is,
we're at Charm City Cakes
to talk to
the cake bad boy, Duff Goldman,
and find out one
of his favorite joints.
Call the cops.
GUY: Is this where
the magic happens?
How are you doing?
Good to see you.
Nice to see you.
So, you open up
the bakery,
you've been doing
this thing here,
but you really come
from a culinary background.
I come to Baltimore, I want to
try some iconic Baltimore food.
Locals know, gotta
get pit beef.
So where's the best
place to get it?
I think probably Chap's.
Chaps's. Let's get
some pit beef.
Alright. Let's do it.
Oh, sweet.
Isn't that nice?
Come on, let me drive.
Seriously?
Seriously, can I?
No.
Oh, come on.
I didn't get to
make any cake.
This thing is awesome.
That way. Now, punch it.
[ Engine growls ]
This is the famous Chap's?
This is Chap's.
Look at that.
You come to Baltimore, and
this is what you better see.
If you don't,
it's not pit beef.
Best pit beef I ever had.
When anybody says "Chap's,"
they know what
we're talking about.
It started 21 years ago,
when Bob and Donna Creager
got married.
DONNA:
As a wedding gift, my father
gave me this little shack.
For lawn tools, or
what was the reason?
Well, no. He said, since
my husband loved to cook,
we should put a pit beef stand
outside of his nightclub.
Fry and a rare.
We started just a grill and
exhaust system and a register.
And learned real quick...
BOB: Two beef on a roll.
Thank you.
...bringing in so many fans,
they had on a dining room.
Somebody get
the counter, please.
But the beef is still the same.
Is this the best pit beef
in Baltimore?
Yes, it is.
Now this is...
It's a bottom round.
You're gonna put about six of
these on to start the day.
You can smell it from
as early as probably
6:00 in the morning.
Once I smelled
that smoke, I said,
"I've got to get
over here."
Just straight on the grill,
just like it.
400 or 500 degrees,
usually.
Baker boy, what do you think?
That's about right.
I'll melt the gold.
Where'd your bling go?
What are we gonna make first?
We'll make a
beef sandwich.
You can do it. Come on,
now. Keep pushing it.
It got to the point where it's
really on the rare side, right?
I mean, we're almost
tartare, right there.
So that goes back
on the grill,
and then we'll bring
another piece out.
So it's just, like,
tag-team meat slicing.
Exactly.
Hey, look at that over there.
Oh, what?
Check that out.
Ohh.
Now, what do you like
to put on these?
Onions, maybe a little
salt and pepper.
Bit of horseradish
on there.
Mm.
Now, how many of these
you guys sell in a day?
A couple hundred.
You know, I like the little
char to it, but I got to say,
the medley of the white onion,
the really nice,
bright horseradish,
a little bit of salt and pepper,
a great roll --
not too much bread.
I hate when you get too much
bread, and it starts to be --
No, it's all
about the meat.
Right.
Ohhh.
That'll just clean you
right out, won't it?
Wow.
That was all horseradish.
It's good for you.
Whoa.
There it is.
My toes are tingling.
[ Laughing ]
Wow!
Welcome to Baltimore.
It's spicy. It's moist.
The meat is so tender.
I give it way past a 10.
And there's way more
than beef.
Three turkeys.
They're putting
everything on the pit.
If you want a variety,
the ham, the turkey,
I like it.
and of course,
sausage, too.
That's another good one.
Oh, yeah.
What do you got there,
meat wizard?
Corned beef.
GUY: Yep. They're even
pit-grilling the corned beef
for killer Reubens,
and combos any way you want.
Mm. It's great, man.
Oh, I like everything
they got in here.
I need a second barbecue,
for a call-in.
They got the best smoky
flavor in the whole town.
Same as always for two decades.
It's like going to a
family member house,
and they got
the grill out...
Great day, sir.
Thank you.
...except they're
always open,
and they don't mind
you stopping by.
You make these
great combos.
Now, can I custom-build
my own combo?
Oh, absolutely.
For my boy Duff?
Shh.
BOB: We'll start
with the beef.
GUY: Some jalapeños down.
The horseradish.
Okay, now put
the ham up there.
Cut the burger
in half.
Nacho cheese sauce.
Sausage. Pickles.
A little chopped
beef, turkey.
Where are you,
Duffinator?
My brother!
Just look at
the cascading joy.
There you go.
There's a champion.
Let's cut this in half.
No, no, no.
Don't cut it.
If you cut it,
it's gonna explode.
Look at the bite
out of that!
Make sure you don't
lose anything.
Congratulations.
You crushed it.
You won. You get the money.
Job well done. Job well done.
That was impressive.
That was very impressive.
Thank you very much.
Thanks.
Alright. More to come.
Don't go anywhere.
Guy, I was there for
you when I saw you
get your star
on the Walk of Fame.
I've been waiting
for this all day.
You crush it.
♪ Black Angus brisket
atop a grilled onion ♪
That's on the A-side
of the album.
You know what? It's just about
having fun, so let me go for it.
You guys are
the real deal.
♪♪
-My favorite --
-Peace out!
[ Laughs ]
We're hanging out here in
the kitchen at the Fieri house,
watching some of the greatest
videos we've ever seen.
My favorite dish of all time.
One of the best spots.
And these are people that
are trying to convince us
that their favorite
"Triple-D" location
is one of
America's favorite.
Roll it.
[ Hip-hop music plays ]
What's up? I'm Gonz,
and Slab BBQ is the dopest.
Slab speaks with their barbecue,
and I speak with my hands
so this is why I
love Slab BBQ.
[ Rapping ]
♪ Great food, great
vibes, Slab BBQ ♪
[ Spoken ] Did I mention I
really love Slab BBQ?
Look at my eyes flashing.
...in particular that I really
enjoy, and it's called El Jefe.
Here's what it
comes with. Let's go.
♪ Black Angus brisket
topped with grilled onions ♪
This is a
full-on commercial
♪ Throw in some
peppers and jalapeños ♪
♪ Taste it with a bit of
that barbecue sauce ♪
♪ Throw it with some
Fritos on top ♪
♪ To add that little sprinkle ♪
♪ With a crunchy treat
like a sundae ♪
[ Spoken ] El Jefe,
you are the boss.
Where's Flavortown, you ask?
It's in Austin, Texas.
With a side of Gold Rush sauce,
they heat slow,
low, and bangin'.
That was money.
Bro.
That was so money.
[ Music plays ]
Bro.
Money.
[ Skipping ]
Bro-bro-bro.
Money.
That's on the A-side
of the album.
For sure.
That was sick.
That was beyond sick.
I'm calling that dude.
You calling him?
GUY: So there's
Mark and Jay from Slab
and our winner, Jonathan.
What's up, my brothers?
Hey!
Hey Jonathan, Mark.
What's up, bro? Hey, Jay.
Dude, that video
was hysterical,
and the music
to go with it.
I don't know
which one was better,
the video or the music
or the rapping.
I was like, you know what?
It's just about having fun,
so let me go for it,
and all my friends
were freaking out, like,
"Was that you rapping
on that thing?"
I was like, "Yeah."
That was sick, man.
You crushed it. You guys
are the real deal.
I mean, the McDowell.
Come on, please.
Could we just have, like,
50 of those shipped out here?
You guys crushed it.
It was a dynamite visit.
♪♪
So, I'm here in Austin, Texas
to check out a...
barbecue joint, you got it.
No, they don't play
country music.
No, they don't serve
meat by the pound.
They're not doing
a meat and three.
No, these dudes all
about making some
crazy, whacked-out sandwiches,
playing some old-school hip-hop,
and they like to keep it
slow, low and bangin'.
This is Slab.
♪♪
Hey, you put
that one down.
MAN: The thing about Slab --
it's irreverent,
because of the '90s
hip-hop vibe.
It's not traditional.
O.G. up, El Jefe up.
But the care that they put
into smoking their meat --
it's really good.
GUY: This backyard-barbecue
party vibe is hosted by
renegade pit master Mark Avalos
and his buddy Raf Robinson.
You know, we were
kids of hip-hop.
You're giving them the great
flavors of barbecue,
but putting it in
a new environment --
But how is
the barbecue different?
Barbecue sandwiches only.
No brisket plate?
No brisket plate.
No ribs?
Ribs, yes.
The McDowell,
a true rib sandwich.
And then we've got
Soul Glo sauce --
No, it doesn't say
"Soul Glo sauce."
Sure.
MAN: Got a McDowell
for table number 7.
It's perfect. They
take the bones out,
they put it between
two great pieces of bread
with a lot of other good stuff.
Nobody does anything like this.
McDowell.
From the movie --
"Coming to America."
One of our favorite
Eddie Murphy movies.
"Oh, can't you see."
This is where things
are gonna get weird.
First, we're gonna
make the rub.
Turbinado sugar, sea salt,
dry mustard, chili powder,
renneated garlic,
cayenne, black pepper,
onion powder, and cinnamon.
Dry-rub it up on
this St. Louis rib,
and how long is it gonna
go down in the smoker?
3 1/2, 4 hours.
The pecan and the oak.
Now we're into
the Soul Glo.
Don't let your soul glow.
These guys have too much
fun in this place.
I'm telling
you right now.
We're making the
Gold Rush sauce.
The Gold Rush and
the Backyard Red
become the Soul Glo.
That's correct.
Dummy.
Mustard,
apple cider vinegar.
Sugar, water.
Brown sugar.
Chili powder.
You got it.
Black pepper.
I'm hungry.
Liquid smoke?
Yeah.
Soy?
Yes, sir.
White pepper?
White pepper.
Cayenne? Holy
heartburn, Batman.
Pepper flakes.
Add a little
bit of butter.
So, cook this down and
then mix that together
with the Backyard Red, and
that makes the Soul Glo?
Soul Glo.
Word.
Rack of ribs.
I dig it.
We'll turn, and we'll
slide. Just like that.
Look at that. You
can work here, brother.
Throwing them bones.
Craps table in
Flavortown, baby.
There you go.
I always start with
a little Backyard.
And the mustard
Gold Rush.
Let's get a little
bit more sauce,
some pickles and onions.
And that's all she wrote.
You guys are the first ones,
in the history of "Triple-D,"
that I've seen actually
make a rib sandwich.
That's gangster.
The rib meat,
super tender.
It's a perfect bun.
The pickle and the onion
countering the sweet
of the sauce --
but there's something
about rib uniqueness
that you only get
from the ribs.
You put it in a sandwich.
But, bro, you don't only
pull it off, you crush it.
You just get freedom.
It's like William Wallace
made this.
[ Both laugh ]
Where did that
come from?
Freedom!!
Two McDowells, here.
It's fantastic.
It's sweet, it's hot.
And the ribs
are super tender.
I just love a good sandwich
like this.
The sides, the craft beers,
the ambiance of this kind
of place is why I come here.
How are you homies
doing over here, man?
The music's always
taking you back.
And then you go to the menu,
and then you see
all the relevant,
you know, hip hop names.
Notorious P.I.G., ChickeN.W.A.
And it's good, man. It's great.
MAN: But yet, they're serious
about the barbecue.
The brisket here
is so juicy and moist.
FIERI: But here, you're only
getting it on a sandwich.
We've got a Jefe
and a potato salad.
CUSTOMER:
Man, the El Jefe.
This is made out of brisket
and unicorn tears.
It's amazing.
El Jefe.
FIERI: Big ol'
non-trimmed brisket.
Dalmatian rub
right here.
Cup or so.
Dalmatian rub.
Smack it up, flip it,
and rub it down.
There you go.
That's it?
Then, we'll flip
to the other side.
We don't put that much
on the other side.
Let the meat shine.
We're gonna let it sit.
24 hours,
and then go to the smoker.
10 to 12 hours --
250.
And what are we gonna
smoke on them?
The common oak.
Brisket down.
[ Chuckles ]
Next up?
We got the backyard
red sauce.
Making in red sauce.
Where you at?
Backyard.
Oh, you making
backyard red sauce.
I'm on my way over.
[ Both laugh ]
Ketchup, apple cider vinegar,
Worcestershire-shire-shire.
Liquid smoke.
Whoa! That is a lot
of liquid smoke.
Mustard.
A little molasses
coming up.
Hot sauce,
black pepper, trumino,
granulated garlic,
onion powder, and sea salt.
Let it come up
to a boil.
I'm gonna let it simmer
for about 20 minutes.
Bring the brisket out.
Look at that.
Chop it like
it's hot.
Chop it like it's...
CREW: Hot.
[ Laughs ]
That's a nice bark
on there.
Yes, sir.
Garlic toasted bun,
little backyard red.
Brisket's down.
A little bit more
of the backyard red.
And then we got
some queso.
Why?
If you're in Texas, brother,
you eat some queso.
Peppers and onions.
Jalapeños.
And we got
another Texas classic,
Got to put a little
corn chip on it.
El Jefe,
like a boss, brother.
Like a boss, huh?
Time to do some work.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
That's a bull
right there, buddy.
Wow.
When you make brisket,
that's that honest
with just a touch of sauce,
that's enough.
That is fantastic.
The brisket is on point.
The cheese sauce
isn't overwhelming.
The backyard red
is the deal-changer, baby.
[ Whistles ]
In the top of the best barbecue
sandwiches I've ever had.
Well done.
Appreciate it, man.
[ Tape rewinding ]
You guys have just
been recognized
as one of America's
favorites,
so, Jonathan,
kudos to you, my brother,
for doing a great video.
Nice.
You win 1,000 bucks,
and you deserve
every bit of this.
FIERI: Next up --
Exquisitely delicious.
This is what I get?
Sorry.
Baked beignets,
frozen pie.
That guy stole
the whole thing.
Mmm...
[ Smacks lips ]
Tasty.
♪♪
So delicious.
It's grrrreat.
Welcome back. Hunter and Guy --
we're going through
some of the most outrageous
videos you've ever seen.
There's no more
gator sausage.
Who's eating
all the gator sausage?
All right. Next up -- Lola's,
Las Vegas, Nevada.
HUNTER: Lola's.
WOMAN: How's the shrimp?
[ Laughs ]
Oh, my gosh.
I don't think this turned out
very good.
Oh, my gosh.
We burnt the shrimp.
Holy cow.
What's going on?
It's my birthday.
This was barbecue shrimp.
I've been waiting
for this all day.
This is what I get?
Sorry.
Fake beignets,
frozen pies.
Where's the catfish
and grits?
[Bleep] cookies.
You know what?
Let's go
to my favorite place, Lola's.
All right.
Let's do it.
[ Both laughing ]
That guy stole
the whole thing.
I'm gonna have to
bleep out the end.
The guy stole the show.
Lola should
actually take it
and make an advertisement
out of it.
Really.
♪♪
So I'm here in Las Vegas right
next to Charleston Boulevard,
almost smack dab
between downtown and the Strip.
Now, this building behind me
used to be Holesome Bakery --
here since the '50s,
serving Las Vegas.
Well, in 2002, it closed.
But it left a vacant spot
for a Louisiana native
to fulfill a lifelong dream.
This is Lola's.
♪♪
Oh, it's totally New Orleans.
This food's so good, it'll make
a man write bad checks.
She can pack this up
and move it to New Orleans,
it'd be packed
every night.
FIERI: But the whole point
of opening this joint in 2009,
was for Louisiana native
Lola Pokorney
to bring the Big Easy
to Sin City.
Everything that
you're going to use,
you're bringing
from New Orleans.
We bring from New Orleans
or make it ourselves.
-You wrote all the recipes.
-Yes.
FIERI: Recipes straight out of
the French Quarter
like a spicy shrimp Creole...
-Shrimp Creole is excellent.
FIERI: ...a seafood-packed
gumbo.
Gumbo!
[ Bell dings ]
...and this N'awlins classic,
the po' boy.
The roast beef po' boy here
is fantastic.
So what are we gonna make?
We're gonna do
a roast beef debris.
Okay,
so how do we make it?
We have a whole
inside round,
and we're gonna
salt him up real good.
I add some pepper,
give him a little massage,
and I'm gonna add a little water
to the pan,
put some foil on him.
And we're gonna roast him
for about 12 hours.
♪♪
Rendered all down.
And this should just be shred,
pulled apart, fork tender.
-Yes.
-And then, from there?
-I'll take the renderings
and I'll make a gravy.
And if you're gonna do gravy,
I mean, do it like this.
Use that rendered fat.
So the fat's moving.
Time for the flour.
And I like to season
my flour now.
Salt and pepper.
Gonna let this go just
a couple more minutes.
Cooked out the flour.
We got a little bit
of color on it.
We're ready to go.
We don't use water.
-We use our au jus.
-And that's gonna get poured
over the shredded beef
in the po' boy.
In the po' boy.
Nothing wrong with that.
All right,
so we got the shredded beef.
Yes.
And onto
the beautiful baguette.
Whose bread?
Leidenheimer's bread
out of New Orleans.
Mm. That's the only one.
So what do we do?
We take a little bit
of chicken stock in our pan.
Just enough to add some moisture
so we can heat the meat.
Yes.
While that's heating up,
you do the bun?
Yes, sir. We butter him up
and we toast it.
Get a good crunch on him.
Mayonnaise
and some Creole mustard.
All righty.
And some tomato
and some lettuce,
Salt and pepper.
And the meat.
And then the gravy.
Yes.
♪♪
I think I'm wearing
half of it.
Thank goodness the shirt's
the same color.
I like it.
Gravy's nice and tight,
not too thin,
doesn't sink in there
and mess up the cold veggies.
On point.
I love it because of the juice,
just rolling out the gravy.
You know, the meat is tender
and soft and spicy.
It just screams New Orleans.
WOMAN: It's a Cajun kitchen
for sure,
but they have a little bit
of everything.
FIERI:
Like the shrimp and grits.
She puts Gouda in 'em,
so they're a little smoky.
It's my favorite thing here.
FIERI: Or the in-house
oyster bar.
And if you thought Mardi Gras
was the New Orleans party,
well, then you never
been to a crawfish boil.
Crawfish up!
[ Bell dings ]
Tell me about crawfish boil.
What's the best part of this?
Whole experience.
You have everybody
sitting around a table
eatin' crawfish.
WOMAN: I learned how to do it
here 'cause I was like
the virgin crawfish eater.
I'd never seen it.
You crack the tail
and break it off.
You can drink a beer
and get another one.
Let's get started.
We got a big pot
of hot water.
You'll salt it first.
-Yes.
-Okay.
I'm gonna put in two bags
of Zatarain's.
-My favorite, crab boil.
-Cayenne.
A lot of it.
[ Whistles ] Garlic?
Next up?
Is my Louisiana
Crawfish Co Seasoning.
This is called
Lola's Trash Pot.
But the celery and the onions
and the lemons
are just
for the flavor piece of it?
-All flavor.
-You're not eating that.
You're not putting that out
on the tray and eating it.
-No.
-Now we go from baby reds.
We're gonna put in butter.
So the fat, the oil in there
is going to make it
so the shells
come off easier on the crawfish?
Yes.
Let this simmer
for, what, another 20 minutes?
-About 20 minutes.
-What's up next?
Crawfish.
Angry little one, huh?
Yeah.
How many pounds is this?
This is about five
and a half pounds.
And this will feed
how many folks?
Me.
And you could really eat
five pounds of this?
Every day.
How long are the crawfish
gonna cook for?
-About eight minutes.
-So when do we put the corn in?
Right before you pull
your crawfish,
you like to float
your corn.
-Who'd you learn this from?
-My mom and dad did it.
My brothers. We used to go
crawfishin' and all the time.
We're ready.
Do I have to put them on there
while it's spinning?
That'll be
the fun of it.
-You could eat all this?
-Yes.
Not all the corn
and potatoes,
but every single crawfish.
Now I'm gonna just top it off
with a little bit of seasoning.
-You want a lesson?
-I know the twist and pop.
There you go.
Mm.
Tasty.
The amount of teasing you did...
This is nice.
I mean, I wouldn't say this is
a mild bowl by any means.
Crawfish are
really buttery.
I just mean in the sense
that they're nice and tender.
Mm. Wow. You think that
tail meat's sweet?
That claw meat's
out of bounds.
Mm. Really tasty.
What do you think?
They're awesome.
Slippery little suckers,
but they're awesome.
Do you eat the corn
and the potatoes?
Mm-hmm. That's the best
part 'cause they all suck
in the seasoning, too.
It's spicy.
So how do you explain
to people when you say,
"I'm going to a crawfish boil?"
People have freaked out.
They get totally
freaked out.
I dig that.
Lola's has become,
in a very short period
of time, a local institution.
We lived in New Orleans
for 19 years.
And so, out in Vegas,
you're look for something close.
This place compares
tremendously.
FIERI:
People got to be thrilled.
Not everybody gets to make it
to New Orleans,
but a lot of folks
do come to Vegas.
If you come to Vegas
and you got to get a double dip,
you get a little
New Orleans experience
at the same time?
Nice going.
Thank you.
For some reason,
I can't stop eating.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI: Up next...
It's what I keep
coming back for.
They've got to be
the real deal.
They got to be
the full package.
WOLKON: Hopefully,
when this all passes
and we come back,
we really appreciate
what it means to be out
to dinner.
They're passionate
about what they do,
and that's why
we keep coming back.
-Well done.
-Nice.
♪♪
Welcome back.
Hunter and I are screening
some of the greatest videos
that you've ever seen.
-Flavor Town favorite.
-Out of bounds!
-Who's America's favorite?
-It's fantastic.
-Yay!
All right. Next up,
Steuben's, Denver, Colorado,
Roll it.
♪♪
WOLKON: Early on,
I think the hardest thing,
the most soul crushing thing
of this entire pandemic
has been when we closed
the restaurants
and we had to let about
170 people -- let 'em go.
These are workers
who live paycheck to paycheck,
rely on tips, and all of
a sudden, that was pulled away.
So it was
really important to us
to find a way
to take care of them.
We kept their health care
going through April,
and we've been offering
free meals off the menu
at Steuben's every day.
-Good dudes.
-Nice.
Today, our vendors are still
cooperating and helping us out
by donating product
for the staff to come by
and just fill up
a couple bags of groceries.
Awesome.
So I spend three main days
a week where I work on
to-go meals
for frontline employees,
whether it be Denver Health,
Urban Peak, St. Joe's Hospital.
We've done a lot of them,
different places.
WOLKON: Hopefully, when it all
passes and we come back,
we really appreciate what
it means to be out to dinner,
and to the experiences
that we provide
as independent restaurants
and what we mean
to the neighborhood
to the community.
And we know we're going
to need help and support.
But it's been a great --
It's a great community right now
to be a part of.
It's amazing,
Denver's independent
restaurant community.
Very nice.
You guys are a
class act, I'll tell you that.
That's exactly what
the heartbeat and energy
and attitude of "Triple D"
joints are.
People always ask us, you know,
how did you pick that place?
It's not just about,
do they make great food?
They got to have the character,
they got to have the attitude,
they got to have energy,
they got to have the story.
They've got to be
the real deal.
the full package.
Steuben's -- well done.
I just love the joints
we visit on "Triple D."
I mean, where are they started,
where they end up,
how it all began.
I'm in the uptown area
of Denver, Colorado,
to visit a joint
that's in a building
that was operating
as an auto garage
until the day it was converted
into a restaurant.
And the name, well, they get
that from a family owned hotspot
in Boston 50 years ago.
And the menu, well, it's from
everywhere across the country.
This is Steuben's Food Service.
-Memphis ribs to the window.
-The food is fantastic.
-Regional favorites.
-Cheese up!
They travel around the country
and bring the best of those
regions to Denver.
Chicago dog going up.
Whatever hometown we are from,
They have it.
FIERI: 'Cause
when owners Josh Wolkon...
Enjoy.
-...and Matt Selby...
-Enjoy, you guys.
FIERI: ...started putting
together a menu
with Chef Brandon Biederman...
-Herb roasted chicken up.
FIERI: It was personal.
Inevitably, we'd end up
talking about things
that we grew up eating.
-Skirt steak.
And that was kind of
how the menu evolved.
It was right there
in front of us the whole time.
Fried chicken
in the window.
-You get a great mix of food.
-From Southern...
-I love the shrimp and grits.
-...to Italian.
-Spaghetti and meatball up.
-Classic recipe.
-Even this New England standard.
-Lobster roll and fry.
-Lobster roll's the real deal.
-Lobster roll in the window.
Get about 500 pounds
of lobsters flown in a week.
Get your own little plane
for that.
All right.
So give me the lowdown.
Okay, some boiling water.
Salt it up.
Then, into the pool.
About 10, 11 minutes.
Lobsters are ready.
Put these in the ice bath.
-Stop the cooking process.
-Yep.
And these will cool for
a minute or two.
Lobsters are done.
This is gonna be awesome.
Pull it out.
Pop off the claws,
pop off the tail, dice up
the tail meat, large chunk,
split the claws.
You got a lot of texture
coming out of the tail meat.
It's real nice
and buttery here in the claw.
Nice balance.
Now goes into a bowl.
And then we make
the lobster roll dressing.
Holy bucket of mayonnaise,
Batman.
-Chopped onion, celery.
-Nice dice on that.
Yeah. Lemon juice, paprika,
some salt, pepper.
-And we just mix it up.
-Nice lobster roll.
You have these shipped in,
or someone make --
-We do, East Coast.
-Nice.
Going a little bit of clarified
butter on the flat top.
-Let them toast up.
-All right.
Good, healthy dollop
of dressing.
We mix them
to order each time.
It seems like it should
be a two bunner.
Nah, you want 'em
overflowing.
I don't want to get it
on your hand.
I was off.
[ Both snickering ]
Do I want a fork?
Do you guys think at home
I want to talk?
Absolutely not. Wow.
I want to be able
to taste the lobster.
I don't want to have
too much going on there.
It's really good.
The fact that you guys
are doing this fresh -- pretty
impressive, man. Nice job.
SERVER:
Lobster roll with fries?
Just like a lobster roll
from Maine.
This is everything
but the salt air, you know?
-Skirt steak.
-All the food is so good.
-It's a cool place to be.
-Full rack of ribs.
What's your favorite
item on the menu?
Herb roasted chicken?
MAN: You can tell these guys
slow roast their chicken.
Do it real right.
-What are we gonna make, chef?
Herb butter
for the herb roasted chicken.
A lot of butter
for a lot of chicken.
We do everything big here.
All right.
Softened, unsalted butter.
Start the mixer.
Some garlic, shallot.
-Shallots.
-Chopped chives.
Some chive.
Chive just keeps that color.
Keeps its little form.
-Some parsley.
-Lemon juice?
-Lemon juice. Yes.
-Nice.
Salt, pepper,
turn it up to two.
And that's it.
And that gets a chance
to marry in a day's time.
-Yeah.
-Okay, take that. And off we go.
-That's it.
-All right.
So we're gonna truss
and brine
some whole chickens
before we roast them.
Truss and brine.
I like it.
Wings go back,
across the legs.
More you keep this all together,
the better it's gonna cook
and the more you're going
to hold in the juices.
These things are just going
to be full of flavor.
Yeah,
we put them in bus tubs.
Then let's make the brine
for the herb roasted chicken.
We get some brown sugar, salt,
some whole cloves.
Whole black peppercorns.
Go for it.
A little bay leaf.
-And then, a grip of water.
-A grip?
It's about five gallons.
Then whisk.
It goes
over the birds.
We're gonna brine this
for about a day?
-24 hours.
-So the brine, 24 hours.
Give them
a little shake dry.
-Oh, this is awesome.
-Olive oil. Rub it in there.
Add salt.
A little bit of pepper.
And in the oven about
40 minutes.
-350 in a convection?
-Yep.
Okay, let's rock and roll.
Pop it on the cutting
board here.
Cut off the string,
take it down at the leg,
We're just gonna mark it
on the grill now.
Brush it with some herb butter
that we made earlier.
-Copious amounts.
-Of course.
Nice.
Flip it over, brush it with
some more herb butter.
It's gonna go with mashed
potatoes and sautéed vegetables.
Okay. Looking good,
feeling good?
-Yep, feeling good.
-Oh, look at that.
So you hit the butter confection
onto the bird.
You also slathered it
on the veg.
-Yep.
-Hmm. Cooked to perfection.
Mm! I try to tell folks
this all the time.
Might say roasted chicken --
mm! --
but there's such
a wide spectrum...
of what it really is
and what it really can be.
Right there, my friend,
that's what it can be.
That's dynamite.
Out of bounds.
-Marking herb roasted chicken.
-Tasty.
Chicken has a nice, juicy,
tender flavor to it.
The herbs really
stand out on there.
-The flavors are always good.
-Cuban sandwich.
We always have something
different when we come here,
but we know it's always
gonna be good.
They're passionate about
what they do and that's
why we keep coming back.
Chimichurri skirt steak
in the window.
Funky joint, fun joint.
Save me a table. I'll be back.
-Right on.
-Okay? Thank you, brother.
-Thank you.
-Good times.
Up next...
Thanks, Taco Bus.
Love you.
I got to tell you
something -- outstanding.
You guys,
the "Triple D" fans, blow it up.
They're crazy.
Favorite!
Who's America's favorite?
We'll find out.
♪♪
Now, that's what
I'm talking about.
♪♪
-Mm!
-I'm actually
already almost drooling because
I can smell it from out here.
Taco Bus, Tampa, Florida.
This place is great.
Roll it.
In the wilds of Tampa, Florida,
lives a special sort
of restaurant.
Fresh, delicious, affordable,
and importantly, beloved
by vegetarians
and meat eaters alike.
Its name is Taco Bus!
And Taco Bus is Guy Fieri
approved.
But most importantly,
it's approved by this very,
very, very picky vegetarian.
So, thanks, Taco Bus.
Love you.
That was awesome!
-The Legos.
-Excellent job.
Yeah, that was nice.
I mean,
artistically, excellent job.
Here we go.
You know, there's just
something about "Triple D"
and finding great food
in unexpected places,
like vehicles.
So here we are in Tampa,
Florida,
to check out some righteous
Mexican food in a school bus.
This is Taco Bus.
Welcome to Taco Bus.
What can I get you?
MAN: The bus is fun.
You feel like
you're in this
little corner of Mexico.
-Two chicharron taco.
-Very authentic Mexican food.
-The tacos are awesome.
-Two tacos coming up.
Chicken burrito, I have a little
bit of an addiction for it.
-The steak tostada.
-This is my favorite food.
That's one of the biggest
taco trucks I've ever seen.
How big is that school bus?
-It's about 35 feet.
FIERI: But when Rene Valenzuela
opened this joint in '91...
First,
we looked at cargo vans,
some little vans,
some little trailers.
We needed
a bigger kitchen.
Order up.
FIERI: So they got a bus.
Carne asada burrito
coming up.
And since '99,
Rene is using it
to crank out the classics
he grew up cooking in Mexico...
Fish tacos.
We wanted to do food
that's very authentic,
very deep in Mexico.
...from fried pork rinds
with salsa verde...
It's spicy.
It's really good.
FIERI:
...to the Mexican classics
with a little vegetarian spin.
For me, it's the healthy food
is what sold me.
I'm having the veggie burrito
right now, and it's amazing.
My new favorite is
the butternut squash tostada.
FIERI: Yeah. He's putting
butternut squash on a tostada.
VALENZUELA: It's still Mexican.
It's not well known,
and that's something unique
that brings you to Mexico.
-This is delicious.
-The squash.
You wait until you try it.
It's famous here.
Okay.
We start
with butternut squash, fresh.
Just gonna cut it
into large pieces.
-And where is this recipe from?
-Yucatan.
So that's it, boil it with
the seeds and everything in it?
-Right.
-Down in the water?
-That's right.
-How long?
Once it boils, about two
or three minutes.
It's got to be tender
but not too much
because, otherwise,
it gets all mushy.
Don't want to get it mushy.
All right.
So now it's boiled
and cooled a little bit.
Now we're gonna
take the seeds out?
Right. We also got
to take the skin out.
-We're gonna chop it up?
-Right.
And what's the next step?
We're gonna put
a little bit of oil, onions.
-Red bell pepper.
-Tomatoes, habanero peppers.
[ Whistles ]
I'm gonna put just
a little bit before
I add the butternut squash.
-Squash.
-Now, the butternut squash
is gonna get
a little softer here.
We're gonna
just cook it down
so it's a little bit
more tender?
That's right.
-We ready?
-We're ready.
So we're gonna top
our tostada with it.
Looks like he's putting
a fruit cocktail on there.
Now put tomatoes, onions,
cilantro and cheese.
There you go.
-That's a lot.
You can do it.
There you go.
It's got good texture.
Tostada is nice and crunchy,
and the squash is
not fall-apart soft.
The mixture of the red bell
pepper and the onions
and that little bit
of the habanero
was really done
the right way.
I'd order it again
in a heartbeat.
-All right.
-It's really nice.
-Thank you.
-Butternut squash tostada.
It's crispy, very light.
Great flavor you can't find
at a lot of places.
Two tacos chicharron
y speciale, rice and beans.
MAN: The Taco Bus, there's
really nothing else like it.
This one was here
before food trucks were cool.
The nice thing is
we don't move it around.
People can find it.
FIERI:
Anytime, day or night.
If you come here at 4:00 a.m.,
they're hungry.
They're all part
of Taco Bus Nation.
Wait. Wait. Wait.
How late are they open?
They're open 24/7.
-No.
-Yeah.
Cochinita pibil.
It's the best Mexican food
in West Florida.
Two steak tacos.
Anybody that's into this kind of
food knows about Taco Bus?
-Yeah.
-Oh, absolutely.
-Can I get a torta chilorio?
-I can go home now, dude.
We'll wrap up the torta
for lunch later, for lunching.
Do me a favor
and wrap up the bus
and take it to my casa.
-All right.
-The bomb.
Up next...
I've got something
for all of your cravings.
I think you're gonna be
really surprised, Guy.
-Delicious. Really nice.
-Yeah?
And I would absolutely eat that
on a flip flop.
That's one of my favorites
of all of these.
That's really awesome.
♪♪
It's super crusty
and wicked smoky.
They have seen me through first
dates, Valentine's Day,
breakups, and eating
my birthday dinner alone.
Mm!
And it's because of
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives."
-You ready?
-Let's do it.
You ready?
Let's roll the tape.
Hi, Guy and Hunter.
This is Peggy from New Jersey.
My husband and I have been
to several "Triple D" locations,
and by far, our favorite
is The Meatball Stoppe
in Orlando, Florida.
I highly recommend everybody
get there right now.
Not only is the food delicious,
but they are truly
like family to us.
We were there in October for our
10th wedding anniversary,
and my mom had passed away.
We went there for lunch
because I needed a mom hug,
and I truly
got that from Isabella.
Isabella and Jeff
pulled up chairs.
They sat at the table with us,
and we just shared memories
of our wonderful families.
I think they have over
a dozen meatballs now
to pick from -- each one
is better than the next.
And it is always so hard to
figure out what you want to eat.
They have the best pasta,
the best soups, polenta,
which is to die for.
And I would absolutely eat
that on a flip-flop.
And I hope that if you get
a chance to visit
The Meatball Stoppe
in Orlando, Florida,
that you tell them I said hi.
That was a good --
That was just down to Earth.
That's one of my favorites
of all of these.
That's really awesome.
That was just genuine,
right to the point.
And then, to throw
a little flip-flop at the end...
And I would absolutely eat
that on a flip-flop.
Yeah, straight from the heart.
Love it.
All right,
ladies and gentlemen,
Meatball Stoppe in
Orlando, Florida.
Shot this with
Chef Justin Warner.
♪♪
So, I'm here in Orlando,
Florida, right off of the 408.
Right between the Space Coast
and the theme parks.
FIERI:
And along for this ride is
"Next Food Network Star" winner
and my buddy, Justin Warner.
Now Justin,
when you come to Florida,
what kind of food
are you thinking?
God, it could be
about mofongo,
it could be
a Cuban sandwich,
it could be ceviche,
it could be.
Just slow it down, buddy.
This is real easy.
This is
The Meatball Stoppe.
ISABELLA: Chicken Marsala
over penne pasta!
This place is
a meatball lover's heaven.
Jeffy, I need
a meatball smash.
I'm a transplanted
New Yorker.
To me,
this is Little Italy.
FIERI: Not surprising,
since Chef and Owner
Isabella Morgia di Vicari
is a first-generation American
from Italy.
And she and her husband Jeff
are serving up
her grandma's recipes
while carrying on
another family tradition.
My family owned and operated
six Italian restaurants
in Orlando since 1972.
Why a Meatball Stoppe?
Who doesn't love meatballs?
WOMAN: This is the sausage,
pepper, and onion.
FIERI: And even though they
serve up plenty of variety...
The Buffalo
chicken meatball smash.
...they're not bailing
on the basics.
What are we making first?
Nona's traditional
meatballs.
Does Nona know that
you're using all these recipes
and giving them away
on TV right now?
All day long, sweetheart.
Okay, here we go.
Fresh garlic.
We're going to add
the basil, parsley.
I'm going to add
a little bit of water in here.
All right.
Ground chuck.
Ground pork,
garlic, and fresh herbs.
Now I have eggs, milk,
bread crumbs,
Romano cheese, cayenne.
I like a kick.
Kosher salt. Here we go.
Do you love meatballs?
Honestly, I don't.
Italian is not
in my wheelhouse.
I never had a Nona,
you know?
[ Giggles ]
Then I'm going to form
the balls with my scoop.
I'm going to bake them
in the oven
for 12 minutes
at 400 degrees.
And you do leave them flat
on one side?
I do.
I can tell you an advantage
though of the flat bottom
is that you eliminate,
"I lost my poor meatball.
It rolled away."
You know what I mean?
Before we serve the meatballs,
we simmer them
in roasted tomato sauce and
chicken stock for 45 minutes.
Okay, what's
this concoction?
This is
creamy polenta.
Got it.
And the secret is I hit it
with the immersion blender.
Super creamy.
Now I add these
beautiful meatballs,
hit it with a little bit
of Italian parsley,
fresh basil,
and we're good to go.
♪♪
Mm.
It's really good.
It's a cross between
light and dense.
A lot of meatballs,
in my opinion, are too dense.
This, when
you bite into it,
there's a good amount
of moisture.
Delicious.
Really nice.
It's very juicy on the inside.
It falls apart in your mouth.
The tomato sauce is tart, and
it's got a little sweetness.
WOMAN:
I come from an Italian family,
and it's like
being back at home.
FIERI: Where three generations
work together,
since their daughter and
Isabella's mom also help out.
Everything about the restaurant
is revolved around family
and the tradition of having
a great meal together.
ISABELLA: Vegetarian meatball
on the white bean ragu.
I never thought you could do
a vegetarian meatball.
Right.
It's so good.
Once you pair it off with
some pesto sauce, you're done.
Okay, so, now
we're onto vegetarian meatballs.
Yes.
Give us the rundown.
We've got carota,
carrots.
Mushrooms.
Oh, you don't like
the mushroom in Italian?
Funghi.
Absolutely.
All right,
I'm just making sure.
Onions, garlic, celery,
kosher salt and pepper,
and olive oil.
I'm going to roast these 400,
about 30 minutes.
Okay. We're back.
We're roasted. We're cooled.
Now we're going
to the food processor.
I'm excited to see
how this works.
I'm a little skeptical
at times.
Yes, I've had
more bad vegetarian meatballs
than I've had good.
I'm going to puree
half the vegetables with basil
and half with parsley.
Now, beautiful
cooked lentils.
Ahh.
Getting mental
with my lentil.
I see where
you're going with this.
Lentils have a natural
emulsifying property.
Yes, it does.
That's going to be the glue
that makes it go.
So, we've got the mixture
with the lentils.
Going to add the egg, lemon,
oil mixture.
The oregano.
Kosher salt.
Gluten-free bread crumbs.
And of course, Romano.
Now, there they go.
These are going to roast off
in the oven.
400, 12 minutes.
Okay, let's do it.
We're going to plate these
with a white bean ragu.
We're going to top them,
a little pesto,
fresh Italian parsley.
[ Speaks Italian ]
Bon Appetito.
I'll tell you this --
they're super tender.
I mean, I like a meatball
that's barely holding together.
I think the lentils is
the real kicker to this.
There's a creaminess to it.
Silky. Yep.
Silky.
The mushrooms,
that's coming out really strong.
The pesto is that nice,
bright, fresh, light acidity.
Out of the two meatballs,
I like the vegetarian the most.
Yeah, seriously.
Thank you.
Not only would
you have had me fooled,
but then
when you told me,
my mind would have
just been blown.
This is something
to write home about.
Thank you.
Very nice.
Vegetarian with
a white bean ragu for you.
It's tender. Let me just -- Mm.
I'm so hungry.
[ Laughs ]
FIERI:
It's even filling up my buddy,
former baseball player,
A.J. Pierzynski.
If you wouldn't have told me
it was vegetarian,
I never would have guessed.
It's the lentils
in it, right?
I probably have never had
one of those.
You never had a lentil?
Ease in. Be gentle.
Yeah, be gentle
to the lentil.
ISABELLA: Ready to go!
Jeff and Isabella have
extreme passion
not only for their food,
but for the people
that they serve.
Well, thank you
for having us,
and Justin's going to stay here
for the next week
and work for you.
I love it.
Italian 101, baby doll.
There you go.
[ Cell phone chimes ]
It's kolache time.
♪♪
Oh, that makes my mouth water
just looking at 'em.
Sausage and gravy.
I'm so hungry right now.
This is such torture.