Hey, everybody!
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives!
This trip...
Boom.
...we're digging in
to chicken and briskets!
This is not
Grandma's brisket.
There's Wicked Wings
in Fargo...
Winner, winner.
That's your
chicken dinner.
...a gas station fill-up
in Florida...
That goes into
another level of weird.
...and I'm bringing
reinforcements to Philly...
[ Goofy growling ]
FIERI: ...to a joint
making healthy-fresh....
Wait for it!
That's my jam
right there.
...good to the last bite.
Not just one hand
picking in the bowl!
You got both!
Let me get my foot in here.
[ Laughing ]
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in Philadelphia
in Center City,
and I'm with the great chef
Eric Greenspan.
Now, Greenie, what would
you like to do?
GREENSPAN:
Climb the "Rocky" stairs.
We'll go to the museums.
We'll check out
the capitol building --
I'm talking about
getting something to eat.
I'm thinking
cheesesteaks.
How about we don't do that?
I got something better.
This is kind of like
the California east coast.
This is Farmer's Keep.
Hawaiian roast pork
with cucumber tomato salad.
If I'm looking for something
good, fast, and healthy,
I'm definitely coming
to Farmer's Keep.
Farmer salad with
barbecue beef short ribs.
I can find ingredients
I wouldn't normally be able
to get downtown
in a fresh, inventive way.
FIERI: 'Cause
Chef Josh Bullock
is mashing up creativity,
local farm-fresh foods,
and a healthy attitude.
We're an allergen-free
restaurant.
Gluten-free, dairy-free,
egg-free, peanut-free --
Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa.
I have a big allergy --
bad food.
We're still
full of flavor.
You got your protein,
your vegetables.
Everything pairs well
with each other.
My favorite's the brisket.
Dijon brisket with
au gratin potatoes.
The flavor's great.
It's seasoned perfectly.
MAN: And the potatoes are
really good, too,
without using dairy products,
which is amazing.
You said he looked like
Joey Fatone?
A little bit.
This is where I get
the close-up
so they can do the
side-by-side comparison.
And your whole team,
you're "'n sync?"
Of course.
We're gonna make our
rosemary dijon brisket.
Pepper and salt.
Whole grain dijon
and smooth dijon.
Is dijon called
"smooth dijon"?
I think it is now.
Parsley on there.
Good amount
of rosemary, okay.
Onion powder,
chopped garlic,
brown sugar,
red wine vinegar.
Little lemon juice
helps kind of break it down.
And we got some water.
Fresh rosemary.
Wrap this and cook it
how long?
225 about 14 hours.
What's up next?
Au gratin potatoes.
No cheese and no dairy.
Yeah.
You know, we're using
coconut milk and margarine.
I love how
you're so committed
to the allergy part
of these recipes.
It's not your problem,
but you've made it
your mission.
Very well-spoken.
Hoh-hoh.
[ Laughing ]
I was channeling
someone smart.
Let's get him out of the show
from now on, then.
I'm sorry you gotta go.
Your bus is here.
What's going on
with our potatoes here?
We soak 'em in water
for a couple hours,
pull some of that
starch out.
We add our margarine,
salt, pepper, thyme.
And coconut milk.
Gives it a nice,
interesting sweet flavor.
I've never
seen this before.
In the oven.
375, 30 to 40 minutes
covered.
Uncover it.
About 10 more minutes
to brown up.
Let's see the brisket.
Smell that
rosemary, huh?
And the smooth dijon.
And when it's cut like this,
It's like grandma's brisket.
This is not
grandma's brisket.
Eyumm.
Potatoes?
You gotta try
the potatoes first.
There's no way you don't think
that there's dairy in them.
isn't that nuts?
That's the only
thing that's nuts here.
Oh!
Haaaaaaah!
He's on fire, folks.
It is a little bit different
than a scalloped potato,
but "little bit"
in a great way.
A little bit lighter.
There's a little bit
more flavor, honestly,
with that thyme.
But what really
is doing it --
It's so good, it's r--
Should I get a little
pour for you?
[ Goofy growling ]
The acid in the lemon juice
is singing through
because you have all
that unctuous fat.
The rosemary
and dijon on top --
Mmm.
Yeah, dude.
That's real.
It's dynamite.
Rosemary dijon brisket
with au gratin potatoes.
It's so tender.
You get some bites
of rosemary.
of dijon.
The potatoes are
super creamy.
It's delicious.
Emily is my
oldest friend
that's ever been
on "Triple-D."
We went to
preschool together
when we were
four years old.
Yes.
Are you missing
the dairy in that?
No, I didn't even know
until you said it.
Got a black bean beet patty
with street corn quinoa.
FIERI: Is there
anything else like this
in downtown Philly?
No, I mean, it's really
an awesome option for lunch
that's going to give you
a different food all the time.
Favorite thing that
they do on the menu.
I like the chicken.
Whiskey cola chicken,
beets and sweets coming up.
Whiskey, cola, chicken --
and what can go wrong there?
Three of the best flavors
in the world.
Another one of the
favorites is the...
Whiskey cola chicken.
All right,
give me the rundown.
Gonna make our sauce.
Cola, whiskey.
That was full
until you got here.
[ Laughs ]
Sriracha.
Give it a little
bit of heat.
Honey, dijon mustard.
Smooth dijon.
It's on his new album.
Ginger powder, oil.
Healthy pepper.
Salt.
And he's very healthy
with the garlic, which I love.
There is so much flavor
in that bowl.
There you go, Eric.
Sorry.
[ Laughs ]
Gonna go on
to our chicken.
It's chicken thighs,
so it's gonna be tender
and juicy and delicious.
Sauce right on top.
Right in the oven.
Next up?
Our beets
and sweets salad.
So, garlic...
Onion.
So much garlic.
Roasted all the sweet potatoes.
Got our kale into the bowl.
And then, the beets?
Roasted off,
lightly seasoned.
Sweet potato, garlic,
and onion mixture.
Some rosemary,
parsley, cilantro.
[ Laughs ]
Wait for it!
That's my jam
right there.
That's the face
I was looking for.
Not just one hand in
picking in the bowl!
You got both.
Let me get my foot in here.
[ Laughs ]
You know the key
to that is?
Blooming that garlic
and that onion.
It's amazing.
Get the cola chicken out
before Greenie gets
the whole body into the bowl.
All right.
Let's get a little
extra sauce on there.
Hold on.
There we go.
It's imperative.
I didn't see
any pear go in that.
[ Laughs ]
The sauce...
It's insane.
It is very insane.
This with this?
Wow!
The sweet, the garlic,
the chew of the kale.
You're doing such a nice job
on this food.
I mean, you're like
a giver.
You're giving these
monstrous portions.
Delicious food.
You're taking care of
everybody's health.
Scratch-made,
creative, eclectic.
It's real-deal, man.
Thank you.
Whiskey cola chicken
with beets and sweets up.
The chicken has a really great
balance of sweet,
a little spice.
And then, when you get a nice
little crisp piece of kale,
it's a really,
really good bite.
Need a tandoori chicken
with Green Goddess salad.
Farmer's Keep's
a little gem in Philadelphia.
And the service
is outstanding.
Crushing it.
GREENSPAN: Feels like home.
It's great.
Do you take a two-party,
out-of-state check?
Absolutely.
Let's go get
something to eat.
Up next, elevated
every-day eats
in Fargo, North Dakota.
That's right
on top of right
and added some
more right.
From a mac and cheese
flavor bomb...
This comes with a side
of treadmill.
...to a power-wing explosion.
I mean, like,
boom, dude.
♪♪
You know, we have
shot "Triple-D"
in just about every state
in this great country of ours,
and finally, we arrived here
in Fargo, North Dakota.
This is our first time.
Now, being that this is
a college town --
and go, NDSU Bison --
we knew they'd have
some funky joints.
So we found a place
where two buddies
that went to
school together
built a place that
everybody loves to go to.
This is Pounds.
Chicken tendie melt
in the window.
It's our go-to
date night.
Great spot for food,
drinking, dancing.
KASIN: Got your elote over
ready to sauce up.
Favorite thing
on the menu.
MAN: I had never heard
of a poutine,
and they said that
this place has gravy
and fries and cheese curds
all mixed in one.
And I was like,
what the f-- is that?
FIERI: Well, it's the
kind of stuff
Brandon Herz and Alan Kasin
are putting together
after a journey
that started in high school
and ended as owners
of this joint.
We actually didn't like
each other in high school.
You didn't like each other
in high school?
That's a good way
to start the business.
Well, we worked together
in this place
before it was Pounds.
The offer came up
to buy it,
and we pooled together
money really quick.
What's the food?
Well, we wanted to take good
culinary foundation
and apply it to, like,
everyday --
Everyday concepts.
Porker mac in the window.
MAN: The barbecue pork
mac and cheese --
all around
just a very flavorful dish.
Oh, I think it's kind of
a guilty pleasure, actually.
What dish are we
making first?
Pulled pork on macaroni
and cheese with barbecue sauce.
The health craze
has taken over Fargo.
We're gonna make the
spice rub for our pulled pork.
Brown sugar, paprika,
chili powder,
cayenne, garlic powder,
onion powder...
Kitchen sink.
...dried oregano, coriander,
cinnamon, nutmeg...
Fenugreek...
...dry mustard powder...
...sumac.
[ Laughs ]
...chipotle powder.
Nothing else
you want to add to it?
Why weren't you guys
friends in high school?
Well, I didn't get the seat
at the cool-kid table.
Well, who's the one
on the show right now?
The tables
have turned, yeah.
Hoh-hoh!
How are you
enjoying the lobby?
We're gonna take our pork --
we score it a little bit.
We want the salt to be
in every little square inch.
Really work
its way through.
Yeah.
Black pepper,
as well pork.
Pork rub.
Now we're doing
the mustard.
This has vinegar in it,
which is gonna help break down
a lot of the connective tissue
that we have here.
We're gonna grill it
with the mustard.
That's correct.
Okay.
It's like that
char flavor.
Now we're gonna get our
braising liquid together.
Beer, cola,
cider vinegar,
some Worcestershire,
liquid smoke...
A lot of it.
...salt.
Pour this in.
Braise this for about
2 1/2 hours --
just until
you can shred it.
Dig it.
Next up, mac and cheese.
Half and half.
In the double boiler.
It's so he doesn't have
direct flame contact
so he doesn't burn it.
Heavy cream,
cream cheese,
shredded white
American cheese.
You think you want to
get a bigger pot?
Shredded cheddar.
No, it'll mix.
Gotta give it
some time.
Oh, I'll get
the thyme for you.
What do you want?
No.
I need my
assistant back.
Alan!
[ Laughs ]
You're into gouda.
All right.
It's so "gouda."
A little Guy bird feeder.
Just put some gouda
out there.
Now we're gonna make
our little sauce mixture
for the mac sauce.
Buffalo sauce,
salt, pepper,
onion, and garlic.
Stir that up.
Add it to our sauce.
Take our immersion blender
and make sure everything
gets incorporated properly.
What do we have left?
Barbecue sauce, ketchup,
Dr. Pepper,
Worcestershire,
cider vin, brown sugar,
paprika, cayenne,
chili powder,
garlic powder...
Onion powder.
Onion powder,
bay leaves, salt.
Bring it up to a boil
and then simmer
for about a half an hour.
Gosh, there's a lot of
ingredients in this monster.
Take a little bit
of oil, pork.
Let this sear off.
Noodles into our
mac sauce.
Plate our pork, sauce.
This comes with a side
of treadmill.
Pickled jalapeños.
To make sure that things
are safe and sanitary,
my production crew have
awarded me the hippo fork,
and it also recognizes
small portions.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
That's a dynamite dish.
Everything's gotta
be right.
Any one part of this
not being right,
you just put two sides together
and called it a main dish.
That's right on top of right
and added some more right.
The pork is delicious
and not dried out.
The barbecue sauce...
it's got fantastic tang
and not overly sweet.
The mac sauce gives you that
thin, silky, creamy texture,
and the real kicker
to the whole thing
is the diced jalapeños.
Little bit of the acidity,
a little bit of the heat.
Delicious dish.
I mean, like, "Really have to
take it away from me,"
"I want to eat it all"
kind of dish.
KASIN: Got the barbecue porker
mac and cheese.
WOMAN: The pulled pork has
a really nice flavor,
and the mac and cheese
is nice and gooey.
It's just the perfect amount
of sauce on it.
It has a little bit
of a tang.
You have three
all day, right?
KASIN:
Three all day, Herz.
Alan and Brandon have done
such a great job
of incorporating
the vibe of Fargo.
It's a new
up-and-coming city.
We can all come together,
like, during the winter.
to stay warm,
you know?
FIERI: And things are always
heating up around here
with a zing on their wings.
I've got some
Torch Sauce wings here.
The Torch wings have a really
sweet, spicy sauce to them.
So -- "Oh,
there's the Torch."
Don't go anywhere.
We're hanging out at Pounds.
We're in Fargo,
North Dakota.
We'll see you
in a bit.
You better bring the wings
next time, pal.
Vrrrrrooooooom.
Nyoooooooom.
Auuummmmm.
Nyooouu--owhm.
♪♪
Welcome back.
We're at Pounds in Fargo,
North Dakota.
That mac and cheese with the
pulled pork on top of it
was out of bounds.
The food that they
come up with is so special.
HERZ: Plating a TBA
right here.
You can come here
for a full meal.
for an appetizer.
Their wings
are incredible.
Torch wings.
MAN: When it comes
to the torch sauce,
If you like something a little
spicier, it's very good.
They're the best wings
in North Dakota, hands down.
FIERI: Probably 'cause
they're knocking 'em out
with some culinary muscle.
We're confiting
the wings?
Yes, sir.
Straight up, baby.
We need to make the rub
for the wings.
Paprika, cumin,
garlic powder,
pepper, onion powder
cayenne,
salt, meat tenderizer.
On to the wings.
We're just gonna let the meat
rest and chill overnight.
Okay.
Pack it with lard.
Look at that
white, creamy fat.
Wrap it, throw it
in the oven at 375
for an hour and a half.
These wings are
just gonna melt.
Dig it!
Let it cool,
fry it for service.
Yes, sir.
And what kind of sauce
are we putting on this?
We're gonna put some
torch sauce on this.
Some whuh?
Torch sauce.
Complete with
ghost pepper powder.
With ghost po--
Oh, boy.
So, we're gonna start
with pineapple juice,
brown sugar, chopped
garlic, salt, honey.
Juice a lemon in here.
Bring this up to a boil,
reduce this by about 1/3.
All right, I'll just
stand right here.
[ Laughs ] We've got our
cornstarch slurry.
Ghost peppers.
That looks like it hurts.
Does anything come
with these wings?
Well wishes?
Some well wish,
some "fare thee wells,"
and some blue cheese
to cool you off.
[ Laughs ] The wings are
out of the fryer.
Season them with
our torch sauce.
There we go.
Nice and thick.
Give it a toss.
[ Whistles ]
♪♪
[ Chuckling ]
That might be one of
the most tender, juicy,
succulent, delicious wings
we've had on "Triple-D."
It pulls off the bone
like that --
and not dry, mind you.
This is 9.8 in the world
of cooking a wing.
That torch sauce gives you
a little bit of the sweet
and a good amount of heat.
There's not too much of it
that it's overpowering,
and you really taste
the chicken.
Delicious is right here.
That's where
your wings are.
Winner, winner.
That's your chicken dinner.
I got torch wings ready
to drop back here.
MAN: It sounds cliché,
but the meat really does
just fall right off the bone.
There's a good balance
between the sweetness.
The heat kind of comes
in a little later.
It's not gonna
blow your head off.
We got a gouda
queso fries.
I love coming to Pounds.
MAN: I always
come back for it,
so I know they're doing
something right in the kitchen.
Outstanding.
Thank you.
I mean, like,
boom, dude.
Everyday food the best way
it can be cooked,
and these guys right now
are killing it.
Put Pounds on your list.
I wish I had
a fifth stomach.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up,
a unique take on Mexican
in Parkland, Florida.
You're flavor assassins.
Bumpin' bold bites...
That quesadilla
right there is gangster.
...all out of
a gas station.
You know you want to
find this place.
It is worth the visit.
♪♪
FIERI: So, I'm here
in Parkland, Florida,
about 20 minutes
from Fort Lauderdale
to check out a joint
where two chefs
are knocking out
some Mexican food
in a gas station.
Oh, there's a line.
Does this usually
take a long time?
[ Scoffs ]
Depends.
Did you bring a book?
I hear it's
worth the wait.
This is Los Bocados.
I got a carne asada taco.
The food is amazing.
Fire one Bocado bowl.
It's not what you would expect
in a gas station.
FIERI: 'Cause the dudes
filling up folks here --
Robby Bushman
and Anthony Hoff --
are real-deal chef buddies
who stumbled on
this surprising spot.
When I found this location
with the hood,
I called Anthony.
I said, "I think we should
open a restaurant.
Mexican?
Mexican-ish.
I want a T-shirt
that says,
"Los Bocados --
Mexican-ish."
What can I get you today?
Can I get tostadas?
I pretty much ate everything
because I'm here too much.
Pork quesadilla
coming off right now.
The pork quesadilla
is full of flavor.
It's got a lot of
the nice, spicy citrus.
Pork is delicious.
We're gonna start off
with Robby doing the cooking.
If Robby, at any time,
cannot handle things...
bringing Anthony in.
We're making
the citrus pork.
Salt and pepper.
Marinate it with
this concoction.
Onions.
Oregano.
Cumin.
Garlic.
Thyme.
Two big fat
Scotch bonnets.
Lime juice, fresh Florida
orange juice,
blended oil.
Is that a little vinegar
sitting back there?
It is.
Blend this up.
Right into the pork.
Into the pressure cooker.
Little bit of water
and she's good to go.
How long?
20 minutes.
While that's working,
what are we working on?
Guajillo glaze.
Guajillo.
Mexican-ish.
This guy kills me.
[ Southern accent ]
Come on, honey.
We're going to go down
to Los Bocados,
get some of that
Mexican-ish food.
Guajillo peppers,
brown sugar,
rice wine vinegar.
That goes into
another level of weird.
Oh, this one's Anthony's.
Bring this to a boil.
We're gonna rehydrate
the peppers.
Into the blender.
Through a chinois.
I like the way
you party.
We're gonna make
the chipotle sauce
that goes on the quesadilla
The chipelote.
Yep, boiled
and skinned tomatoes.
Yep, an onion
boiled whole.
Lime juice,
salt, cilantro,
water, garlic,
chipotle, and adobo.
And that's all
she wrote.
That's delicious.
Thank you.
Time to go!
Monterey Jack cheese,
the pork that
we cooked off.
I wanna be
buried in that.
Our house-made
pickled red onions.
Chipotle salsa
that we made.
Onto our flat top.
Guajillo glaze, crema.
Flip it, pat it down.
This is it.
It's like a taco
ran into a burrito.
♪♪
I got good news
about this.
The bad news is, Chef,
you are putting a lot
of Mexican restaurants
in a bad situation.
That quesadilla
right there is gangster.
The pork's dynamite.
The cheese is super creamy,
super melty.
The guajillo glaze should be
on the shelf for sale
in your Mexican-ish restaurant
inside of a gas-station-ish,
mini-mart-ish place-ish.
Heard-ish.
Thank-ish.
The discipline to what you're
doing in food -- fantastic.
BUSHMAN: Pork quesadilla
going down.
The pork is incredible.
It has, like,
a citrus kick to it.
It's good.
I have some special guests
here on "Triple-D" today.
A good buddy of mine,
Armando --
as everybody knows him
as Pitbull --
has put together
a school called SLAM.
I think there's 11 campuses
across the country right now.
What's the whole
school about?
Incorporating sports into
kids' learning lives.
What do you think
of the taco?
The taste was extravagant.
For a small gas station
restaurant,
it made a big impact
Boom!
Anthony and Robby
are really proud
of the food they make.
Who's in charge,
by the way?
We flip a coin
to make decisions.
What was the last one
we flipped a coin about?
About who was gonna cook.
Who was gonna cook.
Yeah.
Barbecue brisket tostada.
The tostada is amazing.
MAN: I think Robby's been
making brisket
since he was like
seven years old,
so it's just great.
Robby just cooked
your dish.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now Chef Anthony is gonna
cook Robby's dish.
The next recipe
we're gonna do
is the barbecue
brisket tostada.
We'll start with salt,
white sugar,
black pepper,
brown sugar paprika,
chipotle chili powder,
cayenne pepper, garlic powder.
What is that?
The black magic.
They're burnt onions
for the final flavor.
These guys get weirder
as the time goes on.
And it goes
right in the rub.
You tasted it by itself.
Taste the rub, though,
with the black magic in it.
I dig it.
So, we're gonna
dry-rub this.
Roast it at 500°.
Now we're gonna go
into the braising.
Onions Scotch bonnet,
carrots -- oranges, as well.
You're in Florida.
You should make it happen.
Big fat brisket.
All the drippings
right in.
Beautiful.
Now we're just gonna add
the beer and the water.
12 hours, and what temp?
250.
All right, we are gonna make
the rodicue sauce.
A little bit
of olive oil, onions,
garlic, Scotch bonnets.
These guys love the
Scotch bonnets around here.
Black magic -- also known as
burnt onions.
Salt, and then a little bit
of the brisket rub.
Tomatoes.
After the brisket
is braised,
we save the liquid.
We're gonna add
the guajillo glaze.
Lot going on
for a gas station joint.
What's our last piece?
The pickled
jalapeño relish.
You get a point up
on Robby.
It is jalapeño.
White vinegar,
the jalapeño seeds.
Onions...
Jalapeños.
...carrots, and then
salt and sugar.
After that,
we finish with ice.
Make it happen, Cap'n.
So, here's the
brisket shredded,
and we put the
rodicue sauce inside.
Avocado crema,
Cotija cheese,
pickled jalapeño relish.
The filling definitely
outweighs the "tort-illia."
♪♪
Chef, you got a very interesting
way of doing stuff.
You've got a lot of sweet
from that barbecue beef,
and it is really
nice barbecue beef.
The crema's delicious.
You didn't have the
jalapeño relish on there...
...you'd really be
missing it.
It's Mexican-ish
because you don't follow
the Mexican rules.
You're flavor assassins.
Thank you.
Barbecue brisket tostada,
avocado crema.
The meat on there
is so tender.
WOMAN: The avocado crema,
little bit of pickled onions
and carrots --
it all melds
very Well together.
Chicken Bocado bowl,
side of elote.
It's consistent.
It's always high quality.
I've never come here
and not enjoying my food.
FIERI:
It's delicious,
it's Mexican-ish,
and it's in a gas station.
You know you want to
find this place.
It is worth the visit.
Adios.
That's "goodbye"
in Spanish.
Goodbye. [ Laughs ]
So, that wraps this edition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives."
If you want to get
some of the recipes
from today's show,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking
for you next week
on "Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives."
[ Clicks tongue ]
We want people
to enjoy themselves
and not have to feel like
they need to wear something.
Wait, wait, wait, it's a
clothing-optional place?
KASIN: Exactly.
HERZ: That's right.
You don't see that!
I would not expect North Dakota
to be clothing-optional!