Hey, I'm Guy Fieri,
and you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun!
I'm on my way to Flavortown.
This is
Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives.
This trip...
We're having a ball, folks.
Come on down.
...we've got Vikings,
wings, and Persian things.
That's a lot of flavor.
That means
funky chicken in OKC...
Definitely a go-to.
...real-deal Iranian
in Florida...
"Iranian comfort-food
101," dude.
...and in Portland, Oregon...
Wow, that's good.
...big Scandinavian flavors...
How about existed this long
without having this?
...coming out of
a little trailer.
This place is magical.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Triple-D"!
♪♪
One of my favorite things about
coming to Portland, Oregon,
is to come and see
all these food carts they got.
So we're here
at The Bite on Belmont,
and you can find yourself
a Mexican cart --
let's see,
a Brazilian cart.
You got a
mac and cheese cart.
Back here, we got
a sushi cart,
I think we got
a bar cart,
and one that
I've never heard before.
How about Scandinavian?
This is Viking Soul Food.
♪♪
Crackin' snacks
coming out.
It's hard to find
good Scandinavian food.
Something with a little bit
of a twist is nice, too.
Meatball and a
troll hunter stew.
Something you've never
had before.
SERVER: Got pickled
eggs for ya.
WOMAN:
There's so many flavors.
I just love them all.
FIERI: And those tastes are
straight out of Norway,
where Megan Walhood's ancestors
and someone from my
childhood came from.
We had a Norwegian exchange
student when I was a kid.
So when I was an
exchange student in France,
I went and spent
Christmas up there
for a month
with their family.
And how was that?
Oh, my gosh.
Wonderful country.
What do people in this area
know about Scandinavian food?
There's a decent-sized
Scandinavian community here,
so it's not
completely foreign --
No pun intended.
It's been a little bit
of a hurdle
introducing people
to what lefse is.
Firing one lefse!
It's kind of like
a bread where they wrap it.
You can put any kind
of toppings on it.
Can I get
the meatball wrap?
The meatball wrap is
Norwegian meatballs
mixed with a sauce
that's made out of gjetost,
which is a
Norwegian cheese.
FIERI: What's on
the game plan?
Norwegian meatball
lefse wrap.
lefse is the
Scandinavian crepe?
Sort of like that,
but imagine with potatoes.
I want to see it.
Okay.
Dehydrated Idaho russets.
Rehydrate with water.
Extra virgin olive oil...
Okay.
...kosher salt.
So, one time, I was
having some lefse,
and I couldn't eat it all,
so I "lef-some"
on the plate.
[ Sour notes play ]
[ Laughter ]
We need our mashed potatoes
and our flour.
Now we're gonna
ball it up.
We're having a ball, folks.
Come on down.
We're having a ball.
Bring the kids.
We're gonna
roll them out.
So, for every
lefse you make,
you have to go through
this whole process?
Correct.
Can you make them
ahead of time?
Yep.
You have some lefses over.
What happens
if you flip it?
Is it the "right-sa"?
[ Laughs ]
No?
If you say so.
We make it
with the lefse...
BOTH: And we make it
with the right-sa.
You can go ahead and
put that on a T-shirt.
So if you tried to pick this up,
it would just break off?
I would tear.
And you have your
Harry Potter sword,
and you're gonna be able
to pick that up?
This place is magical.
This is the lefse wand.
And then you come over to
the griddle and you roll it out.
It's going to cook usually
about 35 seconds each side.
But once it gets cooked...
It will hold together enough
that you can use it as a wrap.
[ Tremulous exclamation ]
There you go.
♪♪
Mm, delicious.
Okay.
Think about the nicest,
lightest, fluffiest
flour tortilla you've had.
Okay, our next game plan is,
we're gonna make our
gjetost gravy.
Gjetost.
This is a roux.
So I kind of
brown the butter
and I brown the flour
a little bit.
Milk, white wine...
Great.
...Madeira wine,
kosher salt,
our gjetost cheese --
and it has a texture
that is almost fudge-like.
Oh, cheese-fudge.
Nutmeg.
And this is part
of the meatball wrap
that goes with
the "lafos."
"Lafos."
I like that version.
What is it?
lefse.
Lafos, lowtoes,
lactose, agh--
I don't know
what I am.
Next, meatballs.
Start with our
fried bread crumbs,
milk and cream, eggs.
The toasted flour
that we end up with
from making lefse,
we save it and use it.
Well done.
Caramelized onions, salt,
black pepper, allspice,
ground beef,
and ground pork.
Chill this
for three hours.
And then, we're
gonna bake them off?
For eight minutes.
About 475.
We've toasted our lefse.
Green cabbage.
And then,
this is the surkal,
which is a sweet
and sour purple cabbage
with caraway seed.
"Caraway" with it.
This is the gjetost gravy
that you saw.
Yes.
Meatballs.
Roll it up.
Kind of like a burrito.
Cut it in half.
Do I want the lefse
or the right-sa side?
[ Laughing ]
How have I
existed this long...
[ Laughs ]
...without having this?
Delicious,
tender, nice meatball.
Gjetost sauce --
lights out.
The cabbage
is the perfect break.
You need the crunch,
and then you need the acid.
Exactly.
Not too heavy,
not too light.
Super flavorful.
Outside of the spectrum
of what people normally
are going to eat.
Wow, that's good.
Thank you.
♪♪
Here's your meatball wrap.
I love the cheese sauce.
It's, like, very malty.
I want, like, pot of fondue
of the cheese sauce.
WOMAN:
The meatballs are really juicy,
and then it has this, like,
bright punch of the cabbage.
So, yeah, hit all those notes,
and it's really fun
that they operate
out of an Airstream.
What year is this baby?
1958.
This is awesome.
WOMAN:
A lot of magic happens
in this tiny box.
It's a box of wonders.
[ Laughs ]
All right, so,
what's next?
Smoked salmon lefse wrap.
Well, the smoked salmon's
always excellent.
That's my favorite item.
I'll see you in a minute.
Where did you learn
to do this?
My grandmother.
[ Laughs]
Did she have
the Harry Potter sword?
She did.
Did she use the lefse
or the rights-- [Laughs]
♪♪
Welcome back.
"Triple-D" hanging out
in a funny little
food cart pod
here in Portland, Oregon.
They got a Mexican cart.
They got a bar cart.
They got a Thai cart,
a mac and cheese cart,
a coffee cart.
But at the end,
you will find Viking Soul,
a Scandinavian food cart.
It's got this crazy stuff
called lefse.
I want you to think about a
crepe meets a flour tortilla,
but doesn't have any egg,
and it likes potatoes.
So, my family background
is Norwegian.
We would have lefse
with butter on the side.
And I love Viking Soul Food
because they really
turned it into,
"Well, you could put anything
inside the lefse."
Got a smoked salmon wrap.
Smoked salmon wrap
is one of my favorite dishes.
It's got dill
and cream and salmon,
and it's got that good
pickled cabbage in it.
It's just
a nice combination.
Now we're gonna get into
our smoked salmon,
so we're gonna make
a salmon cure.
Just what I thought
we would do
in this tiny little
1958 Airstream.
Kosher salt, brown sugar,
cardamom, caraway, coriander.
Got it.
Where's the salmon from?
It's Norwegian
fjord salmon.
Gerdy-verda-hurda.
How did I know
you were gonna do that?
How long is this dry rub
gonna go on?
I cure it for five days.
Then into the smoker,
and what kind of wood
are we smoking with?
Juniper...
Where do you get juniper?
...whenever I can get it.
You burning a
Viking warship?
[ Laughs ]
You know what I think is great
about having her on the show?
She laughs at every
stupid joke I say.
What else is going
on with this fantastic
wrap that we're making?
We have some
pickled shallots,
champagne vinegar,
water, sugar,
kosher salt,
juniper berries...
Ooh, very nice
Vanna to that.
...bay leaf, and bring
that to a boil.
Gonna thinly slice shallots
on the mandolin.
Okay.
We're gonna pour
the brine over.
We actually let these sit
for a month.
Next?
We're gonna build it.
Let's see it!
Greens, cabbage,
extra virgin olive oil.
Okay.
Freshly squeezed
lemon juice, no seeds.
I "seed" what
you're saying.
[ Laughing ]
This is pun and fun.
I mean, you're nailing it.
Pickled shallots,
dill, creme...
Cured home-house-smoked
salmon.
And the salmon's
from where, again?
[ Norwegian accent ]
Fjord.
[ Laughter ]
See?
Starting to rub off now!
♪♪
Look at you with
your little Food Network,
cut-and-slice,
open-profile-look thing.
You are just stealing
the show, sister.
♪♪
Salmon's delicious.
Not over-smoked.
Not over-brined.
♪♪
Love the cabbage.
Freshness of the lemon
really needed and appreciated.
It really is impressive.
Thank you.
Salmon wrap for you.
It's unique and delicious.
You can really taste
the juniper they smoke with.
Lingonberries
going over the top.
I love the food here.
WOMAN: It's gonna
warm your soul. [ Laughs ]
Makes you feel good.
FIERI: What you're
doing in here --
the tribute
to Scandinavian food
but with your own
funk and flair --
you really delivered.
Thank you.
Good job.
[ Laughs]
Thank you.
FIERI: Up next,
in Oklahoma City,
I enjoy getting wild
with wings...
Watch out for
this guy, huh?
...with righteous recipes
that are all over the map.
So, you're gonna take the
center of all great wingness
and you're gonna
mess with it.
Yep, we are not scared.
♪♪
Back in the day, when I was
going to college at UNLV,
chicken wings were either good
or they were bad.
I mean, no one was really
blowing up the wing scene.
But nowadays, man,
they're either good,
they're bad,
or they're gourmet.
So I'm here in OKC,
where a husband and wife team --
well, they're doing wings
old-school,
they're doing 'em new-school,
and they're puttin'
a little Asian twist.
This is Chick N Beer.
♪♪
Six traditional buffalo!
The first time I came into
Chick N Beer, I was hooked.
The flavors are gigantic.
Kimchi fry.
I'm waiting on
the roasted shishito.
The Asian influence here is
what makes it kind of special.
Which comes from owners
Cheyenne and Truong Le,
whose eastern-western menu
reflects their own
bicultural backgrounds.
I'm born and raised here,
but my parents escaped the war
from Vietnam
in the late '70s.
Okay.
So we have, like,
an Asian twist
to every single one
of our flavors.
So it might say buffalo...
Yep.
...but it's gonna
have a little --
It's a buffalo sriracha.
Ah-hah.
Buffalo sriracha.
These are my go-to.
Buffalo's kind of the classic,
but with the sriracha,
it gives you the added heat.
It's one of the better
examples of buffalo sauce.
I see that we're gonna
get into a brine...
Yep.
...which is something
I believe in.
We're gonna add
the salt to the water,
mix it up a little bit,
and then we'll let it sit
for about a day.
Next, we'll get into
making some sauces.
Buffalo sriracha.
So, you're gonna take the
center of all great wingness
and you're gonna
mess with it.
Yep, we are not scared.
All right, let's see it.
Louisiana hot sauce,
melted butter.
So far, we're
starting off right.
White vinegar,
sriracha sauce.
This is sriracha powder.
Sriracha powder.
Yes.
And then, xanthan gum.
Keep it all stabilized.
Exactly.
I always have
a hard time pronouncing.
I think it's
"let-thinson"?
"Lectithin."
Let's talk about how
we're frying the wing.
We coat the wings first.
I'm out.
[ Laughs ] Why?
You do not need
to coat the wing.
We'll talk about that
after you eat it.
Okay, we'll talk it
as I'm walking.
[ Laughs ]
All right, so,
the sauce is done.
We'll make our fry batter.
Go with your dredging and your
coating-the-wingy thingy.
Water, potato starch.
Throw the wings in.
All right, so it's not
as battery as I thought.
I'm gonna back off
a little bit, but --
This will just give it
a light crisp.
We do a double fry here
at 345°
for about three to four minutes
the first fry.
Bring out, hold them.
And then, we put them
back into our dredge,
and then we fry them again,
two to three minutes.
Now, I'm an extra-crispy-wing
kind of guy.
From here, we toss them over.
Quick sauce.
Voilà.
Blue cheese crumble on top.
Look how convenient
that is.
It comes with its own
little wing holder
so you don't get
your fingers dirty.
♪♪
I dig it.
That's legit-size wing.
That's a small turkey.
[ Turkey gobbles ]
The salt brine
is definitely great.
You can taste the flavor
all the way through the chicken.
This coating is so light...
it grabs the sauce.
And the sauce -- I mean,
definitely a go-to.
Delicious.
The tongs have got to
come with it, by the way.
[ Laughs ]
Six traditional
buffalo sriracha.
MAN: You get this
wonderful crunch
followed by this beautiful,
juicy meat.
It's got that sriracha flair in
there that's not too hot,
but it's got
a little bit of spice.
What makes the wings
so good here?
It's not common that you can
have wings where they're crispy
and you also get
all the sauce on it.
There's ten, fifteen sauces.
Every one of them's unique,
and every one's delicious.
Bourbon teriyaki.
Let's go.
Definitely a wing-lover
who just wants something
a little bit
on the lighter side.
The bourbon teriyaki is perfect.
Sweet, savory,
really solid wing.
All right, what are we
gonna make next?
Bourbon teriyaki.
Could be my middle name.
Guy "Bourbon Teriyaki" Fieri
coming by.
We're gonna start off
with a little bit of oil,
minced ginger,
and the minced garlic.
Shaoxing wine,
soy sauce, brown sugar,
little bit of bourbon.
Rice wine vinegar.
Gonna let it go for about
fifteen minutes,
and then we'll
add in the slurry
to kind of
thicken up the sauce.
We'll put it in a blender
to make sure
that everything's --
To get everything done.
All right,
get some wings fried.
I'm ready for this.
Little bourbon teriyaki.
Very thin sauce.
It is, and so, that'll hold
the texture even better.
♪♪
Sauce is dynamite.
Thank you.
I actually like that you didn't
add too much cornstarch to it
to where it
tightens it up so much
to where
it's really super sticky
and becomes too sweet.
Yeah.
Great soy.
Love the little sting
of the bourbon.
Great crunch.
Excellent.
The bourbon teriyaki has a great
balance of ginger, teriyaki,
and the bourbon kind of gives it
something else different.
They're not too smothered
with the sauce,
and they're just crispy enough
and juicy enough.
Favorite wing
in the menu?
The Szechuan
Parmesan-garlic.
Where do you get that mix?
Saving the best for last.
Szechuan Parmesan-garlic.
We're gonna
infuse our oil.
We're gonna sauté off
the garlic,
add in the vegetable oil.
The Thai chilies.
Chilies.
And this will go for
about 15 minutes or so.
And the dry rub is?
We toast off the
Szechwan peppercorn.
Okay.
Once we blend it,
we'll add it
to the parmesan cheese.
Red chili flakes.
Exactly.
Garlic powder.
So the wings come out.
This is the garlic
and Thai chili oil.
Yep, and this will really help
hold on to the dry rub.
And then dusted
in this mixture.
That's just the
doneness I like.
♪♪
Mmm.
Delicious, crunchy.
It's tender, it's moist.
Not too much breading.
The garlic Thai oil
fits perfectly.
You know what makes that?
That Szechuan peppercorn.
It's got a little bite.
It's got a little tingle.
Mmm, you can't put
enough Szechuan for me.
[ Chuckles ]
Really nice balance.
For a dry wing, dude,
it was great.
Well done.
Thank you, thank you.
Garlic-parmesan up.
Super tasty, and the
Szechuan garlic is awesome.
You get the unique
Asian flair.
The parmesan's
really good.
A great balance
of all the three flavors.
LE: Got a kimchi fries
and a beef platter
for table number four!
You never get something
that is the same
as what you'd find
anywhere else.
It's amazing.
Definitely a home run.
FIERI: I think there should be
a chicken wing challenge.
If you can eat one order
of all the chicken wings,
you should get something.
They're so diverse.
Watch out for
this guy, huh?
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
FIERI: Coming up,
in Sunrise, Florida...
You're living on
the edge, huh, buddy?
...authentic
Iranian specialties...
Buttery, melt-in-your-mouth
ridiculous.
...broadening my
culinary horizons.
I've never seen this in my life,
and it's delicious.
♪♪
So, I'm here
in Sunrise, Florida,
about 15 minutes
west of Fort Lauderdale,
and I gotta tell you,
I love coming down
to this part of Florida.
I mean, you get
every nationality,
every type of cuisine.
We got Dominican.
We got Haitian.
We got Cuban.
Why not throw in a little
Iranian for good measure?
This is Kababi Café.
♪♪
Five minutes on the kebab.
If mom is not around,
this is the first place I come.
It's exactly like they're
making in my country.
Chicken on the bone.
How would you explain
this type of food to folks?
WOMAN:
An explosion of flavor.
Explosion.
FIERI: Those big flavors
are something
that chef and owner
Hamid Shirdel brought along
when he came here from Iran.
Did you cook in Iran?
No, I actually took
the recipes from the families
and put them together,
and I start cooking here.
Everything he cooks
comes out very nice.
It's very good.
Excellent rice.
Bagali polo with
dill rice ready to go.
Bagali polo is rice
with dill and fava beans,
and it comes with
a lamb shank.
It's so delicious.
What are we gonna make?
Lamb shank...
Okay.
...with dill rice.
That's a big "dill."
Huh?
[ Cricket chirping ]
"Big dill."
[ Laughing ]
Basmati rice.
We got the dill.
Then we peel fava beans.
Double peeled.
We gotta do our mix.
Water, oil, egg,
yogurt, and saffron water.
This goes on the bottom?
Yes.
Start pouring
the rice in there.
All piling it up.
Like a mountain.
Mount Basmati.
We cover it.
Nine minutes on high
and nine minutes on low.
Not ten.
You know why nine?
Tell me.
'Cause in case
you're back there...
Right.
...by the time you get here,
it gets ten.
[ Breathy ]
Ahh.
So, we're gonna make
the lamb shanks.
Okay.
We're gonna let it boil.
Tomato sauce...
Okay.
Salt, turmeric,
black pepper.
Paprika.           Paprika.
In stereo.
Garlic powder and cinnamon.
Green onion,
white onion, garlic,
Rudolph's nose.
Radishes,
parsley, and cilantro.
How long is this
gonna simmer?
About three, four hours.
Our lamb shank is ready.
This is our mountain rice.
Saffron rice.
Put a little
juice in here.
Got it.
Then you put your meat --
you put it on there
and you eat it.
♪♪
The dill complements
the lamb really nice.
Mm-hmm.
I mean, lamb that's
basically stewed or boiled
doesn't have a ton
of its own flavor,
but you end up getting a bunch
of the flavor of the vegetables
that it was cooked in
and the nice tomato broth.
♪♪
Really tender lamb,
very unique rice.
Thank you.
Delicious.
Here's your bagali polo
and dill rice.
Lamb is very soft and tender
and falls off the bone.
Basmati rice is
very good, actually.
Mediterranean mix.
The time that goes
into making Persian food --
There's no thyme
in that, actually.
What do you mean?
T-H-Y-M-E.
Oh, that's how it's --
Good one.
You got me there.
But I agree --
a lot of work...
Yeah.
...a lot of big flavor.
Most of the things
are rice-based
and stew-based.
Pomegranate stew
with white rice.
Chicken pomegranate,
it's savory, it's sweet.
The chicken melts
in your mouth.
Everything about it
is wonderful.
Now we're gonna
make fesenjan.
Fesenjan?
Pomegranate stew.
♪♪
[ Whispering ] There's no
pomegranates here.
But we have the sauce,
the molasses.
Ohhh.
We have molasses.
Grind the walnuts.
Water.
[ Normal voice ]
Next step?
Oil into the pot.
We're gonna put
the onion in there.
Puréed onion.
We're gonna mix
our spices.
Okay.
Sugar, salt,
black pepper,
turmeric,
cinnamon, water.
Lots of cinnamon
in Persian food.
Yes, and it's healthy.
Cinnamon and turmeric.
I take them
every morning.
Onions are done.
So, we're ready to get
the pomegranate molasses,
Pour the whole thing in.
You're living on
the edge, huh, buddy?
Tomato paste.
Our spice mix
that we made.
Last but not least,
walnut water.
Mmm.
How long is this
gonna cook, Chef?
Three hours.
So, now we're gonna
marinate our chicken.
Okay.
Green pepper, yellow onion,
salt, pepper.
Let me guess -- paprika?
You got it.
And turmeric.
Saffron water.
We're gonna put
our chicken in it.
How long is this
gonna marinate, Chef?
24 hours.
And how do we steam it
on the skewer?
I'm gonna show you that.
Fantastic, just
keep on learning.
Right in the middle.
Where are we gonna
steam it at?
So, now we've
have this pot.
Pot of boiling water.
There you go.
Put this on top of it.
Let it cook.
Very weird.
Why is weird?
'Cause I've never seen it.
It's very weird.
Hi, I'm Weird.
Have we met?
Chicken is ready.
Take it out
of the skewer.
Nothing like the old
pomegranate-walnut gravy.
Put it on the plate.
Don't start telling me.
I got it now.
Maybe I do.
Maybe I don't.
♪♪
I've never seen this in my life,
and it's delicious.
The chicken is buttery,
melt-in-your-mouth ridiculous.
That's a lot of flavor.
Very simple, very rich.
♪♪
"Iranian comfort-food
101," dude.
Chicken pomegranate stew.
The tastes are like
sweet and sour,
and the chicken is tender.
It really,
truly is amazing.
Gravy made out
of ground-up walnuts.
Who would have thought?
Who would have thunk?
Crispy rice with
green herb stew.
The food here tastes so much
like my mom's cooking --
even better.
[ Laughs ]
It's kind of a mini-trip
back to Iran.
One thing about Iranians,
we don't like anybody
to leave hungry.
Hungary and Iran aren't
close together, are they?
Huh?
[ Laughing ]
I mean, I wouldn't want anybody
to leave Hungary either.
Wonderful country.
Delicious.
Great.
Thank you for having me.
Thank you.
♪♪
So, that's it for this trip,
but don't worry --
there's plenty more
"Triple-D" joints
all over the country!
I'll be looking
for you next week
on Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives.
Jeff bellydances.
Jeff, let's see something.
[ Laughter ]
Jeff, not while
people are eating.
I've told him
enough times.
MAN: That's it.
There you go!
Show's over!