You know, people are asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint
you checked out
in that one city when
you were doing 'Triple-D,'
how'd they do it?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all...
This is ridiculous,
dude.
...but it turns out,
it was only the beginning
because "Triple-D" joints
have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip,
we've got diners...
[ Speaking indistinctly
with mouth full ]
Thank you, thank you.
...drive-ins...
Barbecue and order of fries.
...and delis.
It is like being
in my grandmother's kitchen.
FIERI: Like the sandwich shop
in Florida still serving
hoagies by the hundreds.
Your 26,251
is a big hit.
Nice job.
Ah!
In Norfolk, Virginia...
You would like this.
...a cool spot creating cones
for over a century.
That's damn good.
Damn good he said.
And a deli in Denver
staying true to their roots.
It's a delish knish.
And here's our
jalapeño cheddar knish.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is "Triple-D Nation."
♪♪
So back in 2009 --
When was 2009?
That was forever ago --
I was here
in Hollywood, Florida.
Matter of fact, it was Jeff,
our sound guy's first shoot
that we ever did
on "Triple-D."
And we come to this funky place.
Oh, the sign has changed,
but I hear the food is
Still rocking it just the same.
This is
Sonny's Famous Steak Hogies.
MAN: There's no surprise that
"Triple-D" would come here
because this is the best
of the best.
MAN #2: I eat here so often,
I was actually here
when "Diners, Drive-Ins
& Dives" filmed
the first episode.
Four Generations,
all eaten at Sonny's.
-Yeah.
-That's great.
It's always going to be fresh,
always delicious.
I was probably
his first customer
the day he opened.
FIERI: That was back in '58,
long before Sonny Nigro's
John and his wife, Marilyn,
took over
the family biz.
♪♪
Nice to see you.
What's up, buddy?
Hi.
That was
a million years ago.
God, we only got
better looking, dude.
I agree with you.
I'm telling you.
Tell me a story here
about why "hogie"
out on the sign
is "H-O-G-I-E-S."
Thought there was an "A"
in it.
My dad did it on purpose.
He wanted people to say,
"Where's the 'A'?"
And that was
the very beginning.
That was the first
few years of doing
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives,"
and he set the bar
pretty high.
How many rolls
do you make a day?
We make between
30 and 50 dozen a day.
So you started to go
30 and 50,
I'm like "Wow, sure seemed
busier than that today.
Not 30 or 50."
30 or 50 dozen,
oh, okay.
We start with the water.
This is fresh yeast
heated up in some water.
This is the big-shot way
right here.
Then I have salt,
I have dia-malt.
Who?
Dia-malt is the food
for the yeast.
Flour, 11 and 1/2
pounds to start with.
We're gonna mix it
for a little while,
and then we'll add
some butter
and shortening.
Another 12 pounds of flour.
Got it. Not your first rodeo,
is it there, Johnny?
No. The dough starts
being carried by the hook,
it's ready to go.
FIERI: Now we take it out
and where does it go?
It goes into a dough box.
For how long?
About an hour.
Then we punch it down,
and then it starts
to come up again.
You should feel
how warm it is.
Mm!
What size are we going for?
JOHN: 4 1/2 ounces.
Oh, you're good.
That is dead on.
I'd say that's perfect.
Thank you. I'm out.
That was perfect.
We want to fold it little up,
turn it over, roll it out.
That's good.
We're still doing them
by hand.
Remember, one by one?
That's why he's got
those Popeye forearms.
Look at those things.
Look at that, huh?
Arm wrestling champ.
These must be the ones
I rolled.
Yeah.
Mmm.
Great crust but light.
That's a good one.
It's nice to come back
and visit.
I can't believe the years
have burned off so fast.
I know.
What's been happening? We still
got our 95s and our 50s.
This is the 95.
We haven't gone
to normal methods?
No. [ Laughs ]
Number 90 with mozzarella.
There's four kinds
of steak hoagies.
Yes.
A 50, a 95, a 90, and a 9?
Right.
Mm-hmm.
5 is like an "S" for sauce.
Zero, "O" for onions.
The 9,
you turn it around,
it's a "P," plain.
A 50 is "S-O,"
sauce and onions
A 95 is plain with sauce.
And a never 9
is totally plain.
So you have the 50.
The 90.
[ Buzzer ]
What number is that?
That's a 90.
I still don't know
how to do it, okay?
FIERI: And what we have here
is boneless rib eye?
Just a little bit frozen,
and you're going to just
pop it in the sleeve.
JOHN: We're looking for like
a 16th of an inch.
You cut that so thin
there's only one side to it.
[ Laughs ]
Goes on the line.
Yellow onions.
Going to put a little bit
of butter on the side.
Always better with butter.
And then cover it.
We're just waiting for it
to get to a point
to where we can break it up,
put a little salt on top,
a little butter again.
Mix it all together,
and now I'm ready
to put my provolone cheese.
And that's all she wrote.
It's ready to go.
Mmm.
[ Speaking indistinctly
with mouth full ]
Thank you. Thank you.
You know what the kicker
on that is?
The butter.
I think I've had everything
on the menu,
but Katie's
making something special.
And what do you call this?
A 90 with American
and provolone.
Here's your 90
with American and provolone.
FIERI: So you get the creaminess
of the American
and the saltiness
of the provolone.
KATIE: And the density
Katie, how long
have you worked here?
I've been here seven years.
Seven years. Alright.
So five days a week
times let's say 15 dozen.
I want to figure out
how many you've made.
You've made
over 26,250 hoagies.
This is 26,251.
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
Alright, let him chew.
So what'd you call this?
A 95 with --
It's a 90 with American
and provolone.
Never can get it right.
Well done, sister.
MAN: I'm having a 90
with provolone and American.
It's excellent.
It's the steak --
they cook it with the butter,
the onions.
He shaves it so thin
that it almost melts
in your mouth.
Can't go wrong
with the onions,
the American cheese,
and the provolone.
It's the best.
Your 26,251 is a big hit.
Nice job.
Ah!
[ Applause ]
FIERI: And the hits
just keep on coming.
It's so good, though.
But it's not all
about the numbers.
WOMAN: Chicken Parm.
No, I'm good.
I can go on like this.
Thank you.
Up next.
I'm in Hollywood,
not California,
but Florida,
where I am getting ready
to enjoy a Philly cheesesteak
and not seafood
at a place
called Sonny's
that's owned
by a guy named John.
That was my first visit
back in 2009.
But I'll tell you,
it wasn't my last.
What's up, buddy?
I haven't found
very many places like Sonny's.
Weighing out the meatballs
to making little footballs.
JOHN: We make them
into little footballs.
FIERI:
So they fit cylinder-ly --
cylindritch-ical-ily-ily.
Cylindrically?
Cylindric--
PRODUCER: Cylindrical.
So they fit
cylindrically.
Wow, that doesn't sound right,
does it?
So they fit on the roll.
[ Both laugh ]
-Scooping them out.
-Set, scoop,
off the palm of the hand,
down.
Like this?
Yes.
We're a good team, Johnny.
Coming to play at your house
more often.
Go in the oven,
400 degrees.
An hour.
At 400?!
Wow.
It's a long time.
They come off with a little bit
of color on top of it
and it's still very tender.
That's nuts.
Actually,
those are meatballs.
Take a roll,
take a couple of meatballs.
They're going in an angle.
Put some sauce on it.
The meatball is tender
as you can find.
Oh, yeah. Nice job.
Thank you.
Anything new
on the menu?
Do you have anything
for me?
Yes, yes.
What do you got?
Chicken Parmesan.
We butterfly the chicken
and pound that out
and we dip the chicken
into the egg wash
and use homemade
bread crumbs.
We'll grind up
our bread,
and then we'll add
granulated garlic,
parsley, grated cheese,
and then dip the chicken
into the bread crumbs.
I'm going to add some oil.
Our chicken,
put a weight on it,
add a little bit
of butter, cheese.
And then I want to put my lid
on top of it
in order to melt
the cheese.
Grab my roll, put our homemade
red sauce on top of it.
I remember making the red sauce
with you.
This is celery,
carrots, and onions.
And now we have some garlic,
which has already been smashed.
Okay.
I bring this
to a boil.
Now we're going to add
our spices.
Oregano, basil?
Basil.
Salt and pepper.
Yes.
Then hit it
with the tomato sauce?
Yep. We're going to put it
through that strainer assembly.
It'll push
everything down.
♪♪
Mmm.
[ Chuckles ]
♪♪
No, I'm good.
I can go on like this.
Thank you.
It's so good, though.
Mmm.
I love the chicken Parm.
The red sauce is excellent
on anything
that you would want
to put it on.
It tastes like
it's straight from Italy.
Chicken Parm.
How's business?
Still cranking?
Excellent.
Been great.
If you recall,
when we did the show,
we had just closed
on Sundays.
Seven days a week.
Actually in 2006,
we changed to six days.
Six days.
So we're closed
on Sundays now.
Okay, now that's
going to change.
Yeah.
He'll be going back,
won't he?
We ended up
opening on Sundays again.
I finally talked him into
closing a day,
and you said, "No, Johnny,
you got to open on Sundays."
[ Laughs ]
So we're open on Sundays.
Open every day,
and business did go up
at least 30%, 40%.
You deserve much success.
You run
a really nice operation.
Kudos to you, my friend.
You're the stories
that make this so easy.
You're shining examples.
People that watch the show
say, "You know what?
I can go make
my own mom-and-pop joint.
I can make it work,"
and you've done it.
So, happy for you.
You guys are awesome.
Oh, take care, Guy.
Thank you.
Keep it up.
♪♪
Next, we're headed
to Norfolk...
Up, over.
Yeah, that's right.
Roll.
...where this drive-in
has been dishing out
sweet treats...
Move on to a freeze.
Oh, please.
...for over 100 years.
Mmm. That's good.
Co-ed sundae.
FIERI: Now, back in 2008,
I set off to answer
an age-old question --
where was the ice cream cone
invented?
Well, today on "Triple-D,"
we're going to take you there.
And with another decade
under their belt,
it's still one and the same.
Doumar's, Norfolk, Virginia.
This is going to be great.
MAN: I saw Doumar's
on "Triple-D,"
and I was proud of it and I
thought it gave a spotlight
to something that we've
been enjoying for years.
This is the most sweets
I've eaten
in probably
the last two years.
WOMAN: I've been coming here
since not long
after World War II.
It's one of our favorites.
Takes you back
to your younger years.
FIERI: Or even further,
like back in 1904
when Abe Doumar invented
the ice cream cone
at the St. Louis World's Fair.
The Smithsonian has said
this is the dude that did it.
And they've kept it
a family business,
passed down
to Abe's nephew Al
and great-nephew Thad.
Would your uncle --
Would he be proud to see
that you're still
doing this,
that you still got this
running out here?
He'd be out of his mind.
[ Laughing ] He'd be out
of his mind.
We still make all of our cones
on the original machines.
People appreciate
the effort,
and of course,
if you do it yourself,
you know what you're getting.
Alright. Here we go.
Okay.
And there it is.
Is that right?
That's alright.
That's okay
for a rookie?
He and my bad really
hit it off.
Look at this one
right here.
My dad was 92 when he died,
and he had worked here full time
for 68 straight years.
Okay. So, up, over.
Yeah, that's right.
Roll.
Like that?
That's damn good.
Put it right there.
Damn good he said.
[ Chuckles ]
Next on the hit parade
is our strawberry willie.
Next on the hit parade.
Vanilla ice cream,
our crushed-up cone chips.
So these are the cones
that didn't make it?
Strawberries on there,
a little strawberry syrup.
Mmm.
[ Speaks indistinctly ]
You would like this.
THAD: My great-uncle started
the ice cream cone.
Right.
My granddad really started
the restaurant.
THAD: Over the years,
my granddad did
many gimmicky things
just to advertise.
So he came up
with a co-ed sundae.
And he called it the co-ed
so that a high school couple
or a college couple on a date
can share it together.
We start with two dips
of vanilla ice cream.
We add 2 ounces of hot fudge
at 150 degrees,
half of a sliced banana.
Then we add whipped cream,
cherry,
and there's your co-ed.
♪♪
The co-ed sundae
is delicious.
It was just
so warm and gooey.
You'd think it'd just be
like a normal sundae,
but then, like,
it has the bananas.
Kind of surprises you.
Move on to a freeze.
Oh, please.
Once the show aired,
we are instantly jammed.
We had the biggest month
we've ever had.
Our top three sellers
are lime-aids...
Oh, that's refreshing.
...our ice cream cones...
That's good.
...and our barbecue sandwiches.
I could easily smoke down
about 19 of those.
We're making our pork
barbecue sandwich.
I'm using a Boston butt
and we're putting them
in the pans for roasting.
I'm just roasting
in its own juices.
We're cooking at 425
for approximately six hours.
Once my butts are cooked,
you just debone it,
and then we'll prepare it
for grinding.
So now that we've ground up
the pork,
we add apple cider vinegar
to it.
Next, we add
our Doumar's hot sauce.
Start with tomato puree,
apple cider vinegar,
mustard, brown sugar,
ground red pepper.
We just stir it all together.
Next we add salt, water.
We let it simmer
for about 2 hours,
and then it's ready
to be served.
Add your slaw.
And we top it with the bun,
and then this is
Doumar's barbecue sandwich.
Pick up a barbecue
and order of fries.
It's so flavorful.
They have this fine
diced coleslaw
that adds just a good crunch,
and the house sauce
adds just enough spice.
The vinegar and the spices,
that's what makes it.
And if you've never eaten it,
you haven't experienced
heaven on a bun.
Will there be more
Doumars coming?
I'm not married yet,
but I hope so one day.
Ba-dum-bum.
THAD: We just keep on doing it
one day at a time
and do the best job we can.
♪♪
FIERI: Up next in Denver...
That is the bite right there.
...a Jewish deli
blasting out blintzes...
Order of cheese blintzes up.
...straight from
Bubbe's kitchen.
-Matzo ball soup.
-Mmm.
This is killer.
Jalapeño cheddar knish.
When I say Denver, Colorado,
what comes to mind?
Well, definitely the Broncos
at Mile High Stadium
and the gateway to great skiing,
but do you think Jewish deli?
Well, that's exactly
what I found back in 2011.
We're talking recipes passed
down through the generations.
We're here to check out
The Bagel Deli & Restaurant.
I was on that episode.
The food
is absolutely tremendous.
I said tremendous
because the food is.
I took
a bite of a huge sandwich.
FIERI:
What makes it so good?
It's made with love.
When you come here,
you never leave hungry.
It is like being
in my grandmother's kitchen.
FIERI: That's because
they're Bubbe's recipes.
Bubbe is grandma.
Bubbe means grandmother.
And Bubbe belonged
to Rhoda Kaplan.
Give Ro-Ro a kiss.
I missed you.
To be recognized
as a great Jewish deli
and to be able to pass
my grandmother's recipes
out to the world,
that's been fabulous.
It's such
fabulous brisket,
we decided
to make a knish out of it.
It's a delish knish.
Hey, that's good.
Okay, first in?
Carrots in.
Just whole like that?
Whole like that.
Celery in.
Then we put these lovely
peeled yellow onions in.
Thank goodness
we cut the onion at least.
I know.
Semi-cut the onion.
Now?
The pepper, garlic powder.
Yummy. And then this
an au jus mix.
Beef base.
Yeah, we just
cover it with water.
Okay,
so everybody's in the pool.
And it's really important
to cover it
really really tight.
Throw it in the oven,
what temp?
This goes in the oven,
400, 5 1/2 hours.
Juicy, juicy, juicy.
Perfect.
Thanks, dear.
I better get
a Hanukkah card.
And then
we're going to make the mix
for the meat knishes
out of that.
Don't you think we should pick
at it and eat some first?
Well, yeah.
Mmm. Now, this all goes
in the buffalo chopper.
Go. Nothing like big
kitchen equipment.
That's about
the consistency.
Now we're going to take this
out of here.
On goes the gloves because this
gets kind of messy now.
White pepper.
Garlic. Season-all.
Eggs.
Little chicken binder there.
Yep, sautéed onions.
That gets all mixed up
really good.
And then
these pastries here?
Put them here on the middle.
Then we're going to paint.
This is just eggs and milk,
a little egg wash.
Scoop it in, bring the ends up,
twist it, smash it
so it looks about
like that
Oh, wow.
More -- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Put this
on that cookie sheet.
A little bit of
the same egg wash.
Bake them off at what, 350?
350 for
about 35, 40 minutes.
That's a knish.
Mmm.
Smells good, huh?
Mmm. That's great.
Not overly salty.
So this is
red horseradish.
Mmm.
Good stuff
that red horseradish, huh?
That is the bite
right there,
when you complement it
with the two.
Mmm!
Great job.
♪♪
We went from maybe 50 knishes
a month to like 500.
And so we thought
we're going to get creative.
I always ate
the brisket knish,
and then when they introduced
this new one,
it's become my new favorite.
Jalapeño cheddar knish up!
The jalapeño cheddar
cream cheese knish.
Well, the first step is that
I get our whipped cream cheese.
We add jalapeños,
cheddar cheese,
and we'll just mix
this up really, really good.
And that's ready now
to put into our pastry shells.
We're going to fold these
the same way
we folded the meat knishes.
Push it down,
and there you go.
Put some more egg wash
on them, some more cheese,
and then we pick out
a really pretty jalapeño.
Bake them at 400
for 15 minutes.
We put it on the plate,
and there you go.
And here's
our jalapeño cheddar knish.
A little bit savory,
a little bit traditional.
Kind of goes pop
in your mouth.
It was excellent.
MAN: And it has a kick.
Any time I get a chance
to eat it, I will.
I had a grandmother who was
a wonderful cook and baker.
I'm immediately transported
back to her kitchen.
I only knew how
to make matzo ball soup
from being taught by
my grandmother.
MAN: Matzo ball soup.
What are we into?
Eggs. White pepper.
Ginger.
Are matzo balls
always with ginger?
They should be.
You do not know
how many people have come in
and said to me,
"I've started adding ginger
to my matzo balls
and it makes a huge difference."
Salt, oil.
Okay.
Mix this real good.
Very nice.
Now, matzo meal. You have to mix
really carefully.
Or you'll get?
Lumps.
We put that in the refrigerator
for how long?
Four to five hours.
So it's chilled up,
congealed enough
that it'll be able to scoop.
Correct.
Okay.
So now we're going to roll
the matzo balls.
Put your hands in the oil
like that.
Smoothing them out.
That's it.
How long do they take
to cook?
About 35 minutes.
We'll take the stock,
add a little bit
of a chicken base, carrots.
Yep.
Put in the chicken.
Parsley
with a little bit of water.
Dig it.
Now we take the matzo balls.
See how big they got?
Yep.
How many gallons of this
do you go through?
15, 20 gallons a day.
What?
Now we've doubled it.
It just flies out of here.
Mmm.
This is killer.
Originally, my parents started
this business,
and then our son Jared,
he's been here
for about 14 years full-time.
And so that means
what my parents started
is going to continue on.
I've known Jared since
he was a tot.
He works really hard.
The food is consistent.
Me and my friends
come here every Sunday.
We normally get, like,
the matzo ball soup.
We love the blintzes.
Order of cheese blintzes up.
JARED: First step is
we're gonna take the eggs,
the milk, flour, water,
little bit of powdered sugar
for sweetness.
Then we mix it up.
Now we will make the Crepes.
Roll it around.
3 to 4 minutes on one side,
then you flip it,
turn off the heat,
and then they'll be done.
Next thing we'll do
is we'll fill them
with the ricotta filling.
Cream cheese, ricotta, eggs,
powdered sugar, and vanilla.
We're going to take a scoop
in each one, fold it in,
and pull it out
with our fingers, fold it over.
We want to make sure
the edges stay inside.
We're going to put them
in the pan.
5 to 7 minutes each side.
And then we serve them
traditionally
with sour cream
and homemade cherry sauce.
Sweet on the inside, very light.
You just want to get in there.
It has a little bit of savory,
so it's the perfect combination.
It has everything
that you're looking for.
MAN: If somebody comes
to Denver,
I will personally
take them here.
You get a jalapeño knish.
You get a cheese blintz.
I would eat it with them.
[ Laughs ]
Congratulations.
Awesome place.
Check it out.
FIERI: But these aren't
the only joints
that should be on your list.
Between the diners...
Green peppers
and mushrooms.
...the drive-ins...
Alright.
...the dives,
and the delis...
Pastrami, corned beef,
and Swiss up.
...the options are endless.
Enjoy.
And we'll see those
next time on "Triple-D Nation."
Well, it's like a lime shake
or an orange shake.
Uh-huh.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
Oh, I did it again.
Don't laugh.
Ohh!