I'm Guy Fieri.
We're rolling out looking for
America's greatest...
CROWD:
..."Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives."
[ Cheering ]
This trip...
Yeah!
...we're stuffed...
Wow!
...stacked...
I have to smash it down,
I can't get my fat mouth
around my fat sandwich.
...and out of the ordinary.
Well, this seems like
more fun than I can handle
in a whole day.
We've got a Peruvian sandwich
shop in Hollywood, Florida...
If this is what
I've been missing in Peru,
I got to go.
...a funky pizza joint
in Fargo, North Dakota...
I can just go on and on
about it.
...and a Philadelphia
pierogi palace...
Fantastic is
an understatement.
...taking old school Polish
to a whole new generation.
What are we gonna make?
-Golumpki.
I can't say the name
of the dish
and I don't understand
the culinary process.
That's all right here
right now on "Triple D."
♪♪
So back in the day,
if you told somebody
that you were gonna get them
some German food,
some Polish food,
or Russian food,
most people would say,
nah, I'm good,
I'll just have Italian.
But what you're seeing now
is people are taking
these old world foods,
put new school spins on them,
and just doing
these awesome pop-ups.
So we're here in Bridesburg,
right in the northeast side
of Philadelphia,
to check out a joint where
they're using grandma's recipes
to make it the real deal.
This is Mom Mom's Kitchen.
Two orders of potato pierogies
coming at you.
Mom Mom's is soulful
Eastern European food.
They put a little spin on it.
The roast pork pierogi
for table three.
They make everything by hand
and you can tell.
FIERI: That scratch-made menu
put out by self-taught chefs,
Kaitlin Wines and Ryan Elmore,
is all about Kaitlin's roots.
-My Mom Mom is my grandma.
-Mom Mom?
Mom Mom. Yes.
We do a mix of traditional
Polish and new generation.
-New generation Polish.
-Yeah.
Two pickle souls for the bar.
This is our roots.
Even when they do
cheesesteak pierogi,
they're still a total homage
to Mom Mom.
Philly cheesesteak pierogi.
The Philly cheesesteak pierogi
is basically a Philly
cheesesteak
wrapped up into a pouch.
You actually don't even
miss the bread
because the pierogies
are that good.
All right,
so what are we gonna make?
We're gonna start
with our dough.
We start off
with some sour cream.
This is Mom Mom's recipe?
It's actually not.
Ryan and I developed these
recipes on our own.
Melted butter, oil,
whole eggs,
and whole egg yolks.
-AP flour.
-Yep. Kosher salt.
How long are we gonna mix it?
Three to five minutes.
It does rest for how long?
Usually overnight for us.
Take the dough,
we'll sheet it out,
punch out the rings.
So you made that look
real easy peasy.
Now we make the filling?
We'll start off with little oil
on the grill.
Then we place rib eye here.
Look at that, pushing one
spatula off the other.
This is some
Cooper sharp American cheese.
To think that you didn't have
a culinary background,
you sure move like you have
a culinary background.
Quite a few pierogi
that we've made.
How many you think it is?
I wish I knew how many
I've eaten in my lifetime.
[ Laughs ]
All right,
so a nice mixture of that.
The dough is ready to go.
Should I start timing her?
[ Laughs ]
Oh, look at that
little technique.
Mm-hmm.
Try not to get any filling
in the seam there.
In between the two.
Turn it over,
little pinch again.
And there you have it.
That's a good-looking
pierogi.
These go into the water
for three minutes.
Bring them out,
let them cool.
Toss them on
our flattop grill to sear
for a couple of minutes
until crispy on each side.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What is that?
Black pepper ketchup.
Ketchup on cheesesteaks?
I've never heard of it.
I mean, I'm a fan.
-Really? Yeah.
-Really?
It's a big thing.
Ketchup and egg.
Ugh!
Okay, he's a no.
Scrambled eggs.
Oh, God!
You be the judge.
Caramelized onions
and these cooked for hours
so they're super sweet.
Little scallion.
-And that's all she wrote.
-There you have it.
Am I supposed to eat these with
my hand or with a fork?
Hand is totally acceptable.
-Yeah, that's what I'm thinking.
-Yeah.
♪♪
I've had a lot of pierogies
on "Triple D"
and I've had a lot of pierogies
just in regular life.
That pierogi dough with
the sour cream
and the whole barnyard
of chickens.
It's silky, luxurious
melts in your mouth. Wow.
It's absolutely wrecking regular
cheesesteaks for me right now.
And you guys made this up?
-Yeah.
Don't get me wrong,
I like a little sauce.
Nice to have that little acid,
little sweet.
Dynamite, dynamite.
I mean, this isn't just like,
hey, my grandmother was Polish.
This is like
a legitimate ground-breaking
destination dish.
Got a cheesesteak pierogi up.
Very meaty. Very cheesy.
Very saucy.
Kind of just melts
in your mouth.
I'm one of those cousins
that has a cousin
in every part of the country,
and I know that you all know
how to eat.
This would be
the kind of place
you'd cruise in
and come get a...
Oh, absolutely.
-Yeah.
-It's fantastic.
Sauerkraut going down.
FIERI: What was this building
before you guys got here?
It used to be a garage.
Our landlord has formed
a commissary.
There's a large lot
for a bunch of food trucks.
That's how we started off
with a little food cart.
-You started off with a truck.
-Yes, exactly.
When you have a hidden gem
like this, it gets around.
FIERI:
And people are showing up for
more than just the pierogies.
Got the golumpki platter.
The golumpki's
a homemade cabbage wrap.
And it's super comforting.
I'm gonna finish these.
You go answer the emails,
come back.
You're not gonna want
to miss this. Delicious.
Why don't you do one?
All right,
when you're in Philadelphia
and you're feeling like you
want a Philly cheesesteak,
but -- but you need a golumpki
instead, come to Mom Mom's.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Guy, we're back. Wake up.
Oh, welcome back,
"Triple D"
hanging out in --
we're in Philly, right?
Yeah.
Kaitlin just got done serving me
this Philly cheesesteak pierogi
and did it incredibly well.
Which is how things roll here
at Mom Mom's Kitchen
where they're rocking out
Polish comfort food.
Got the golumpki
going on the plate.
Golumpki's my favorite thing
on the menu.
That's three meats with rice
wrapped up in cabbage.
Cooked in a really nice
tomato sauce.
I love it every time.
A real traditional Polish dish.
What are we gonna make?
Golumpki.
[ Whispers ]
How do you spell golumpki?
Golumpki has some letters
that we don't have
in our English alphabet.
G-O-L with a dash,
A with a little squiggle thing,
B-K-I.
Golumpki is just not
the sexiest name
for a food item.
-We call it glob for short.
-Oh, glob.
Two globs for the people
out front!
So we're gonna start
with our sauce.
So we have some whole
peeled tomatoes here,
salt, cayenne.
Is there a lot of heat
in Polish food?
No, not really and this
is something we kind of added.
It doesn't make it spicy,
but it just sort of
brightens it up, livens it up.
Yeah!
-Give it a little stir.
-And then butter?
The butter's gonna go in
as I blend.
I can't say the name
of the dish
and I don't understand
the culinary process.
We're gonna make the filling
and stuff the rolls.
So I like how you do it
on a small scale,
keeping it easy going.
Ground beef,
some pork, veal.
So everything we love about
our favorite Italian meatball.
Cooked white rice,
cooked onions,
whole eggs, kosher salt,
fresh cracked pepper.
Mix this up.
So we're gonna
stuff our cabbage now.
Drop the cabbage heads
into the boiling water.
As the outer leaves soften,
we'll peel those off one by one,
and get ready to roll.
Sort of like a little burrito,
envelope kind of thing.
Burrito of sorts.
Well, this seems like
more fun than
I can handle in a whole day.
Now the veg stock,
the house made veg stock.
We're just gonna pour
a little bit on there.
And we're gonna steam this.
What temp?
425 to start.
Then we're gonna reduce
that a little bit.
Wow.
Now we hit them with
the buttered tomato sauce.
Cover them real nice.
Makin' it nice.
We're gonna bake this again.
And we serve it
with the tomato sauce?
And some tatoes on the side.
And potatoes on the side.
Throw those everywhere, yeah.
Crack them open to let
some of the steam release
and then they're ready
to go into the fryer.
Just get a little vinaigrette
in here, fresh dill.
Some nice maldon salt,
fresh cracked pepper,
scallions, and just toss it up
a little bit.
We serve ours with
a little sour cream.
There's you with
your schmear.
Potatoes on the plate here.
Ta-da!
Let's get a couple of these.
A couple?
Comes with two, a little
extra sauce for those.
Fresh dill on top.
Wow. That's one of the best
stuffed cabbage I've ever had.
It's probably one of
the most intense
and most developed
stuffed cabbage I've ever had.
The three meats steaming
in the vegetable stock,
the two layers
of the tomato sauce,
the little kiss of the dill.
It's all just tying together.
I've made a lot of
stuffed cabbage,
mine never tastes this good.
Listen, you can hear my cousins.
They're on their way.
Get some golumpkis ready.
The cabbage
is cooked perfectly.
It almost tastes like
it's a meatball inside.
And the sauce, it's got
a creaminess to it
that's to die for.
Just a little bit better
than what I could do.
Chocolate ganache pierogi
and a kielbasa platter
with rye.
They put so much love
into the food that they make.
Reminds you of eating
with your family.
It's just delicious
every single time.
This is what people want to see.
They want the culture.
They want the heritage.
Fantastic is an understatement.
Mom, you got to be proud.
Up next, a passport
to Peru in Hollywood, Florida.
It's not just great food.
It's Peruvian pride.
From stand out sandwiches...
You want to eat more,
you want to eat the other half.
...to a bowl full of flavor.
This is my secret recipe.
So don't show it.
I'm not gonna tell anybody.
Shh, everybody be quiet.
Thank you.
♪♪
So I'm here in Hollywood,
Florida,
not too long ago
in this same downtown area,
I went to Krakatoa,
a funky little Indonesian place,
serving up a type of food
that people have heard about,
but probably haven't
tried that much.
So it can't be that
I'm at another place
with the same situation
has happened.
I mean, everybody's talked
about Peruvian food.
Everybody knows lomo saltado.
But did you know
that Peru is known
for their street sandwiches?
This is J28.
Here comes the beef.
This place is amazing,
people that open it
obviously show love
that they have
for their cuisine.
Empanada.
It's very creative.
The food is on point.
And it's served up
by brothers
Javier and Marco Rondon,
who are repping
the Peruvian taste I know about
and then some.
When I think
about Peruvian food,
I don't think about
sandwich shops.
In Peru, sandwiches is
very popular.
Like you guys do hamburgers.
-Right.
You do sandwiches.
If I come here,
I get the same thing
if I went to Peru.
-Pretty much, yeah.
So if I look for a while,
I'll be kind of "peru-sing"
the menu.
-Definitely.
"Peru-sing" the menu.
I'll be here all week.
Try the mushroom quinoa bowl.
Marco, I got your mushroom
quinoa coming up.
The quinoa mushroom bowl
is fantastic.
It's got the right amount
of seasoning and flavor
in there
just to make every bite pop.
FIERI:
What are we making?
These peppers called
amarillo,
and I use it as a base
for the mushroom quinoa bowl.
It's a little spicy.
-Right.
We need to boil it down
three times --
Okay.
so we get the spiciness out.
Peel the skin.
-Okay.
And blender, that's it.
This is ketchup
to the gringos?
You can say that.
Yeah.
-I just did.
-Exactly.
-Thank you.
This is the sauce for
the mushroom quinoa stir fry?
Exactly.
Amarillo paste
the one we just did.
Don't mix that up
with the baby food.
This is my secret recipe.
So don't show it.
I'm not gonna tell anybody.
Shh, everybody be quiet.
Thank you.
Garlic goes in,
ginger paste,
red wine vinegar,
soy sauce.
Aribba.
I'll have some of that to go.
All right, chef,
let's fire it up.
-Oil.
-Cremini mushrooms.
Toast it off in the oil
hot and fast.
Red onions, roma tomatoes.
Just scarring
those veggies right now.
The jus that we made
with the aji amarillo.
The soy sauce, the ginger,
and the garlic.
The mushrooms in.
Let's switch woks.
Cooked quinoa.
Little bit of juice again.
Quinoa on the bottom.
The mushroom mixer
with tomatoes, onions,
the juice.
My mouth is starting
to water.
Green onions and cilantro.
♪♪
You get these
big pieces of the mushroom.
It's got a lot
of texture in it.
But, you know, the key is this?
This quinoa has been cooked
so perfectly,
each little bite
pops, pops, pops,
giving you this little
extra bits of texture.
That's one of the most
basic dishes
we've ever done on "Triple D."
But I will tell you,
the flavor is through the roof.
Dynamite.
-I'm so happy right now.
Here's your mushroom quinoa.
I like how fresh it is,
how light it is.
It gives a good,
consistent flavor.
Every single bite.
Yes. Burt Reynolds'
younger brother
does live down here
in South Florida.
My buddy Rich and Chad.
So are you a quinoa fan?
Yeah, this is perfect dish
for me.
The mushrooms
are tender and marinated.
Amazing.
Making the turkey sandwich.
I stumbled across J28
two and a half years ago.
Been coming here ever since.
A lot of people
don't understand that J28.
July 28th is for...yeah.
And we opened on July 28 also.
So it's not just great food,
it's Peruvian pride.
I've been to Peru
and the sandwiches
here are always perfect.
Here's your chicharrón sandwich.
The chicharrón sandwich
is one of a kind.
The pork belly,
it's made to perfection.
We're going to make a pork belly
chicharrón sandwich.
That's right.
We're gonna make the rolls.
-Okay.
Flour, sugar, salt, yeast.
Mix it a little bit
as water goes in.
Okay.
After two minutes,
we add shortening.
We'll let this mix
how much longer?
10 minutes more.
-And then we'll cut it, proof.
-For two hours.
-And then we'll bake.
-For 20 minutes.
Got it. Where are we at?
So this is our fire sauce.
In Peru, it's usually these
peppers, the rocoto peppers.
I got you.
We took these
other pepper called limo.
This is a spicier
than this one,
but go together
the combination is really good.
Yeah, I bet.
-The salt, oil.
-And a little water.
Let's see it.
So this is the marinade for
our pork belly sandwich.
Ginger, oregano, five spices,
brown sugar, salt and pepper.
-Aji amarillo.
-That's right.
Aji panca paste.
Aji panca.
Garlic paste,
white wine vinegar,
soy sauce.
How long is this gonna
marinate in the pork belly?
Overnight.
Then we're gonna boil it
in the marinade and water.
Drain the water
and we fry it.
Crispy, slice it, go.
That's right.
All right,
let's see it, chef.
We have our beautiful
roseta roll.
Listen to this.
[ Crunching ]
The crunchy?
I hear the crunchy.
-The mayo, sweet potato.
-Okay.
The pieces of pork belly
on top.
Pickled onions, picked with
a little bit of lime juice.
Got some cilantro also.
And the fire sauce.
Cut it.
This is our sandwich.
Look at that.
I have to smash it down.
I can't get my fat mouth
around my fat sandwich.
When I think of chicharrón,
I think of Mexican chicharrón.
The crunchy skin.
-Yep.
The bread gives me
that crunch.
After that, you get that
creaminess of the sweet potato,
the much-needed acid
of the onion,
and the tender juicy pork
and then the little icing
on top, that pepper sauce.
This is fantastic.
Thank you so much.
You want to eat more.
You want to eat the other half.
You want to eat the one
that the person next to you
has not finished yet.
Chicharrón coming up.
I taste the pork.
I definitely taste the onions.
All the flavors just pop.
The bread
has a nice like crunch
on the outside,
but it's very fluffy inside.
How many of those sandwiches
can you eat?
-I could probably do three.
-Thanks for telling the truth.
After his three, we take about
a dozen of these empanadas home.
Coming here is almost as good
as actually going to Peru.
I love everything
that I get here.
FIERI: If this is what I've been
missing in Peru, I got to go.
Congratulations.
-Thank you so much.
Coming up,
a wood-fired hot spot
in North Dakota...
We're in Fargo.
We're gonna do it the way
we want to do it.
...going outside the box
with their pie.
This is unconventional
to 99%
of the pizza joints
I've ever gone to.
...and looking back
to the family tree.
So we're gonna let
lebowegian meatballs.
♪♪
So I'm here in Fargo,
North Dakota,
and if you haven't been here,
you should come
and check it out.
You know, things are
a little different up here.
Let's see, the weather, well,
it could change dramatically
at the drop of a hat
and the food scene,
it will surprise you.
You know,
folks up here kind of go
to the beat of their own drum,
kind of like the joint
we're gonna check out now.
Six and a half years of making
wood-fired pizzas their way.
This is Blackbird Woodfire.
♪♪
Basil going on the harder,
hotter salami.
The food is fantastic.
MAN: Wild mushroom pizza,
table one.
There's absolutely nothing
like a wood-fired pizza
coming straight
out of the oven.
This was the first legit
wood-fired pizza place.
And so, we were kind of
over the moon.
FIERI:
And that pie biz was born
when respiratory therapist
Casey Absey
turned tinkering
into a whole new career.
I was gonna build
an old-fashioned barbecue
in my backyard,
made a wood-fired oven.
And the next year,
I built one on a trailer
and we started
doing festivals.
What makes you different in
the world of wood-fired pizza?
I think we have more of
a Mediterranean spin on things.
My dad's folks
came from Lebanon.
But my mom was Norwegian.
Lebanese, Norwegian.
I'm lebowegian.
A lebowegian.
Got a pep going in hot!
I think you have to judge
a good pizza by its dough.
Dough-n't you know?
Sorry I had to take the shot.
It's just that perfect level
of crispiness,
but it still stays chewy.
-We're gonna make pizza dough.
-All right.
Two cups of salt.
Now wait a second,
salt before yeast?
Yeah.
Water.
When in North Dakota.
-One bag of flour.
-All purpose.
Then I throw my yeast in.
Are we gonna bloom
the yeast?
-Nope.
-Okay.
Bread flour.
-No high gluten?
-Nope.
No double zero?
-Okay.
We're not trying
to be Italian.
Okay, your house.
How long is this gonna mix?
-20 minutes.
And then you'll let
this proof?
We'll ball it up first.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
You're not gonna proof before
you ball?
Nope, proof in the box,
24 hours in the cooler.
This is unconventional
to 99%
of the pizza joints
I've ever gone to.
Just lots of experimenting.
Putting apples
on the sausage apple pizza.
Sausage and apple pizza
is literally the one
I have every time.
When it comes to the table,
it's a piece of art.
Sausage apple pizza's
a norm around here.
Nope, just here.
All right,
what are we on to now?
The béchamel.
Half a pound butter, flour,
and make a roux.
Then we add the milk,
garlic powder,
parsley, bay leaf,
chili flakes, nutmeg,
and salt and pepper.
Béchamel's done. Next up.
The sausage,
it's all local pork.
Salt and pepper, fennel.
-A lot of it.
Oregano, sugar, parsley,
chili flakes, granulated garlic.
-Mix this up.
-Bake it 425.
Let's take a look at this dough.
It's gentle.
Boy, that's got a lot of
elasticity for bread dough.
Béchamel on it, parmesan.
Our homemade sausage,
apples, sage.
Goes in.
-And that's all she wrote.
Gorgeous, oh, square.
Snap pea micros.
Yeah, it's your every day
Lebanese Norwegian pizza.
♪♪
That is one delicious pizza.
Great chew to the crust.
Get a nice crackle
on the outside
with true gluten style
flour pull.
And this little béchamel
parmesan cheese program
works completely right.
Sausage still has
good fat to it.
A lot of great apple.
The key at the end, though,
that fresh herb on top.
I can just go on and on
about it. Outstanding.
Thanks, sir.
Sausage apple pizza,
table four.
There's this sweet combination
between the sweet
of the green apple.
And then, you also get the salty
of the sausage.
It's a perfect crust.
It's the reason
why we come here.
FIERI: I'm impressed with
the Fargo food scene.
You have this whole
we're in Fargo,
we're gonna do it the way
we want to do it.
The chamber
a couple of years ago
came out with the motto,
North of Normal.
We kind of just make
our own rules.
FIERI: And this chef's throwing
in a little family heritage
on top of it all.
Mediterranean bison meatballs.
Mediterranean meatballs
one of my go-tos.
It's super good.
With a beautiful
little creamy sauce on top,
it's a great appetizer.
So we're gonna have
lebowegian meatballs.
80-20 local bison.
Almonds, raisins,
fresh mint, parsley,
salt, pepper, chili flakes,
and garlic granules.
He's the kind of
the granulated garlic.
Just so you know.
-We'll add that to the beef.
-Love all that texture.
Add a little oil,
crack two eggs in.
There you go.
We're gonna mix
that up a little bit
and then we'll add the rice.
-The what?
-Basmati.
All right,
so ball these out.
Cook it 15 minutes, 425.
-Next up?
-Tzatziki sauce.
So we're taking something
from the Greeks now.
No, no,
this is very Lebanese.
-What do the Lebanese call it?
-Leben.
So we got some plain yogurt,
parsley, mint, honey,
olive oil, lemon juice,
salt, pepper.
Fantastic. What's up next?
We got the sauce,
do a little oil,
sweat the onions, garlic,
deglaze it with
a little red wine,
parsley, mint,
a little oregano --
Bay leaf.
...chili peppers.
-Interesting sauce.
-Salt and pepper, tomatoes.
Let this simmer, what,
20 minutes?
20 minutes tightens up
and then we're done.
Okay.
So we're gonna plate
our Mediterranean meatballs
add a little olive oil,
get them sizzling,
and then we'll add sauce
and reheat that.
We'll plate it up with
our pita bread,
tzatziki sauce that we made,
then we'll garnish it
with mint.
Gorgeous.
I can already feel
the crunch.
That's fantastic.
That meatball,
I love the texture in it.
Wow.
When you get that play
between that tzatziki,
the fresh herbs, the mint
singing through, for sure.
Yeah.
This right here
has its own identity,
really should be experienced.
That's dynamite.
You got the Mediterranean
bison meatballs.
They're sweet and savory.
It's got a little kick to it,
but not overpowering.
A little package of flavor
when you just pop it
in your mouth.
Pepperoni pizza, table eight.
He cares a lot about the food
he puts out,
it has a special meaning to him.
FIERI: That's what's great
about the restaurant business.
You get to play your own music
and a lot of people
are showing up for the concert.
Well done.
I want to buy the album.
So that's it
for this road trip.
But don't worry,
we got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives."
What is that over there?
Is that...
What? Where?
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughter ]