Alright, Hunter,
here's the game plan --
Months ago, you sent out a video
saying to people
you wanted to know their
favorite "Triple-D" location.
Remember that?
That's right. I do.
We want to know what is your
favorite "Triple-D" joint?
People submit their video --
-My favorite --
-Our favorite --
-Favorite --
Favorite "Triple-D" joint --
Mmm-mm!
They to describe why
they like it.
Mm-hmm, their
favorite dish.
They could be funny.
They could be sad.
They could sing a song.
Whatever they wanted to do
to draw attention
to why this "Triple-D" location
should be on America's
favorite list. Mmm!
People were very excited about
this. Thousands of submissions.
You and I sat,
you and I watched,
and we picked.
I think,
some of the best.
[ Silly voice ] Just look at how
delicious this stuff is.
[ Laughs ]
Those winners, Hunter,
each are gonna get
1,000 bucks
and they're gonna
get featured on their own
special edition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives."
On top of that,
we're not only
gonna show you their video.
Hi! I'm Guy Fieri
and we're rolling out.
We're gonna show America
that "Triple-D" location again
so they can understand
why they're on the list
of America's favorite
"Triple-D" joints.
We're on the same page?
Yes.
Oh, yeah.
FIERI: Like on this trip --
Empanadas that'll
make your eyes water...
Do you like it?
Little more than like.
Ohh!
...burgers that
know no bounds...
That's how we roll, man.
We gotta get crazy back here.
...and breakfast worth
waking up for.
[ Record skips,
doorbell rings ]
[ Chuckles ]
I was dreaming?
Stay with me. Stay with me.
No! 1, 2, 3!
Think
of all the sandwiches!
[ Laughter ]
♪♪
I'm hungry.
Yeah, yeah!
Food is just phenomenal.
That is the best "Triple-D" spot
to visit.
[ Animalistic growling ]
Yuuuh!
So good.
FIERI: Alright, Hunter,
let's get things started.
We are looking for
the creativity, the delivery,
and can they convince us
that their favorite
"Triple-D" joint
should be on the list of
America's favorites?
Definitely.
MAN: That is gangster.
Let's see what we got.
Roll it.
Fat Sal's, Los Angeles.
Congratulations.
What are you gonna do next?
I'm going to Fat Sal's and I'm
gonna get the Fat Sow sandwich
that's thinly sliced ribeye
steak that'll melt in your mouth
and crunchy onion rings that'll
make your mouth water.
On a hot summer day,
you know you want to head down
to Fat Sal's
for a cold, refreshing milkshake
filled to the brim
to satisfy your
sweet tooth.
BOY: Help!
[ Whistle blows ]
♪♪
Stay with me. Stay with me.
No! 1, 2, 3!
Think of all
the sandwiches!
Crispy bacon, mozzarella.
[ Coughs, gasps ]
Barbecue, pastrami,
and brisket.
Yes!
The Fat Texas.
Yes. Yes,
stay with me.
Yes! Yes!
Mmm-mm! Yes, sir.
The Fat Texas.
[ Whip cracks ]
You best believe I'll be
going down to Fat Sal's
to get myself
a chicken finger-filled sandwich
that's fit
for a cowboy's appetite.
[ Crickets chirping ]
It's the middle of the night.
You're dreaming of Flavortown.
Fat Sal's has got you covered
until 2:00 a.m..
MAN: [ Grunts ]
Sir, sir, sir!
Where are you
running to next?
Uh, you know,
I'm pretty tired.
I think I might turn around
and go to Fat Sal's.
[ Chuckling ] Oh, my God.
That was the --
Okay, I don't know
who these dudes are --
I don't know who
these dudes are,
but I want to hang out
with those guys.
Those are full-blown residents
of Flavortown.
That was the best video
I've ever seen.
That was awesome.
We're calling those dudes.
You have to.
That was so good.
Here we go, Hunter.
From Fat Sal's,
We've got Spencer,
Alex and Daniel.
What's up, guys?
What's up?
What's up, Guy?
[ Laughs ]
Well, gentlemen, I'll tell you
what -- You crushed it.
Crushed it!
Thank you.
We have seen some funny stuff,
but I'm telling you --
Let's see. It was the Texas dude
the pool dude, the graduation,
the Forrest Gump at the end.
Are you kidding me?
It was so good.
You guys killed us.
I mean, we were dying.
It was super fun to make.
And we love making
these types of videos.
You're dreaming of Flavortown.
Tell me about Fat Sal's.
What is it about the place
that made you go?
I mean, you really went over
the top with it.
What is it about Fat Sal's
that you love so much?
I just love how, like, it's open
until, like, 1, 2 a.m..
Definitely
the atmosphere, too.
Oh, and you got that parking
lot. Everybody hangs out there.
[ Chuckles ] Yeah.
You see your friends there.
They just happen to be there.
FIERI: That's my buddy
right there.
His name's Jay
and he's a buddy of Jerry's.
So, fitting that I get
you two here.
Well, gentlemen,
I gotta tell you something.
The enthusiasm, the energy,
and the creativity
that you put into it,
I without question
understand why
Fat Sal's should be
on the list.
♪♪
Fat Bahn Mi-ki.
You'll never try
another sandwich like this
anywhere else.
Waiting on the Ruben rolls.
Chili cheeseburger.
It's crazy.
MAN: They take the appetizers
and the French fries
and they put them
on the actual sandwich itself.
Serving up monster sandwiches
is the brainchild
of owners Josh Stone,
Sal Capek, and Jerry Ferrara,
three New York buddies who
invaded health-conscious Cali
with their
greasy spoon concept.
We couldn't find the kind
of food that we wanted to eat,
so we were just like, whatever,
let's just make ourselves.
And since they opened
in 2010,
their cravings have
caught on.
If you bring somebody
from the East Coast
that's out here visiting,
will you bring them here?
I always do.
Take them to the Hollywood sign
take them to the Walk of Fame,
take them to Fat Sal's.
I'm not gonna lie.
The only reason
I come to Westwood
is for Fat Sal's sandwiches.
I have no idea
what else is here.
Fat Jerry.
WOMAN: I'm having
the Fat Jerry's
and it's just like
the best thing I've ever had.
So this is the Fat Jerry?
This a Fat Jerry.
Named after?
Jerry Ferrara.
FIERI:
Yeah, that'd be Jerry,
a.k.a. Turtle from HBO's
"Entourage."
Everybody that's
in movies or TV
wants to be
in the restaurant business.
Everybody in sports wants be
the restaurant business.
Everybody in the
restaurant business?
Wants to be in --
Movies and sports.
[ Both laugh ]
Alright. So let's go.
Starts with our
extra-wide hero bread,
which we call Fat Bread.
Okay.
Give this thing
a little bit of that butter.
Get it started
on the grill.
Okay.
We're gonna drop
chicken fingers,
mozzarella sticks,
and French fries.
Oh, what else is
going in this?
Bacon, eggs,
cheesesteak, onions.
All for one sandwich?
All for one sandwich.
A little bit of salt.
A little bit of pepper.
I'm gonna give this
a little turn.
I'm gonna chop up
our Philly.
We got a little
American cheese, bacon.
We're gonna take this
Philly cheesesteak, an egg --
Okay, that thing's
looking good.
Chicken fingers,
mozzarella sticks --
And...fries.
This is not even
humanly possible.
We do a little bit of ketchup,
a little bit of mayo.
This is ridiculous,
by the way.
This goes here.
This goes there.
Look at the
gore-met in you.
Yep.
And then we give this
a nice roll, nice cut.
Look at this thing.
♪♪
Cheese sticks,
Philly cheesesteak,
French fries,
chicken fingers.
Bacon.
[ Muffled ] Oh,
and bacon.
Bacon.
No lettuce.
None of that.
Not screwing it up and over
vegetable-izing it, you know?
Legit job.
Little nostalgia.
Nice job, my friend.
Thanks, brother.
Fat Jerry.
MAN: I'm indecisive,
so I like to take all the things
I might want,
have it all on
the same sandwich.
And you would think that
it would be just weird,
but it's really amazing.
It kind of makes me feel young,
eating something like this.
So what can I
get you today?
Hi.
If you come to L.A. and you're
visiting me,
we're going to Fat Sal's.
[ Tape rewinds ]
Spencer Alex, Daniel,
congratulations.
The three of you
have elevated the game.
You really crushed it.
I hope you take that
1,000 bucks that you won,
do something really productive
with it. Job well done.
Well done.
Seriously.
Nice job.
Thank you so much.
[ Chuckles ]
Thank you.
FIERI: Up next...
BOTH: D & J Rollin' Out.
Peace.
I can't stop eating
empanada!
[ Both laugh ]
It made me hungry,
It made me laugh,
and now I'll never
forget that.
Goodness!
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Hey, "Triple-D" family.
HUNTER: Welcome back to
"Triple-D: America's Favorites"
Oh, it's so good.
So delicious.
So incredibly flavorful.
You can put it on a flip flop.
Let's eat.
Roll it.
I eat cookie, cookie, cookie
all day long,
and I started feeling like
too many cookie.
I said me try empanada.
Well, guess what?
Empanada good.
So then I try second empanada.
Yep, yep.
And then third
and then fourth
and now I can't stop
eating empanada.
Me -- me can't stop...
[ Laughs ]
...eating empanada.
Me Empanada Monster!
Maria Empanada Monster!
Okay, now things are completely
out of control, you guys.
What --
That was hysterical.
[ Laughs ] What --
What just happened?
Maria Empanada.
That was --
He actually did a --
That was a really good
impression on that.
Oh, my gosh.
That was funny.
That was actually --
That was great.
But again, the whole thing is
it made you hungry.
It made me hungry,
it made me laugh,
and now I'm never gonna
forget that.
There she is,
Lorena from Maria Empanada
and our Empanada Monster,
Victor.
Ohhh, my goodness!
[ Laughs ]
Victor, Lorena,
how are you? [ Laughs ]
Hey, I gotta tell you,
that was awesome.
I didn't see it coming. I mean,
we saw so many great videos.
I mean, hundreds of them.
But I'm gonna tell you,
that voice, the activity,
the empanada -- Of course, we
all love the empanadas, Lorena.
But, Victor, you
crushed it, man. Congrats.
It got so
out of control.
It started off all slow
and then it just went nuts.
[ Both laugh ]
How did you come up
with the idea?
You know what?
I woke up thinking,
"What can we do that's really
creative and unique?
And he needs to have
a different diet."
And I figured, what better diet
than empanadas, right?
[ Impersonating
Cookie Monster ] Yep, yep, yep.
I looove empanadas!
[ Laughs ]
Oh, my gosh. It's outrageous.
Victor, what do you do for work?
So I do marketing and PR,
and this lady here
started as a client of mine
a long time ago.
Lorena, when was the last time
we saw you?
When was last time?
When were you there? 2000...?
You came in 2015.
People ask me about "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives"
and they're like,
"What are the places?"
This is it.
You've got a character,
you've got a story,
and you've got
great food.
Thank you.
It was a wonderful visit we had.
You do a great job.
I love all the energy
that you bring.
The empanadas, of course,
are world class.
♪♪
Caprese.
Nothing compares
Maria Empanadas.
You really feel like
you're in
a little part of
Buenos Aires.
Vamanos, Melissa.
You can feel that it's made
with passion.
And determination...
All from owner,
Lorena Cantarovici.
So how did you get
from Buenos Aires to here?
I just got $300, a backpack,
and three words in English --
Hi, hello, and ciao.
Ciao?
Ciao is not English.
[ Laughs ]
And how did the
empanada empire start?
Because I miss it a lot.
And I didn't find any
empanadas here in Denver.
So I need to make it.
FIERI: [ Chuckles ]
And does she ever?
Since opening the joint
named after her mom in 2011,
she now cranks out, get this --
up to 1,500 a day.
You would think there's an army
back in the kitchen
making empanadas.
How authentic
are these empanadas?
They could learn
in Argentina.
That authentic?
[ Laughter ]
Beef empanadas.
I love the beef empanada.
MAN: Ground beef,
onions, peppers,
seasoning, wrap them like a
turnover pastry. It's amazing.
CANTAROVICI: This is
corn oil, okay?
And then we
put some onions.
We have red peppers.
Okay, next?
Ground beef.
Who taught you
to make empanadas?
My mom.
So we put some salt here.
Look at this. Pepper.
Crushed red pepper.
Cumino.
Muy bien.
And this is pimenton,
Spanish paprika.
Not spicy?
Not spicy.
We are going to
let it cool.
Okay, what are we
gonna make?
Chimichurri.
Si.
Parsley. Red Pepper.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
What, what, what, what?
This is chimichurri
with red pepper?
This is chimich--
The authentic one.
Oh.
[ Tiger growls ]
Okay. Come back.
Garlic.
I like garlic. Okay.
I like garlic.
Salt and pepper.
Pepper.
Then we have some
then some --
BOTH: Pimenton.
Si.
Okay.
Then we have
crushed red pepper.
Ut, ut, ut, ut!
I-- I -- I --
Vinegar, oregano,
and olive oil.
Beautiful olive oil.
How long do we
let this set up?
Three to four days.
Now we make the empanadas.
Let's empanadas. Vamos.
We grab a disc that we made
before, we put some olives,
some of this filling
that we make.
So each one gets
this fold-over?
Yes, yes.
[ Whistles ]
If you look in the dictionary
under empanada,
that's what it looks like.
That's impressive.
A little egg wash.
Exactly.
We bake them at
what temperature?
375,
10 to 12 minutes.
So empanadas are ready.
Are you ready?
Listo.
♪♪
Do you like it?
Little more than like.
Ohh! I like you, too.
There's a subtlety.
A subtle flavor,
a subtle texture,
just a uniqueness.
Not too spicy.
♪♪
You gotta have
a chimichurri.
It's light, little flavor,
a little crust, simple.
That's what an empanada's
supposed to be.
[ Chuckles ]
Excellent job.
Thank you.
Very good.
Easy to eat. Great flavor.
It's delicately done.
Very savory.
The chimichurri sauce
is the ultimate compliment.
Could I get the
Beef Classico please?
MAN:
When you look at that case,
you just want to dive in
and eat them all.
You don't want to leave.
CANTAROVICI: Okay,
thank you.
Thank you.
Was it always this big?
Was it here at this location?
No, I did have
a very small location.
It doesn't even matter
what she's talking about.
All of a sudden,
it became dramatic.
[ Dramatic music plays ]
Then what happened?
You want to really hear
what happened?
Ohh, yes, I do.
Tell me!
Are you ready?
Ayyyyyeee!
[ Laughter ]
We just decided that
the business grew a lot
and we needed to move.
Hnng.
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: But it's a happy ending
because now she's got a space
to make all the empanadas
she wants and more.
The tarta analia.
It's amazing.
Now we're going to make a?
Tarrrrta.
[ Chuckles ]
There's not that many R's
in it, really.
Okay, tarta analia.
It has a full medley
of different veggies.
MAN: A nice cream cheese
at the bottom
and it's got a flaky crust.
So we have the butternut squash
right here, carrots,
and zucchinis.
Eggplant, yeah?
Eggplant. Yes.
The red onions, salt and pepper,
and some olive oil.
How long are we going
to roast this?
30 minutes.
So roasted veggies.
And now some basil.
Basil.
Alright.
Yes.
And the green onions.
Look at the color here.
Isn't that great?
Beautiful.
Beautiful!
Now we knead the dough.
Let's try to take all the air
that is under --
On the sides?
On the sides, yes.
And then we put some
cream cheese.
Cream cheese is
Argentinian?
Queso crema!
Alright, queso crema.
A little bit of
Parmigiano.
And now we can put
the filling here.
Need more cheese?
I need more parmesan.
There you go.
Beautiful colors.
Now, we make these
little --
Of course,
you have to do some
little disco dance
when it goes
all the way around.
Of course, yes.
So we bake this off
at what temperature?
425 for 50 minutes.
♪♪
Ping! There you go.
A little basil on top.
♪♪
That reminds me
of almost like a calzone.
Nice, bright,
fresh vegetables.
They key is that little bit
of cream cheese,
a little bit of acid at the
bottom, and a little bit of fat.
And you're able to eat it almost
like you're eating a sandwich.
People dig it.
♪♪
[ Tape rewinds ]
What we were trying to find
is America's favorite diners,
drive-ins, and dives,
and who could
really explain it to us
in a quick
60-second video?
I gotta tell you, Victor.
I gotta tell you, bro --
if there's somebody
that brought it, you brought it.
Job well done.
Empanada Monster.
Yeah. Nice job.
That was awesome.
FIERI: Coming up...
My favorite restaurant.
They are our absolute
favorite place.
We are waiting for you.
Don't miss it.
Have mercy.
Do the hunch.
Come on.
Do it.
Do the hunch.
"Triple-D" fans are nuts.
They drive up
and everything.
Horses, combines,
tractors, you name it.
♪♪
FIERI: Welcome back. This is
"Triple-D: America's Favorites."
Well, hello, there.
They're waiting to fill
your pie hole.
♪ Now let your
soul--soul--soul flo-ow ♪
Go big or go home.
Yeaaah!
Yeah!
"Triple-D" fans are nuts.
Alright, Hunter, let's roll it.
Junction City, Oregon.
This is
Junkyard Extreme Burgers.
Alright.
What's the big deal
about
Junkyard Extreme Burgers and
Brats?
Let's go see.
I like her
"Triple-D" hat.
♪♪
So...what's the big deal
about Junkyard Extreme Burgers
and Brats?
I love the junkyard theme.
It's very authentic.
You know? Let's go see
Where do you find
an airplane on the roof?
She has
a sweatband on.
Like, come on.
And I love the outdoor seating,
either rain or shine.
Oh, look at the painting.
That's awesome.
Junkyard's literally
in the middle of nowhere.
I mean, look.
I mean literally.
Hey, welcome to Junkyard.
What would you like
to eat today?
Here's the menu.
Ummm, yeah.
I'm thinking I'm just gonna
take my regular,
the one that Guy ate.
For sure.
Here's that order for you.
Oh, I remember that.
Now, that's what I'm talking
about.
Have mercy.
Do the hunch. Come on.
Do the hunch.
Do it.
Do it!
♪♪
[ Muffled ]
Oh, yeah.
Well done.
Not bad, not bad.
Great job.
I mean, she's funny.
I mean, everything.
I love the hat.
Yeah.
I love the bite...
Her sweatband.
...at the end.
[ Muffled ]
Oh, yeah.
That was awesome.
That was great.
[ Tape rewinds ]
♪♪
SERVER: I've got a Wisconsin
and a Chicago.
I'm a big eater
and I like big hamburgers
and big hot dogs,
and this is definitely it.
You can expect to get messy.
We never suffer from a lack
of food when we come here.
FIERI: And that's how owners
Craig and Kim Zumwalt like it,
[ Chuckles ] big and bold.
After working
in Nashville's music biz,
Craig hit it back home
and opened this place in '06.
How many people live here
in Lancaster?
ZUMWALT: Hmm.
Probably about 30.
Wow.
Is this a trailer?
It's a race trailer.
And then you built the shed
on next to it?
Yes.
Awesome.
And they're definitely trying
to kick it into gear
when it comes to their
high octane signature burger.
I've got a Big Block.
The burger is bigger
than my head. That huge.
This is just explosion of taste,
literally.
I mean, because there are just
so many ingredients in it.
We're gonna make
a Big Block.
Big Block. Okay.
Let's do it. We have our bread
made for us.
Then --
Ooosh!
We're gonna put some butter
on that bun.
Bring a little parmesan.
Put it right across there.
Bring out
some burger here.
Looks like about a half-pounder
right there to me.
That works.
Get two of those.
This is a
one-pound burger?
Yeah, a one-pound burger.
Yep.
Now we're gonna
throw this on here like this.
We're just gonna take this
and concave her a little bit.
Grab a little onion.
Gonna throw on
a little bit of bacon.
It's going right
in the middle.
Yep.
Gonna smash her down.
Gonna caramelize it real good.
Now we're gonna cut a hole
in the middle of the bun.
We're gonna add an egg.
Now we're gonna add a little
cheddar cheese sauce.
About like that.
Put a little cheddar
on the top.
Is this the
family plan?
Yes.
Alright, now we're going
to build a cheese skirt.
We're gonna start out with
a little parmesan, cheddar,
onion, mozzo, bacon.
Does it come with
a heart paddle?
[ Chuckles ] Right?
Stack on
a little bacon.
Then we're gonna stick
this dome on top there.
So our cheese is just about
ready to roll here.
just so everybody's
up to speed.
Close to a cup of cheese has
been assembled in this abuse.
I mean, this dish.
Well, looks
like everything's ready.
Now we're gonna take this,
slam that right over on that.
Then we're gonna
take this guy,
put it right there,
add a little lettuce.
We got this,
mayonnaise, tomato.
Don't overdo it.
No, I won't.
More meat.
More mayo.
Pickle.
There we go.
A little more lettuce,
a little sprig of onion.
Big Block.
♪♪
There it is.
You have a scale?
Right here.
3.4 pounds. Probably
all lettuce and tomato.
♪♪
[ Chuckles ]
[ Muffled ] Oh.
That's ridiculous.
Look at that hummingbird bite
I took out of that.
So --
Well, I'm gonna take the rest
of the month to enjoy this.
[ Chuckles ]
Mmm!
Here's the thing, buddy.
I've seen some Big Blocks
in the design
and disaster category.
You've pretty much taken
first place on that.
I got that going for me.
Which is a nice.
Yeah.
Way to go.
SERVER: Big Block.
The best part
about it is the meat.
It just melts in your mouth.
You have to laugh when this
thing shows up at your table.
It's like, how are you
gonna finish it all?
FIERI: Well, you could always
take it to-go,
because this place also has
one funky drive-thru.
This is an old
farm community.
So they drive up
in everything --
Horses, combines,
tractors, you name it.
Bo and Luke Duke
come by often?
Junkyard is unique foods
that you just can't find
anywhere else.
This is a hidden gem.
I'm telling you, dude,
we've seen some crazy stuff
on "Triple-D."
This is up there.
Crazy Craig
and the car carrier.
Lovin' it.
Very nice, man.
Don't go anywhere.
Hunter and I are screening
some of the greatest diners,
drive-ins and dives,
blooper fan-based voting,
supporting videos
that you've ever seen.
Does that make any sense?
No.
[ Doorbell rings ]
I was dreaming?
♪♪
Here we go.
Guy Fieri here.
I'm Guy Fieri!
Ah, muy Fieri!
Little, wee Guy Fieri.
[ Laughs ]
Things are completely
out of control, you guys.
MAN:
[ Deep voice ] I'm Guy Fieri
and I approve this message.
Okay, next up, Miss Shirley's,
Baltimore, Maryland. Roll it.
MAN: I'm so hungry.
What should I eat?
Daddy, your favorite's on.
[ Inaudible television ]
He's got the screensaver
of the Camaro.
[ Television
playing quietly ]
There you go.
Oh, that makes me hungry.
This is gonna be so good.
[ Doorbell rings ]
[ Chuckles ]
I was dreaming?
Oh, that's awesome.
Honey, surprise --
Shirley's delivery.
Guy, Hunter,
I nominate Miss Shirley's Cafe
for your next
"Triple-D" visit.
We want to see you in that red
Camaro here back in Maryland.
Bring Flavortown
back to Charm City.
Well done, man.
That was super cool.
Okay --
The dreaming.
[ Chuckles ]
They gave it all to me. He had
good reference to the car,
your daughter
is super cute,
love the plug for
Miss Shirley's.
All the shots of
all the different food.
[ Doorbell rings ]
Awesome job.
You wanna talk about a place
that's packed
and people love
that joint --
if you want to go there
on Sunday for brunch,
you gotta get in line
Saturday night.
[ Tape rewinds ]
♪♪
So here I am in the Roland Park
neighborhood
of Baltimore, Maryland,
on Cold Spring Lane.
Well, more fondly known
as Eddie Dobkin Way.
That's because back in the '90s,
Eddie had, like, five rockin'
and restaurants in this area.
And the one he was most widely
known for is a funky,
big breakfast joint
known as Miss Shirley's Cafe.
♪♪
Your shrimp and grits.
This place is unlike
any other.
Miss Shirley's affair
with Oscar.
It's always a treat.
WOMAN: People will stand in line
for literally an hour,
hour and a half, two hours.
It's something
that is worth the wait.
FIERI: It's something Eddie
would have been proud to see.
My father,
he's really smiling down.
That's 'cause
since he passed in 2013,
his son, David,
and daughter-in-law, Brandy,
have carried on what he started.
MAN: They put an enormous amount
of pride and love
into their food
and it becomes infectious.
Your coconut cream-stuffed
French toast.
This is definitely a dish
I spoil myself with.
It's two
large pieces of challah.
Stuffed with this amazing cream.
FIERI: Which is the creation
of Chef Bridget Bledsoe,
who's been heading up
this kitchen
since they opened in 2005.
Chicken waffle.
Eddie knew
she is big on talent.
Hey, but when I got here
she was a little short on voice.
So what are we
gonna make?
[ Hoarse voice ]
Coconut cream filling.
[ Chuckles ] That's easy
for you to say.
[ Chuckles ]
Not really, though.
We're gonna start off
with some cream cheese.
We're gonna add
mascarpone cheese.
Mascarpone? Okay.
Shredded coconut, coconut
extract, vanilla extract,
honey.
Darling.
Where's this going
to go?
We're gonna stuff it
in our challah bread.
Challah.
[ Chuckles ]
Now we close it up.
[ Stomps foot ]
[ Laughs ]
Alright,
let's cook it.
We're gonna go ahead
and dip it in our mix.
It's like a pool raft.
And then add a little bit
of butter.
Okay.
And that probably takes as long
as a prime rib does to cook.
It's gonna take
about 10 to 12 minutes
Finish it in the oven?
Yes.
Okay.
I cut this.
This is a raspberry puree.
Diced strawberries,
then we put our coconut on here.
More shredded coconut,
syrup, cinnamon,
powdered sugar,
mint, and bruleed bananas.
Okay.
So how do I eat it?
[ Laughs ]
Oh.
With a fork and a knife.
[ Chuckles ]
It's delicious.
It's not overly sweet.
I love the texture
of the coconut.
Great texture
on the outside of it
'cause you cooked it
a long time with the challah.
That's really great.
Awesome.
That's an
adult French toast.
Oh, I like that.
And the coconut cream-stuffed
French toast.
WOMAN: Oh, my gosh.
WOMAN 2: Each bite, you get the
texture of the coconut,
the sweetness with the crunch.
I have no problem giving it
a wow-wee.
And, uh --
Did she just drop
a "wow-ee"?
Wow-wee, it's amazing.
FIERI: Apparently, that's
something you might have heard
when Eddie was around.
One of his favorite
expressions was "wow-wee!"
And this is a wow-wee.
So this guy was the
life of the party.
Yeah.
WOMAN 3: Eddie was a big part
of Baltimore
and his legacy
still lives on here.
Your crab cake po' boy.
Where are we making
next?
A bacon, onion,
Tabasco jam.
Okay.
Olive oil, sweet onions,
chopped garlic,
Bacon?
Bacon.
There we go.
Next up?
Coffee.
I like where this
is going.
Apple cider vinegar.
Maple syrup.
A little hot sauce.
Brown sugar
and a little black pepper.
Okay. All this
is gonna cook down?
For 2 1/2 hours.
So now we're gonna
finally make the crab cake?
Yes. Mayo, eggs.
Mmm!
Worcestershire, Old Bay,
yellow mustard, kosher salt.
Mix this together.
Okay,
what's going on now?
Now you're getting
two pounds of crab meat.
Whoa!
Roasted red peppers, parsley,
crab cake mix.
Okay.
This is cracker meal.
So this is just enough effort
to combine it?
Yes, that's what
I call a crab cake.
I am in awe.
Now show me what the size of
a crab cake is around here.
Two ounce. Three of them
will go on the sandwich.
Okay.
Now we have our bacon jam.
Plenty of that on there.
Okay.
Old Bay remoulade.
I'll get this for you.
Old Bay.
Yeah.
A bit of lettuce,
red and yellow tomatoes.
Okay.
And then we have
our mini crab cakes.
Okay.
We're gonna garnish with
parsley and Old Bay.
♪♪
This is outrageous.
The way you composed
this sandwich is so next level,
You give me greatness.
Thank you.
I appreciate that.
Some of the best crab cakes
I've ever had.
I would order it
every chance I got.
I need those
strawberry waffles.
When you leave, you always have
a huge smile on your face.
So give it up for Eddie
and a little...
TOGETHER: Wow-wee!
[ Laughter ]
FIERI: Coming up...
We've just got dust,
cattle, and sadness.
You're about to make
a grown man cry.
I'm telling you what --
This is primetime, buddy.
Who's America's favorite diners,
drive-ins and dives?
We'll find out.
Don't go anywhere.
Guy,
I love you so much.
♪♪
WOMAN: [ Chuckles ]
So delicious.
FIERI: Here we go. More of
America's favorite videos.
I mean,
thousands of submissions.
And I gotta tell you
something outstanding.
Best "Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"
restaurant ever.
Alright. Paradise Valley
Burger Company. Roll it.
There ain't nothing that I like
more than a burger
from Paradise Valley
Burger Company.
See, out here on the range,
we don't get any of those fancy
sit-down restaurants.
We've just got dust,
cattle, and sadness.
But Paradise
Valley Burger Company
makes me happy.
And when I come home,
take my boots off,
throw my hat down -- You know.
Is this the
"Wild, Wild West"?
I'm ready for
a Paradise Valley Burger.
[ Chuckling ]
Gotta love that brûlée
Sometimes I just dream
about it out on the prairie.
[ Hooves thumping ]
[ Laughs ]
Riding the trails.
Paradise Valley
Burger Company...
for president.
It's like --
Where is he?
I don't know.
but it's like part Yellowstone,
part Clint Eastwood.
Yeah.
He spoke so quietly,
but with so much authority,
I was hinging on every word
that he said.
And I love Paradise
Valley Burger.
I'm ready for
a Paradise Valley Burger.
[ Register dings ]
[ Tape rewinds ]
♪♪
MAN: If you love burgers,
this is the place to come,
not just in the state
of Arizona, but all over.
The Beach House Burger.
MAN 2: The creativity
and craftsmanship
that goes into
making their burgers,
I couldn't even duplicate
if my life depended on it.
FIERI:
And they're all the brainchild
of chef and owner,
Bret Shapiro,
who opened this joint
in 2011.
A good burger should?
When you'd be like,
"Blaow!"
That's what a good
burger does?
That what a
good burger --
It should speak
to you.
And speaking of burgers...
Country fried burger
for you.
The Country Fried Burger
is another one of my favorites.
MAN 2:
Green chili bacon cream sauce
on top of deep-fried patties.
That's America right there.
What's gonna be in
the Country Fried Burger?
We're gonna start off with
the country-fried gravy.
We're gonna add some
olive oil, diced red onion,
sliced jalapeños,
sliced garlic,
generous on
the salt and pepper.
Shake up the pan a little bit.
Get them nice and tender.
Would you like a towel?
Monster hands.
Been doin' this
since I was 15 years old.
Rahhh!
There you go.
Okay, so the gravy is going.
Gonna hit it
with our heavy cream now.
Now this is going
to simmer down.
Simmer down now.
Cook it for about
15, 20 minutes.
That's gonna reduce it by half.
Add our fresh thyme.
Now we hit it
with the immersion blender.
And then that's gonna go
on top of the burger.
Tan it, tan it,
tan it.
What is the suntan lotion
you're spraying on it?
A little bit
of heavy cream.
Heavy cream in a
mister bottle?
Exactly.
Flour, flour, flour.
Patties going in.
Byuuu!
Ohh, that's how it goes?
That's how we roll, man.
We gotta get crazy back here.
Dude, you got issues
and I like it.
Next up, a little bit of lettuce
to protect the brioche.
Gonna add our country-fried
burger patties.
Double patty up.
I like this.
Now we're going
to add our gravy.
A little bit of fresh thyme
End of your timer.
♪ No time ♪
Tomatoes.
Fried onions.
♪♪
And that's all she wrote
for the Country Fried Burger.
You got beach towels?
[ Chuckles ] Beach towel?
Of course, my man.
It's legit,
it's enthusiastic,
it takes the regular everyday
burger to another level.
I mean, it really is, man.
It's great.
Awesome, dude,
I appreciate that.
MAN 4: It's very filling.
It actually leaves
wanting more, though.
It's so delicious.
[ Chuckles ]
I'm married to a chef and even
she'll admit
that she can't cook burgers
nearly as well as
Paradise Valley Burger Company.
Your burger
interpretive dance --
What would it look like?
Start with a nose plug.
Work its way down.
That's where it's at.
[ Chuckles ]
Slowly switch.
And...
Line dance.
There we go.
You've seen it
a million times.
He's putting it
all together right here.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
One minute till
burgers are done.
Sometimes you see something
that's just like, wow,
I never would have imagined
that in the burger.
Got a Booze Burger and 'slaw.
So what
are we making?
Green chili, bacon, vodka cream
sauce for the Booze Burger.
Green chili, bacon,
vodka cream sauce.
Okay, get into it.
Alright.
First you want to start
with a little bit of olive oil.
Render it on the bacon.
Cook it like it's --
[ Crowd responds, "HOT!" ]
That's also a good
Gonna drop in
our sliced red onion.
Okay.
Jalapeños? This is like
an Arizona breath mint.
More or less, man.
Okay.
Get our garlic going.
[ Whistles ]
Once those
have sweated down,
we're gonna add some vodka
to it.
We're gonna add
our heavy cream.
You get some sound effects.
[ Imitating glugging ]
Blo-oo-oop.
Bloo-oop.
Nice.
Salt and pepper.
They're brothers.
They're best friends.
So you roasted the peppers,
seeded, stemmed them,
skinned them.
Exactly right.
Okay, and now
a bunch of cilantro.
Blend it.
Next up,
we cook this burger.
Yes, sir.
Okay.
Salt and pepper. Now we're going
to beer batter our patties,
and then drop in the deep fryer
for about 2 1/2 minutes.
Okay.
Let's get our
beer-battered patties.
[ Whistles ]
Add our green chili, bacon,
vodka cream sauce.
And finally, our
pickled Fresno chilies.
♪♪
Hands down, what makes that
burger was Fresno chilies.
I agree, man.
You got all kinds
of great crunch, salt,
little spice coming in there.
You've got a passion for it
and it comes out
in the burger, man.
You're about to make
a grown cry.
I'm telling you what,
this is primetime, buddy.
The Booze Burger
is such a perfect combination.
It's magic.
[ Tape rewinds ]
FIERI: Up next...
Oh, no, he's doing it.
It all started 10 years ago
when my dad was watching
your show.
My favorite restaurant to go
and visit.
Like a speed bump
in Flavortown
Right now on "Triple-D."
♪♪
It is amazing.
Amazing.
Absolutely amazing.
Welcome back.
Hunter and I are here.
We've been watching fantastic
submissions from "Triple-D" fans
that are voting for their
favorite "Triple-D" restaurant
to be America's favorite.
Hello.
Next up, we have Metro Diner,
Jacksonville, Florida.
Roll 'em.
It all started 10 years ago
when my dad
was watching your show.
He said, "Guy found a place
that looks really great.
It's local.
I think we should go."
So one morning, we went
to the one Metro Diner
and got in the freaking
long liner.
When we finally got seated
outside in Florida,
it was heated,
but we saw Yohola go by
and hoped it would be finer.
Indeed, we were not
disappointed.
The flavors made us feel
disjointed.
Cream cheese banana-stuffed
French Toast,
cinnaroll pancakes at the most.
This chef must have been
God's anointed.
The eggs are gigantic.
The bacon just right.
The home fries are such that
I dream of at night.
Can we talk about
those waffles and chicken,
spicy syrup,
and strawberry butter?
My arteries happily thicken
with a mug
of snickerdoodle coffee
to follow each bite.
If it weren't for you
and your show, Guy,
would we have continued
to go by?
Metro Diner's
everywhere now.
As a Jacksonvillian,
it makes me proud.
And it's because of
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"
Nice. That was good.
Awww. Well done.
That was really cool.
Well done.
I didn't know what we were
getting when she started.
Indeed, we were not
disappointed.
The flavors made us
feel disjointed.
Excellent job.
DAVOLI:
Pancakes, banana, granola.
This is phenomenal food.
They cook everything fresh
daily.
Stuffed portabello sandwich up.
On our first time here, we
looked at each other and said,
"This should be
on Guy's show."
So you wrote in and told me
to come here.
I did.
I wrote in because
I bring people here
every time they come into town.
The food is awesome.
Anything you order.
Pittsburgh steak salad up.
It's absolutely
amazing.
Real good food. He actually
cooks everything fresh.
Pastrami sandwich up.
Runner, please.
It's just a really
great diner.
There you go.
You guys enjoy.
DAVOLI: When I walked in here
the first time,
I just fell
in love with the place.
FIERI:
Sous Chef Mark Davoli...
Two eggs and grits.
FIERI:
...bought the joint
I need a runner,
please.
Then talked his dad, John...
Okay,
here we go, fellas.
...A corporate restaurant vet,
into joining him.
How is it?
He handles promo.
He's the ambassador?
DAVOLI: Yep, yep.
You manage the kitchen?
I do the kitchen, yeah.
Metro Melt, medium.
It's home cooking.
Meat loaf, up.
The meat loaf
is unbelievable here.
Now, is meat loaf a staple
on the menu?
It's definitely a staple.
Okay,
so you get it going.
Alright.
We'll start with the carrots.
We're gonna blend them.
This will break it down
to the size
that it can be cooked
all the way through,
but not being a big,
intrusive chunk.
Yeah. Yeah.
Intrusive chunk.
Okay.
[ Chuckles ]
Without a doubt.
That's a term
you use often.
[ Chuckles ] Yeah.
You know what? Come on down for
our meat loaf here at Metro.
No intrusive chunks.
Celery.
We're gonna blend them.
Alright.
get those to the
optimum size.
Yep. The mushrooms.
Mushrooms,
very gingerly done.
Just mushrooms, not ginger,
but you know what I meant.
Now you do the onions.
Yeah. Yeah,
we're gonna blend them.
Alright. So this is all ready
to go with this nice veggie mix
and this brand new bowl.
That's been here all 20 years,
at least. I wouldn't --
Yes, it --
[ Chuckles ]
[ Laughs ]
Yeah. Yep,
it's carbon dated A.D..
Alright. Now we got some, uh,
the meat trio.
Yeah. Ground beef.
Pork?
Add pork.
Have to.
Then ground turkey.
That's a way to
get healthy with it.
Mmm-hmm.
Okay, so you incorporate
all the meats?
Yeah.
Ready?
There you go.
Beautiful.
Oh, I like
the veggie content.
Uh-huh.
Okay, so what are we got
for seasonings?
Pepper, salt,
and Worcestershire.
I was gonna say there's got
to be some Worcestershire.
Anything else incorporated?
What about a binder?
Yeah, a little bit
of egg.
Okay. Breadcrumbs?
Yeah, breadcrumbs.
I think I like this.
Yeah.
So you form up the logs.
Yep.
Three out on a tray.
Bake it off at 350?
Yep.
For?
40 minutes.
Bring it out.
Let it cool. Look at that.
Like a speed bump
in Flavortown.
[ Chuckles ]
So two big slices.
Over to the flat top.
Yep.
Put a little
margarine down.
The meat loaf on.
About two, three minutes
each side.
This is the art
of crustification.
Uh-huh.
And then what
do we serve it with?
Mashed potatoes,
zucchini and squash,
and a little
French baguette.
Things you would just
expect in a diner.
[ Chuckles ]
That's a big portion.
Yeah.
Mmmm. I think diners
across the world
have to take a lesson
on this one.
Tender, juicy,
good exterior crust. Mm!
But it's the crustification,
the adding that extra layer,
all that little crunch
on the side.
The meat loaf plate?
It was really good. The spices
and the gravy on top.
MAN: It's very savory
and very moist.
It melts in your mouth.
Fill your stomach meal.
The breakfasts here
are just so wonderful.
Pancake up.
Oh, my gosh. The pancakes are
amazing. [ Laughs ]
San Francisco eggs Benedict.
breakfast pie
with hash browns up.
Yohola.
Stuffed French toast. We call it
the Yohola on the Square.
Why do you hold your hands
like this
when you tell me
about it?
It's about as big
as your head.
Okay.
A little bit of a margarine.
We take bananas,
throw them in the pot,
add a little brown sugar.
[ Chuckles ] Okay.
A little stir.
Hit it with a little
Frangelico.
Nice.
Yeah, you've activated
the bananas.
Then we're gonna take
our cream cheese.
we're gonna fold the banana
mixture into the cream cheese.
Okay, what's next
in this 'Hola?
We're gonna make a blueberry
strawberry compote.
Blueberries.
Okay.
Little bit of water.
Now goes in
the brown sugar.
So the slurry
goes in?
Yep.
Cold cornstarch slurry
just to tighten that up.
Then I put the
strawberries in last.
If you put the strawberries in
too early, they break up.
Strawberries go in.
Let that cook down,
kind of till it all breaks,
thickens up.
Yeah.
and that's gonna go on
top of the --
Holy challah. Wow.
You know, traditional challah's
normally a little flatter,
but I had to get my baker
to change it up a little bit.
It's like the dancing tooth
from Saturday morning cartoons.
[ Laughs]
We're gonna take our
bananas mixture.
This is ridiculous.
Yeah.
What are you
gonna do with that now?
Now we're gonna dump it
in our egg wash,
which is egg, cinnamon,
nutmeg, vanilla, sugar, cream.
Margarine.
Necessary, of course.
We're just going
to grill up all --
All the sides.
Yeah.
Toast is done.
Here you are.
That's nice.
And we're topped with
a blueberry strawberry compote.
That, dude,
is out of control.
You've gotta just
kind of dive in.
Oh, dude.
That's more French toast than
I've eaten in the last 10 years.
[ Chuckles ]
One bite.
Dude, that is worth
coming here for, no question.
Yohola.
The sweetness and
the freshness of the blueberries
and the challah,
it's just delicious.
How much of the challah
can you enjoy?
Maybe a quarter.
Can you take the
challah home?
Oh, I take the
challah home.
If it's half a challah,
do you help challah half a
challah home?
I help challah half
a challah home
with my cat.
[ Laughs ]
Did you just pinch me
on the arm?
No, no, I was just giving you
a rouse. I love you.
That's so funny, 'cause the
pinch under the arm
is one of my favorite
games to play.
But I used to pinch you under
the arm when you're a little boy
and you'd cry and your mom would
come and go,
"You gotta quit."
[ Chuckles ]