So when I come off the road
from doing Triple D,
the first thing I want to do
is get home to my kitchen
and cook my food
for my family.
-And after a few weeks,
they're gonna be--
-Hey, Dad, can we just...
I mean, please,
go to a restaurant
at least one time?
They start to revolt.
So I came up with an idea.
How about we reach out
to some of our favorite chefs
and have them
send us dinner, huh?
I like that idea.
[Guy] And I know
some Triple D joints
that would love
to send it to us.
We've got monster ribs
coming from John Mull Meats
in Las Vegas.
This is how you do
barbecue right here.
[Guy]
A hamburger waffle mash up
from Buttermilk,
out of Atlanta.
It's like
a full parade in Flavortown.
Dynamite wings
and prime time pie
from Dough Pizzeria
in San Antonio.
Man, that's good.
And a fully loaded burger
from Hodad's,
carrying on
a San Diego OG legacy.
Dynamite. I mean, legit.
And on top of it all,
they're going
to video conference in
to give us the true
Triple D experience.
This is
Triple D Takeout.
And there's a few more
in the trunk.
Of course there is.
Well, there's a cast
of characters.
-What's up?
-We have OG,
we have new G,
we have Triple D,
and we have Triple D Nation
all in the same house.
How's everybody feeling?
-Great.
-Delightful.
-Whoo!
-Fantastic.
Down there in the bottom,
that's our buddy Shane Hardin,
son of the great
Bossman from Hodad's.
Even before
his pops passed away,
we talked about
how he was going
to take over the company.
So he was bred
to make milkshakes?
Actually, he was born
with a greasy spoon
in his mouth.
Shane, how old were you
when we first met you?
That was 2007,
so that was 40 years ago.
I was 16.
And I'm,
uh, 68 now, so...
[Guy] Sixty-eight.
And time flies.
You look great.
[Guy] Doug, were you next?
Were you 2011?
-Yep.
-Is it "Dough"?
'Cause I can't see
any logos.
You know, shameless.
[Guy] Doug is your name.
-Your last name is...
-Horn.
Oh, no.
His name is Dough
-with an "H".
-Right.
Let's go over to my buddy
Chuck in Las Vegas,
John Mull's Meats.
-What year were you
for Triple D?
-2012.
Is that a Diners, Drive-ins
and Dives' shirt and bandana?
How you like that, man?
It says, "Welcome to fabulous
Las Vegas" on the backside.
Road Kill Grill.
Road Kill Grill, baby.
All right, well,
let's talk to the newbie
but not so much a newbie,
because Buttermilk was,
like, five, six years ago.
Suzanne from Atlanta.
I love the T-shirt
in the back, by the way.
I had to share my love.
The reason
that we invited you back is
residents of Flavortown
love you.
And we were getting
a little hungry.
So, we started calling
our favorite Triple D joints
and saying,
"Hey, send us
something hot on the menu
that you're doing,"
and we do the final steps
in preparing the dish.
This is an opportunity
for people to learn
how they can get you
to ship this food to them.
It gives them a chance
to have the Triple D
experience.
By the way,
just to remind you all,
at the end of this,
someone will get the award
of best dish.
So let's start with the OG,
Shane and Hodad's.
Have we done
the restoration yet
on your dad's
little mini microbus?
-If we took a quarter
from every burger...
-[Shane] Yes.
-...we could have this
done in what?
-We need your money.
-Donate now
for just pennies a day.
-For just pennies.
We have not done
the bus yet.
We've been focusing
on the brewery.
Is there Hodad's beer?
-Yeah.
-Is that what's in here?
Uh, no.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Time out.
Did you really
not send us any beer?
Dude, no,
because we're canning
later this month.
Sounds like an excuse.
Wait,
where are you going?
Shane, you killed our show.
I guess
let's just do it
without him.
Just because
of the other three, Shane,
I'm coming back.
"Follow your heart,
and anything is possible.
I believe in you."
Is that
your high school picture?
It is.
I do believe in you.
-What is wrong with him?
-Enough of the shenanigans.
What are we making?
This burger was made up
by my dad and Panini Pete,
another Triple D alumni.
They were in a group
called Messlords.
They have traveled the world
taking care of our troops,
and cooking for them,
and cooking with them.
So they were on
the USS Enterprise.
And they're
taking ingredients,
and figuring out
what they're going to make.
[Shane] So this one's called
the angry Hawaiian.
We take a bacon cheese,
sub out the American
for Provolone,
and then, on top,
we do pineapples,
jalapenos
and some barbecue sauce.
[Guy] So, I know this,
the boiled bacon of Hodad's.
-What is this?
-It's bacon.
[Guy]
It's like bacon soup.
And then he would make
these patties out of it.
Turn it over.
It looks almost
like hash browns.
Do you guys
have a press for that?
Of course I do.
Look at that.
[Guy] What you want
done with the buns?
Toast 'em.
Did you throw down
those beef patties yet?
I took this bacon,
and I started 'em
in this cast iron
to season it
before I dropped
those patties.
[Shane]
Little flavor saver.
Everything tastes better
when it's cooked
in a little bit
of bacon residue.
[Guy] And season these with?
[Shane] Some season salt.
Throw that cheese on there.
And one per bacon.
Oh, and hit the bacon.
Tomato on the bottom bun,
and then the lettuce snowball
on top.
Boy, if that's not
a Mike Harden 101.
We call this
the lettuce snowball.
Bada-bing.
So you have
the pineapple, the jalapeno
and the barbecue sauce.
-We got 'em right here.
-Mix them up.
Now, that's looking good.
Yeah, I'm getting hungry,
honestly.
Bacon patty
on top of the beef patty.
It goes
to the top of the lettuce.
Fit as much of that
pineapple jalapeno
barbecue sauce.
Without falling off?
Look at that.
Do you have the burger diaper?
Do you have the wax paper?
-Where are they?
-They should be in the box.
-I didn't see any.
-Right next to the beer.
[all laughing]
No burger diaper.
You're on your own, man.
Look at this thing.
Wow.
I'm jealous.
That's all I can say.
That's, like, so unfair.
That looks amazing.
You go from that sweet
barbecue and pineapple
to just that
bacon and burger.
[Guy] You know
who we got to call?
Say hi to Panini Pete,
everybody.
Hey, Panini.
So we're having this thing
called an angry Hawaiian.
Do you remember
making this burger?
That is a legit burger, bro.
This bacon patty
always prevails.
Then you get the Hodad burger,
which is cooked
on that flat-top,
simply seasoned.
But that juxtaposition
that you get
with the pineapple
and that pickled jalapeno
chopped up on there,
I got to tell you, man,
I can't believe they let you
walk off the ship
if you were making this.
Say goodbye.
-Bye.
-Bye, Pete.
All right.
Hey, dynamite.
I mean, legit.
Is there any left?
[Guy] "Is there any left?"
When we go to commercial,
that's what Hunter and I
are going to be eating.
Listen, don't go
anywhere, folks.
Hanging out the back yard.
Triple D Takeout.
And we'll see you
in a little bit.
All right, Rochambeau
for this last one.
We got two of them.
-Oh, that's good.
-Yeah.
Welcome back,
everybody.
Hunter and I are hanging out
in the backyard
with some of our favorite
Triple D characters.
We just had
Shane from Hodad's.
Burger was outstanding, man.
What do you call it,
the angry Hawaiian?
The angry Hawaiian.
All right, well,
let's talk about somebody
who's not angry.
Always got a smile
on her face,
makes fantastic food
all the way down in Atlanta,
in Hotlanta,
Buttermilk Kitchen.
Suzanne,
what have you been up to?
We're shipping
all over the country now.
Wrote a cookbook.
A cookbook?
Did you see it?
-I didn't see it.
-Oh.
Maybe you need
to open the box, Guy.
[laughs] All right.
We were there in 2015.
Whoa!
We had chicken and biscuits,
and we had a blast.
Are we just pinching them off
on the side like this?
Absolutely. We sell
about 1,200 biscuits a week.
This is 12 of the 1,200?
I'm already
gonna be asking for time off.
Oh, you did send
the cookbook.
Hey, I signed it, too.
"To my frosted-tip homie."
Somebody sent a press.
-I'm impressed.
-Hey, there it is.
Capital "T" tasty.
And that is money.
Oh, look,
I'll put it in front
of this little kid's picture.
That's fine.
[Guy] What is
the game plan here?
So we're making
the Ray's waffle burger.
Ray is my father.
Unfortunately, we lost him
a couple of years ago.
He used to love
bacon with waffles.
Ran out of bacon one day,
and he had a hamburger,
put it on top
of his waffle,
and that was
his favorite breakfast.
-I like this guy.
-That's awesome.
You're going to start
making the burger patties.
Are you just going to snack
on that cheese the whole time?
Why did you send
so much cheese?
[Suzanne]
Because last time
I was on Triple D,
you closed the cheese aisle.
You, like, wanted me
to make a grilled cheese.
Oh, there was no cheese?
Suzanne took a pizza
and put in the microwave?
[man]
She's getting cheese off it.
[woman] Oh, that's smart.
[Suzanne] It was
a real easy competition.
Thanks a lot.
Ah, it's funny.
Let's start making
the burger first.
Half sausage, half beef.
You want two patties.
We're gonna stuff it
with cheese,
if you have cheese left.
What kind
of cheese is that?
It's, uh,
a pepper Jack cheese.
It's delicious.
[Suzanne] Guy, if you want
to start cooking off
-some of the bacon.
-[Guy] Okay.
[Suzanne] So, Hunter,
just do, like, an ounce
and, kind of,
ball it in your hand,
and then
you're gonna want to put it
in the center
of one of the patties
and put
the other patty on top.
Crump up all the creases,
so the cheese
doesn't escape.
And then,
you guys should have
some coffee rub.
[Guy] What's in it?
[Suzanne] Coffee,
chili powder, paprika,
kosher salt
and raw sugar.
You want a liberal
seasoning on this?
Yeah, make love to it.
Oh.
[Suzanne] And then
if you have some of that
bacon fat rendered off,
you can use that
as your grease
for the burger.
Oh, yeah,
that looks good.
Now, let's talk
about this waffle.
Okay. All right.
Quit waffling.
All right, Suzanne?
[Suzanne]
So, crack your eggs.
Hard boiled?
They come out hard boiled,
it's so hot in Atlanta.
[Suzanne] Grab the wet mix.
-Buttermilk, regular milk.
-Sour cream and eggs.
And then,
you're gonna take
the dry mix package.
What do we have
in the waffle mix?
[Suzanne] Flour, sugar,
baking powder,
a little bit of salt.
And then, you've got
a waffle maker over there.
You want about
a cup of batter.
Boy, I love how this activates
right off the bat
with the buttermilk,
and the baking soda
in there.
It's already nice
and puffed up.
[Suzanne]
And then, we're going
to make the maple aioli.
There's so many things
we're supposed to be doing
around here.
Make this, do that.
Go here.
-Mayo for aioli.
-Maple syrup.
[Suzanne] How does
the waffle look, Guy?
[Guy]
I think I might have given it
a little bit more than a cup.
-Nothing wrong with that.
-What else is going there?
Worcestershire?
[Suzanne]
Cider vinegar, pinch of salt
and some dry mustard.
[Guy] It's a pretty
interesting concoction.
I like that.
It's not too breakfast-y.
All maple.
It's a little more mature.
A little lunch
with the fat of the mayo.
And we make our own mayo
in house, too.
Well done.
How's that waffle looking?
Is it good?
It's light, it's airy.
But it's got a great crust
on the outside.
But it's not sweet.
It's not too sweet. Good.
I'm sorry. Was I supposed
to cut these into portions?
I was about to say,
"What are you doing?"
You want to make that waffle
to be the same size
as your burger.
And then slather both sides
with that maple aioli.
Put the burger
down on the bottom.
Take that bacon,
put the other piece
of waffle on top,
and that's
your Ray's burger.
I want that.
I'm not gonna lie.
I didn't know what to expect
out of that.
That pork in there
is really nice, actually,
the pork and the cheese.
If there was ever a sandwich
that I was gonna call
a brunch sandwich.
Not too sweet,
where it's right in the
beginning of breakfast.
Not so burger-y
that it forgot
where it came from.
Little of that breakfast fat
that you love with the bacon.
Delicious patty.
Cutting it with the pork
in there is genius,
and I think stuffing it
with the cheese makes it...
I love what you did
in paying homage to your pop.
He's got to be
so proud of you
and all that
you've accomplished.
-Well done, Suzanne.
-Thank you.
We gotta
slow things down, folks.
We're gonna take
a little brief break,
maybe lay down,
maybe do some yoga,
clean the kitchen.
We come back,
Triple D Takeout.
We'll see you in a bit.
I'm gonna eat...
-I'm gonna have this.
-Okay.
Dad,
I think we're rolling.
Oh, we are rolling.
Hi, everybody.
Welcome back.
My name's Guy.
I'm in a food coma.
What's your name?
-Who?
-Yeah.
We're doing
Triple D Takeout,
and we got first attacked
by Shane from Hodad's,
in San Diego,
with the ridiculous
angry Hawaiian burger.
And then Suzanne,
from Atlanta,
with Buttermilk Kitchen
with a brunchy burger
named after her dad,
done with a waffle.
Hopefully, the next two
are something like a parfait
and a sorbet.
-Yeah, a small salad
or something.
-A salad would be great.
Not a chance.
That's our buddy Doug
from Dough.
Doug, be nice.
You're going to have
to power through.
Oh, he sent us
a pizza oven.
There you go.
That's how we ended up
seeing you the first time.
I'm a big fan of great ovens.
[man]
That thing is rocking hot.
Mmm.
Too bad
you didn't want any.
Prosciutto nub. Holy!
A whole prosciutto.
You've got to see
where the nub comes from.
-You're going to--
-I appreciate it,
because I was wondering,
"Where would one
get the nub?"
[Guy]
This is expensive stuff.
[Doug]
It is. It's dear.
It's actually pork.
But that's delicious.
You know,
if you're going to make pizza,
you need a pizza hat.
-Hey, I'm making a pizza.
-That's good.
And we go cycling.
It's so tight
on my fat head.
-[Hunter] That is awesome.
-Wow.
Can you walk me through
what we're making?
We're going to start with
the Calabrian diavola wings.
Let's get a cast iron pan
with a little bit of oil
in the oven.
These wings
have been brined.
What did you
brine them in, Chef?
Salt, sugar, bay leaf?
You have honey, aromatics
for about four hours.
Then we marinate them
in Calabrian wing sauce
for 24 hours.
What's in it?
[Doug] Olive oil, onions,
minced garlic,
the Calabrian chilies,
rosemary,
salt and pepper.
So, are you actually
parboiling those
ahead of time or what?
I roast them
till they get cooked through.
I love it.
Hunter, grab that pan.
[Doug]
Right back into the oven.
So you want to get
some nice color on that.
Well, that works.
I see that
you sent us something
for a pizza.
Talk to me about the sugo
that's going on it.
[Doug] We go through
a lot of hams.
And we ended up
with all these nubs left over
that you can
no longer slice.
We cook 'em
until you can pull
the meat apart.
And they'll take
that pulled prosciutto,
put it in the sugo.
It picks up great flavor.
So, you sent me some
braised prosciutto butt.
Yes. You can make
this sugo really easy.
Oil in the pan.
Put your mirepoix in there,
little salt and tomato paste.
-[Guy] Got it.
-Hunter, did you give
those wings a turn?
Yeah,
he gave them a turn.
[Doug] Put that wine
in there now,
and I think you're ready
for the wings.
Rosemary
and the chopped
Calabrian chilies.
The garlic goes right in.
This smells
so good right here.
Hunter, back in the oven
to finish those wings off.
All right, Chef,
I've cooked out
all my veggies,
my wine's reduced.
-What's the next step?
-[Doug] Italian plum tomatoes.
[Guy] Dried thyme.
Sugar now, Chef?
[Doug] Yep.
[Guy] Pepper.
[Doug] Yeah.
[Guy] Couple bay leaves.
Chili flake,
a little dried oregano.
It's coming to a boil now.
All right, let's go in
with that pulled prosciutto.
It's like a full parade
in Flavortown.
[chuckling]
Full parade.
[Doug] Only last bit
is the Doughanzola
dipping sauce.
[Guy] Calabrian chili as well?
[Doug] Yes.
Those wings
are ready to roll.
Coming over, Dad.
Those look
out of bounds, man.
[Guy] Gorgeous.
-Show 'em up. Yeah.
-There you go.
Yeah.
I don't know anybody
watching at home to think
"Well, I don't have
a wood-fired oven.
I can't do it."
You can.
You've just got
to crank that oven,
get that cast iron
in there.
I love the fact
that you've got
the brine on it,
the roast on it.
Super tender.
I want to be buried
in a gallon of this.
Oh, that's the sauce.
-Doughanzola.
-Doughanzola. Very clever.
[Guy] The little kiss
of the rosemary.
And then,
the Calabrian chilies,
they add that
nice little bit of heat,
and not overpowering.
Ah. Man, that's good!
All right, walk me through
what we're doing
for this pizza.
[Doug] You're gonna
form your dough.
[Guy] Got it.
Sugo down, put a little spiral
of your extra virgin
olive oil,
then the Fontina cheese.
Where's the sausage
coming from?
[Doug]
We make it in house.
What mushrooms
do we have here?
[Doug]
Shitakes, portobellos,
creminis,
roasted peppers.
And then, you're going
to grate some cheese
and go in the oven.
-Launch it.
-Whoo. That was close.
Good job,
you guys.
[Guy] That's going to cook
for 90 seconds.
Take a look at that.
Nice.
I'm dying
over here right now.
I know. I'm so hungry.
That crust,
really nice and light,
but very chewsome.
It's got a good chew.
And it takes a little char
on the bottom.
It can handle
the high heat.
To get a pizza
and wing combo like this
at the higher level
of culinary expertise
is what people want.
Now, that's what
people can get.
A little
Triple D Takeout, baby.
Listen, folks,
we're at first and goal
and there's minutes left.
But don't worry.
Our good buddy Chuck
from John Mull's Meats
in Las Vegas
is going to come through
at the end
and deliver a salad.
Try it again, man.
-I hope so.
-We'll see you in a bit.
It's gonna be a great salad.
Little salad, petite.
Welcome back, everybody.
We are in the final quarter.
-Yes.
-We're at fourth and goal.
We had great burgers,
we've had great waffles,
-we've had great wings,
we've had great pizza.
-[Hunter] Mmm-hmm.
But our buddy Chuck,
down in Las Vegas,
where Hunter and I
both went to school.
A barbecue machine
at John Mull Meats
Road Kill Grill.
So your grandfather opens
this place in the '40s.
Then your dad had it,
then your uncle had it,
and then you got it in '81.
It started out butchering,
and it turned into everything.
[man]
Would you like some ribs?
How about some chicken?
Little brisket?
You need to get
the hot leg.
[Guy] All right,
let's see what we've got.
Oh, you did send
the bandanas.
Yes, dude.
That's so awesome.
It's kind of what you did
when you were over here
the first time, when you shot.
Worcestershire sauce solids.
[coughing]
We don't even have to cook.
We can just put on
all the cool gear
and say, "Good night."
Now, that's just
awesome, brother.
Let's talk about
what we're getting into.
[Chuck] We're gonna make
a brontosaurus beef rib,
which required
about 16 hours of marinade.
Our marinade
has kosher salt,
hydrolyzed vegetable protein,
garlic powder, onion powder,
mustard flour,
celery salt,
cayenne pepper.
Our secret ingredient.
This is a Certified Angus.
When you inject it,
it makes it much more tender.
After it's marinated,
we're gonna go ahead
and rub it.
Kosher salt, brown sugar,
white sugar,
coarse black pepper,
granulated garlic,
granulated onion.
Our secret ingredient,
turmeric, seasoning blend,
chili powder and paprika.
And 16 hours of smoking.
Holy.
Yeah, that's nice, huh?
[Hunter] That's large.
[Chuck] We've actually
got those in boiling bags.
You just want
to bring 'em to a boil.
-Really?
-[Chuck] Bring it
up to temp.
What are we doing next?
[Chuck] Collard greens.
So put a little olive oil
in the pan,
and saute
that chopped onion.
-Turkey.
-[Chuck] Just cover it
with water
and bring it to a boil.
No, with no onions.
No onions.
A separate stockpot.
Come on!
You're not putting it
in there?
Isn't it all gonna
party together eventually?
Heck yeah, man.
We just don't want any bones
in those collard greens, man.
All right, so the garlic in
with the sweated onions.
[Chuck] Put your
collard greens in that pot.
[Guy] Let them sweat
and pull out
their own moisture.
[Chuck] Correct.
[Guy] Warming this rib up.
-Love this technique.
-Mmm-hmm.
To be able to get this
big, old, authentic
smoked meat.
You got that Chuck flap
in the water, too?
-You want that in?
-[Chuck] Yeah.
Hey, hold on.
We have Mario
from Four Kegs, man,
with my Stromboli.
[Guy] When we
first started Triple D, one
of the producers asked me,
"So, you have any places
you really like
that are, like,
like Triple D joints?"
And I said, "Huh."
College kid favorite,
that's where we met
our brother Mario.
I want
the Stromboli recipe.
We'll give you 80%.
Did we have the Stromboli
delivered to us?
-I don't think we did.
-Well, we love you, brother.
Thanks, brother.
Be good. Peace out.
What else are we putting
in these collard greens?
[Chuck] Take that turkey stock
and add that to it.
Collard green ninja dust.
Go ahead, put it in.
Crushed red pepper, yeah.
When do you want to drop
this turkey meat in?
Go ahead
and add it right now.
[Guy] Smells so good.
Somebody's
getting this at home.
You send the greens
where they're already done,
set, ready to go?
[Chuck] Yeah, and that's
actually a boiling bag
right there also.
[Guy] Walk me through
these green beans
you sent me.
We basically make them
the same way
as the collard greens.
Add some russet potatoes,
red onions.
Now, what do you want us
to do with this rib?
[Chuck] Just plate it up
on that flat plate.
-Oh, my gosh.
-[Chuck] Cut that Chuck flap.
Man, look at
that knifework.
Comes with two sides.
Oh, great.
Come on down.
Feed the family of ten.
Can I put
the barbecue sauce on now?
-Hit it now. Hit it.
-[Hunter] Oh, yeah.
I can smell it
from here in San Antonio.
You're definitely
being tortured.
[Chuck]
Hey, you should garnish
with the onions first, man.
That kicks it off.
There's not enough
beef rib in my life.
And beef rib
is so much different
than any other part
of the animal.
-So tender.
-[Guy] The smoke on it
is beautiful.
-What kind of wood?
-Pecan and hickory.
It's got good fat.
Half inch of smoke ring on it.
This is how you do
barbecue right here.
The collards,
they're tender.
Not too salty.
Little bit
of that turkey in there.
And that is about
as old school
Southern a green bean
as you get, man.
Outstanding.
Well, here's the deal,
folks.
And I want
to say thank you.
You've all been fantastic.
The dishes are super creative.
Unfortunately, we get
to this tough part
of the show
where we have to pick
a best dish.
Let me go talk to Hunter.
Hold tight, please.
I don't know. Those wings
looked pretty good.
Yeah, you guys killed this.
Well, folks,
not an easy decision.
What's the line,
Hunter, we usually say?
-Winner, winner,
chicken dinner?
-Right.
But today,
it's got to go
winner, winner,
big beef rib dinner.
Give it up
for our buddy Chuck.
Congratulations.
Listen, here's the great thing
for all you fans of Triple D.
These chefs want to send you
these outrageous dishes.
Go to their websites.
You guys are awesome.
-Adios.
-[Hunter] You guys killed it.
Thanks, Guy.
-Mine's adios, yours is?
-Um...
-Hasta luego!
-Great job, you guys.
-That is awesome.
-Hey, who needs
a face lift?
[Guy]
Wow. Best day ever.