I'm Guy Fieri
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's
greatest diners,
drive-ins and dives.
This trip...
[laughing]
...we got sandwiches...
What a monster.
...spice...
Goodbye, Guy.
...and everything nice.
Well, you got my attention.
...like handheld
flavor bombs in Sioux Falls...
That sandwich right there
will blow your doors off.
...wild Alaskan pizza
in Fairbanks.
This is where
things go off the rails
right here, folks.
And in Fargo, North Dakota...
Food coma comin'.
...a culinary oasis
straight out of India.
I have taken 16 bites.
I am off the rails.
I have to go back
to my Triple D meeting.
That's all right here,
right now on Triple D.
[theme music playing]
You know, most restaurants
have a variety of items
on their menu.
Let's see, if you're
a Mexican restaurant,
you'll have tacos,
and tortas, and burritos.
If you're Italian restaurant,
you'd have pasta and pizza
and chicken dishes.
But when you're a restaurant
and you serve one type of item
on your menu,
you better nail it.
I'm here in Sioux Falls,
South Dakota,
where I hear these dudes
are nailing it
with sandwiches.
This is Bread & Circus.
Got a gyro
and a schnitzel for table 12.
Bread & Circus
is the gourmet sandwich place
of Sioux Falls.
[Jordan] Plating the falafel
with naan.
Adventurous fusion food,
and it's always
kind of surprising.
[Guy] And it comes
from South Dakota buddies
Jordan Taylor
and Barry Putzke,
who took a detour to Portland
before heading back
with these culinary tricks.
We came home to pick
what Sioux Falls needed.
And a funky
sandwich joint was it?
-Well, yeah.
-Well, you got my attention.
You got a lot of people here
who are meat and potatoes
their whole life,
and they're trying things
like Vietnamese banh mi
chicken sandwich.
Dropping two
Vietnamese fried chicken.
Their Vietnamese
chicken sandwich,
you've got the
cilantro aioli, radishes.
Keeps you wanting more.
-Let's get into this.
-So, it's a take on banh mi,
kind of,
the sandwich as a whole,
except it's not on a baguette.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
what's it on?
Potato bun.
-It's almost like a take
on a Nashville hot.
-I'm outta here.
[laughing]
You have an identity problem.
You're an Asian cowboy now.
Well, yeah, kind of.
So we're just
going to start with
a simple buttermilk dredge.
Chicken thigh,
boneless, skinless.
[Jordan] Make sure it's coated
for at least 12 hours.
-Next up?
-The pickling liquid
and the pickles.
Water, rice vinegar, salt,
sugar, and one star anise.
And we're going
into carrots...
[Jordan] Onions and julienne
daikon radish.
-Just a little quick pickle.
-Yep. Yep.
Now we're on
to the cilantro aioli.
Three egg yolk...
Add a little water,
it helps the emulsion
and get it foamy.
Foamy for my homie.
And why did you
want to be a chef?
I don't know.
I think I wanted to be
a rock star chef.
I wasn't good at guitar.
Join the club.
I like this little technique.
-Get those yolks
really whipped up.
-Yeah.
You hit it with the oil,
and you're gonna
get a nice, light,
creamy whip.
-[Jordan] Lime juice.
-[both] Lime zest.
-Pinch of salt.
-[Guy] And a truckload
of cilantro.
And then just
blast it through.
-[Guy] Next up?
-The glaze.
It's a take on nuoc cham,
like, the dipping sauce
-that usually accompanies
spring rolls and whatnot.
-Oh, I-- Yeah.
-Lime juice,
water, fish sauce...
-Soy sauce.
Brown bean paste,
and we got
honey, garlic and jalapeno.
Cook for 20 minutes.
Bring it to a boil.
Hit it with a slurry,
immersion blender,
and then strain it
through a chinois.
So, a simple dredge
for the chicken.
Salt, AP flour
and garlic powder.
Our buttermilk-brined
chicken thigh in the fryer.
-Three-fifty...
-Eight-ish minutes.
Boom. Salt,
and then just the glaze.
-Cilantro aioli.
-The daikon, carrot and onion.
The chicken. Ready to go.
What a monster. Nice bun.
Everything is done right.
One minute, it's a Nashville
chicken sandwich.
The next minute,
it's a banh mi.
It depends on
what bite you get.
Chicken's cooked perfectly.
Veggies are nicely pickled.
Not too soft. Not too firm.
Lime aioli... nice, light.
Bread, just enough
to keep it together
to where it's not
melting through.
But you know what?
I think we need to
bring in a pro.
I want to bring in
your buddy Derek.
I want you to give me
your Triple D explanation
of what the sandwich
tastes like.
-[Jordan] Oh, yeah.
-[Guy] There we go.
It's really good.
The chicken's really
nice and crispy.
And I like that sauce
with the bun.
If you can sell it
to a 12-year-old,
you know
you're doing something right.
Appreciate your help, bro.
Grabbing two Vietnamese
fried chicken.
I would be lying to say
if I didn't want to order
this every time.
[woman] The pickles
have a bite to them,
then you bite into the salty,
crunchy chicken.
And the cilantro aioli really
is that nice finishing touch.
[Jordan] Naughty Fry
for table 12.
Not only are you going
to be blown away by the food,
but there's
excellent opportunities
to see the city as well.
The Sioux Falls' namesake
is right down the street.
The food culture
is just getting better
year on year on year.
This end of town
wasn't even close to
what it is right now.
Even three years ago,
when we moved in,
it was a lot
different landscape.
Every community
that really blows up
is based on their food.
Barry and Jordan
are good enough
that you're willing
to try things.
[Guy] Like what's
coming up next!
Three Curried Cauliflower
headed to the window.
-The cauliflower wraps
are a umami bomb.
-See you in a bit.
Big bite.
-That wasn't a big bite.
-[laughs]
That was like
a hummingbird bite.
Get that thing... Come on.
-Oh, yeah.
-There we go.
Welcome back.
We are at Bread & Circus.
You're talking about a place
that only makes sandwiches.
And I'm going to tell you
that identity crisis
chicken sandwich we had...
The bomb.
Jerk salmon.
[woman] They're doing
really cool things,
and has been a game changer
for Sioux Falls.
It's one of the few
places in town
where I can get really great
vegetarian food.
Plating three
curried cauliflower.
Their curried
cauliflower sandwich
is outstanding.
Perfectly roasted.
The spice mix is just dead on.
It's packed with flavor,
for sure.
All right, how are we
startin' this off?
Red lentil hummus.
So, instead of
garbanzo beans--
Everything you do
just has this
little idea of go left,
and then you go right.
-Yeah. Pretty much.
-Go up, then you go down.
-Yeah.
-I like the way you roll.
Red lentils, one bay leaf,
cover with water,
cook until they're tender.
Ten, fifteen minutes.
We're going to add it
to a food processor.
Couple cloves of garlic,
Greek tahini.
Don't be a weenie.
Use more tahini.
Lemon juice,
lime juice, lemon zest.
Then we're gonna buzz it.
And we'll drizzle in
the vegetable oil.
Salt.
This is the cooking liquid.
Just like with pasta?
The lentil hummus is done.
Next up?
[Jordan] We're gonna
roast the cauliflower.
You're not as good
as broccoli.
-[Jordan laughs]
-No.
Oh.
Vegetable oil, salt.
A little bit of pepper. Toss.
Spread it out.
-Oh, and roast it in the oven.
-Exactly.
-[Guy] What temp?
-350, twelve to fifteen.
-[Guy] What's our next step?
-Yellow curry base.
-Okay.
-[Jordan] Whole coriander,
fennel seed.
Whole cumin seed.
Couple cloves.
Give that a little toast.
Definitely smell
the curry going on now.
Grind it off, and then
we can start the base
for the curry itself.
Little vegetable oil
and a little julienned onion.
Green onion, diced jalapeno.
This is a puree
of ginger and garlic.
The spices that we toasted.
And then we have a combination
of curry powder,
smoked paprika, amchur powder.
-Hamster powder?
-[laughing] Amchur,
which is dried mango.
Never had it.
I'm always willing to try.
And a little bit of salt.
Quick toast.
Then we'll add the coconut.
After 25 minutes,
-we'll just hit it
with this lime juice...
-And cilantro.
[Jordan] We're just gonna
basically glaze the
cauliflower itself.
Little pinch of salt.
Then we're gonna
toss it through.
Comes on naan bread.
You get some
or you don't get "naan?"
-You get all of it.
-Thank you.
I'll be here all week.
-[Jordan] We got
the red lentil hummus here.
-Okay.
Some local arugula,
some of the curry,
cilantro and radish.
-You roll it up?
-You could fork and knife it.
-Sandwich shop.
You don't eat with a fork.
-[laughs]
But you do wear
half of it, it looks like.
You're gonna need the hunch
for this one.
Any Indian
restaurants close by?
There's a couple.
If I was an Indian restaurant,
I was within two blocks,
I'd move,
tear down the sign and go.
That is one of
the better curries
that I have tried in a while,
in or out
of an Indian restaurant.
Awesome. Thank you.
It's balanced,
it's fragrant, it's fresh.
It's a real curry.
Now, you're getting
that coriander,
all those toasted seeds.
You're really picking it up.
Loved the little bit
of jalapeno in there,
-the little bit of that
herbaceous heat.
-Yeah.
The ginger, the garlic,
very nice.
Cauliflower is still tender.
Naan's a great vessel.
Vegetarian, not vegetarian,
like curry, don't like curry,
I don't care what it is,
that sandwich right there
will blow your doors off.
I got a curried
cauliflower sandwich.
Quite honestly never thought
cauliflower could
taste that good.
Just the right amount
of spice.
This is probably
one of the only times
that I eat the vegetables
that I should.
Pork belly gyro
and asparagus with naan.
The food's always great,
-people are always friendly.
-[laughing]
It's definitely
the place to be.
-[Guy] Dynamite.
-Thanks, man.
Balanced, creative...
List goes on and on.
Excellent, brother.
[Guy] Up next,
wood-fired pie
in Fairbanks, Alaska.
You should expect
that it's gonna be
a little bit different,
but dynamite.
Going from a sour specialty...
Whoa! You're goin'
pickle happy on this!
...to a sweet, spicy finish.
That is a fantastic pizza.
I'm here in Fairbanks, Alaska.
It's been a while
since we were up here.
I always find
an eclectic mix of food
in this area.
So what I am up to try?
A pizza joint.
Now, not just any
average pizza joint.
You see, he makes
the pizzas inside,
but then he's got
a hole in the wall,
and he cooks in the wood-fired
ovens outside.
In Alaska weather?
Are you kidding me?
This is Hungry Robot.
Got HooDoo Hops Sticks
for James.
You can smell pizza
from miles away. [laughing]
Everything I've had
has been wonderful.
[woman] I've got
a Supreme right here.
It's crazy to me
that the pizzas
are cooked outside.
-It only gets
a little chilly here, so...
-[man laughs]
[Guy] And since everything's
a little more wild like this
in Alaska,
it's no surprise that
Randy Bezdek's journey
from IT specialist
to pizza pro
isn't exactly normal.
We started just doing
marshmallows and stuff
out of our house.
-Didn't see that coming.
-Yeah.
We wanted to branch out
into something
that was savory.
'Cause you'd
already cornered
the marshmallow market.
[Randy] We were like,
well, nobody's doing
wood-fired pizzas.
They just do
unique combinations,
and they're delicious.
Got a Dilly Dilly
up for table 6.
Huh, pickles on a pizza.
Sounds interesting.
It's just really flavor-packed
and one of my
personal favorites.
[Guy] What are we
gonna make first?
-[Randy] We can
make the dough.
-I'm gonna be honest with you.
Might be one
of the biggest mixers
I've ever seen on Triple D.
-I'd get in that.
-Yeah. [laughs]
-No. I'm not doing it.
-[man laughs]
[Randy] Water, flour, yeast,
olive oil, salt.
-The big old hook.
-This used to anchor a ship.
It's ridiculous.
[Randy] You might
as well go big.
[Guy] This does not
look like pizza dough-making.
Let that go for about
ten to 15 minutes.
We typically ball it
right after we mix it,
put it in the fridge
and let it grow overnight.
-[Guy] What do we do next?
-[Randy] Wanna shred cheese?
People like
the convenience
of pre-shredded cheese,
but there's a silica
they put on the cheese
that keeps the cheese
from coagulating
when it's in the bag.
So when you can
shred it yourself,
the melt that you're going
to get is very worth it.
[imitating Schwarzenegger]
You can do it.
Push harder. Use your muscles.
Shredded marshmallows.
Nice, light, fluffy,
lays out on the pizza great.
Tastes like mozzarella.
[Randy] Now we're
going to make
the sweet Italian sausage.
Garlic, thyme,
oregano, paprika,
-brown sugar...
-Wing of bat...
Fennel, onion powder,
red pepper, basil,
-parsley, black pepper.
-Where's the dill?
-Oh, that comes later.
-Oh.
[Randy] Salt
and red wine vinegar.
So, we mix that up
into this pork.
[Randy] And then we put it
in the fridge overnight.
Now we're going to
make our Dilly Drizzle.
It starts with a ranch base.
So we have mayonnaise,
sour cream...
-Got it.
-...parsley, onion powder,
salt, thyme...
-[Guy] Dill.
-...water, chives,
granulated garlic,
black pepper.
And that's our ranch.
To make it the Dilly Drizzle,
we'll add red pepper,
-parsley, Parmesan, garlic--
-And a little olive oil.
That's like ranch gone wild.
If you get me a spoon,
I'll just eat this
as a cold soup.
-Yeah. [laughs]
-What's next?
-Roasted garlic white sauce.
-So, we got roasted garlic...
[Randy] Some butter, cream,
Parmesan, black pepper.
Cook that down,
make it a nice paste.
-Let's see it, chef.
-First we stretch the dough.
Look how nice and light
and tender that is.
[Randy] The white sauce.
-Spackle.
-Mozzarella.
This is where
things go off the rails
right here, folks.
Whoa! You're going
pickle happy on this.
[Randy] We do a lot of pickles
on the Dilly Dilly.
[Guy] And just
a little sausage. Very nice.
Let's go, uh, cook it.
In the oven, how long?
[Randy] Ninety seconds
to two minutes.
-[Guy] The type of wood?
-[Randy] Birch.
[whistles] Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Look at that thing. Medieval.
A friend of mine's
a blacksmith.
-So he made slicers.
-Nice.
The Dilly Shaker,
which is Parmesan,
Romano and dill.
-And then we have
our Dilly Drizzle.
-Schnizzle with the drizzle.
It's delicious. The crust is
about as spot on as you get.
Light, full of pockets,
but it's got good chew.
It's tender.
I like biting into it
and getting
the pickle crunch.
I like the fresh acidity
contrasting to
the creaminess
of the base spread,
and then you get the crumble
from the sausage,
and I think that
the sprinkle's dynamite.
-That's a destination pizza.
Congrats.
-Thank you.
Dilly Dilly with sausage
going in the oven.
What makes the pizza
amazing for me is the crust.
It's got a good crisp to it.
And the pickles are
kind of crunchy on there.
You can definitely taste
the birch smoke
coming through.
I crave it. I think about it
all the time. [laughs]
-We have to talk.
-We do have to talk.
Got some arugula
going on the No Truffle.
Hungry Robot is just
the best pizza in Fairbanks.
By the way,
how did Hungry Robot...
[Randy] The ovens look like
a robot head,
and we're constantly feeding
wood and pizza into 'em.
All of his ovens
just hook on
as a little trailer thing,
and he can go around
to different events.
[woman] They are very good
about bringing all these
different styles of pizza.
And that's something
you don't get around here.
[Randy] Got a Bumble Bee
for table 6.
The Bumble Bee pizza,
it's got a perfect mixture
of the peppers,
the pepperoni, and the honey.
It's my go-to pizza.
-What are we making next?
-[Randy] Red sauce
for Burning Bumble Bee.
We start with tomatoes,
and tomato paste,
diced tomatoes.
-[Guy] Got it.
-Salt, basil, oregano.
[Guy] And garlic.
-Delicious.
-Now we're going to
make the ancho chili honey.
Thank you, sugar.
Ancho chili powder.
So we just let this infuse,
and we're good to go.
-Yep.
-Well, let's do this!
We start with our red sauce,
pepperoni, mozzarella,
cubed pepperoni.
This gets on top
'cause then it gets crispy.
-And then pepperoncini.
-In the oven.
Look at that
cute little pizza.
-This is our spicy honey?
Gorgeous.
-There you go.
That is a fantastic pizza.
Beautiful tomato sauce.
The pepperoncini
giving you a little bit
of that vinegar acid
and just the right amount
of ancho in the honey...
to where the honey's got
a little sting to it.
-You know, it's got a--
Ha-ha...
-Yeah.
[Guy] Listen, dude.
I don't know what IT is,
but I know what delicious is,
and you programmed that.
Well done.
I've got your
Burning Bumble Bee.
This is an elevated pizza.
I like the spicy honey.
Very good crust. Definitely.
How's this pizza? One to ten.
-I'd give it--
-Ten.
You give it a ten.
[Randy] Got a Bogan for Nick.
I'm all about this place.
It's my favorite.
They keep me coming back
every time.
The whole thing's weird, bro.
The gigantic mixer's weird...
And when
the pizza ovens sit outside
in Alaska temperatures,
you should expect
that it's going to be
a little bit different...
A lot of bit different,
but dynamite. Thank you.
Coming up...
Come to Fargo, North Dakota,
'cause the Indian food's
the bomb.
From lights-out
lamb comfort food...
It's giving me goose bumps.
...to spicy shrimp
with a kick.
That is just
how it's done right there.
You know,
for different regions
that we shoot
Diners, Drive-ins and Dives,
they're known for things
like a great sports team.
They're known for
fantastic weather,
maybe a geographical location,
maybe a historical monument.
Well, I'm here
in Fargo, North Dakota,
and they're known
for a lot of things.
But from what people
have been telling me,
they should be known
for their Indian food.
This is Passage to India.
Chicken Tikka, please.
I was overwhelmed
by the explosion of flavors.
There's something
for everybody.
Bread's coming out.
[man] I could close my eyes
and tell you that I was home.
It reminded me
of my mom's cooking.
[Guy] And it was that longing
for Indian flavors
which led engineer
Sam Rangaswamy
to merge careers
after moving to Fargo
with his wife, Dana.
How did you go
from software engineering
to the restaurant business?
Well, that was always there
in the back of my mind,
all the time cooking,
love cooking.
We said that we're going
to stick on to authentic food.
We didn't make
any changes at all.
Lamb Rogan Josh.
I've never had a better
Lamb Rogan Josh anywhere.
It takes an art
to cook this dish.
-[Guy] All right,
what are we into?
-The Lamb Rogan Josh.
Rogan josh, not Joe Rogan?
[chuckles] No. So, the lamb
that I'm using today,
grass fed, goes very well
with Indian curries.
-Okay.
-I'm going to use
a little technique
that grandmothers
like to follow.
Put some yogurt, turmeric
and salt to it.
-And let it pull out
the impurities.
-Yeah.
[Guy] Also creates
part of the flavor profile.
In India, everybody
has pressure cookers.
It looks like you could
split atoms with this deal.
-[Sam] Mustard oil.
-[Guy] I've never had
mustard oil.
Now we're going to bloom
cardamom, cinnamon,
black cardamom...
[Sam] Bay leaves, cumin seeds,
ginger-garlic paste.
This is called the asafetida.
-Asafetida?
-Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
-[Sam] Then we add our lamb.
-Put a little sear on this.
[Sam] Add turmeric
and let it steam
for about 20 minutes.
Now I'm going to
make onion base...
Now, this is the
foundation of so many
Indian curries.
[Sam] Yeah.
Vegetable oil, onions.
[Guy] Ginger-garlic paste.
[Sam] Kashmiri chili powder.
Very much like paprika.
Coriander powder, turmeric.
[Guy] Garam masala.
Is there an actual
written recipe around here?
Or we just eyeball everything?
Certainly the Indian cooking
is that you don't
measure up anything.
Water.
All right, so we cook
this down
till it's nice and soft.
Let's do the naan.
We make many, uh...
-You make many varieties
of naan?
-Yeah.
Food coma comin'.
Garlic naan, mint naan.
See, I thought it just went
seven, eight, naan, ten.
-[chuckles]
-[laughs]
[Sam] All-purpose flour,
baking soda,
yeast, homemade yogurt.
-Oh, homemade.
That's the way I do it, too.
-Yeah.
Salt, some sugar, oil.
This is the most
unmeasured recipe
I have ever seen in my life.
[Sam] Rest at least
for an hour.
-[Guy] And then roll it out.
-[Sam] The traditional way.
Use the fingers.
And now you're gonna
show me the magic
of the green onion
and the garlic.
[Sam] Sure.
[Guy] Garlic on the outside...
So awesome.
That's the pad.
[Sam] Put it inside
the tandoor oven.
Stuck to the side of the wall.
All right, chef.
[Sam] Let's make
the Lamb Rogan Josh.
Start off with mustard oil.
[Guy] Black cardamom,
cinnamon and green cardamom.
[Sam] Asafetida.
The old asafetida.
[Sam] It smells
very pungent, so.
That stuff, not so much
to try by itself.
[Sam] Onion base,
white onion sauce.
[Guy] And then in with
the pressure-cooked lamb.
Add some ginger powder now.
Garam masala.
Cumin powder, a bit.
Kashmiri chili powder.
Fennel seeds powder.
-Love that.
-Some yogurt.
This is the longest
Indian dish
we've ever made in my life.
-[Sam] Kasuri methi.
-[Guy] Some who?
Kasuri methi. Spice.
[Guy] Saffron.
[Sam] Stir fry till the sheen
and the oil oozes out.
[Guy] It's gorgeous.
Little of the gravy
into the basmati.
This is next level.
It's giving me goosebumps.
It's not one flavor.
You get the lamb, the onion,
you get the curry,
you get the pepper.
You're not just cooking
from the heart,
you're also cooking
with that analytical mind
that you have,
which makes it very precise.
I have taken 16 bites.
I am off the rails.
Oh.
Here's your Lamb Rogan Josh.
The lamb is excellent,
it's very tender.
The sauce that's with it
is absolutely decadent.
I'm a big fan of naan,
and they do it
really well here.
I'm making malai methi murgh.
-This is my first time
with Indian food, actually.
-In your life?
Yes. And I'm
pleasantly surprised.
They just bring out
so many different flavors.
Devil's Shrimp Curry.
[man] Devil's Shrimp Curry
is kind of a spin
on tomato soup.
It does have the spice kick.
It does have the creaminess.
Defined in an Indian way.
-[Guy] Chef,
what's the next dish?
-Devil's Shrimp Curry.
And this goes way back
to the southern tip of India.
Lemon juice, some turmeric.
[Guy] Little salt.
-How long is that
gonna marinate?
-[Sam] 15-20 minutes.
Got it. Next step.
[Sam] Coconut oil,
a little mustard,
curry leaves.
-Cumin, red chilies.
-Hot.
[Sam] Onion base
and onion gravy,
fenugreek seeds...
[Guy] Tomato puree.
Tamarind, garam masala now.
Chili powder,
ginger-garlic paste,
black pepper.
I lost count.
I gotta take my shoe off
-'cause we're over 20.
-Water.
-[Guy] A little salt.
-[Sam] Shrimps.
-Coconut cream.
-And a little bit
of heavy cream.
Goodbye, Guy.
Look at that bite.
Mmm.
Shrimp are tender,
just lightly bathed
in that sauce,
lavished in the curry.
For the average person,
it's got a little heat.
But it's not overly spicy.
Every time you get a bite,
kind of like a lotus flower,
just continuing to open.
That is the just
how it's done,
right there. Outstanding.
Devil's Shrimp Curry.
The shrimp is excellent.
Too spicy?
Uh, it makes me sweat.
[laughs]
Gobi Manchurian.
You can taste
the passion in the food.
You will never leave
empty stomach.
Any time someone tells me,
"Oh, I'm not a fan
of Indian food,"
I just look at 'em and say,
"Have you seen a movie in 3D?
Have you seen a movie
in color?"
Come to Fargo, North Dakota,
'cause the Indian food's
the bomb.
-Thank you.
-[Guy] Real deal.
So that's it for this edition
of Diners, Drive-ins
and Dives.
But don't you worry.
There's funky joints
all over this country,
and I'll be looking for you
next time on...
[all] Triple D!
[all cheering]
Here, just
come over here and...
Let's try this one time.
Everybody at home,
get your face
real close to the screen.
Come in fast, okay?
And let's eat.
Cover your teeth. Ready?
[laughter]
-[Guy] Yeah. Good job.
-[laughter]