Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri.
And we're rolling out, looking
for America's greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
[music playing]
This trip-- wow, how you doin'--
it's hearty helpings
and an unhinged jaw
to be able to eat this.
It'll stick to your ribs.
I have no clue exactly where
this is going to end up.
We've got off-the-chain chops,
and mega-meatloaf in Alaska.
When you go up to Fairbanks,
this is a place to check out.
A clean take on comfort
in South Dakota--
It good.
Yeah.
Make yum now.
And in Moorhead, Minnesota--
dude, outstanding-- a
Midwest global mash-up--
this is a monster meal--
with a fried chicken chaser.
That is super crunch-a-taceous.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Diners,
Drive-Ins and Dives."
[music playing]
Triple D hanging out in
Sioux Falls, South Dakota,
with the one-and-only,
Chef Justin Warner.
Now Justin, you are
from around these parts.
Tell me what kind of
food can we expect?
Ah, you know, pizza,
burgers, mac and cheese--
All-American stuff.
- Great.
So if I tell you I'm going
to take you to a joint that's
doing all of that
food, but they're
doing it locally-sourced,
organic, a lot of the options
are vegan, and it's just
all about clean eating,
what would you think?
- What, in Sioux Falls?
That's awesome.
- Fantastic.
This is Daily
Clean Food & Drink.
[music playing]
Bison burger up.
This place is about
good, clean food.
Spaghetti and
meatballs, order up.
All the staples, but with
those healthy ingredients.
GUY FIERI: Which
was a recipe that
cooked up big changes for
chef and owner, Shaley Bolks.
I lost 160 pounds in one year.
Just from clean eating
and taking care of yourself?
I basically taught myself
how to eat, how to exercise.
I didn't just want to
be skinny on salads.
I wanted to, like--
Eat real food.
Eat real food, yeah.
So I wanted to bring
that to Sioux Falls.
I have the Mightiest
Mac for you.
Mightiest Mac is a
grain-free, gluten-free item.
The noodles are chickpeas.
It's so good with, like,
the creamy mac and cheese,
the buffalo meatballs, and
then the spicy chimichurri
sauce on top.
The number one seller is
definitely the bison meatballs.
Ground bison, lean
and very healthy.
We throw some turkey
in it to moisten it up.
And I'm sneaking some kale in.
Don't have to sneak it.
Red onion.
Is that nooch?
Yes.
What's nooch?
Saccharomyces cerevisiae,
the same stuff that makes beer.
Oh!
"Sacramenative simenyvichmeh."
This is nutritional yeast.
Awesome to work with.
Gluten-free oat flour,
some scrambled eggs.
They're super orange.
Minced garlic, red
pepper flakes, oregano.
Love it.
Fennel seed and
a little salt. Roll
it up into
ounce-and-a-half meatballs.
Got it.
Roast them in the oven at
425 degrees for 15 minutes.
Next up.
The chimichurri.
Some lemon juice--
Some, huh?
Avocado oil.
I like the avocado oil.
I saw a poster in
the lobby that talks
about all the things
that are local
and all the things
that are organic.
It is a billboard this big.
Fresh parsley,
cilantro, oregano.
Are you serious,
that much red pepper?
We like it spicy and
we like it garlicky.
Is it to remove paint?
Chop it down, maybe
a couple of pulses.
Wow!
That'll wake you up.
How you doin'!
Woo!
All right, we are making
the roux for our Mighty Mac--
butternut squash, some
whole milk, vegetable broth.
You can't do mac without butter.
Salt, dash of nutmeg--
Nutmeg with dairy-- classic.
We stew it down for 15 to 20
minutes just to kind of get it
a little bit thicker.
As we continue on the
journey, I have no clue exactly
where this is going to end up.
Throw it in the processor.
Heat it up pretty lightly.
And then we throw
our cheddar cheese.
And we melt it down so that it
turns into a nice, thick goo.
And chickpea pasta.
Keeping it gluten-free.
These are great.
Mix this all together.
See the texture on that?
A nice little bed
for our meatballs.
Picking out the best
three just for you.
Now the chimichurri 9,000.
Stay on your side.
I promise.
[music playing]
What you are referring
to as chimichurri
is the most [thwack]
chimichurri I've ever had.
But in this dish, the
richness of that squash cheese
sauce and the meatball cuts it.
I mean, it is the
perfect [thwack] hi-ya.
Yeah, these three things,
I feel like their sum
is greater than their
individual parts.
And it's delicious.
It good.
Yeah.
Make yum now.
Two Mightiest Macs, up.
Every bite was
really, really good.
And you'd never
know all the veggies
that are hidden in there.
Scoop of the
Moroccan chicken salad.
There's some kind of stigma
if you go to a place like this.
It's just going to
be really expensive.
You're only eating salad.
You're not going to feel full.
Where this, I think,
breaks that mold.
So a big thing is
the accessibility.
It makes it very
approachable for everybody.
Anything on the
menu is awesome.
Jeb's No Bull
Burger, order up.
If you didn't know
it was a vegan burger,
you probably wouldn't
have been able to guess.
The spice in it-- incredible.
What's on the menu now?
Jeb's No Bull Burger,
named after one of
the original founding owners.
[music playing]
Some olive oil,
garlic, green olive.
I like the little
kick of the olives.
Jalapeno, artichoke,
mushrooms, red onion--
And some red bells.
Let it go till the
vegetables are soft.
Add gluten-free oats,
garbanzo beans, black beans.
Flax seed blended
up with some water,
and then we refrigerate
it for a little bit--
makes it a little gelatinous.
A vegan Worcestershire--
shire--shire--shire--
Worcestershire sauce
without the fish in it.
A little more flax.
Just the flax--
Just the flax, man.
Ha ha!
Oat flour, red pepper flakes,
salt, dried sage, cumin.
Great.
Celery salt.
Kitchen sink.
Cayenne, smoked paprika,
black pepper, oregano.
Patty 'em up.
Make it into a burger.
We are going to make our
vegan mayo coconut milk.
Thick.
Mustard powder, apple cider
vinegar, garlic granules,
salt. Slowly add
the avocado oil.
Take this now
and combine it with
the sriracha, yellow mustard.
Slather it on our bun,
and toast the bun off.
Some greens.
Set our burger on top of that.
Tomato, onion, pickles, and--
[music playing]
Mm.
It's a good veggie patty, man.
And the bun itself
is outstanding.
Cooking the mayo onto
the bun adds another one
of those textural points.
It, like, makes
the burger eat in 3D.
The olive, which
actually contains fat,
that's what really sells
it and makes it craveable.
As soon as you put
all the accoutrements
of the pickles,
onions, and tomato,
you start to sing
the song of burger.
It's delicious.
Can I have another one?
I have the Jeb's
No Bull Burger.
Unbelievably juicy.
More flavor than a
regular beef burger.
Moroccan chicken
salad, order up.
I think Daily just really
knocked it out of the park.
You taking control
of your life,
and then you take
that same philosophy
and apply that
into a restaurant,
can be nothing but successful.
Well done.
You've got to come
meet this girl.
She'll change the way
you look at things.
Up next in Fairbanks, Alaska--
make it happen, captain--
their dishes may sound familiar.
This is definitely a pork
chop I would order again.
But what they're adding--
22 ingredients so far, folks.
Everybody keeping up at home--
takes it to a whole new world.
You got your own jam
band going on right here.
[music playing]
So I'm here in downtown
Fairbanks, Alaska,
right on the Chena River.
And I gotta tell ya,
this is just about where
Fairbanks was established.
You gotta look it up--
so much awesome history.
Anyhow, speaking
of history, there's
two local restaurateurs
who are doing business
in this town for a long time.
And then a big
hotel chain came in.
And they said, we want to
open up a restaurant inside
of our hotel that's
got that local flair,
that local attitude and energy.
Well, it actually happened.
This is Lavelle's Bistro.
[music playing]
I got a lobster
cake kickin' fast.
Lavelle's is a
treasure in Fairbanks.
Potato-crusted sockeye salmon.
What makes it so special?
Just the atmosphere.
Everything's from scratch.
It's family-owned and run.
GUY FIERI: By Kathy Lavelle and
Frank Eagle, who opened up shop
inside a hotel in
2001, then teamed
up with Chef Cleveland Kenney.
We had been in the
restaurant business.
Then we started catering.
People started coming in.
It was turning into a
little pop-up restaurant,
and that attracted somebody
from the hotel group?
KATHY LAVELLE: Exactly.
FRANK EAGLE: Exactly.
What kind of
food are we doing?
It's more of a
French dining place,
but pineapple to the Big Apple,
that's how I like to see it.
Firing three
lollipop pork chops.
This is the first time
I've had this pork chop.
It's really good.
It's always just a
beautiful presentation.
First dish, we're going
to do a lollipop pork chop.
We're going to start off
with making the brine.
I add my water first.
Now, when you say
lollipop pork chop,
it's because you're
pulling all the meat
off the bone of the chop.
Yes, sir.
Orange peel, salt, bay
leaves, brown sugar,
coriander, peppercorn mélange.
Can you spell that?
Mélan--
M-E-L-lange--
That's how I spell it.
That's how you spell it?
Get ice to it, let it chill,
and then we'll brine the chops.
Yes, sir.
Let me see these beauties.
All of our meats
come in fresh.
Which is a big deal
all the way in Alaska.
So they come in trimmed,
boom, ready to go.
You're not sitting here
with a little paring knife
skinning back those--
No, I don't got time.
We put thyme in here?
[drum roll, cymbal]
How long are we going
to brine the chops?
- Two days.
- What's going with the chops?
Horseradish, apricot
marmalade, oil, garlic,
deglaze it with triple sec.
A little orange
liqueur, got it.
Horseradish, Dijon mustard,
brown sugar, apricot jam.
Apricot, not "aypricot."
Apricot, that's what I say.
I say apricot.
I don't say "aypricot."
Stir it up and let it steep
for about 10 to 12 minutes.
- Make it happen, captain.
- All right.
Oil my pan--
GUY FIERI: Black
pepper, kosher salt.
It has a lot of
salt in it already.
We don't want to oversalt it.
So it's just like
(high-pitched) oo oo.
That's the noise of
it doing its thing.
Sear one side, flip it.
Put a little cube
of butter on there.
Into the oven at 450 for
six to eight minutes.
When it comes out--
We put fresh
brie cheese on top.
Let this melt down.
Mashed potatoes on
the plate, like so.
Lollipop pork chop
with the melted brie.
Put our marm down on there.
What's the zucchini
being finished with?
Just salt and pepper.
There we go.
Well, any time you put
the brie on anything,
I'm good to go.
[music playing]
Cleveland, I'll tell
you what, buddy.
I don't typically order
pork chops in restaurants.
One of the main
reasons is, I don't
think people cook them right.
The pork chop, in particular,
the way we raise pork,
it needs fat, it needs flavor.
The brine is perfect.
So there's flavor all
the way through this.
You get into that
salt and that sweet,
and you counterbalance it
with the funk of the brie
and the tang of the
horseradish and the tang
of the Dijon mustard.
That marmalade's just
packed with flavor.
And the mashed potato is the
definition of mashed potato.
I mean, it's delicious.
It's balanced, this
is definitely a pork
chop I would order again.
Lollipop pork
chop up top, ready.
The pork chop is wonderful.
Nice glaze on top.
Very tender pork.
Restaurants like Lavelle's,
are there a lot of them?
No.
For special occasions,
this is where we come.
Kathy and Frank, they've got
an amazing collection of wine
that they've gathered
from all over the world.
The selection is
the best in town.
But a glass of milk is what they
recommend with the meatloaf.
And it is delicious with it.
What else you
got up your sleeve?
25-ingredient meatloaf.
Not 24, not 26.
Not 23.
The meatloaf is
delicious, hearty,
and it's a wonderful meal to
warm up with in the wintertime
in Fairbanks.
You go grab the meatloaf.
25.
And I'll be counting it
all down when we come back.
[music playing]
Hey, Cleveland, why
did she get three pieces
of meatloaf and I only got two?
She's special.
OK, good talk.
Thanks, buddy.
Triple D is chillin' at
Lavelle's Bistro, which
has served up scratch-made,
elevated comfort to the folks
here in Fairbanks, Alaska.
It gets to 50
below here sometimes,
so having really
wholesome food just
makes you feel a
whole lot better
about being in the
cold and the dark.
About to flame up over here.
Watch yourself.
This is where you want to go
on a Friday or Saturday night.
Or every night.
- Or every night.
I was going to say, if
they've got meatloaf
on the menu, then every night.
Three meatloaves,
coming at you.
The 25-ingredient
meatloaf is the best
meatloaf you've ever had.
So many flavors.
It's got vegetables in it.
And the demi-glace
sauce tops it off.
So 25-ingredient meatloaf.
Yes, sir.
First, we're going to
sweat the vegetables.
One-- one ingredient.
That's hamachi oil.
Onions.
Two ingredients, heh heh heh.
Celery.
Three.
Carrots, red peppers, yellow
peppers, orange peppers,
garlic, green onion.
All right, so 9 of the 25.
Next step is--
The wet mix, starting
with cumin, cayenne, thyme,
white pepper, garlic,
sugar, black pepper,
salt, paprika, cilantro, whole
eggs, ketchup, half-and-half.
22 ingredients so far, folks.
Everybody keeping up at home?
Now we're going to
make our meatloaf.
We're going to add Italian
sausage, certified Angus beef,
sweated veg.
Now we're going to
add our wet mix.
Panko.
[ding, ding]
Now, are you
free-forming this,
or are we going into pans?
I'm free-forming it.
I got to beat this thing up.
You want to get all the
air pockets out of it.
Cover with foil
in the oven, 350.
How long?
18 to 22 minutes.
And then we're going to
remove that aluminum foil.
And we're going to let
it sit-in there again
for another 12 minutes or so.
What do we serve
with this dish?
We're making a demi-glace.
Let's start with that.
We're making a veal stock with
these dinosaur bones in here.
I like it.
The veal bones--
- Absolutely.
- Got it.
Carrot, celery,
and onion mix here.
Kind of just dump it on there.
Here we go.
I'm ready for you.
In the oven--
Hour 15 minutes.
When you get into something
like the demi-glace,
to make it yourself,
the flavor difference
is just unquestionable.
Astronomical.
So go in with
some water first.
Peppercorn, thyme,
and my bay leaf.
Got it.
I want to dilute
this tomato paste.
This is when the splash is
going to start happening.
And lastly--
The bones.
Boil for six hours.
Final step, Chef.
This is reduced significantly.
So now I'm going to actually
add a demi-glace base to it.
- You're going to fortify it.
- Fortify it, right.
I gotcha.
So our meatloaf is done.
Plate mashed potatoes,
loaves right on top,
sides of vegetables.
GUY FIERI: A splash of demi--
And it's ready to serve.
[music playing]
Cleveland, on
Triple D, I think
one of the things that
people expect to see
are dishes like meatloaf.
For something so simple,
there's a lot of ways
that people could
take wrong turns.
What you have here
is a very tender,
well-seasoned,
fortified meatloaf.
I love the Italian sausage and
the ground beef going together.
I could see the veggies.
They've been sweated
down enough, but not
too much that they disappear.
You've got a good
ratio of nice crust
on the outside of the
meatloaf to juicy interior
of the meatloaf.
When you're going to say we
make 25-Ingredient Meatloaf,
it really better be
one of those dishes
that people say, hey, when
you go up to Fairbanks,
this is a place to check out.
- Sweet.
- Well done.
Thank you.
Two meatloaves, table 22.
Let's go.
Delicious.
Nice texture, great flavors.
The demi-glace is
icing on the cake.
And the mashed potatoes
are nice and creamy.
Wait a second,
there's cake in there?
Banana wontons
with créme anglaise.
Been coming here
for about 20 years,
and they are very good at
making everybody feel welcome.
I love all your enthusiasm.
You love cooking.
You got your own jam
band going on right here.
- Thank you.
- Good job, buddy.
Coming up in Moorhead,
Minnesota-- ba-boom--
a funky joint going
out of the ordinary--
come down here for the
Midwestern bipimbop--
double it down on flavor--
chicken-fried,
chicken-fried-fried,
chicken-fried sandwich.
[music playing]
[mooing]
You know, at "Diners,
Drive-Ins and Dives,"
I have been to just about
every state in the country.
And finally, today, I hit
it here in North Dakota.
Uh, sorry.
I don't mean to interrupt, but
you're actually in Minnesota.
- I'm in Minnesota?
- You are.
Wait a second,
where's North Dakota?
Um, you'll just
go a little bit
more down the way and you'll--
you'll be in North Dakota.
Aww.
You almost made it.
You missed it by that much.
By that much.
I'm here in Moorhead, Minnesota,
to check out a joint where
the chef is doing
farm-to-table, Midwest style,
like you've never seen.
This is Sol Ave. Kitchen.
[music playing]
Platin' up two Cubanos.
Sol Ave. Is global street food
with a Midwest interpretation.
Potatoes Bravas.
What they brought to the
community is not your standard,
run-of-the-mill stuff.
Put out by
not-your-average cook.
Ryan Nitschke snagged a
James Beard nomination
for Best Midwestern Chef before
pairing up with co-owner, Nikki
Berglund, to open this spot.
Where'd you learn to cook?
Tech program here in Moorhead.
This is, like, a
grassroots program.
Yeah, big-time.
I dig it, man.
He's just got a
great way with flavors
and putting unique combinations
together, like a bibimbap,
but a Midwest style.
Plating bipimbaps.
The bibimbap is amazing.
They're using pickles with
mushrooms, with the pork belly.
Every single bite just keeps
getting better and better.
What are we making?
Midwest Bibimbap.
Come down here for
the Midwestern bibimbap.
We're going to cure
up some pork belly.
Salt, brown sugar, black
pepper, smoked paprika,
guajillo, ancho, bay leaves.
GUY FIERI: Put a rub on this.
RYAN NITSCHKE:
We're going to let
this sit overnight to cure up.
GUY FIERI: Into the oven.
RYAN NITSCHKE: 275,
for about four hours.
Next up?
- Ssamjang sauce.
- Ssamjang?
Yep.
Kind of like a
variation on gochujang.
We're going to start
with the gochujang.
Toasted sesame
seeds, some honey,
sesame oil, garlic, ginger.
That's some jang.
That's what the gochujang
has needed all its life.
RYAN NITSCHKE: Now we're
going to do our pickles--
white vinegar, water,
sugar, black peppercorns--
GUY FIERI: And bay leaf.
Let that sit there and
steep a little bit.
RYAN NITSCHKE: Once it's cool,
add it to the sliced cucumbers
and onion.
How long is this
going to pickle?
RYAN NITSCHKE: Overnight,
and ready to rock.
What's the final step?
Gonna slice up a pork belly.
Sear it off on the flat top
with the clamshell mushrooms.
Rice in the bowl, throw some
of the ssamjang, pickles,
radish, mushrooms over here.
Pretty generous on
the pork there, pal.
Heck yeah.
You need to eat.
The microgreens.
GUY FIERI: And then last but
not least, look at those gems.
So what's the story on the eggs?
RYAN NITSCHKE:
We're going to add
soy, water, mirin, sesame
oil, maple, garlic, chilies.
And then pour over
our soft-boiled eggs.
That's a nice umami
bomb in there.
But you're holding my egg.
I appreciate that.
[music playing]
Oh, I'm sorry, I forgot.
Did you want me to
comment on this?
Right.
The ingredients are delicious.
The fresh pickle, the
treatment of this pork belly--
perfect amount of sear
and crunch and render--
your ssamjang, bro.
A little pepper from the radish.
A little clean-up
from the cucumber.
Umami mushrooms.
This is a monster meal.
Mm.
Pork belly bibimbap, up.
The ssamjang sauce
is kind of spicy,
but those pickles help
break up the heat.
The pork belly, it's
crispy on the top,
but then it has that really
juicy layer underneath.
It's hard to kind
of load your chopstick
up enough with all the pieces,
which is what I want to do.
Hummus, up.
Chef Ryan works very
closely with the local farmers
on bringing in fresh
ingredients that are seasonal.
People have gotta be
flipping out for this.
Yeah, exactly.
They offer this little escape.
Getting new and
interesting things.
Things like kimchi on a
double-fried chicken sandwich.
Dropping chicken sammies.
This is absolutely my
favorite fried chicken
sandwich I've ever had.
It's massive.
I think I used four napkins.
We're going to make
the chicken-fried,
chicken-fried-fried,
chicken-fried sandwich.
I'm going to make the
batter to go on them.
Boneless chicken thighs--
Calm down.
What's the batter?
[music playing]
Start out with
an egg, buttermilk,
flour, pepper, salt, hot sauce.
It's going to
marinate overnight.
Dig it.
And we're going
to make our dredge--
flour, salt, black
pepper, white pepper,
cayenne, smoked
paprika, onion powder,
garlic powder, baking powder.
Out of the
marinated buttermilk
batter, into the dry.
Drop it in the fryer for
the first time at 300 degrees.
Bring it up and let it rest.
And then we're going to fry
it again to finish the cooking
and make it a
little more crunchy.
All right, what else
is going with this?
We're going to
do some lime aioli.
Hit it.
Mayo, lime juice and
zest, roasted garlic, sugar,
white pepper, salt, and blend.
- Let's build the sandwich?
- Yeah.
GUY FIERI: Toasted bun.
RYAN NITSCHKE: Lime
aioli on the bottom.
Kimchi on there.
That's generous.
Place our chicken.
Well, somebody
evidently didn't
make the bun the right size.
Get some ssamjang.
Boy, you are not light on
the portions of the sauces.
It's all about the sauce.
House pickles, and an unhinged
jaw to be able to eat this.
Here we go.
[music playing]
My friend, that is some
excellent fried chicken.
That is super crunch-a-taceous.
I have a chicken joint
called Chicken Guy.
And I say that
sauce is the boss.
When I watched you put on
all that ssamjang, I'm like,
just call it the
ssamjang sandwich.
But it's this balance that
goes on between the fat
of that lime aioli with
the acid of the pickle.
And it's, like,
clashing right there
in the middle of the
chicken sandwich, ba-boom.
Dude, outstanding.
Double-fried
chicken sandwich, up.
The cilantro lime
aioli is to die for.
And then a hit of
spice from the kimchi.
The chicken is just so juicy.
The breading adds this
nice crunch to it.
He's not lying, by the way.
Dressing up dumplings.
You can't find anything
like it in this area.
Everything just pairs
so beautifully together.
It really makes your
palate go on an experience.
You have two dishes with
the pickles and the ssamjang,
yet they're worlds apart.
Outstanding.
- Thank you.
OK.
12 to go.
So that's it for this trip.
But don't worry.
There's plenty more Triple D
joints all over the country.
I'll be looking for you
next week on "Diners,
Drive-Ins and Dives."
[music playing]
And you got to really calm
down on having a bad attitude,
because this negative
energy of yours
and not smiling or-- whoa,
aren't you the chameleon.
Uh, not at all.
[giggles]