You know people are asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing Triple D,
how did they do it?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
[engine revving]
[Guy] Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out
it was only the beginning
'cause Triple D joints
have been blowing up
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip,
we're hitting the road.
Takes a bus to Flavortown.
[laughs]
[Guy] For barbecue.
I want you to look
at this smoke ring.
Pubs and local grub.
[woman]
It just tastes like home.
[Guy]
In Pacifica, California,
a barbecue joint
taking old face...
Yeah, a little tasty-taste
goes with mixy-mix.
[Guy]
...and making new waves.
Love it, brother.
A Colorado college town
hangout.
A disco party,
yes, I want to dance.
[Guy] Still creating a buzz
with their breakfast.
Call the patent office
right now, dude.
That's good.
And a local brewery,
grab the beers and burgers.
You're laying it on there.
-Flavor.
-[Guy] The Minneapolis way.
Living on the edge.
Mmm.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook
flavors.
This is Triple D Nation.
[rock music playing]
[Guy] I'm here
in Pacifica, California
to check out Gorilla Barbecue
served out of this
orange train car.
From what I'm told,
the barbecue is on point.
And the rumors are true.
Do we deliver?
Because since
I was there in 2009,
the lines only got longer.
Mmm.
This is Gorilla Barbecue.
Every time you come
to Gorilla Barbecue,
it's really, really good.
We've been coming here
ever since they opened.
First time they were on
Triple D , we were blown away
because we're like,
"That was our hometown stop.
[man] It's barbecue like
you've never tasted before.
[woman] It's awesome.
Takes a bus to Flavortown.
[laughs]
[Guy] Or in this case,
the train.
[train whistles]
[Guy] 'Cause my buddy,
Rich Bacchi AKA Gorilla,
turned an old
railroad freight car
into a bonafide
barbecue epicenter.
Gorilla Rich.
But our story goes
further back
than just a stop
on the Triple D Express.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the one only Gorilla Rich.
It was 2008.
I mean, yeah, NASCAR.
I'm there with my buddies
and coming down the hill,
there's a larger than life
character
with a cowboy hat on
that was too small,
and he says,
"Hey, I got a barbecue joint
and you gotta come
check it out."
Bought a nice slab
of beef brisket.
We're gonna rub it,
slather it on.
Getting all those little nice
nooks and crannies.
[Guy] Did you just say cranny?
Cranny, yeah.
And then you give it a flip.
You know, you can never have
too much rub on a brisket.
The flavors are rendering down
through the thick layer of fat
that's on the top.
Brisket's ready
to throw in the smoker.
-This is the baby?
-Yes, sir.
Okay.
A nice...
Give it a little sweet talking
"Hey, baby.
You're gonna be pretty
when you're done."
Talks to food.
Sixteen hours.
-There she goes.
-[Gorilla] Look at that.
[Guy] He let this rest
about a half an hour.
[Gorilla] That way, it makes
a little easier to slice.
[Guy]
Look how beautiful that is.
Little crust on that.
The smoke penetrated through.
Mmm. Great bark man.
Nice and tender.
That was great.
[Gorilla] We had to buy a
second smoker after your visit
because
we couldn't keep up.
You guys enjoy.
It's really unbelievable
the volume of food
that we put out of here.
It's 10 times
what it was.
I love it.
[woman] They'll stand in line
and hopefully get
right out of the brisket
by the time they get up here.
It's worth the wait for sure.
[Guy] What did you bring me?
I brought you some ribs,
corn on the cob,
and corn bread.
St. Louis style rib.
[Gorilla]
No. That's a full spare.
-So, you do a full spare.
-Yes.
But we call it
the California cut,
the way my butcher
trims 'em up.
I have my butcher square
'em off,
remove the flank,
peel the silver skin
from the back,
which helps to cooking it.
What we're gonna do now,
give 'em a little
rub-a-dub-dub
with our super combo
spice rub mix.
A little rub-a-dub-dub.
[Guy]
We're making the dry rub.
[Gorilla] We're gonna add the
ground cumin, ground oregano,
garlic powder,
granulated onions,
little salt
from the lovely sea,
some paprika, brown sugar,
and some black pepper.
Now we put it
into the magic mixer.
If this thing had an odometer,
it'd have a million
and half miles on it.
[Guy] Really?
I can hear a...
[wheezing]
Yeah. Sometimes it has
a little rod knock
in the morning when it's cold.
Rod knock.
That's an engine term.
-Yeah.
-[Guy] Rod knock.
[Gorilla] Give it a mixy-mix.
Did you just say "a mixy-mix"?
You can't be Gorilla Barbecue
and say mixy-mix.
All right. We got the super
combo spice rub mix.
I think the rub
is about ready.
-A little tasty-taste.
-Yeah.
A little tasty-taste goes
with mixy-mix.
Little sweet,
little bit of savory.
And we'll give it
a little flip.
More rub.
We're ready to throw 'em
into the smoker.
Two thirty, two forty
for about four to five hours.
The ribs are ready to pull.
Cut them from the back side,
you got a better view
of the bone,
so they're easier to cut.
Look at the juice
running out of it.
A little bit of a smoke ring.
Put a little sauce on it.
Carolina paste.
I love the vinegar. Mmm.
How often do you make
the barbecue sauce?
[Gorilla] Every day.
We're going through
a whole pot daily.
[Guy]
A whole pot that size daily?
-Whole pot every day.
-[whistles]
[Gorilla] For years,
we've only done one sauce.
Some customers ask for
something a little spicier.
So I developed
a new habanero vinegar.
Give a little kick to that
but not blow your face off.
[Guy] I appreciate the not
blowing my face off part.
-Yeah.
-[Guy] This is about
as real deal Carolina house
in Carolina
'cause it's pork,
but it has a little bit
of a Texas attitude.
With the dry rub
that's on it,
it's super simple.
The pork is not competing
with the spices,
nor is it competing
with the smoke.
-It all works together.
-[Guy] Yeah.
I don't know what you're
calling the habanero vinegar,
but don't forget to call me
when it goes on sale, buddy.
[dial tone, rings]
[laughs]
[man] The ribs are nice
and tender
but the end caps have
a little more char to them.
You gotta have barbecue sauce
on everything.
You better bring napkins.
[man 1] I mean, you can just
tear it right off the bone.
It's delicious.
It always has a nice
bark
corn is always good over here.
[Gorilla] We put
a little twist to it.
-We boil fresh corn.
-Okay.
[Gorilla] And then
we roll it in butter
and put a little bit of
the super combo spice rub mix.
Give it a little flavor,
you know,
rather than just buttery corn.
The rub, it's...
You can use it
on everything and anything.
-Delicious corn.
-Thank you.
You know what corn
always gets?
-What's that?
-Not appreciated.
[dramatic music playing]
-True.
-[laughter]
[Guy] But the corn
is not the only thing
getting my attention.
I may have to go home
and shampoo my goatee.
I've got my eye
on a Texas-Philly mash-up.
-Call it southwestern Philly?
-Sure.
[Guy]
And barbecue, Cali style.
Eighty-four racks a day, bro.
No way, man.
Delicious.
[rock music playing]
[Guy] Back in 2009
in Pacifica, California,
I hopped on board this
can't-miss barbecue train.
You'll see it,
a big orange box car
and you could come,
get some pork ribs.
Whoo.
[Guy] Cooked up by
none other than Rich Bacchi,
better known as Gorilla.
Not only
it's the barbecue dine out,
but the character...
You got it daddy-o.
...make the whole meal.
I usually don't get
like a C minus in goatee,
but I mean, that.
Give me jazz hands.
He ain't gonna give me
jazz hands.
[laughs]
Where did the name Gorilla
come from?
From my dad.
As you can see, I'm a little
bigger than normal.
And... See, and I just thought
it was my TV.
Gorilla,
how much you downed in weight?
Probably a hundred pounds ago,
you guys filmed in '08.
-You've gotten married since.
-Yes.
Here you go, papa.
[Guy] You are
the sole proprietor now.
Since 2013, yes, sir.
[man] Rich really knows
what he's doing.
[man 1] Oh, I've had pretty
much everything on the menu.
[man 2] I'd order everything
again that's all wonderful.
[Gorilla] Philly cheese steak
sandwich with smoked brisket.
[Guy] I gotta be honest
with you, brother.
I think Philly cheese steaks
need to come from Philly.
Well, let's give it a whirl
and see what you think.
All right.
I let you do it.
Olive oil. Got some fresh
cut vegetables, onions,
bell peppers, the magic rub.
We use it
to season everything.
Some of the fresh brisket.
Cut a couple real nice pieces.
Barbecue sauce.
I like where you're going
that we got so many flavors
in there.
You call it
southwestern Philly?
Sure. We'll put some cheese
on there, American Swiss.
Put a little lid on there.
Little splash of barbecue.
-Chop it up.
-[Guy] I gotta see
the inside of this thing.
Look at that.
Mmm.
What you do have...
is a fantastic
southwestern
cheese steak sandwich.
Delicious.
May have to go home
and shampoo my goatee.
[Gorilla] I think
I might've changed Guy's mind
on the Philly.
Mmm.
It's real deal barbecue.
You only make what
you're gonna sell
and once it's sold out,
it's done.
Do you have a limit
of what people can order?
Nope. Not at all.
You want 20 racks?
No problem. Here we go.
-We do...
-No problem.
-...84 racks a day bro.
-No way, man.
[laughter]
-[Guy] What's on this?
-[Gorilla] All right.
Now we got some
of my pulled pork.
Break it down for me.
[Gorilla] We like bone
and pork butt
'cause the bone gives
it a little more flavor.
We don't like to trim them.
The fat keeps the pork moist.
Rub it with my super
combo spice rub mix.
Put the butts in
with the fat cap up
because we want the fat to
render down through the meat.
[Guy] And how many butts
are you going through?
Fourteen butts a day.
Cook it for about 14 hours.
Let it rest a little bit
and then we pull it.
We serve it
with the sauce on the side
so you can sauce it
at your discretion.
When did you start using
words like "at my discretion"?
[laughs]
I want you to look
at this smoke ring
that is on that pork.
Dynamite.
Here you go
with some pulled pork.
[man] The smokiness
in his pulled pork is amazing.
It's not overpowering.
It's more subtle.
Perfect.
[woman] It's moist
and it's a little crunchy
on the outside and you have
the real juicy inside.
It pulls apart
and it melts in your mouth.
[Guy] I think the only thing
that we all wish
is that there was like
Gorilla one, Gorilla two,
Gorilla twenty,
Gorilla fifty,
but you just keep doing
what you're doing
-because you're the real deal.
-Thank you, man.
-Love it, brother.
-Appreciate it.
Delicious.
And coming up
in Boulder, Colorado.
I am so out of my element.
Crepes you can't find
anywhere else.
Mmm.
I've never seen this before.
We'll be back
right after this.
[laughter]
Hey.
I'm here in Boulder, Colorado
in the downtown area,
about a five minute walk
north of Colorado University.
Now, Triple D,
we've checked out joints
for tortillas,
pizza, pasta,
chicken wings, cheese steaks,
I mean, you name it.
But we've not yet found
a joint
that's been rocking
the crepe.
Mmm.
Now, I may have eaten
my fair share of crepes
on the show
since that visit in 2011,
but this college crowd
loving spot hasn't changed.
This is Foolish Craig's.
[rock music playing]
[woman] I was a part
of the first filming.
I live in the neighborhood
and it's my go to place.
I know that people saw
that episode
and drove from miles.
[woman 1] Foolish Craig's
is a Boulder institution.
It has been here
for 23 years.
The same amazing food,
the same owners.
[Guy] That's Craig Moelis
and Mitch Arden,
two guys who met
working at a bagel shop.
I was baking bagels and
Mitch was the general manager.
When Guy was here,
we were a pretty busy
breakfast, lunch place,
we had a great time.
He really hit it off
with our chef, Timmy.
I want to go the party now.
I want to go disco party.
Yes, I want to dance.
We're going make a crepe.
The crepes start out
with eggs.
Like a family reunion
in there.
Exactly.
Some milk,
blend these guys up
just a little bit.
[Guy] Makes you want to just
dive right in, doesn't it?
[Timmy]
And I add in the sugar,
a little salt,
and then some melted butter.
[Guy] Is it labor or labor?
-I don't know.
-It's labor.
I only took two years
of French in high school.
[Guy] And now the flour?
-So...
-Oh.
Oh.
We'll be back
right after this.
Welcome back to Diners,
Drive-ins and Dives.
Ugh.
So I didn't wanna do that.
Okay. So, I think...
[Timmy]
We're putting the flour.
-[Guy] Need some help?
-[Timmy] I don't know,
you dropped the whisk
last time.
[trombone plays]
[laughter]
[Guy] You're gonna go
to the mixer.
[Timmy]
Yes. Throw that in there.
[Guy] Ugh, it's clean
the way you work.
[Timmy] It's definitely
a messy process regardless.
Let me just turn this on.
[Guy] I've already learned
why my crepes
are not that good
'cause I don't put in blender.
[Timmy]
Yeah. We like 'em smooth.
Now we'll strain it.
All right. So you got
this thing nice and hot.
You add in your batter.
[Guy] What is this?
[Timmy] That is the
official crepe twirler.
I am so out of my element.
Grab your crepe twirling
device,
spin the batter around
-just like that.
-Awesome.
[Timmy] Work the crepe,
flip the crepe.
Let me get down with this.
-[Timmy] Right in the center.
-[Guy] Here we go.
I think I went
a little too aggressive
in my twirling and spinning.
Oh.
[Guy] This one wasn't that
good there Mary Lou Retton
-[laughter]
-It was funny?
Okay. There's one.
When Guy was here,
he had the Duxelle.
[Timmy] The chicken
Duxelle crepe.
Wow.
That's got a lot
of unique flavor to it.
And the butter rum
caramel crepe cake.
[Timmy] Three crepes down.
[Guy speaking French]
Then we hit it with just
a little bit of the sauce.
So I get your butter
and some brown sugar,
little cream,
little bit of rum.
-[Guy] Wow.
-Three more crepes.
-[Guy] Okay.
-And we just keep doing this.
[Guy] Let it cool
then we frost it.
-Yes.
-[Guy] All right.
[Timmy] Cream cheese frosting.
[Guy] Oh, yeah. Wow. Mmm.
I've never seen this before.
[Timmy] It's a great recipe.
[Guy] Call the patent office
right now, dude.
Mmm. That's good.
[Timmy] Butter rum crepe cake.
When I saw that layered butter
rum crepe cake on Triple D,
I knew it was a done deal.
I had to come here.
[woman] It's one of my
favorite Triple D episodes.
I could not wait
to come back here.
[Craig] So Timmy moved on,
I've kind of taken over
some of his duties
as has Mitch.
Every time I come back,
I see a lot of the same faces
which means they're doing
something right.
[man] It doesn't matter
what time of day,
you can get your crepes.
for your breakfast.
[woman]
The chorizo Benedict
is one of my favorite
breakfast here.
It is so good.
[Mitch] Chorizo Benedict.
So we're gonna put the chorizo
on the grill first
and then we're gonna poke some
eggs while this is cooking,
and those are gonna cook
for three to four minutes.
While our chorizo is going,
we're gonna throw
the English muffins
on the grill for a second.
We're gonna put the chorizo
and the English muffin,
and I'm gonna grab
my poached eggs,
and green chili goes on it.
In order to make
our pork green chili,
we're gonna start with
a little bit of oil,
some garlic, onions,
jalapenos,
salt and pepper,
our green peppers
and tomatoes,
green chilies,
chicken stock,
Worcestershire sauce,
so this is our
slow-braised pork.
And then we're gonna add
a roux with butter and flour.
And we'll just finish this
off with the house potatoes.
And voila, Chorizo Benedict.
[woman] The pork green chili
is great.
When you cut into
the Benedict
and you got the chunk
of the pork
and you got the chorizo,
it's a great blend
of the flavors.
It's nice and spicy
and it's on a muffin
but I also get toasts,
because I like
the fresh breads.
-[Guy] le loaf
-[Timmy] le loaf
-Cut it out.
-[Guy] Mmm, smell that.
[Craig] We had
the oatmeal beer bread.
We make all of our breads
in the house.
Mmm.
-Hey.
-[laughs]
Chicken crepe up.
It kind of exploded
after the episode aired.
[Mitch] It's crazy.
We're just gonna continue
to try to make this
the best place for breakfast
and luncheon time.
[Guy] Coming up.
You wanna drag the turkey
through the garden.
and give me some job
on the drink side.
[Guy] A Minneapolis brewpub
serving local favorites.
Wild Rice in the window.
Ah, that's beautiful.
No matter the obstacle.
I'm blind completely
in one eye
and weakly blind
in the other.
I think you're
an inspiration, man.
[Guy] Back in 2015,
I was in a spot on the
south side of Minneapolis.
Now, I'm here to check out
a joint
that started up
in a crazy way.
Well, they didn't get
startup money from the bank
and they didn't get
startup money from family,
and they didn't go
with Kickstarter.
No, they came up
with a concept called
"beer for life."
And the lucky folks
who jumped on that bandwagon
are still reaping the benefit
because now you can find them
all over town.
That's my kind of joint.
This is Northbound
Smokehouse and Brewpub.
[upbeat music playing]
[woman] It's just
a Minneapolis restaurant
doing great quality food
consistently.
[woman] It's great to have
awesome beer
and great food
in the same place.
[Guy] And it almost
didn't exist.
You said to people that
if you give us
a thousand dollar investment,
we'll give you beer for life?
-Exactly.
-Genius move.
[Jamie]
The free beer drinkers,
they are the true natives
of Northbound.
[Guy] How many people did it?
Uh, 75 people.
Do you not know the crew from
Diners, Drive-ins and Dives?
We could have built
20 of this.
[Jamie] People thought
it was unbelievable.
Now we have some people who
are regretting not buying in.
Really, we just missed
the boat on that one.
[man] I come up
drink beer every week,
it's what keeps me
coming back.
[woman] As a brewpub,
you make your food menu
to pair well with delicious
beer that you're brewing.
[Guy]
The job fell into the hands
of Chef Jason Foster.
And as if that
wasn't hard enough...
I'm blind completely
in one eye
and legally blind
in the other.
What?
How did you learn to cook?
[Jason] Like everybody else.
-[Guy] Smell and taste?
-[Jason] Smell and taste,
that's all you need, and ears.
[Guy] Brother, I am impressed.
We got to do
our 18-hour porketta.
-Let's get after it.
-[Jason] All right.
Fennel seed,
black pepper, salt,
garlic powder,
oregano, basil,
give it a good stir.
[Guy] So we're not going
traditional with the porketta
with the belly
and the whole thing?
[Jason] We are doing
a Boston butt specifically.
Living on the edge.
Let's see this.
[Jason]
Butterfly our Boston butt,
take our dry rub,
next our garlic.
[Guy] You're laying it
on there.
-Flavor.
-Get it, brother.
Fennel.
Drop it more of the fennel
and we just stack at in there
with the 9,000
other ingredients.
You wanna drag the turkey
to the garden
and give me some job
on the drink side.
What do you
wanna do here, buddy?
[Jason] I wanna add
a little more fennels on top.
[Guy] There you go.
That's right.
[Jamie] Next,
our smokehouse flavor
and then we cover it in foil,
and that goes into
the smoker for...
[Guy] Eighteen hours.
Look at that.
[Jason] We are ready
to make a sandwich with it.
Little sautéed onion,
-Swiss.
-[Guy] Steam that up,
-melt the cheese.
-[Jason] That's ready to go.
[Guy] That's beautiful.
[upbeat music playing]
[Guy] Its succulent,
tender pork.
A lot of that big flavor from
the garlic and the fennel.
-Nicely done, chef.
-Thank you. [chuckles]
[man] The smoked porketta
is my favorite.
Delicious, it's great.
[man 1] When I first started
coming here,
uh, it was all about
the porketta.
Nowadays, you know,
they just keep on
keeping the menu fresh.
I'm a carnivore but
I love the Wild Rice Burgers.
Wild Rice with fries.
We start out
with our whipped eggs.
We add our seasonings
to the whisked eggs.
Nobody wants
a cayenne pepper bite.
It's better to add it all
to the liquid egg
and that way you can
get it mixed evenly.
Next, we're adding
our oregano,
salt, pepper,
and we go ahead
and whisk that.
Now, we're gonna make
the base of the patty
with our wild rice,
we add our breadcrumbs,
our smoked cheese,
minced celery, onion,
and last is our garlic.
Our egg with seasonings.
We mix it by hand.
We're gonna make it
into patties.
We do about
six ounce patties,
throw 'em in the oven at 350
degrees for about 50 minutes.
Toast our bun.
Next, we put our patty.
There's a lot of cheese in it
already
but Minnesota,
we love our cheese.
To finish it,
we put garlic mayo,
lettuce,
and tomato on the lid.
And here's Minnesota's
best Wild Rice Burger.
[man] Wild Rice Burger.
[man] The wild rice gives it
a great texture.
There's some kind
of smokiness in there.
Something like this
just really hits the spot.
[woman] The wild rice,
it provides like a nutty,
very flavorful texture
that I'm a big fan of.
[woman] Wild rice
is a Minnesota staple.
It just tastes like home.
[Jason] Are you blind?
[Guy] What? What did you say?
What are you? Blind?
[laughter]
[Jason] Since the show,
we have gotten busy
every time it's aired.
[Jamie] It didn't really have
the capacity
for all the excitement
for the place,
so we, started the food truck.
Anything that we serve here
at the brewpub,
you can have
on the food truck.
[woman] I love
when I'm working downtown
and I see
the Northbound food truck
and I'm like,
"Oh, great, lunch."
We're really proud that
we've become
such a staple for the
community and
the neighborhood,
and we're really happy
to share that
with the rest of the country.
We're breaking
a few rules here.
We're breaking a few rules.
You're the guy
that can break 'em.
I think you're an
inspiration, man.
Corned beef hash.
[Guy] Of course,
these aren't the only
Triple D spots marching to
the beat of their own drum.
-Brisket up.
-All right. Enjoy.
[Guy]
There are loads of joints
busting boundaries
and carving their own path.
And don't worry,
we'll go find them
next time on Triple D Nation.
Let me ask you a question
before we get started.
What do you think
of this blue on me, huh?
How's smashing is this?
-It looks all right.
-Really?
-[laughter]
-I was expecting something
-with a pattern honestly.
-[man] That's right.
[man 1] Okay. All right.