You know, people are asking
me all the time, hey, Guy,
that one joint you
checked out that
one city when you were doing
"Triple-D," how they do it?
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): But
it turns out it was only
the beginning,
because "Triple-D"
joints have been blowing
up, and we're going
back to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip.
What?
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
We've got hearty--
Mm.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--heaping--
Mm.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--helpings.
We're going to have
trouble eating all those.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
A Pittsburgh
joint serving local staples.
SERVER: Sausage,
biscuits, and gravy.
This is what we grew up with.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
And family favorites.
That's one of the surprise
dishes I've had on "Triple-D."
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
A diner in Florida--
Did you say glob?
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--getting their inspiration
from up North.
I feel like I'm
back home again.
I just can't get enough
of that matzo ball.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
And in Oklahoma.
[chuckles] I love it.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): A second
generation churning out chili
that would make dad proud.
SERVER: Frito chili pie.
It's dynamite, man.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off the hook flavors.
This is "Triple-D Nation."
[music playing]
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Back in 2009,
I met this self-taught
diner owner who
dove headfirst into the biz.
Took out a small loan
and bought a little joint
in a strip mall, and turned it
into a neighborhood favorite.
KELLY O'CONNOR: Here
you are, ladies.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Now she's the number one
choice in two different hoods.
Got to check out KellyO's.
COOK: Plating the polenta.
Sausage, gravy
and biscuits up.
"Triple-D" and KellyO's
are a match made in heaven.
Perfect comfort food diner.
She was big before
"Triple-D" came to town.
Her legend just grew after that.
KELLY O'CONNOR: Here's your
KellyO's Pittsburgh chili.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): He's
talking about the one and only
Kelly O'Connor--
Kelly O, O, O.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): --a
fearless waitress turned
diner owner who threw
caution to the wind.
You come in.
You don't have any real
culinary experience.
You've been in the
restaurant industry forever.
And then you say, I'm just
going to open up my joint
and start serving
things I like to eat.
Yeah.
Nice to see you.
How long ago was it?
2009.
You're one of the original
gangsters of this whole thing.
I meet people all the
time, they'll say,
yeah, I went to that
funky little place.
It's out in Pittsburgh.
And I go KellyO's,
and it's like, yeah.
And I had the noodle
dish with the ka--
yeah, the haluski.
Yeah.
How long have you
been making this dish?
My whole life.
Some butter in there.
GUY FIERI: Some regular onions.
KELLY O'CONNOR:
Boil the cabbage.
GUY FIERI: Just cooks.
No salt in the water, anything?
KELLY O'CONNOR: No.
Nothing like a hot
warm cabbage facial.
Oh, I agree.
You ever try those
in the morning?
I agree.
It's great for pores.
And then just cut it.
Are you going to cut it for me?
Whatever you want
there's sunshine.
KELLY O'CONNOR: OK.
Just julienne it. in there.
There you go.
Put it right in there.
In the pool?
Yeah.
it will caramelize.
It will turn like
brown, you know.
Dig it.
Garlic salt, bacon.
Lots of bacon.
GUY FIERI: How
much goes in here?
KELLY O'CONNOR: 10 ounces
of cooked chopped bacon.
GUY FIERI: I'm already
liking what I'm seeing.
Once you have it,
you won't forget it.
GUY FIERI: So some egg noodles
that are cooked al dente.
KELLY O'CONNOR: Just a
little Romano cheese.
GUY FIERI: You going to
hit a little bit on there?
Oh.
The first time I
ever had haluski.
That's one of the surprise
dishes I've had on "Triple-D."
That's exactly what I would
want to eat every day.
Really?
I'm making this
weekend when I get home.
I took haluski back
to California, made it
for my friends,
and everybody said
there's no way it can taste this
great, and it is that great.
Mom, I found a new haluski.
She's going to spank your
cabooski when she finds
out you love this haluski.
[laughs]
How are things at KellyOs?
Give me the rundown.
Well, since haluski, we have
made like a Pittsburgh platter
with haluski, and
pierogies, and kielbasa.
And then we have a Pittsburgh
chili, just a version of chili
with no beans, a lot of meat.
Pittsburgh chili up.
KELLY O'CONNOR: Our
homemade Pittsburgh
chili is made with hot sausage.
We make it here in house,
a little bit of pepper,
a little bit of fennel,
sage, red pepper flake,
and it has a nice
kick spice to it.
We add ground chuck, green
pepper, red pepper, onion,
spices, chili powder,
cumin, red pepper
flake, and then once that
simmers, we add tomato sauce.
We serve our Pittsburgh
chili with a little side
of cornbread.
Pittsburgh chili.
It's a little bit spicy, but
no other seasoning is needed.
The flavors are so
perfectly married.
It's unbelievable.
You got three generations
working in the same joint.
You got your daughter
working here,
you got your son working
here, your mom's working here.
This is Judy, this
is Kelly's mom.
Hi.
Nice to meet you.
Hi, camera.
It's a family atmosphere.
They're going to recognize you.
That's what you want in a place.
My whole family
comes down here to eat.
It's just wonderful
warm place to go.
You are definitely one of the
"Triple-D" family favorites.
KELLY O'CONNOR: I
came from a big family
so I love making family recipes.
It's like grandmas
in the kitchen cooking.
Now, what else do you make?
I make fried mush.
My grandmother served
fried mush for breakfast.
You know what mush is?
Polenta.
I know what polenta is.
You call it mush?
Let's get it going.
A little bit of
salt, your polenta.
I'm in the stirring mode.
You want me to make
motorboat jumps?
KELLY O'CONNOR: Yeah.
Stir it.
Stir it, get it really thick,
and then you loaf pan it.
Cooled down.
Yup.
Slice it, deep fry
it until it's crispy.
Now what do you put on yours?
KELLY O'CONNOR:
Butter and syrup.
Butter and syrup on polenta?
Yeah, it's a breakfast.
I grew up, my grandmother
served it with syrup.
Oh, wow.
What?
Don't put that on mine.
I'm putting syrup on mine.
Oh, taste a little tiny
baby taste with syrup.
Quit it.
This is how you get it
going, with some bacon.
Mm.
Oh no.
Way better.
KELLY O'CONNOR:
After Guy showed me
how to do the fried mush with
the bacon, I put it on my menu
and people love it.
Guy's mush, table 12.
She makes the best polenta.
It's actually better
than my grandmother's.
All the items that we did
on "Triple-D," it has its own
specific section on the menu.
People come, they
want to try it.
Because Guy loved
it, they love it.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Loved it
so much, she had to multiply--
I have two.
Oh, you're big
shotting it now.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): --and
make way for more on the menu.
That's winner, winner,
jerky pot pie dinner.
Sausage, gravy,
and biscuits up.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Next.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
I'm in Pittsburgh,
PA hanging with a self-taught
chef I met back in 2009.
Kelly O, O, O.
We were just getting started.
What were you, a year old then?
You're like one of
the OGs, an owner
with a lot of
personality, a restaurant
with a great following
and unique food, food
that we don't see everywhere.
I've been cooking all my life,
I've never heard of haluski.
These things that Kelly
has on her menus, this
is what we grew up with.
Not only does Kelly have,
you know, normal food,
but she has some
off the wall items.
COOK: Platter up.
GUY FIERI: Tell me about
turkey pot pie soup.
Start with a bone-in,
breast of turkey.
What do you do to
the turkey to roast it?
Um, nothing.
I didn't have any
culinary training.
You can just accentuate
this a little bit.
KELLY O'CONNOR: So I didn't
know all of the tricks
and the magic little secrets.
Make a little
bit of a dry rub.
A little seasoning salt,
little bit of parsley,
basil in, that won't hurt us.
Paprika, garlic powder.
KELLY O'CONNOR: I
was really honored
that he would take the time
to show me a few tricks
that he has.
I don't debling
just for everybody.
Now you get up underneath
that turkey skin, like this.
KELLY O'CONNOR: All right, yeah.
GUY FIERI: See how the
seasoning is sitting
off, sitting on the meat.
I'll go ahead and
throw some onions down
in there, carrots in there.
KELLY O'CONNOR:
We roast 3 and 1/2
hours, get it nice and golden
brown, boil off the carcass.
GUY FIERI: With all the
veggies that we roasted,
simmer in a bunch of water.
Get a little flavor
in the broth, strain it.
GUY FIERI: Now we're left
with our turkey stock.
KELLY O'CONNOR: I add
the celery and onions.
How long is this going
to sit there and simmer?
10 minutes?
Now ready for the potatoes?
Frozen vegetables in.
GUY FIERI: That's a
heaping helping, huh?
I'll give it to you on
the frozen veggie thing
because that's kind
of what people expect.
All the turkey that we
pick from the bones,
we'll make a little roux.
OK, ready?
Now we're going to go down.
It's thickening up.
That's just my two cents.
I like your two cents.
And we still use
that to this day.
I made pie crust.
GUY FIERI: Mm, that's just
creamy goodness right there.
I mean, that tastes
like a baked--
Pot pie?
Yeah, that's winner,
winner, turkey pot pie dinner.
Thank you.
Good job.
Turkey pot pie
soup, it's phenomenal.
Really, really one
of my favorites.
You just keep evolving, you're
just going to keep getting
bigger, and badder, and better.
Rumor has it, you've
done another one.
Yep.
KellyO's in the strip.
So I'm right in the heart of the
strip district of Pittsburgh,
which is now
booming and growing.
Super awesome to have
KellyO's in the city down here.
Both locations are
packed constantly.
That's for a reason.
Oh, you're big
shotting it now.
I like it.
Take it and run with it, sister.
It's been a blessing.
I'm so happy to hear that.
It's been such a blessing.
And what are the
big hits on the menu?
KELLY O'CONNOR: Sausage,
gravy, and biscuits.
That's your claim to fame?
KELLY O'CONNOR: Here's your
sausage, gravy, and biscuits.
My papa handed down this recipe.
We use our homemade
sweet sausage.
We add fresh thyme,
the heavy cream,
and then we tighten
it up with the slurry.
Our biscuits are made in house.
We start off with
flour, sugar, salt,
baking powder, cream
of tartar, and then we
incorporate the frozen butter.
And then add your
egg, buttermilk,
and mix that all together.
You pat that out, and
then you cut your biscuits
and bake them at 450.
Sausage, biscuits, and gravy.
She makes her own sausage.
It's perfectly seasoned.
It's delicious.
Sausages like all
into the white sauce,
and her biscuits are homemade,
and they're really fluffy.
You don't even need
butter on them.
It's so yummy.
GUY FIERI: Great
story, great visit.
KELLY O'CONNOR: It's
been an amazing journey.
Just unbelievable.
The people from
all over the world.
Dude, I'm world famous.
You are world famous.
You are.
I'm world famous.
You did it.
I appreciate you guys.
Mwah.
KellyO's.
[laughs]
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Coming up--
[laughs]
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): --a
fan favorite in Florida--
It's the real deal.
Show's kind of right here.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): --still
serving up New York staples.
I haven't had
a lot of knishes,
but the ones that I've had
do not compare to that.
Delicious.
Here are your latkes.
Enjoy.
You know, diners come
in every shape or size.
I think we've seen that as
we toured with "Triple-D"
around the country.
We've seen our freestanding ones
and the ones in strip malls.
Today, I got a combo
joint, a diner bakery deli.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
This place
was dishing out
traditional Jewish foods
with serious New York cred.
It's the real deal.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
And since 2009, they've
blown up all around the state.
We've got to
check out Flakowitz.
[music playing]
As a "Triple-D" die hard,
I saw Guy came to Flakowitz,
and I started coming.
Didn't steer me wrong.
Everything's so good.
Being a boy that grew
up in Brooklyn where
all this type of
food is famous, I
feel like I'm back home again.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Which makes
sense because owner, Robert
Pirozzi, is from New York too.
I wanted to move to Florida.
So I called my dad and
asked him to come down.
I wanted to get him
out of the cold.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
You wanted to get
him out of the cold,
or you just knew that that
madman could bake anything.
ROBERT PIROZZI: Correct.
GUY FIERI: Because
your pops was one
of the premier Jewish
pastry bakers in the area.
Without a doubt.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
That would be Angelo.
You know how to skip.
- Yeah.
- You remember?
OK.
So let's skip.
[laughter]
Before you guys
came, my father had
no clue what "Triple-D" was.
He just thought it
was just another one
of my harebrained schemes.
[laughs]
And we're going
to make the knishes.
This is pre-boil.
I'm going to start chopping
them into little sections.
Add the onions to it.
This is the white
pepper, garlic.
GUY FIERI: I call
that vitamin G.
Yeah, OK.
And this is a salt.
GUY FIERI: All right, be quiet.
I heard you.
[chuckles]
ANGELO PIROZZI: Now
this is the butter.
I'm not going to
put all of it in.
I'm going to cube
this up a little bit.
I didn't think we're
putting it all in.
We might as well.
So what temperature this
is going to be in the oven?
About 350, 375.
[laughter]
GUY FIERI: Where-- the show--
the show's kind of right here.
My father, he just wanted
to get the work done,
and Guy was fooling
around with him.
ANGELO PIROZZI: We're going
to put the potato mixture.
GUY FIERI: Into
the mixture, right.
ANGELO PIROZZI: We
put the sour cream in.
GUY FIERI: So are we done now?
ANGELO PIROZZI:
Yeah, this is done.
It's mixed enough?
ANGELO PIROZZI: I'm going to
take one piece of phyllo dough,
at a time coated
with butter, fold it,
and then you're going to
put a nice glob in there.
GUY FIERI: Did you say glob?
I like that.
OK, let me jump in here.
ANGELO PIROZZI: Very good,
should we sign them up or what?
Beautiful, Guy.
And then I wash it with eggs.
GUY FIERI: To get a nice sheen?
ANGELO PIROZZI: Right.
GUY FIERI: It'll go in the oven.
ANGELO PIROZZI: For
about 20 minutes.
GUY FIERI: We're going to
have trouble eating all this.
Is there a method
of eating it or?
ANGELO PIROZZI: Try
with a little mustard.
Delicious.
I haven't had a lot of knishes,
but the ones that I've had,
do not compare to that.
Oh, thank you.
Since the last time
you guys were here,
my dad, he's
retired, but we sell
more knishes than we can make.
It's fantastic.
So we saw the potato
knishes on the first episode,
and we said OK, what
else does he have
in the potato end of the world?
SERVER: And here
your latkes, enjoy.
The latkes are
out of this world.
Truthfully, I love them.
ROBERT PIROZZI: To
do our potato latke,
you get the boiled potatoes
and then white onions.
We grind them in
the Buffalo chopper
and we add white pepper,
salt, and garlic powder.
And we grind that up until
we get the right consistency.
Through that, we're going to
add eggs, matzo mill, and flour.
And we're going to
mix that until it's
a very smooth consistency.
We're going to spoon
them out and fry them
until they're a golden brown.
SERVER: Here are your latkes.
Very fresh on the inside,
very crispy on the outside,
and very delicious
to your palate.
It's a traditional
Jewish food.
Is a little bit
like a hash brown.
So thick, it's amazing.
ROBERT PIROZZI: Last
time Guy was here,
we made traditional Jewish
dishes, stuffed cabbage.
Mm, we have matzo ball soup,
Mm, I just can't get
enough of that matzo ball.
There are so many
different things.
You sit down and
look at the menu,
and you say, what am
I going to do today?
The sloppy Joe here at
Flakowitz is delicious.
ROBERT PIROZZI:
Our sloppy Joe is
not like a regular sloppy Joe.
It's more like a Reuben
and it's a big mess.
[chuckles]
To make corned beef, we boil
brisket with a pickling spice,
and then we put it in the
steamer for three, four hours.
To make our
sandwich, we're going
to take four ounces
of corned beef
and four ounces of pastrami,
take a dollop of coleslaw,
and put it right in
the middle, and then
we're going to roll it.
Then we're going to take some
Russian dressing and Swiss
cheese, put it on the sandwich.
Here's your sloppy Joe on rye.
Corned beef and pastrami
is tender, not overly spiced,
but just a combination of
different types of textures
and really delicious.
The pastrami and the corned
beef are actually very light.
And it's lean meat, and
it's just very, very tasty.
It's just like you would get
in a great New York restaurant.
He was able to bring that
right here to South Florida.
Since 2009, the
business has rocketed.
We've opened up five cafes,
another location in Boca Raton.
What a pleasure.
What a great place.
Thank you very
much, appreciate it.
Thank you very much.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
And coming up in Oklahoma,
a family dinner featuring
their award-winning chili--
Two-time state champ.
Mm.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): --on
all kinds of creations.
There's a chili dog.
SERVER: Frito chili pie.
MAN: Chili on the fries.
It's all so great.
You know, one of my favorite
things about doing "Triple-D"
is cruising Main Street, Main
Street of small town America.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
That was back
in 2009 in Norman,
Oklahoma, where
I found the Main Street Diner
serving up more than just eggs.
Southside Burger.
You get A in chili
cheese fries, student.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Now,
a new generation's taking
over the family-run joint.
Welcome to the diner
they call The Diner.
"Triple-D" came
down here, and I can
tell you it's
definitely a place that
is worth being on their show.
It's just that place where
you feel like you're home
and you're part of a community.
It really is its own
little family-run business.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): A family
that was run by this character,
Mark Amspacher.
Think it's going to be hot?
It's a hot dog.
Two men enter.
One man leaves.
Welcome to The
Diner Thunderdome.
Dude, that's winner,
winner hot-dog dinner.
[laughs] I love it.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Sadly,
Mark passed away in 2010.
But his legacy isn't forgotten,
thanks to his daughter, Bonnie.
My dad had very definite
opinions about food.
And he taught me all his
secrets and all the recipes,
like burgers--
SERVER: I've got a
chicken-fried steak.
--and chili.
Award-winning chili.
Oh, I like how you
threw that in so smooth.
Well, you know.
5 pounds of ground beef.
A little 80-20?
So you're gonna cook
that meat down first?
No.
It's all gonna mesh together.
Some diced tomatoes.
We're just gonna
dump everything in?
Yep.
That's how we do it.
Two-times Oklahoma
State chili champion.
Then I will stand down.
I wouldn't question.
I--
You know?
We're gonna to put about
a cup of dark chili powder
in there, fresh pureed garlic.
You can't make
chili without some--
MARK AMSPACHER: Cumino.
GUY FIERI: --cumin.
I like where this is going.
I mean, you got all the
right ingredients in here.
Where's the heat coming?
We're gonna any heat?
Oh, there we go.
Crushed red.
Whoa, I love
your real precise,
scientific measurements.
Thank you.
Salt, ground black
pepper, a little sugar.
Put the buffer on.
Smoothing it out.
Now, kick this around,
get it started.
And you want to try
and keep it covered.
About 2 hours into
cooking, I like
to put a couple more tablespoons
of each of the spices
to be sure it's nice and tasty.
3 hours later, this
is what you get.
GUY FIERI: Look at that, man.
There you go.
There's chili.
Mm.
It's dynamite, man.
You know what I'm talking about?
MARK AMSPACHER: I'm hearing you.
You're picking up
what I'm laying down?
I'm smelling what
you're stepping in.
That's kind of the
Oklahoma version of picking
what I'm laying down.
MARK AMSPACHER: There you go.
My dad was really
proud of his chili.
A little bit of heat in that.
A little.
And he was happy to get
to show it to America.
That's really good chili, bro.
And now it's also
on the Indian taco.
If you're from
Norman, Oklahoma,
you know that The
Diner's a great place
to get an Indian taco.
It's so delicious.
It's a favorite.
I just love the frybread.
It's a simple dough,
flour, baking powder,
salt, and warm milk.
We mix that up and let it
proof for a couple hours.
Once it's proofed, we can now
roll it out and flatten it.
We'll put the frybread into the
fryer until it's golden brown.
Once the frybread is done, we're
ready to assemble our taco.
We start with our
house-made beans.
Then we'll add our
world-famous chili.
We'll top it with some
onions, cheese, and lettuce,
a little more cheese
and some tomato,
green onion, and jalapeno.
Indian taco.
The Indian taco?
Nice, zesty, not too
spicy, good amount of meat,
and a really delicious meal.
I'd recommend it.
The richness of that
bread-- and it's kind of like
the texture of a
freshly made doughnut,
then the beans and chili.
It's all so great.
Your leading character in
this, of course, is that chili,
two-time state champ.
After the show aired,
we were really busy.
I didn't ever imagine
that it would be such,
like, a huge onslaught.
It brought a lot of people
in from all over the place.
I'm here at least weekly.
I feel a real sense of
connection with my dad,
cooking his food
in this building.
And he was happy that
Guy liked his cooking.
And it meant a lot to him.
You gonna [inaudible]
spark that Camaro?
We'll be here for a week.
Sure.
Nice job, brother.
Here you go, folks.
MARK AMSPACHER: But
those are the only places
dishing out hearty helpings
of your favorite foods.
Sausage gravy and biscuits up.
We got plenty more
joints to look back on all
over the "Triple-D" nation.
Interesting.
Maybe we could open up a spa.
All right, after it's
actually baked, we put it in--
He's not even going
to pay attention
to any of my one-liners.
Just right past him.
[laughter]
He's a jet liner,
and I'm a pigeon.
Just a-- whoo.
All right.