Hey there. I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
[theme music]
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
This trip--
[laughter]
--it's a Fairbanks,
Alaska adventure--
GUY FIERI: That'll
stick to your bones.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): --filled
with a world of flavor.
GUY FIERI: If you don't stop
me, I'll eat the whole thing.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Like
a jamming Cuban joint--
GUY FIERI: Bring the whole
family down for this one, huh?
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--classic American comfort--
GUY FIERI: It takes you
right back to a log cabin
hanging out with grandma.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--and a funky food trailer--
GUY FIERI: Wow.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): --driving
you straight into Germany.
GUY FIERI: I'm just
trying to figure out how
to get more of it into my face.
That's all right here,
right now on "Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives."
[theme music]
[music playing]
So I'm here in Fairbanks, Alaska
with the one and only Benny Lin
from Pagoda Restaurant.
BENNY LIN: I want to
take you to this place.
Moi Moi, she used
to work for me.
Oh, so we're going to
a Chinese restaurant.
No.
Her friends, they partnered
together and opened this place.
She also worked at
the hospital before.
OK.
So it's a Chinese
place by the hospital.
- No, no, no.
- OK.
No, no.
And those two,
they love tequila.
They--
GUY FIERI: Wait, wait, wait.
So it's a Chinese
restaurant by the hospital
that serves tequila?
No, no, no.
They have a place
called Salty's On 2nd.
This is Salty's On 2nd.
I'm so confused.
[music playing]
MONICA KISSINGER: Crab-stuffed
mushrooms ready to go.
SALTY'S CUSTOMER 1:
Salty's is a great hotspot
here in Fairbanks.
I got a biscuit and gravy up.
My favorite time to come
here if for breakfast,
but I definitely love their
lunch and dinner as well.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
But things actually
began with brunch, when owners
Vanessa Stebbins and Monica
Kissinger set out to
pair scratch-made food
with boozy drinks.
GUY FIERI: So Benny says this
is a great place to come.
Says you girls like tequila.
That's how we got
the name Salty's.
VANESSA STEBBINS: We both
have worked in the bar
business for close to 20 years.
Just started with us wanting
to do something on our own.
Everyone in town knows
Monica and Vanessa.
SALTY'S CUSTOMER 2: I knew
that they'd do a great job.
MONICA KISSINGER:
Meatball subs in the oven.
The meatball sub, it's
really, really, really good.
Their marinara sauce is
just absolutely amazing.
The bread is always soft.
You definitely need
two hands to pick it up.
They are huge.
GUY FIERI: All right, chef.
What's the game plan?
We're going to make
our homemade bread
for the meatball sub.
GUY FIERI: You don't bake bread.
I cook rice.
[laughter]
MONICA KISSINGER:
We're going to put
the power flour into the bowl.
GUY FIERI: Don't let it
fall on the floor, Benny.
MONICA KISSINGER: Wheat
flour, granulated garlic--
GUY FIERI: Interesting.
MONICA KISSINGER:
--sugar, salt, yeast.
GUY FIERI: Where did you
get this recipe from?
From my grandma.
We just mix it around,
and then I'm going
to start putting the water in.
GUY FIERI: Let this go
[inaudible] in the bowl.
Yep.
Now we add oil and
mix it a little more.
Leave it in the bowl
for about 45 minutes,
and then it rests on the table
for about another 45 minutes.
GUY FIERI: Then
we'll portion it.
MONICA KISSINGER: And
put it in our fridge.
This is after it's
been sitting overnight.
Go ahead, Benny.
BENNY LIN: Gentle, huh?
MONICA KISSINGER: Gentle.
And then just roll it.
BENNY LIN: Oh, OK.
MONICA KISSINGER: Yeah.
Cornmeal, and on the tray.
Once they're proofed,
into the oven--
MONICA KISSINGER: 20 minutes.
GUY FIERI: Next, meatballs?
We got our ground pork.
GUY FIERI: 80-20 ground beef.
House-made bread that
we soak in milk, onion,
parsley, Parmesan cheese.
GUY FIERI: A lot of it.
Wow.
MONICA KISSINGER: Eggs,
granulated garlic,
fennel, pepper, and salt.
GUY FIERI: Benny,
go get your gloves.
You gotta make meatballs.
- All-- all right.
All right.
MONICA KISSINGER: Ball it up.
- Just like that?
- Yeah.
And it goes in our
oven 20 minutes.
You make your own
tomato sauce too?
Yes.
GUY FIERI: Everything.
I should just quit
asking if they make it.
MONICA KISSINGER:
We're gonna start
with the oil, fresh
garlic, onion,
pepper, oregano, salt, sugar.
GUY FIERI: Let that
caramelize a little bit.
MONICA KISSINGER:
Crushed tomatoes.
How long are we
gonna let this cook?
MONICA KISSINGER: Four hours.
- Build the sandwich.
Yep.
We take our house-made
bun, add a little bit
of provolone cheese, meatballs,
marinara, mozzarella,
and then it goes in the oven.
GUY FIERI: Just to
melt the cheese.
MONICA KISSINGER: Yes.
GUY FIERI: Now
watch this, Benny.
I'll show you how to do this.
- I'm ready.
You ready?
[laughter]
BENNY LIN: Wow, Monica.
MONICA KISSINGER:
Usually calls me Moi Moi.
BENNY LIN: "Moi Moi"
in Chinese is "sister."
GUY FIERI: I gotta
tell you something.
That bread with that little
garlic kick, that's dynamite.
Meatballs are tender.
Got great texture.
Sauce is delicious,
this really nice tomato.
It's legit.
I mean, I could
easily be in an East
Coast sub shop getting this.
BENNY LIN: Good job.
- Thank you.
- Can I order that thing to go?
- Sure.
Please.
Well done.
SALTY'S CUSTOMER 1: The
meatballs are spiced perfectly.
Nice zesty marinara sauce.
It's killer.
It is killer.
MONICA KISSINGER:
Trudy's Pizza for Liz.
SALTY'S CUSTOMER 3: Salty's is
definitely my favorite place
to come in Fairbanks.
I'm happy to bring
my kids here with us,
but then when we want to have
an adult time in the evenings,
it's a great place to come.
SALTY'S CUSTOMER 4: They
turn this place into a club.
Vanessa's husband
actually is the DJ.
- It gets going.
All right.
- Yeah.
SALTY'S CUSTOMER 5:
When you enter in here,
it's always very
warm and inviting,
and the food is very
hearty and homey.
I have your chicken pot pie.
SALTY'S CUSTOMER 2: The
gravy on the chicken pot pie
is my favorite.
SALTY'S CUSTOMER
3: I actually think
the amount of crust to the
rest of the dish is fantastic.
Chicken pot pie.
MONICA KISSINGER: We
start with our chicken.
Season it up with a
little bit of oil.
Stuff it with some butter,
garlic, crushed red peppers,
rosemary, salt and
pepper, little thyme.
GUY FIERI: OK.
In the oven.
350 for--
MONICA KISSINGER:
Hour and 15 minutes.
GUY FIERI: All right.
So we pulled the chicken.
We're going to make our stock.
Water, bones and scraps from
the chicken that we cooked off--
GUY FIERI: Got it.
--scraps from the kitchen--
bay leaf, carrots, cabbage,
onions, garlic, celery.
GUY FIERI: Let this simmer down
now four hours, five hours?
Seven hours.
Overachiever.
MONICA KISSINGER: Now we're
going to make our filling.
Chicken stock, carrots,
celery, onion, house spice mix.
Add the chicken.
GUY FIERI: Once this
comes to a boil--
MONICA KISSINGER: Thicken
it up with our slurry.
GUY FIERI: And then
drop in your potatoes.
That'll cool it down.
Next?
We're going to make
the crust for on top.
Start with our lard.
GUY FIERI: Looks like we're
getting to make biscuits.
Kind of, yeah.
BENNY LIN: It does.
Mind your own biscuits
and life will be gravy.
MONICA KISSINGER:
Flour, salt, ice water--
GUY FIERI: She wants
it shortening cold
so the shortening will stay
separated inside of the flour
so when she makes it
it creates layers.
Oh.
MONICA KISSINGER: Roll it
out, cut it into circles,
put it in the oven.
Then we got our pot pie filling.
GUY FIERI: [whistle]
- Wow.
MONICA KISSINGER: Pull it
out, and it's ready to go
on top of the chicken pot pie.
Crumbly, crusty.
[music playing]
Moi Moi, one thing that really
says something is a pie,
you need a pie crust.
When you bust into this
and you let that soak up
all that filling, it takes
you right back to a log cabin
hanging out with grandma.
When you say that you're going
to put a pot pie on a menu,
better taste like that.
Definitely.
GUY FIERI: Deconstructed
chicken pot pie.
Of all that I've had, this
sits at the top of the menu.
MONICA KISSINGER:
Chicken pot pie up.
The gravy has
fantastic flavor to it.
SALTY'S CUSTOMER 6: The
crust, it's so crispy.
GUY FIERI: Just legit?
It's perfect.
We have your
loaded avocado toast.
SALTY'S CUSTOMER 7:
I am a Salty's fan.
It's like my second home.
[laughter]
It's like you and
Vanessa got together
and said let's make
the kind of food
we like for all of our friends.
Let's have a really good time.
Proud of you guys.
- Thanks.
GUY FIERI: Everybody, by
the way, when you come,
ask for Moi Moi.
- That's Moi Moi.
[music playing]
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Up next
in our Fairbanks food fest--
GUY FIERI: Look at that.
Gorgeous.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--from spaetzle to pretzels--
Hand-made all day.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--totally legit German--
GUY FIERI: It's
beyond delicious.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): --coming
out of a surprising spot.
GUY FIERI: This is what "Triple
D" is all about, my friend--
funky joints like this.
[theme music]
[music playing]
Well folks, I'm
doing what I do best.
That's right, cruise
around random parking
lots in a convertible on a cold
day here in Fairbanks, Alaska.
Now I'm looking for funky
joints, but I got to be honest.
This one might be
a little too funky.
Now my buddy Benny
told me don't worry--
the food's legit.
He's serving up
German specialty food.
This is Mein Diner.
Guten appetit!
Oh boy.
[yodeling music]
[music playing]
I put the
schnitzel in the pan.
MEIN DINER CUSTOMER
1: Mein Diner
is one of my absolute
favorite places to eat.
KONRAD BOLZ: I got the
currywurst done too.
MEIN DINER CUSTOMER 2: It's
amazing authentic German food
right in Fairbanks, Alaska.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Which
comes from Konrad Bolz.
Guten appetit.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Worked
25 years in his family's
restaurant in Germany,
but eventually he
answered the call of the wild.
[wolf howling]
GUY FIERI: What did you
do when you came here?
I trained dogs
Wow.
All of a sudden you
just said I'm going
to put a kitchen in a trailer?
Yeah.
I was thinking go
back to my roots.
GUY FIERI: Make your food
the way you want to do it.
KONRAD BOLZ: Yes sir.
Here's the spaetzle
is on the way.
MEIN DINER CUSTOMER 1:
Spaetzle is actually
my absolute favorite dish here.
MEIN DINER CUSTOMER 3:
It's like German macaroni
and cheese almost,
except it's got the gravy
on it, which is amazing.
GUY FIERI: What are we
going to make today?
My gravy for the spaetzle.
- Spaetzle.
- Yes.
GUY FIERI: I don't say it that
way, but I love "spat-zle."
KONRAD BOLZ: First
we make the pork.
GUY FIERI: Score the skin
so we can get down in there.
KONRAD BOLZ: Caraway seeds.
GUY FIERI: Don't get
carried away with that.
[laughter]
KONRAD BOLZ: Salt,
smoked paprika, garlic.
Then put it nicely on the pork.
And now the mustard.
GUY FIERI: A little
southern barbecue
rubbing with the
mustard game going here.
We're going to sear
this in the pot?
Yes.
Chicken broth, bay leaves,
fresh thyme, the crushed garlic,
a little bit more mustard.
GUY FIERI: Last but not least?
KONRAD BOLZ: Pickle juice.
[whistle] And let this simmer?
KONRAD BOLZ: Around three hours.
I do cornstarch--
GUY FIERI: To tighten that up.
KONRAD BOLZ: --then
I just shred it up.
GUY FIERI: Just what you thought
it was going to be-- pork
mustard caraway gravy sauce.
That'll stick to your bones.
Then we go for the spaetzle.
Regular flour, kosher
salt, whole eggs.
And you got to slap this
thing until the dough
creates bubbles.
[laughter]
GUY FIERI: I have been making
spaetzle wrong forever.
KONRAD BOLZ: This one goes in.
It's boiling.
GUY FIERI: Look at that.
Little pearls of pasta
right there, folks.
KONRAD BOLZ: That's it.
For service, you'll
heat it up in butter.
KONRAD BOLZ: Little butter.
Or a lot of butter.
KONRAD BOLZ: This is a
mixed shredded cheese--
Asiago Parmesano.
GUY FIERI: Is everything
made to order,
or do you hold any food hot?
Everything to order.
This is maybe a little
bit sometimes my bummer.
My bummer.
[laughter]
KONRAD BOLZ: Spaetzle
slightly brown.
Wow.
KONRAD BOLZ: Konrad's gravy,
and you are ready to enjoy.
[music playing]
GUY FIERI: It's
beyond delicious.
It's the mustard
right off the bat,
a little bit of the pickle.
The pork's tender.
It's creamy.
It's not heavy.
The depth of flavor, the
creativity, the textures.
I'm just trying to figure
out how to get more of it
into my face.
I'm in a car trailer.
What this is deserves
to be in a restaurant.
What a delicious dish.
[music playing]
KONRAD BOLZ: Spaetzle
ready to roll.
MEIN DINER CUSTOMER 4: The
spaetzle is extremely tender.
The pork sauce in it
is just to die for.
It's a very warm
and comforting food
for the winter time especially.
You're open all
year round unless it
gets what temperature?
15 below is my cutoff.
I shut down.
Stuff breaks.
Yeah.
KONRAD'S SON: Dad,
we got one brat.
OK, my son.
I get it going.
GUY FIERI: This guy's legit?
Oh, very.
Yeah.
GUY FIERI: I can't say the
trailer's anything to look at.
It's the quality that
comes out of the trailer.
Always really good.
Two salty pretzels going in.
Excellent German pretzels.
Salted, cheesy, whichever
way you like it.
GUY FIERI: What
are we making now?
The pretzel dough.
GUY FIERI: Let's get into it.
KONRAD BOLZ: Water,
and not too hot.
You don't want
to kill the yeast.
The sugar.
GUY FIERI: Yeast
loves the sugar.
KONRAD BOLZ: Salt.
Just a little bit mix.
Melted butter.
And now?
KONRAD BOLZ: The flour.
GUY FIERI: All-purpose?
KONRAD BOLZ: Caputo.
So a little more chew to it.
KONRAD BOLZ: A little bit in.
GUY FIERI: No recipe.
I do have a basic recipe.
- It's all up here.
- Yeah.
Right.
Crazy man.
KONRAD BOLZ: Add
step by step flour
until your dough has
the right consistency.
And then you have to
let it rise for 3 hours.
Make our portions.
GUY FIERI: I want to see
how he does the old spin.
[laughter]
This one, right?
GUY FIERI: Beautiful.
Once they proof,
they go to the water.
And anything in the water?
KONRAD BOLZ: Baking soda.
GUY FIERI: That
gives a little bit
of that sheen on the outside.
KONRAD BOLZ: It should come up.
GUY FIERI: Some get an
egg wash and get salt--
KONRAD BOLZ: Yes.
GUY FIERI: --and then some
get the shave of the cheese.
KONRAD BOLZ: Correct.
Then into the oven.
12 to 14 minutes, 450 to 460.
GUY FIERI: Wow.
Gorgeous.
[music playing]
I love pretzels.
Oh!
Great pretzel salt on top.
Nice crust on the outside.
Great chew, light and tender.
Hand-made all day.
And the key is the cheese
nice and dry on there.
I could eat my body
weight in pretzels.
I don't want to hear any jokes.
[laughter]
Two salty pretzels going.
MEIN DINER CUSTOMER 5: I
really like the salt pretzel.
There's like salt in every bite.
MEIN DINER CUSTOMER
2: The cheesy pretzel
probably my favorite thing.
MEIN DINER CUSTOMER 1:
He adds a lot of cheese
on to those, which
makes them incredible.
KONRAD BOLZ: Schnitzel sandwich.
MEIN DINER CUSTOMER 6: I've
been to Germany numerous times,
and this is like bringing
Germany to Alaska.
GUY FIERI: This is what "Triple
D" is all about, my friend--
funky joints like this.
If it hadn't been
recommended, I would not
stop here in a million
years when I saw
the outside of this trailer.
Half of the letters are missing.
But what's inside
and what you do
and how you make
people feel, well done.
- Thank you, sir.
- All right.
Let's get these to go.
I'mma wrap these up.
[laughter]
What?
[music playing]
[theme music]
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Coming up,
we're still eating up Alaska--
GUY FIERI: This is
pushing it over the top.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--with a real cool
cat bringing Cuba up North--
GUY FIERI: One taste,
one love, one Rico.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--and the music--
GUY FIERI: As soon as I started
talking to him about it,
he starts to dance.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--on the plate.
Lights-out delicious.
[theme music]
[music playing]
GUY FIERI: So I'm here
in Fairbanks, Alaska.
And folks, I have come
to expect the unexpected
when I come to this town.
You never know what
you're going to get.
You get folks from
all different walks
of life, which means you get
all different types of cuisine.
So when I hear there's a jazz
joint that has a real deal
Cuban chef that's cooking in a
tiny little kitchen that looks
like you're in
somebody's apartment,
well, that says
"Triple D" all over it.
This is Jazz Bistro on 4th.
Here we go.
[music playing]
Salmon Cuban-style ready.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 1:
It's really quite amazing
that you can come to Fairbanks
and find authentic Cuban food.
Pork sliders, order up.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 2: We
love the atmosphere here.
Live music, it just transports
you to another place.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Thanks
to husband and wife team Rico
Zavaleta and Lenora Byam who
found each other through music
but stayed for the food.
From Cuba to Alaska.
RICO ZAVALETA: I know.
GUY FIERI: Was the intention
to serve food and play music
or have music and we
should probably have food?
RICO ZAVALETA: My
first passion is music.
GUY FIERI: You're
into music as well?
I sing.
RICO ZAVALETA: She wanted
to own a restaurant,
and I've been in the restaurant
business all my life.
GUY FIERI: 'Cause
you're a musician.
Yeah.
GUY FIERI: Of course you have.
We had to put the
music in the food.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 3: I love
everything on the menu here.
RICO ZAVALETA: Lechon asado.
Vaminos!
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 3: My
favorite is the lechon asada.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 4: It's
marinated pork, bell peppers,
onions.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 5: The
sauce he put on the food
is awesome.
GUY FIERI: All right, chef.
What's up first?
Lechon pernil asado.
The lechon pernil.
And that comes with
rice and beans?
You got it.
I'm gonna start by
stabbing the pork.
GUY FIERI: Stud it with
some garlic cloves.
RICO ZAVALETA: I'm gonna
pour some olive oil
and set this bad boy in there.
Lemon-lime juice,
salt and pepper.
GUY FIERI: Achiote, so
the beautiful color.
RICO ZAVALETA: Cumin
and some oregano.
Let that sit for about an
hour and a half, two hours.
GUY FIERI: Next step?
RICO ZAVALETA: We're
gonna make some sazon.
Now people know sazon because
they see it in the container,
the dried sazon.
This is the legit sazon.
This is a legit sazon.
GUY FIERI: Spanish
olives with pimento.
RICO ZAVALETA: Basil.
GUY FIERI: California chilies?
RICO ZAVALETA: Yes.
So not spicy, but herbaceous.
RICO ZAVALETA: Onions,
sweet bell peppers.
GUY FIERI: The whole lemon.
RICO ZAVALETA: You got it.
Olive oil and a
little bit of water.
Bland this.
GUY FIERI: Pour this
over the top of it,
and then after that we can
start to cook the pork?
You got it.
Why-- why as soon as
I started talking to him
about it he starts to dance?
Well, in the kitchen we
usually have music going on.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Well, you got it going
on in your head right now.
I know, I know, I know.
I'm going to make a mojo.
Garlic, orange slices, olive
oil, salt and pepper, oregano,
culantro, achiote,
lemon-lime juice,
hand-squeezed orange juice.
After all that's rested, we're
gonna put sazon that we made
and the mojo that we made--
GUY FIERI: Onto the pork
and then into the oven.
RICO ZAVALETA: 350, and raise it
to about 425 in the last hour.
Then we'll make the beans.
RICO ZAVALETA: We'll start
with some black beans, organic,
and water.
GUY FIERI: So we're not
going to soak these.
We're just going to let
all those flavors build.
RICO ZAVALETA: Onions,
salt, and pepper, oregano,
cilantro, garlic, achiote.
Slow simmer?
RICO ZAVALETA: For about
2, 2 and 1/2 hours.
GUY FIERI: Right.
RICO ZAVALETA: Then we're
going to make a lechon asado.
Jump in that.
RICO ZAVALETA: Oil,
onions, garlic, red bells,
shredded pork.
I just don't see
any flavor in there.
Do you guys?
None at all.
RICO ZAVALETA: Then we got
some rice, black beans.
This is a normal portion?
RICO ZAVALETA: Yes.
Bring the whole family
down for this one, huh?
RICO ZAVALETA: The
slaw goes on top.
GUY FIERI: And what's the
slaw made out of, chef?
RICO ZAVALETA: Vinegar,
achiote, lemon-lime juice,
oregano with garlic.
[music playing]
If you don't stop me,
I'll eat the whole thing.
Amazing flavor from a lot
of citrus and cabbage,
very simple foods done
in the correct balance.
You're going to get your
crunch out of your slaw.
You're gonna get your
fat out of your pork.
You're gonna get the acid
coming from the mojo.
You're just going to get all
your little components that you
want that fortify the dish.
Outstanding.
This is Cuban Alaska, buddy.
Delicious.
Lechon asado.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 6: It's
rich and full of flavor.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER
2: Very tender, juicy.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 7: The
beans are absolutely amazing.
I do everything
but lick the bowl.
Have you ever been
here for the music?
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 6:
That's really what hooked us.
Everybody had gotten
their food, and
so Lenora and Rico were just
like oh, let's play some music.
As soon as you're
done, why don't we
just have a jam session?
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 6: Yeah.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 7:
The music is amazing,
and the food is just so good.
You can't get enough of it.
[music playing]
GUY FIERI: I'm going
to finish this.
You go play some music, because
I know it's driving you nuts.
When we come back, more
Cuban fantastic-ness.
RICO ZAVALETA: Churrasco!
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER
8: The steak
dish is one of my favorites.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 9:
It's definitely different,
in a good way.
GUY FIERI: Jazz on
4th, Fairbanks, Alaska.
See you in a bit.
Can I get a little
bit more of the slaw?
[music playing]
Gosh, I can't-- I'm
watching them eat this,
and my mouth is still watering.
The food is so good.
I could take that plate.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER
10: If you want a bite,
you can grab a fork.
It looks so good.
[beep]
[music playing]
Welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out
in Fairbanks, Alaska
for exactly what you'd expect--
Cuban food.
That's right.
At Jazz Bistro on Fourth,
a small little restaurant
serving a lot of big
flavor with awesome music.
The pork was
lights-out delicious.
What are you going to
follow that up with?
What's the encore song?
Churrasco, order up.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 9:
The churrasco actually
reminds me a lot of carne
asada, with the lemon juice,
parsley, and tomatoes.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 1: It's
a really rich and yummy dish.
We're chanting.
We're standing in the lounge.
We're going to do a sofrito.
We start with cilantro and
parsley, fresh tomato, salt and
pepper, fresh oregano, paprika.
GUY FIERI: Mixed peppers again.
Yes sir.
Onions, cumin, jalapenos.
This-- I don't--
I've never seen that many
jalapenos in a Cuban dish.
RICO ZAVALETA: We
won't put them all in.
Bell peppers, water,
red wine vinegar.
Heat it up in the pan.
GUY FIERI: Next up?
We're going to make
a Rico Song sauce.
GUY FIERI: You named the
sauce after yourself?
And actually that's
the name of my band too.
"Song" means music, mambo.
Why every time he
talks he makes it cool?
(CUBAN ACCENT) Your
car has a flat tire.
Your toilet is backed up.
[laughter]
RICO ZAVALETA: We start
with the peppers, carrots--
GUY FIERI: Yellow bell peppers,
onions, red bell peppers,
and again the jalapenos.
Rico Song is going loco.
RICO ZAVALETA: We got
some lemon-lime juice,
tomato juice, salt and
pepper, and some oregano.
Cilantro again.
RICO ZAVALETA: Water, olive oil.
Rico Song pushing the blender.
Yeah.
[laughs] Rico Song pushing--
Rico Song pushes the blender.
[laughter]
Ha ha!
What do we got?
- [inaudible]
GUY FIERI: OK.
RICO ZAVALETA: I'm going to
slice up about a quarter inch.
Add some olive oil.
Get that really hot
before we put the steak.
[music playing]
Green olives, onions, garlic.
We add the meat.
GUY FIERI: That's
how I always put out
my pan fires Rico Song style.
Rico Song salsa, vinegar--
RICO ZAVALETA: Sofrito
that we made earlier.
While that's cooking, we're
going to make a chimichurri.
Cilantro-parsley
mix, fresh onions,
salt and pepper,
paprika and achiote,
culantro, cilantro, tomato--
GUY FIERI: Little olive
oil and some lemon lime.
So we're going to
plate the churrasco.
Chimichurri--
Let me Rico it.
RICO ZAVALETA: Mambo, baby.
Mambo.
[laughter]
I want to just jump right
into the rice and beans,
'cause I know how
fantastic they are,
but I got to go right
over here to this.
It's actually dangerous to think
of you with a real big kitchen.
Then I don't know
what would happen.
Because if this much
flavor is coming out
of this little kitchen,
you're like the culinary Tony
Montana right now, dude.
Well, one taste,
one love, one Rico.
[music playing]
Flavors are dynamite.
Energy is amazing.
This is push-it-over-the-top.
Churrasco for you.
The meat is just so
tender and so nicely cooked.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER 4: It
just melts in your mouth.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER
9: The salsa
put over it coincided with
the meat all work together.
RICO ZAVALETA: Put the
love in the cooking.
JAZZ BISTRO CUSTOMER
8: This place deserves
a billboard in the airport.
[laughter]
One taste, one love, one Rico.
Don't forget that man.
[inaudible]
I'll take this to go.
[laughter]
[music playing]
So that wraps this edition of
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives."
If you want to get some of
the recipes from today's show,
go to foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next week on "Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives."
[theme music]
Hey, you freezing to
death people out there,
what would you like to have?
Oh, you can't speak
because your jaw is shut?
[tapping on glass]
Hello sir.
Would you like something?
Ice water.
One ice water coming up.