You know, people
are asking me all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint
you checked out
in that one city
when you were doing Triple-D,
how are they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
-We should check it out.
-[engine revving]
[Guy] Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
because Triple-D joints
have been blowing up
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
-[engine revving]
-[Guy] Like on this trip,
-it's California dreaming.
-[oven dings]
First, a [indistinct]
family favorite.
There's got to be a place
that I go to all the time.
That's become a legendary
local hang in my hood.
It's still some of the best
wings you'll find anywhere
in the country.
Then, in Los Angeles...
[man] Order of Panuchos.
[man] It's such
a little secret.
[Guy] A small spot
cranking out big flavor.
Off the hook.
Courtesy of a classic
Mexican menu.
It's a Yucatan hotdog.
[laughs]
And straight up the highway,
a sandwich shop.
If you love pastrami,
you would flip over this.
Known for slowing down
fast food.
Hit the smoker
for about four hours
and viola.
Hmm, a killer.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more
off the hook favorites.
This is Triple-D Nation.
[upbeat music playing]
So far, we rolled
into some of the America's
best Diners,
Drive-Ins and Dives.
Now, my stompin' grounds,
Northern, California,
the wine country.
That was back in '07,
in the pilot episode
of Triple-D,
where I got to show off
my local joint.
It's been a family
favorite for decades.
And it's called
the Russian River Pub.
[upbeat music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[woman] We were just out
driving around
and saw on the sign
that it was a diners,
drive-ins, and dives spot.
We decided to stop in
and it's been I go ever since.
[man] Because everybody knows
what Triple-D is,
but once it draws you in,
the food and the atmosphere,
it's like this
is a great place to be.
[Guy] Thanks to my friend,
Wendy Gause.
All right.
So, when we started Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives,
we're going
all around the country.
We're rolling out
to find some of America's
best Diners, Drive-Ins,
and Dives.
And I said
to the production team,
I appreciate all the places
we're finding
but there's got to be a place
that is my Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives.
You know, a place
that I go to all the time.
How many years have you had
Russian River Pub now?
-Fifteen years.
-[Guy] Fifteen years.
So, she bought it
when she was in eighth grade.
[Wendy] I always wanted
my own place
and it was really time.
I had the opportunity
to work for several
different people,
Hank over at Hank's Creekside.
Oh, wait a second.
Did I forget all about that?
Because Hank's was on Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives early on.
-[Wendy] Uh-hmm.
-Wendy worked with us
at Hank's Creekside.
It's the perfect setting
for her.
I walked in the door,
I felt the warmth's.
I saw the diamond
in the rough
and I just...
I loved it here.
[Guy] And you just decided
I'm gonna take food
that I like, an attitude
and energy that I like,
a tribute to your dad.
My father has been passed away
for about 12 years.
So, my stepmother
walked through the door
and she goes,
"Oh, my gosh, your father
tried to buy this place
20 years ago."
-No.
-This exact place.
You didn't change it,
you made it better.
You've made it
a really good restaurant.
-This is awesome.
-Isn't that great?
[Wendy] I want everything
that comes out of my kitchen,
I wanna be proud of it.
[Guy] And Chef Brenda Weddle
is still making that happen.
-Order up.
-[bell rings]
[Guy] This is eyeball recipe?
No. We got it down.
Everybody has a good eyeball.
[Guy] Some people have two.
-[Brenda] Two.
-[laughs]
I think I could
put this on a flip-flop
it would test good.
Mmm.
[woman] The food
is incredible.
I try something
different every time.
What did you bring me?
[Wendy] So, this is the Killer
Prime Rib sandwich.
You really can't go wrong
with the sandwiches here.
[Wendy] We start with an Angus
prime rib, rub it
with a mixture
of granulated onion
and garlic,
salt and pepper.
Let that slow roast
for about two hours
until it's medium rare.
[Guy] So you make
real deal prime rib
that most people
would serve for a meal,
so it is a real
prime rib sandwich?
Yes. Throw it on the grill
and we'd serve it
on a toasted French roll,
top it with our sauteed
onions,
mushrooms,
and melted Swiss cheese,
and my mom's potato salad.
We first make the dressing,
sugar, apple cider vinegar,
yellow mustard, and mayo.
We take cooked off potatoes,
bacon, chopped onion,
pickle, black olives,
hardboiled eggs,
a little bit
of salt and pepper,
pour the dressing
over the potato mix,
and mix to coat.
[Brenda] Killer
Prime Rib sandwich.
[woman] It's a nice slice
of prime rib, just delicious.
You don't need to add
anything to it.
How are we looking
on that Killer Prime Rib?
[woman] It's super juicy,
super tender,
and I am a big fan
of Wendy's mother's
potato salad.
It's just amazing.
-It's delicious.
-[woman] Every time
you walk in,
there's something that's just
a little bit different.
Wendy is constantly
making it better.
[woman] She has been able
to expand
but keep the ambiance.
A lot of this is history
for a lot of people.
People come in and they say,
oh, I remember when we all
wrote our names on the wall.
Fast Freddy right over here.
[Guy] You took out
the pool table.
You put more tables in.
You did this
unbelievable patio.
[man] The back patio
is fantastic.
It's what people come out
to this area for,
sitting under the red woods
and having a great time.
All right, Laura. We got
a Killer Prime Rib sandwich
and two Pulled Pork's
for the bar.
[Guy] I see the kitchen
has got a little bit larger.
It has.
[Guy] I feel like
I'm gonna get plowed
into any second and end up
in the fryer.
You offer a big menu.
It's always been
an institution
for great wings.
[man] Ain't no thing
but a chicken wing.
We recently had you
on Triple-D Takeout.
Give me a rundown
of what we're making.
[Wendy] We're going to do
wings and barbeque sauce.
[laughs]
It's still some
of the best wings
you'll find anywhere
in the country.
How expensive is the menu now?
It is at least twice as large.
[man] I pretty much
tried everything.
I've never had
a bad thing here yet.
[Hank] It's a restaurant
and a pub,
so you have all
your traditional pub foods
with some real nice twist.
[woman] Pulled pork sandwich.
I had the barbeque
pulled pork,
a little bit of heaven here.
When Guy was here,
the pulled pork
was a pork dinner.
-[Brenda] Boneless pork butt.
-[Guy] Boneless pork butt.
If there was leftovers,
the next day,
we would do
the pulled pork sandwich
but it was so popular,
I just decided to go ahead
and put it on the menu.
First, we make a rub,
granulated onion,
coriander, granulated garlic,
Cajun seasoning,
chili powder,
cayenne pepper, cumin,
chipotle powder,
pepper, salt,
a little bit of brown sugar.
We place the pork butt
into the rub,
then let them rest overnight.
We sear them
and then braise them
with garlic, onion,
and two local beers.
Once it's braised, shred it,
heat it up with our homemade
barbeque sauce
made from liquid smoked,
Worcestershire,
salt and pepper,
Dijon and horse radish,
garlic, and onion puree,
local pale ale and IPA,
molasses,
apple cider vinegar,
ketchup, brown sugar.
We then put that
on the Brioche roll
with lettuce
and pickled onion.
-Pulled pork.
-[man] Nice big portion
of pulled pork.
It's got a nice kick.
[woman] I love
the barbeque sauce
that the pub does here.
It's actually not too spicy.
It's just that perfect
little tinge on your palate.
Everything here is always
cooked to perfection.
[Guy] When I talk
about Triple-D
and I talk about OGs,
you are the shining example
and you have been
the benchmark
that people had to follow,
and you've done it
with such grace,
and such poise,
and such positive energy.
[laughs]
And, uh, you continue
to crush it.
Wen, you're the best.
Thank you so much.
[Guy] Coming up
to Los Angeles.
You see me wolfed down
through those sausages.
The Yucatan, Peninsula.
Word to the Yucatan.
[Guy] Find itself
on the West Coast.
Oh, my gosh.
[upbeat music playing]
I'm here in Los Angeles,
just a few blocks
from USC to check
out a funky little joint
that's housed here
in the Mercado La Paloma.
Now, they've got a family
in here from the Yucatan
that is serving up legit
real deal Mexican food
that you probably
haven't seen before.
-How rich?
-Full on flavor explosion.
[Guy] And back in 2015,
it was more of a local's only
kind of place.
But now,
the word's gotten out.
This is Chichen Itza.
[upbeat music playing]
[woman] We first came
to Chichen Itza
when we saw it on Triple-D
and it's just been amazing,
so we've been coming here
pretty consistently
ever scene.
[woman] It stays authentic.
It tastes really close
to what it taste
like in Merida, Yucatan.
So, I feel like I'm back home
and my grandma
is making these dishes.
[Guy] Probably because
that's exactly where
owner Gilberto Cetina
got his inspiration.
This is what my grandma
used to cook.
This is what my mom
used to cook
growing up in Yucatan.
Yucatan, Mexico.
The Yucatan, Peninsula
is geographically
more isolated
than the rest of Mexico,
which means that
our native ingredients
are different.
Word to the Yucatan.
-What are we gonna make?
-The Longganisa Asada.
Longganisa Asada.
[Gilberto] Longganisa
is a Yucatan style
smoked chorizo.
We're gonna start
with pork shoulder.
-This is ground fat.
-[Guy] Pork fat?
[Gilberto] Pork fat
and ground beef.
-Next.
-Oregano, garlic powder,
clove...
onion,
and we're gonna add
some vinegar.
[Guy] Salt and...
-Cumin.
-Got it.
Mix this all by hand.
[Gilberto] And we're gonna
add the achiote paste.
[Guy] This is what gives
the great color
to a lot of Latin food.
All right. So, the casing
goes on.
[Gilberto]
Natural sheep casing.
Crank her down.
[Guy] Oh, nice and thin.
[Gilberto] Yup.
We're gonna hang them
on a stainless steel valve
over, uh, embers.
They're gonna sit there
overnight.
[Guy] A little bit of heat,
a little bit of smoke.
And we're gonna grill these,
serve it with some tortillas,
fire roasted onions,
and then fire roasted salsa.
So Yucatan hotdog.
-[Gilberto] [laughs]
-Mmm.
A little bit of salt,
touch of spice,
great meat to fat ratio.
Definitely get
the wood in the smoke.
-Perfect gastro.
-Thank you.
[man] It's so good.
It doesn't taste
like anywhere else
that you had it before.
[woman] Everything
is homemade.
It's really good ingredients.
You see me wolfed down
through those sausage
and two tortillas.
[Gilberto] The longganisa
[indistinct]
they're very popular.
Now, it's gonna be serve
along with the Poc Chuc
and it's kind of, like,
a traditional Mayan,
Pre-Colombian dish.
We have this piece
of pork shoulder.
We're gonna use a cure
that's gonna have
black pepper,
coriander seeds, one bay leaf,
and we're gonna grind this.
[machine whirring]
[Gilberto] We're gonna add
one part sugar,
two parts kosher salt,
the, uh, zest
of one sour orange.
I'm just gonna mix that.
It's gonna flavor the meat,
but it's also going
to slightly cure the meat.
After two hours in the fridge,
we're gonna rinse it
in cold water
and marinate it
with sour orange,
blended with garlic,
a little bit of kosher salt,
and then, uh, mix this well.
This is the longganisa we made
when Guy was here,
and then Poc Chuc.
So, Poc Chuc on the plate,
we're doing some of the, uh,
roasted tomato salsa,
the, uh, grilled longganisa,
and a side
of black bean puree,
the Poc Chuc.
[upbeat music playing]
[man] Yeah.
[man] It's spicy
but not too spicy.
It's really, really nice.
[woman] You can taste
a little bit
of that chard flavor on it,
just full of flavor
and really well-balanced.
It tastes amazing.
It feels like
a home cooked meal.
Dude, you're making
scratch made
legit food like this
from a little kiosk
in a market.
It's very hidden.
It's such a little secret.
[Guy] But coming up,
the secret is out.
It got much busier.
People are coming
from all over the place.
We'll be right back
after this.
[upbeat music playing]
[Guy] All right.
So, we're back
in Chichen Itza
here in Los Angeles.
And back in 2015,
it was still a secret
in the neighborhood.
It's one of those hidden gems
that really needed
to be discovered.
+You don't wanna miss it.
After Triple-D aired,
we had a lot of new exposure,
a lot of new people
heard about us
and started coming in.
[man] It got much busier.
It's full of people
and I believe
people are coming
from all over the place.
[Gabriel] And after that,
I opened up
a second restaurant
in the same space
called Holbox.
It's a seafood restaurant.
I love being in the space.
I get to...
For one location take care
of both of my babies.
The whole market
just increased its volume
by about a thousand percent.
I'm really happy for them
that more people
get to experience their food.
[Guy] All right.
So what's the next dish?
-Panucho. All right.
-Panucho.
So, first, we're gonna
break down the turkey.
We're gonna boil the legs
and we're gonna sous vide
the breast.
[Guy] Because that's what
you see every day
in a little kiosk
Yucatan joint.
[Gabriel] Kosher salt,
take a sous vide bag,
a little bit
of cilantro in there.
-Are we gonna vacuum this?
-[Gabriel] We are.
[Guy] Okay,
hundred and fifty degrees?
-[Gabriel] Yeah.
-[Guy] How long?
-[Gabriel] Two and half hours.
-This is simmering
to where it's so tender
that when you open it out
in the bag, it will just
fall apart. Okay.
[Gabriel] So, we're gonna make
the tortillas
-now for the Panuchos.
-Tortillas.
[Gabriel] So, we're gonna
make little balls of masa.
In it goes.
[Guy] So why is this going
to pop up open?
Mine don't often pop up.
[Gabriel] Ones both layers
are cooked evenly,
you pressed down
on the tortilla,
that creates better contact
on the surface of the plancha,
it generates more heat
and more heat generates steam,
and the steam is what
balloons the tortilla up.
Learn something new
every day, baby.
-Okay.
-[Gabriel] Open it up.
Some black bean puree.
[Guy] Okay.
Cover the hole
and you spread it out.
-[Guy] Love it.
-Now we're gonna fry them.
-[Guy] All right.
-Little bit of lettuce,
some of the shredded leg
and the sous vide breast,
some pickled red onions,
tomato,
and a slice of avocado.
[Guy] And that's all
she wrote.
That is the Panucho.
Man, it's so tender,
delicious.
It's subtle, it's authentic.
That's a nostalgic dish.
Oh, my gosh.
Order of peking chick for 23.
[woman] Coming
from Mexico and coming back,
it was like I was back
in Mexico again.
[Gabriel] This dish
is called cochinita pibil.
It's probably the most
representative dish
of Yucatan cuisine.
Here we have a 70-pound pig
that's been cut in half.
We're gonna separate head,
shoulder, loin,
and the ham.
And then we're going
to inject it.
So, this marinade
is made with achiote,
lime juice, fresh squeezed
orange juice,
garlic cloves,
and kosher salt.
Now, we're just gonna pour
the rest of the marinade over,
and, uh, we're gonna add
two heads
of roasted garlic.
And then, uh, part
of the pibil cooking technique
is wrapping it
completely in banana leaves.
We cook it in the oven
but we don't turn the oven on.
We just put the hot embers in.
After about 12 hours,
the cochinita is fully cooked
and it's falling apart.
We have a good mixture here
of all the different
parts of the pig.
We're gonna garnish
this with pickled red onions
and one habanero pepper.
Cochinita for table two.
[man] It's got sour orange,
it's cooked in bananas,
slow roasted braised,
so it's tender.
It's a little bit sour
but full of flavor,
meaty, delicious.
[woman] There's zest,
there's like vinegar
that helped amplify
the sauciness,
the pork itself
makes the dish salty.
The whole process of making it
is really special
and you can taste
all the love
that goes into it.
I can't keep eating.
I'm gonna pass out.
-Real deal.
-Thank you.
Off the hook.
[upbeat music playing]
[Guy] Next stop,
we're staying in LA.
Should've majored taste
division subscriptions.
To check in
on a sandwich spot.
Pick up a pulled
pork sandwich.
[Guy] Quick serving,
slow cooking.
They smoke them overnight.
You know I do this stuff
for you guys.
[upbeat music playing]
[Guy] Back in 2010, the debate
over quick service spots
was a hot topic.
Now, my position is this,
quality not quantity,
handmade not over processed.
And from what I'm hearing,
The Oinkster
in Eagle Rock, California
is just that.
Amazing. It's a great place
to take your friends.
[Guy] These days, the food
is still flying up the line.
Pick up
a pulled pork sandwich.
[Guy] This is The Oinkster,
slow fast food.
[upbeat music playing]
[man] I love this place.
It never fails to impress me.
[woman] The Oinkster
is an institution
in Los Angeles.
They just [indistinct]
about great food
and great service.
-[man] Order up.
-[man] I saw The Oinkster
on Triple-D and I had
to come check it out.
[man] The food
is just so great.
Why would you not love
this place?
[Guy] Good question.
There's no reason not to
with Andre Guerrero
serving his scratch made
but speedy sandwiches.
[upbeat music playing]
[Andre] I didn't re-invent
fast food.
All I did
was just make it better.
After you've been here,
you know
that you're not eating
at a regular
fast food restaurant.
A killer.
[Andre] When Guy was here,
we made the pastrami.
It wasn't good enough
for you to just get
a really nice artisan
gourmet named pastrami.
You figured
just make your own.
This is the mixture?
[Andre] Fresh ground pepper
and coriander.
[Guy] That is awesome.
Hit the smoker at 240
for about four hours
and voila.
-[Guy] Look at that thing.
-[Andre] Let's pull this out.
[Guy whistles]
Come here and check this out.
Look at the juices
just flowing.
-[Andre] Watch this.
-[Guy] Oh,
sump up some of that.
You know I do this stuff
for you guys.
Juicy dripping goodness.
Don't cut anymore,
just get that in the car.
[Andre] We're gonna do, uh,
our Oinkster pastrami,
nice big pile of pastrami.
-[Guy] Wow.
-[Andre] Caramelized onions,
Gruyere cheese,
and then some of our
red coleslaw.
And then Pasadena
High football teams
are gonna come over
and eat it with me.
Hmm.
If you love pastrami,
you would flip over this.
[Andre] Before Guy came,
we were doing
approximately 1200 pounds
of pastrami a week.
After the show aired,
everything doubled.
[Guy] Should've majored taste
division subscriptions.
It wasn't just pastrami,
it was everything,
the burgers, the pulled pork.
Our rub is just on pepper.
We smoke them overnight.
[Guy] I got it.
Same team, same team, go.
Catch and release.
Looks great.
Definitely falls apart.
[Andre] And then we put
some of the juices
-right back in.
-[Guy] So that's just like
-liquid smoked porka flavor?
-[Andre] Yeah, exactly.
[Guy] You can quote me
on that.
Liqua smoka porka flavor.
Liqua smoka porka
flavor, got it?
That pork really
is a unique style.
Very rich, mmm.
[man] It's a little bit spicy
and it's smoky,
which I like.
It's a combination
that's just unbeatable.
They have so many crazy
and delicious meals here.
My favorite is definitely
anything with chicken,
The Cluckster.
The name kind of goes
with the Oinkster
but, uh, chicken version.
To make the dredge, start
with our all-purpose flour,
cumin, garlic salt,
celery salt, white pepper,
basil, regular salt,
ginger, dry mustard,
paprika, and black pepper.
We have this pre-brined
chicken breasts.
Dip it in the buttermilk,
put it in our dredge.
We fry this for five minutes.
Now, we have our ranch
dressing on there,
shredded lettuce,
some Dill pickles,
the chicken breast,
and a little bit
of our buffalo sauce,
and there we have it,
our chicken Cluckster.
[woman] We got the Cluckster.
[woman] The chicken is juicy,
breading is not too heavy.
It's just crispy
and delicious.
[woman] It's not too hot,
it's not too mild,
it's perfect.
[indistinct]
did you get that?
-Exactly what you mean.
-Oh, my God.
Did you see him laugh?
[upbeat music playing]
I was just kind of low-key
but we had a lot of fun.
Put your hands up like this,
just the jazz hands.
[laughs]
How long on that chicken?
[Guy] It's always awesome
hitting up joints
around my home state.
[Brenda] Barbeque pulled pork
sandwich up. Let's go.
[Guy] But the Triple-D nation
is bigger than that.
It will be cruising
the country going for more.
Would you like a bigger wisk?
[Guy] Wisk one you got?
-You really use this?
-[Gabriel laughs]