You know, people were asking
me all the time, hey, Guy,
that one joint you checked out
that one city when you were
doing Triple-D, how they doing?
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
because Triple-D joints
have been blowing up.
And we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip, we're
crossing the country--
Special this
week, guy in town.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--and circling the globe.
We call it a Polish burrito.
Polish burrito.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
In Alaska,
Not bad movement there.
He's Chuck Norris and
Emeril at the same time.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): --a
good buddy still working
the wok all year 'round.
I know where I'm going to
start spending my holidays.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): A
German joint in Portland,
Oregon staying uber authentic.
They're making over 120
different types of sausage.
Sausage plate.
There you go.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
And a Ukrainian
market in Minneapolis
whipping up
traditional sausage and stew.
Just wheel that
right up to the '67.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off the hook flavors.
This is Triple-D Nation.
I cannot believe it was 11
years ago that we came up here
to North Pole, Alaska to shoot
a Christmas special for Diners,
Drive Ins, and Dives.
Is it always like this?
It's Christmas all the time.
GUY FIERI: It's
Christmas all the time.
And there was one restaurant
in particular that we--
[interposing voices]
Were here again.
Come on, come on.
Let's go.
I have to show you.
This is Benny Lin.
And this is Pagoda.
I've got the chicken.
We saw Pagoda on
Triple-D. We got here.
It was amazing.
We keep coming back.
We just moved to the area.
Our friends told us
to check out Pagoda.
And we just fell in
love with the place.
I have been coming to
Pagoda for about 31 years.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): And that
means she found this joint 20
years before I did.
What makes great Chinese food?
Uh--
Great Chinese cooks.
Oh, that's-- really?
That's what I was
going to say also.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
And that Chinese food
maestro is Benny Lin.
Why did I age
and Benny didn't?
Can we just get a picture
of looking at the two of us?
That's not fair, by the way.
So Benny-- without
question, one of
our favorite Triple-D joints.
We came up here.
It was a really cool special
we shot for the holidays.
I know we're going to
start spending my holidays.
Chinese restaurant, huh?
Pagoda?
No, in your kitchen.
All right.
Put a tree up.
What did we have
last time we were here?
King crab leg
with ginger sauce.
Let's start off with
the King crab legs.
Look at the size of that.
You have something right there.
[joke yelling]
Fire it up.
Now, how many BTUs use do
you think we have in there?
This one is like 55.
55,000?
Yeah.
55,000 BTUs.
The needle out there at
the gas meter's going--
we're going to tear
this out tonight--
OK.
--and I'm going to
move this to my house.
OK.
When I built my new house
and built my new kitchen,
I tried to put a wok
set up like this.
And all Laurie had to do is see
it one time with all the water
and everything on-- she goes,
no, no, that's not happening.
We add some oil and garlic.
We add ginger.
- Ginger?
Yep.
I feel like I should
give the play by play.
King crab legs.
I'm going to take an
elbow to the teeth.
It's like UFC cooking.
Bam.
Ah!
He's Chuck Norris and
Emeril at the same time.
OK.
Black bean sauce.
Some oyster sauce.
- Soy sauce.
- Yeah.
Look at that.
OK.
I'm gonna faint.
Black pepper.
Oh, sugar.
Yeah.
You glaze with
some white wine?
White wine, yeah.
The scallions
and the cilantro?
Yeah.
They'll be the last thing.
All right.
Look at that.
That's excellent.
- Thank you.
Fantastic.
Gosh, that's good.
I feel like I'm mining for
gold in Alaska right now.
King crab leg
with ginger sauce--
those are only seasonal.
But we do have lots
of costumer comes in
and asks for the dish
almost every day.
I'm sure not
gonna eat all this.
So we come back for
Triple-D Nation.
What we like to do
is find out what's
been going on, how you're
doing, and also any new dishes.
Anything new and exciting?
Absolutely.
I get the lobster
Cantonese style.
Lobster Cantonese style.
Here's our Cantonese
lobster tail.
The lobster tail Cantonese
style is just next level.
Let's do it, Benny.
All right.
First, we're going
to hit up the wok.
You're going to add
oil, 375 degrees.
OK.
Lobster tail in the shell.
Got it.
- Yeah.
Getting a quick fry.
And nothing on that,
no corn starch, or--
- No corn starch, nothing.
- OK.
OK.
Just like 3 more minute.
I think I'm getting
taller, Benny.
And you're getting shorter.
- I know.
OK.
Drain off the oil.
Oh, yeah.
All right.
We going to add a
little bit of garlic.
Garlic.
Black bean sauce.
OK.
Ginger.
Carrots.
OK.
Green onion.
White wine.
Little bit of white pepper.
White pepper.
Hoisin and soy sauce.
Soy sauce now?
- Yeah.
Soy sauce now.
OK.
And we add the lobster back.
Lobster back in.
Sautée it a little
bit, a few more minutes.
Not bad movement there, buddy.
Right here.
How many lobsters
was that, Benny?
That's three.
Three lobsters.
That's it.
Benny always does
it on the low side.
All right.
Here you go.
You want to use these?
Here's your chopsticks.
I use fork.
I use--
I use a fork.
Special this
week, Guy in town.
Benny, it's fantastic.
Are you going to try it?
I have to try it.
Good amount of veggies.
The lobster is delicious,
not overcooked, super tender.
The sauce doesn't overpower it.
You can actually
taste the lobster.
You cook it with the shell on.
And you use a fork.
All my favorite things.
Here's our Cantonese
lobster tail.
It's almost spicy but not.
It's a little sweet.
The ginger really makes it pop.
Kind of got a
little tangy to it.
It's amazing.
This lobster is delicious.
I hope he doesn't finish his.
- I love it.
- Thank you.
Delicious.
Thank you
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Coming up, an old favorite
and a hot new dish.
Dragon chicken.
[making animal noises]
Dragon chicken, you're
going to love this.
[music playing]
So here I am,
North Pole, Alaska.
And I find out
they've got an off
the hook Chinese restaurant.
Oh, I got to stop
and check out Pagoda.
That was back in 2009, but now--
We shot Triple-D,
we didn't know you.
You didn't know us.
And ladies and
gentlemen, after that,
it's all a blur because
then Benny became
just a part of the family.
[inaudible]
I do Guys Grocery Game.
Benny.
It is nectar of the Gods.
We had you on Triple-D
Take Out recently.
Yes, yes.
I love that the Pagoda
sign is right behind you.
Right.
We did your
brother's restaurant
down in San Francisco.
How many of these can you eat?
I can get 15.
I can eat 15 too.
We had a blast there,
fantastic restaurant.
After we do the show, getting
at least 30% off the business.
We have waiting lists
almost every night.
And then we had to
add this bar in here
right now for more seating.
Beautiful bar.
The addition of the new bar
just adds that special touch.
I like it better
since the bar is open.
It's always welcoming.
I've never had anybody
that I've sent up here from
Triple-D that hasn't
told me how much
they love their experience.
What did we have last
time we were here?
We had the walnut shrimp--
Shrimp's nice and
tender, nice crunch to it.
--the pagoda steak
That means really killer.
By far the best steaks around.
Everything's right.
It's always hot and fast.
Every time we come
here and, you know,
we get something different.
When they get something
new, they're like, hey, you
want to try this?
And you're like, yeah.
Dragon chicken--
it's dynamite.
You have to try it tonight, OK?
Dragon chicken.
So heating up
the oil in the wok.
Chicken.
(SARCASTICALLY) One thing
you can always expect at Pagoda
is small portions.
OK.
So chicken's done.
- Chicken's done.
Next?
So we had a little
bit of garlic.
And then we had heavy cream.
Heavy cream, got it.
So then we had lobster base.
Lobster base.
Cajun seasoning.
Black pepper.
Jack Daniel.
Jack Daniels?
Yeah.
So Cajun seasoning
and Jack Daniels
at a Chinese restaurant
in North pole.
You hear it every day.
Oyster sauce.
Soy sauce.
So take the veggies,
give those a little blanch.
Yeah.
Broccoli and mushroom.
OK.
The chicken back in.
Sautée it up.
Let it reduce, let it coat up.
Yeah.
Add little bit of oil.
I'm going to come
work on the line
here one day, me and Benny.
All right, Guy.
It's ready.
All right?
Oh, top steak now, all right.
What do you think?
Chicken is super tender.
Veggies have got good crunch.
The sauce doesn't overpower it.
You are putting out a
bunch of whiskey in there,
but that cooked off.
There's a little bit
of Cajun seasoning.
Delicious dish.
How are you guys?
Here's our dragon chicken.
The dragon chicken
is fantastic.
The sauce melts in your
mouth, along with the chicken.
A lot of flavor, and
it pops in your mouth.
It's very creamy.
It's got a little bit of
heat to it, but not too much.
It was so good.
It's the Benny
twist to it, right?
I'll open up
Pagoda in Santa Rosa.
OK.
We'll bleach your hair blond.
I'll go black.
OK.
I get some lifts
in my shoes, OK?
And you've got to
put on some weight.
I've told you this
a million times,
I wish there was a
Pagoda in every town.
Thank you, brother.
- You'll love this guy.
- Thank you.
The food's great.
And he's amazing.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Coming up in Oregon,
Look at that
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Salami and jerky,
straight out of Germany.
Salami sandwiches.
O-M-G.
Thai chili jerky.
Thank you.
[music playing]
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
In 2013, I
was on the Southeast
side of Portland, Oregon
to check out a market
cranking out German sausage.
I find out it's
not just one sausage
or two sausages they're making.
They're making over 120
different types of sausage.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): And these
days, the list keeps growing.
This is Edelweiss
Sausage and Delicatessen.
Currywurst coming up.
I saw Edelweiss
on Triple-D. And I
had to come try it for myself.
And it definitely
lived up to the hype.
If you have gone
to Germany and you
fell in love with
those foods over there,
this is where you'll find them.
This is a multigenerational
family business,
thriving and doing great.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): It
started by George Baier, who
brought all his meatpacking
skills from Berlin
and opened this place in '82.
Then he passed that knowledge
on to his sons, Tom and Tony.
So it's the two of you?
The two of yous?
Is your dad still involved?
No, he's not.
He's down in Arizona.
Since the show, my
brother's retired.
So now it's just me,
my kids, and my wife.
Thai chili jerky.
It's a family business.
And they know how
to do things right.
What are we going to make?
We're going to make a
dry-cured Italian wine salami.
I-talian.
We're going to start
with the pork fat.
So this is all frozen.
This is going to get gnarly.
All right.
Nice fine dice.
Look at that.
We're going to
add the beef to it.
- What cuts?
- Bottom rounds.
Bottom rounds.
Yep.
There we go.
Just got to add the seasoning.
This is a curing salt--
sugar, Morton salt, dextrose.
We'll add the white
pepper, ground fennel,
black pepper, whole fennel--
Nice.
--Juniper berry,
crushed garlic, whole
bottle of Italian red wine.
Italian!
And it's ready for stuffin'.
How magical is that?
I'm getting one of these,
Laurie, for the house.
And I'm shipping it home.
That thing was ancient.
The motor was
probably 55 years old.
Since then, we've
managed to upgrade it
to a brand new one we had
shipped from Germany, thanks
to the show.
We should have
boxed the other one
and sent it to Guy as a gift.
It's going to be right
there next to the new butcher
block I just bought.
All right.
Let me give this a shot.
I'm going to wear half of
this, I can already feel it.
Pull!
Nice.
This'll dry up well.
We'll let it cure and
hang for a couple of days.
Smell that.
[sniffs]
There we go.
Wow.
I would do damage
on a deli with this.
Since the show, we've probably
quadrupled the quantity.
It's just been
growing since then
and has continued
to make recipes that
have that German feel to them.
[inaudible]
sandwich for Gretchen.
There's always something
new to come and try.
This is our Thai
chili pepper jerky.
We take a cow top round.
We slice it-- a little
over a quarter inch
so that it has a little
bit of softness to it.
We're going to add the beef
into our little mixing bag.
Start with some salt,
brown sugar, black pepper,
curing salt, clover honey, spicy
Thai chili pepper seasoning.
We blend our Thai chilies, fresh
garlic cloaks, a little rice
wine vinegar and brown sugar.
Seal this up.
We're going to tumble
it for four hours,
allowing the cells to
absorb the flavors.
We're going to season our jerky
with some crushed red pepper
and then some black pepper.
Smoke it at 200 degrees.
After two hours it, it'll
be completely finished.
Here's your Thai chili jerky.
Thank you very much.
There's a pretty good
balance between the spiciness
and the sweetness.
And on top of that, the
bite is really nice.
It's so tender.
If you like a kick
in your beef jerky,
this is definitely
the jerky for you.
They just have a
great product, a lot
of great products, actually.
Chili cheese dog
with sauerkraut.
O-M-G.
Last time Guy was here,
he had the [inaudible]..
Housemaid balogna, not
just wrapped in bacon,
but cooked in its own bacon.
That's out of bounds.
Guy also had roasted garlic
and fresh rosemary balogna.
Killer.
This is the place
to come and relive
some of that German experience.
There's so many different
things to try here.
We're going to
make pizza loaf.
First thing we need to
do is make the emulsion.
We're going to start
with the back fat.
We're going to dice it.
Here in the monster?
Yep.
This is ground meets.
Chuck and the pork shoulder.
Now ice?
We got to keep a cold
when it's blending.
Because if it gets
hot, it'll separate.
Going to add the salt
and sugar and the cure,
some dried mustard and
smoked paprika, mace
and cumin, cardamom and
coriander, white pepper,
and garlic powder.
Now we'll turn it up on high.
Sun dried tomatoes,
crushed red pepper,
toasted onions, fire-roasted
bell peppers, pork shoulder.
Now we'll add our Swiss
cheese and our cheddar.
The final step, we'll
add our black olives.
Mix it for a minute until
everything's well incorporated.
We're going to go ahead and
put this in the loaf pan.
250 degrees for 2 and 1/2 hours.
Now we're going to slice a nice
steak out of the pizza loaf,
grill it, chop it up into some
sticks, add some marinara.
And it's ready to go.
Pizza loaf with the
homemade marinara sauce.
The pizza loaf is phenomenal.
It's got a little
crunch on the outside.
It reminds me a little bit of
mozzarella sticks but meatier.
It has such a
nice flavor to it.
It's really delicious.
This is great.
Your dad should be really proud.
This is one of the
best I've seen.
Nice job.
Excellent, thank you.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Coming up in Minneapolis--
Right in there.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): --an
Eastern European eatery
still killing it with their
cabbage rolls at Krakowska.
If you're mowing the lawn,
just let it run 'til it's out
of gas and get down here.
[music playing]
I'm here in Northeast
Minneapolis, or Nordeast,
as the locals call it, right
across the Hennepin Avenue
Bridge, in an area that
used to be home to a lot
of Eastern European families.
So of course you'd
expect to find, what?
Eastern European restaurants.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
And back in 2010,
that's exactly what I found.
These days, the third
generation is still serving
scratch-made sausage and stew.
This is Kramarczuk's.
Kramarczuk's is a
family run restaurants
with made-from-scratch food.
It's great when we come
in and we see the poster
Guy and we know we're
at another great,
local, Triple-D restaurant.
It's nice to have something
that you can go to to get
a taste of the old country.
More specifically,
Ukraine, where the Kramarczuk
family came from.
My father made
everything from scratch.
Before it was the
cool thing to do.
Yeah, that's right.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): And then
Orest passed that philosophy
down to his son, Nick.
How many different types
of sausage do you make?
Anywhere from about 35 to 60.
What are we going to make?
We're going to
make Krakowska today.
It's traditionally
a Polish lunch meat.
Look at the size of that.
(ECHOING) Hello.
Luke, I'll make your sausage.
- Are you done?
- Yeah.
All right.
Am I done?
[laughs] That's the best
line I've had all time.
What was that we just put in?
The pork fat bass.
(ECHOING) Build us,
and they will come.
A little bit of sugar,
a little bit of salt.
Right in there.
Curing agent, white pepper,
mace, granulated garlic.
You got it.
The ground pork loin.
Go.
Sirloin.
Mix it up.
Now we put the rest of
our salt, curing agent.
OK.
Then we mix again.
A lot of work for sausage.
Ready?
Fire in the hole.
[inaudible] right up there, son.
Now we load up the hopper.
Yep.
[whistles] Now we're
going to stuff it.
I knew I had brought
glasses for a reason.
Now we thread the casing on.
Grab it as tight as you can.
That's awesome.
We get to the end
there, slide it off.
Tie 'em off on the bottom.
Look at that.
- Nice seal.
And then into the smoker for--
12, 15 hours.
- No kidding.
- Yep.
Pull these out.
[whistles] That's awesome.
Ready to go.
Just wheel that
right up to the '67.
Let it cool.
And we'll be ready
to make our sandwich.
Look at this thing.
Cut the end off here.
Slice that up.
Fire away.
Not too thin.
That's our Polish rye.
Stone-ground Polish
mustard on there,
horseradish mayo,
Havarti cheese,
our Krakowska that we made--
OK.
--some tomatoes,
cucumber, some lettuce.
There you have it,
Krakowska sandwich.
That's a big sandwich.
The Krakowska sandwich is one
of our best-selling sandwiches.
Their Krakowska is wonderful.
Cabbage roll with
tomato cream sauce.
Every time we get food
here it's always been good.
Two brats with kraut.
Very tasty place
if you want to come
from your Ukrainian food.
I'm pretty much
a traditionalist--
the cabbage rolls, pierogies.
Boiled cabbage rolls.
We call it a Polish burrito.
Polish burrito.
If you're mowing the lawn,
just let it run 'til it's out
of gas, and get down here.
[inaudible]
Dumpling madness.
Those are great.
It's like a Polish ravioli.
One of our more traditional
recipes is bigos stew.
We're going to start
with a bunch of bacon,
some cubed pork, kielbasa, diced
onions, margarine, paprika,
whole caraway
seeds, dried porcini
mushrooms, tomato paste, prune
lekvar-- just fruit preserves.
We're going to deglaze the
skillet with some chicken
broth, add sauerkraut, shredded
carrots, shredded potatoes,
salt, and some black pepper.
And we'll let that
stew for about an hour.
Once it's ready, we can take
it up the line and serve it.
Bigos stew.
The sauerkraut is sweet.
The sausage is great.
The mixture is fantastic.
It's comfort food that you
just want to keep eating.
It's made like your
grandmother would make it.
What's so cool about this
place, you guys make it all.
Impressed.
I think you're grandfather
would be pretty
happy to see this going on.
I think so too.
- Here you go, ma'am.
- Thank you.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): But
these aren't the only places
paying homage to their roots.
Two sausages for Jim.
Enjoy.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--so we'll
keep spinning in the globe.
Next time on Triple-D Nation.
To our good
friend, Benny Lin--
[cheers]
Now stop bringing food.
Salt and pepper pork chops.
Oh my goodness.
[inaudible]
GUY FIERI: Right here.