Hey, everybody, I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out,
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
This trip--
"Ah-loo-may."
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): --we've
got all kinds of meats.
Pork-ules!
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
And a little sweet.
It's really delicious.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): There's
a full culinary extravaganza
in Sioux Falls, South Dakota.
This is unique to the
world, just so you know.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Incredible
Indian in Fairbanks, Alaska.
I hope people know
what a gift this is.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): And
in Fargo, North Dakota--
Whoa!
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--things are getting sticky--
No sticky.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
--and totally scratch-made.
Straight out of Flavortown.
That's all right here,
right now, on "Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives."
[music playing]
So I'm here in Sioux Falls,
South Dakota with my brother
from another mother, the judge
and great chef Justin Warner.
Now, chef, I'm taking you
to a special grocery store.
Is it Flavortown Market again?
GUY FIERI: No, this is different
than an average grocery store.
It's a grocery store,
bakery, butcher
shop, coffee shop, specialty
store for restaurants.
And they got a brewery.
Are you sure we're
in South Dakota, Guy?
Exactly.
This is Look's Marketplace.
Cheers.
MAN: The market is amazing.
it's kind of a destination.
Plating tacos.
Incredible food,
incredible beverages.
There's nothing
else like this.
I've come down to get
a couple of steaks.
Pick up some seafood.
Wander back here
to the charcuterie.
We were having a pizza,
have a couple of beers.
I don't know how I
would get out of here.
It's an all-day event.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Which
started out back in 1883
as Carl Look's Butcher Shop.
But when Greg Heineman, his
son Nick, and their cousin
Beau Vondra bought the
place, they went big.
We thought, let's
start a brewery.
Let's start a bakery.
We're part of the
Good Food Foundation,
and we travel around
the country a lot.
We saw places like this, and
we really wanted to bring
it back to Sioux Falls.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
And they brought the pizza
from Detroit along with it.
Motor City, up in the window.
Motor City pizza.
Wow.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
The crust is handmade,
and they have all of
their house-made meats.
What are we making?
BEAU VONDRA: We're
making the pizza
dough for the Motor City pizza.
First, we're going
to take the water.
Then the osmotic yeast.
"Osmatic"?
This just in, folks--
Justin Warner learns something.
Beats me.
The reason for
the osmotic yeast
is we can push the salt
level over 3% on the mix.
The more salt you
can put into the dough,
the bigger the flavor
is going to be.
BEAU VONDRA: Then we also
use the sour dough starter.
Extra virgin
California olive oil.
Kosher salt.
GUY FIERI: I've never
seen that much salt.
Bread flour.
Mix for about eight minutes.
GUY FIERI: Let it proof.
BEAU VONDRA: About a half hour.
Now we're going to make
the hot Italian sausage
that we do here in house.
Kosher salt, paprika,
sugar, brown fennel,
whole fennel seeds.
I get mental with my fennel.
Black pepper.
Crushed chili flake.
Garlic.
Cayenne.
GUY FIERI: And our mixture
over here on the pork?
BEAU VONDRA: It's
shoulder, belly, loin.
Are we casing this also?
BEAU VONDRA: No,
this is going on raw.
And we blend in
some mushrooms that
are grown by our mushroom guy.
You have a mushroom guy?
I have a fun-guy.
It's the guy with two thumbs--
this guy.
BEAU VONDRA: Cut
them down smaller.
Salt and oil them up.
In the wood-fired oven.
Give them a little
roast, and then
we're ready to build the pie.
BEAU VONDRA: We
actually start out
with garlic butter for ours.
We go all the way up the sides.
You don't want to
stretch the dough at all.
You want to push it out.
We're going to start out
with a three-cheese blend.
That's the two-year
cheddar, aged
Widmer, and then a mozzarella.
That cheese right there
is like cheese board cheese.
BEAU VONDRA: And we can channel
the cheese up the sides.
Channeling the cheese.
"Ah-loo-may."
Namaste.
That'll stay right here.
BEAU VONDRA: Our
mushroom melange.
Hot soppressata.
Probably one of
my biggest vices.
There you go.
Come on, Guy.
You want me to beg like my dog?
[guy whistles]
[justin gags]
BEAU VONDRA: The
hot Italian sausage.
GUY FIERI: In the oven.
What temp?
BEAU VONDRA: 550 to
600, about 12 minutes.
JUSTIN WARNER: Hey.
Look at that.
Don't drop Justin's piece.
I forgot there
was dough in this.
BEAU VONDRA: Hot red sauce.
When you say hot,
do you mean spicy?
No, it's actually
temperaturally hot.
It's hot with ricotta,
creme fraiche, and cream.
Basil leaf and a little
bit of olive oil.
Dig in.
JUSTIN WARNER: Oh boy.
Did you just
call me dough boy?
No.
I'm surprised at the
structural integrity.
I mean, look at this.
The crust is like
this cheesy reward.
It's crunchy on the outside.
You get all of this molten,
meaty goo on the inside.
You really get that funk.
And I've never thought
about the funk of a cheese
as being a palate cleanser.
That little acidic bite.
But everything
else is so rich.
This is like you guys
have been in the Detroit
pizza business for generations.
I mean, you've taken all your
expertise as a chef and all
the support that you get
here from the marketplace,
and just swing for
the fences, man.
Thank you so much.
All right, we
got the Motor City.
You take one bite out
of that crust right there,
and it is something else.
The ricotta cheese on the
top reminds me of ricotta that
my mother made on the lasagna.
BEAU VONDRA: Beer cheese sauce
going on top of the fries.
Everything about this
place is an experience.
And you go to the
butcher shop, for example,
and maybe pick up some
seasonings with it.
And then the best
part is the guidance
you can get on how to grill it.
MAN: You know, they make
beer right in the back.
They got varieties
on the wall there.
Don't go anywhere, folks.
Guy Fieri and Justin Warner,
hanging out in Sioux Falls,
South Dakota with this guy.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
And with everything
going on in this
joint, you know he's
got more tricks up his sleeve.
Porcules, up in the window.
The Porcules sandwich
is a carnivore dream.
MAN: It's takes a special person
to get through the whole thing,
that's for sure.
- Look's Marketplace.
See you in a bit.
Come here.
Oh, no.
Blargh!
Comes with heart
paddles, folks.
Welcome back.
Triple D hanging out in
Sioux Falls, South Dakota.
It's a special
edition because I got
my one and only brother from
another mother, Justin Warner.
We are here at
Look's Marketplace.
Now, it's not your
everyday grocery store.
Heatseeker going
up in the window.
There's something
for everyone.
From a complete charcuterie,
to a butcher shop,
to a wine store.
And everything is phenomenal.
Searing the Porcules.
The particularly sandwich
starts out with a Ciabatta
bread that's made in house.
You've got pork, and
then you've got sausage.
It's incredible.
GUY FIERI: What
are we on to now?
Ciabatta.
We have water, yeast,
flour, salt, olive oil.
Start it up.
Very, very slowly add the
remainder of the water.
Let it rest.
GUY FIERI: Portion.
BEAU VONDRA: It goes into the
oven for about 16 minutes.
What are we into?
What are we working
on right now?
Working on our pit
sausage for the Porcules.
Beef chuck.
Back fat in the pork.
JUSTIN WARNER: By grinding
this in the walk-in--
Everything being cold.
JUSTIN WARNER: --you're
preserving the fat.
This thing can actually create
a degree of heat that is
going to self-render that fat.
And if the fat's
already rendered
by the time it's in your
patty, it's not going to make
its way into your mouth.
GUY FIERI: Stack in
for a second grind.
BEAU VONDRA: And
we're going to mix up
the spices inside the grinder.
Salt. Curing salt.
JUSTIN WARNER: Sodium
nitrate, correct?
Correct.
Ground mustard.
Crushed red pepper.
Black pepper.
Coriander.
Totally key.
Granulated onion.
Granulated garlic.
And we're just going
to mix this thing.
Dig it.
BEAU VONDRA: Case
up the sausage.
Smokes for about 45 minutes.
Next up?
BEAU VONDRA: Pork shoulder.
A little yellow mustard.
GUY FIERI: You get the enzymes.
You get the acid.
BEAU VONDRA: So we
hit it with salt
first so the paprika
and stuff doesn't
clog the pores of the meat.
GUY FIERI: Got it.
JUSTIN WARNER: Salt is
going to open it up.
Start the--
GUY AND JUSTIN: Osmosis.
Exactly!
BEAU VONDRA: So now we're
going to hit it with the rub.
GUY FIERI: Whose rub?
Three Little Pig's rub.
Then we hit it with
their Touch of Cherry
as kind of a finishing.
Rest overnight.
Hit it with a little more rub.
It's going to go into our
smoker for about 12 to 15 hours
at about 200 degrees.
Love this.
BEAU VONDRA: Pull it, and then
it's ready for the sandwich.
Pork-ules!
BEAU VONDRA: First, we're
going to split the pit sausage.
GUY FIERI: Nice
wood-fired grill.
Pork butt?
BEAU VONDRA: Pork brisket.
Regular butter to
give it a nice toast.
Let's build that
sandwich for you.
Little chili lime mayo.
Pit Sausage that
we ground together.
Pork brisket.
Pulled pork.
House-made spicy
mustard barbecue sauce.
Got it.
BEAU VONDRA: Pickled red onion.
Arugula on top.
"A-roo-gula."
You know, like the old horn?
I'll just see myself out.
BEAU VONDRA: All right,
and there's the Porcules.
There are three
textures of pork.
Three flavors of pork.
Because three things were
treated individually,
and they brought out
their best selves.
It's a triple punch.
Left, right, left.
The sauce in the
accoutrements is
not overpowering any of that.
It just lets
everybody sing, man.
Being that I'm
the-- or I was--
the host of the show, I agree
with everything Justin says.
This is a wonderful way to
explore the world of pork.
All the pork is fantastic.
Seasoned great.
That Ciabatta roll is
the perfect vessel.
It's a full home run.
Here's a Porcules
sandwich for you.
Thick and juicy because
it's just loaded with meats.
Pork-ception.
Pork-ceptional.
MAN: Everything
mixes well together,
but still stands out on its own.
This is unique to the
world, just so you know.
Hot soppressata.
WOMAN: What they've got
going on is incredible.
I don't know how far you live
from Sioux Falls, South Dakota,
but if you're looking
for a place to get
a well-rounded
experience, bring yourself
down to Look's Marketplace.
You'll love it.
Chef, nice job.
- Thank you.
[music playing]
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Up
next, a red-hot spot in Alaska.
It is everything
you want it to be
on a cold day in Fairbanks.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): Firing
up hearty Indian recipes.
GUY FIERI: Rich and fulfilling.
A tremendous amount of flavor.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Real deal, all the way.
This is fantastic.
I'm knocked out.
[music playing]
Believe it or not, folks, it
has been 11 years since Triple
D was in Fairbanks, Alaska.
I mean, that's when we came here
and met our good friend Benny
Lin from Pagoda Restaurant.
So we come back into town,
and we see that the food
scene has just blown up.
And I say, hey, is there
an Indian restaurant?
They said, you got
to check it out.
This is Hari Om.
Chicken tikka masala.
I've been completely
transformed by this place.
I'm working on palak paneer.
It feels like you're walking
into a different world.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): And
it's all legit thanks to chef
and owner Amit
Paul's culinary cred.
AMIT PAUL: All the
spices come from India.
Do you have enough?
You only have,
like, 80 over there.
[chuckles]
The flavor profiles
that you experience here--
I highly recommend it.
Next order is lamb korma.
Lamb korma is lamb
in a wonderful sauce.
It's amazing.
GUY FIERI: So what are
we going to make today?
AMIT PAUL: Salt, turmeric,
lime juice, chili powder.
Just regular,
old chili powder?
That's the old "clean out the
bowl with the chunks of lamb"
technique.
And how long will
this marinate, chef?
For 30 minutes.
This is make the garam masala.
AMIT PAUL: Cumin seeds.
GUY FIERI: Black cardamom.
AMIT PAUL: Bay leaves.
Star anise.
Cloves.
Peppercorn.
Now, what is this?
AMIT PAUL: Mace.
GUY FIERI: Mace.
The outside of the nutmeg.
AMIT PAUL: Yes.
GUY FIERI: Green cardamom.
Cinnamon.
Toasting these whole spices
just opens up all the flavor.
[blender grinding]
Such a soothing sound.
Makes you want to curl
up with a good book.
What's our next step?
Clarified butter.
Green cardamom.
AMIT PAUL: Cloves.
GUY FIERI: Cinnamon.
AMIT PAUL: And then you
add ginger garlic paste.
What you call something else.
Oh.
That's not what I
was going to call it.
AMIT PAUL: Cook for 10 minutes.
Then you're going to add--
- Tomatoes?
Yes.
Salt.
GUY FIERI: Garam masala, chili
powder, coriander, cumin.
AMIT PAUL: Yes.
It cooks right in the sauce?
Yes, sir.
For 30 to 35 minutes.
GUY FIERI: And you
heat it up for service?
AMIT PAUL: Yes.
GUY FIERI: Melon seed?
So those have been soaking.
That's a new one for me, folks.
AMIT PAUL: Cashew paste.
Cashew paste I've heard of.
OK.
A little basmati down.
AMIT PAUL: Yes.
[music playing]
To get lamb that
tender is amazing.
Never had the melon seed
milk, but it's delicious.
Rich and fulfilling.
A tremendous amount of flavor.
When you have a chance to
taste a fresh garam masala,
you'll want to come
back for it forever.
This is fantastic.
I'm knocked out.
AMIT PAUL: Lamb korma for you.
The lamb korma
is really hardy.
Super tender and super nice.
MAN: It's soaked up
these amazing spices.
There's that nuttiness,
but then there's
a little bit of heat behind it.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
And in Alaska,
a little heat can be good.
Have you done a winter yet?
Yes.
Negative 32.
Not so much.
WOMAN: At the end of a long day
of working with our sled dogs,
it's one of our
favorite places to come.
Chicken vindaloo is
for here, table two.
Chicken vindaloo has a
really nice mix of spices.
It's got a really thick sauce.
I could eat this all day.
What are we making?
Bay leaf.
Green cardamom.
Is green cardamom used more
than black cardamom, correct?
Yes.
GUY FIERI: Pureed red onion.
Very nice.
AMIT PAUL: Ginger garlic.
You have to add all the spices.
Salt.
Garam masala.
Indian chili powder.
And is that spicy?
(WHIMPERS) No.
Gorgeous.
And then tomato sauce.
And how long are we
going to cook this down?
AMIT PAUL: Hour.
GUY FIERI: Boneless,
skinless chicken thighs.
And let this go
for another, what?
AMIT PAUL: Half an hour.
What have the
potatoes been cooked in?
GUY FIERI: Love it.
[music playing]
Mm, it's fantastic.
Vindaloo is one of my favorites.
I love the spice, and
I love the acidity.
A little bit of
that vinegar coming
from that red chili sauce.
Tender chicken.
Lots of flavor, but not heavy.
I mean, it is everything
you want it to be.
Especially on a cold
day in Fairbanks.
Trust me on this one.
Well done.
OK, chicken vindaloo.
The chicken is to die for.
I mean, it just fell apart.
WOMAN: I like the
zip in that one.
It's so good.
Making the little lentil dal.
WOMAN: I really do love
everything I've tried.
It's an experience.
To have this type
of Indian food,
I hope people know
what a gift this is.
How do I say it again?
AMIT PAUL: Hari Om.
Yeah, you better hurry home.
You can use it.
It's funny.
Hari Om.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Coming up, a true bakery
cafe in Fargo, North Dakota.
You are a gift to the town.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Rocking out pecan rolls.
That's ridiculous.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER): And
packing savory flavor bombs.
GUY FIERI: That's a
come-back-to dish, for sure.
[music playing]
You know, the restaurant
scene, the restaurant culture,
is always changing.
And right now, what's hot?
It's ethnic restaurants,
Korean and Ethiopian
being two of my favorite.
But one that was such
a longstanding staple
in the restaurant
business was bakery cafes.
You know, bakeries
that were doing
it all, baking it from scratch.
So I'm here in
Fargo, North Dakota.
And when I hear
about a place that's
been doing it all from
scratch since 2003,
I gotta check it out.
This is Nichole's Fine Pastry.
MAN: Nichole's is
a local staple.
It's fresh-made everything.
Fresh fruit tarts, order up.
They're really known for
their desserts and sweets.
And we always check
out all of the soups
and salads and sandwiches.
It's hard to resist
everything she has.
GUY FIERI (VOICEOVER):
Which is a lot now,
but Nichole Hensen actually
started with the final course.
First year and a half,
it was just dessert.
But we added croissants
and sandwiches,
and we kept putting
it in the pastry case.
MAN: Everything in the
case looks delicious.
It's just, uh, I'll
take that today.
Sticky roll going in the oven.
MAN: The sticky
bun this my go-to.
I don't like them
in most other places.
But this one, they just
have a special taste.
What are we starting with?
Caramel sauce.
Well, let's get into it.
NICHOLE HENSEN: We're
pouring some sugar in.
Cream of tartar,
and a little water.
Cook this to 350 degrees.
GUY FIERI: Corn syrup.
NICHOLE HENSEN: Cream.
Salt.
Let this cool, and
we're going to go.
NICHOLE HENSEN: We're
making the dough.
What do we have
for ingredients?
NICHOLE HENSEN: Mashed potatoes.
- Mashed potatoes.
Secret ingredient.
Helps with the texture.
This is magic.
NICHOLE HENSEN: Sugar.
[guy whistles]
Butter.
And milk.
Heat this up to 115.
You know that you
are the real deal
when you carry your offset
spatula ninja style.
[slashing noises]
Don't serve that cake.
[imitates slicing]
NICHOLE HENSEN:
Once that's done,
we'll add the flour, some
yeast, salt. Pouring in.
Eggs.
OK, how long is
this going to mix?
One minute.
I'm going to put
the dough hook in.
GUY FIERI: So the
all-purpose flour again?
NICHOLE HENSEN: Yep.
One minute.
NICHOLE HENSEN: And then we're
going to speed two for three.
Whoa-ho!
NICHOLE HENSEN: Let it
proof for about an hour.
Look at that caramel.
It's got that tang,
that richness, the funk
that you get from caramel.
I'm not a sweets
person, but that's good.
Buttered in the pan.
Big amounts of caramel.
Sprinkle some pecan pieces.
And then we'll make the filling.
There's sugar.
There cinnamon.
And--
- Cardamom.
Cardamom.
I was gonna say cardamom!
Now we take the proofed
dough, roll this out.
A little melted butter.
Don't sit there and play
the little spoony-spoon game.
Just pour it on.
Roll us up.
GUY FIERI: All this work
for just one pecan roll?
One pan of seven.
You're a ninja.
Into the pan.
Once it proofs,
we go to the oven.
NICHOLE HENSEN: 325,
about 25 minutes.
GUY FIERI: That's ridiculous.
[laughs]
Oh, boy.
We got a problem.
No sticky.
[laughs]
GUY FIERI: There's something
about cinnamon roll
coming out of the oven.
The sugar, the caramel, the
cinnamon, and the fresh yeasty
roll.
I don't know this thing of
putting the potato in it.
But when I eat the dough
on this, it's rich.
It has the texture of bread, but
the light fluffiness of cake.
Not too many pecans.
Not too much caramel.
Yeah?
It's dynamite.
I mean, it's really delicious.
Pecan sticky roll, order up.
The caramel
sauce is delicious.
WOMAN: It's not, like, so sweet.
But it's, like,
crunchy, kind of.
Where did the
baking thing come in?
I got interested
halfway through school
for a business degree.
And then I went up to Alaska.
I worked at a fly-in
fishing lodge.
They bring you in the flour.
They don't bring
in the pastries.
They don't bring in the bread.
- That's correct.
And then I went
to pastry school.
Holy entrepreneur.
WOMAN: There's a lot of
coffee shops in Fargo,
but this one has more variety.
Here's your mushroom
and asparagus galette.
MAN: The galette's a pastry,
and it can be stuffed
with multiple different things.
The mushroom,
asparagus, cream cheese
goes really well together.
I'm not a cream cheese
guy, but I love this.
So what are we going to make?
The mushroom
asparagus galette.
And a galette is a--
NICHOLE HENSEN: Free-form tart.
- We're going to make the dough?
- Yes.
And we're going
to make the filling?
Yes.
And it's only
a half-hour show.
That's right.
GUY FIERI: Cream cheese.
Caramelized onion.
NICHOLE HENSEN: Chopped garlic.
Red pepper flakes.
Flaked thyme, cumin, salt.
GUY FIERI: So we're just
going to soften it up a bit.
Going to pour in some cream.
GUY FIERI: Next up?
NICHOLE HENSEN:
Mushroom mixture.
Crimini, oyster, shiitake.
So a little oil.
Salt and pepper.
GUY FIERI: What temp are
we dropping these in at?
NICHOLE HENSEN: 425.
Same on the asparagus.
We need to make
some galette dough.
[gibberish]
Galette dough?
Oh galette dough.
That's what I was going to make.
NICHOLE HENSEN:
All-purpose flour.
Cornmeal.
Salt. Cold Butter.
Into the food processor.
GUY FIERI: Making the gravel.
NICHOLE HENSEN: So on the mixer.
This is a lot of
equipment for one dough.
Water.
A little sour cream.
I like to make this extra cold.
Keeping the butter
cold is important.
So a little Martini
shaker might help you.
Yeah, it might, actually.
GUY FIERI: No, so we could
have Martinis, is what I meant.
How we looking?
NICHOLE HENSEN: Pretty good.
We let the dough chill.
Chill.
NICHOLE HENSEN: Portion it out.
Scoop of our cream
cheese filling.
Which, by itself, should
just be served on a spoon.
You can just lick it.
Offset spatula.
[swooshing sounds]
NICHOLE HENSEN: We'll a
scoop of the vegetables.
Give it a little pleat.
A little egg wash.
Mold and salt.
30 minutes.
NICHOLE HENSEN: 375.
We'll plate it with
a side salad with
a homemade lemon vinaigrette.
In today's world,
there's not many times
in the middle of
the day that you
can go and find roasted
mushrooms and asparagus
in a composed dish.
Delicious.
Let's first start with
the galette dough.
Very nice, very flaky,
and very not heavy.
The asparagus still have
really nice bite to them.
And you really can still pick up
the earthiness of the mushroom.
The herbed cream cheese is just
straight out of Flavortown.
I mean, that's a
come-back-to dish, for sure.
Plating a galette right now.
MAN: It's hearty.
It's delicious.
The cream cheese garlic flavor
in every bite really hits home.
I'll take all of those.
I'm addicted to Nichole's.
WOMAN: It just very European.
It's just amazing.
I think a lot of folks around
here are probably like, I mean,
everybody just
doesn't have a really
awesome gourmet bakery that's
across-the-board delicious.
You are a gift to the town.
Thanks.
Man, that was a
fantastic visit.
But don't you
worry-- there's funky
joints all over this country.
And we'll see you next time--
On "Diners,
Drive-Ins, and Dives."
Yeah!
Call this, like, the culinary
unicorn of Sioux Falls.
Of South Dakota, yeah.
Hold just a second.
So, um, the culinary unicorn
is what I was going to use.
Oh, shoot.
Sorry, Guy.
So I had that.
It was a really good one.
So [inaudible] mine.
- Got it.
Cool.
- OK?
- Yeah.
- Good talk.
Cool.
So the culinary leprechaun
of South Dakota.
[laughter]
[music playing]