I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's
greatest diners,
drive-ins, and dives.
And this trip is epic.
Out-of-the-gate
dynamite!
"Triple-D's" 50th state...
Here we go.
...with a slam-dunk visit
to South Dakota.
Get cracking.
Let me get my apron.
We've got a true
regional recipe...
Time for the
famous chislic.
...the state's first
Ethiopian emporium...
Delicious.
...a Midwest
down-south mash up...
If it's funky,
I'll find it.
You're welcome.
...and my Dakota
chef buddy...
What?!
...taking the heat
in the kitchen.
Little
sting-bada-bing, huh?
I start to quake in parts
I didn't know I could quake in.
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple-D."
♪♪
So, folks, I'm here in
Sioux Falls, South Dakota,
with my good friend
and chef, Justin Warner...
Listen, I got so excited
that you were coming
to South Dakota
and my new home state,
I thought, "I've gotta
get you exposed
to our state nosh."
I don't know why
it's named this,
because chislic has
an arguable etymology,
and might be Turkish --
related slightly
to shish kebab.
So, generally, we think of
meat on a stick,
but here,
we deep-fry it.
Welcome to
South Dakota, Guy!
GUY: And this is
Urban Chislic.
You gotta cut down
on the coffee, kid.
♪♪
1870 in the window.
I grew up in South Dakota,
so I've known about chislic
since I was a kid.
I got Philly
going -- beef.
Just cubed meat,
seasoned.
Chicken, beef, lamb --
whatever your
heart desires.
That's been
deep-fat-fried.
GUY: And it's this
South Dakota regional specialty
that Hong Phrommany
and his partners are banking on.
HONG: We had chislic
and said,
"You can turn this
into an entire menu."
GUY: So, that's exactly
what they did
with the help
of Chef Ryan Pederson.
Chislic started
150 years ago.
People that had mutton
figured out,
"If we cook it this way,
it's gonna take
some of that gamey
funkiness off of it."
And we've just taken that
and evolved it.
Pork chislic sandwich
in the window.
WOMAN: I had a pork
sandwich today.
It was fantastic.
It has a lot of
nice barbecue flavor,
and the sandwich
is massive.
GUY: What are we
doing first?
Our barbecue base.
Okay.
Tomato sauce,
brown sugar, molasses.
Worcestershire sauce,
soy sauce, liquid smoke.
The quadruplets
of umami.
OJ, paprika,
garlic powder,
stone ground mustard.
Turn into a three-hour
cooking show.
Onion powder, dry mustard,
fish sauce.
You took that right out of
Justin's briefcase.
The quintuplets
of umami!
Wow!
Tamarind paste,
salt and pepper,
a little garlic salt,
sugar.
Let this get heated up
a little bit.
We're gonna split it up
three ways.
It's some other sauce
to make a sweet sauce,
and it's some other sauce
to make a spicy sauce.
Yep.
A theme
in variations.
That's what I was
gonna say.
We'll tighten it up
with a little slurry.
You know, I love
hydrocolloids.
Cornstarch is
one of them.
But you all
knew that, right?
Come on.
He uses words that
you and I can't spell.
Yeah.
And then, we'll add our
stuff to make it sweet.
Butter, brown sugar.
Honey.
Time for the
famous chislic.
Cut off a little bit
of pork here.
Cubing it evenly
so that it all cooks
at the same time
and same temperature.
We don't skewer it?
I heard the old thing was,
we skewered all chislic.
The patron could be doing
the skewering themselves
via a toothpick.
Drop it in the fryer for
right about 90 seconds.
All right, Chef.
We're gonna make
some coleslaw
that's gonna go
on top of our sandwich.
Some shredded green cabbage,
mayo, red cabbage.
Some our house
honey mustard.
You make that also?
We do.
Sugar, kosher salt.
This is our
house dry rub.
We got white pepper,
black pepper,
garlic salt,
onion powder,
apple cider vinegar.
And mix it up.
Nature's whisks.
[ Laughter ]
Now we can finally
make the chislic
that I've been
waiting for?
Absolutely.
We got our chislic
fried off.
Right over to the flattop.
Sweet barbecue sauce.
Taking chislic to another
dimension, right?
Totally.
Chislic and cheese.
Swiss?
Domey for my homey.
It's getting steamy.
Toast off a bun.
I'm very excited
about this.
Slaw on it,
crispy onions strings.
Drizzle a little
barbecue on there.
All right, Chef,
one for you and one for me.
Justin, tell me how this looks
when I take a bite of it.
Sure it's gonna
look great.
All right, Justin,
go ahead.
Whoa, really?
Watch me eat this.
All right --
[ Laughter ]
Go ahead and grab
the sandwich.
Okay.
Now hand it
to the chef.
[ Laughter ]
[ Muffled ]
Go ahead.
That's lights-out, bro.
It's all the flavors of a
great pork barbecue sandwich,
but with just texture
after texture after texture.
The entire piece of pork
is caramelized.
You were talking
about that.
The cut was critical
to make sure that
you have the right ratio
between how crispy it's
gonna be on the outside
and how tender and juicy
it'll be on the inside,
and it's the perfect
balance of it.
The sweetness is there,
but it's not overly sweet.
One element takes it
over the top --
to me, the Swiss cheese.
It's that little bit of funk
that's in the back of it
that ties it all together.
If you're not
a fan of chislic,
this is like
gateway chislic.
Excellent.
Out-of-the-gate dynamite.
You guys both got the
barbecue pork chislic sandwich.
That's a great way
to eat pork, definitely.
The crunch of the coleslaw
was really nice and creamy.
They take chislic
to another level.
PEDERSON:
Nacho set-up.
It's a chislic Philly.
It's a chislic Cuban.
I absolutely love
the stir fry.
MAN: Today, I tried
a taco chislic,
which was unbelievable.
So, here's the deal --
Justin and I are
hanging out here in
Sioux Falls, South Dakota.
We're at Urban Chislic.
When we come back,
something else that's gonna
blow our mind.
Because it's blowing up the heat
in "Triple-D's" 50th state.
Regret lamb burger up.
I've never had anything
hotter than that burger.
Holy cow.
MAN: You don't have to
go to the gym.
You're gonna pour.
GUY: If you can pull off
the next dish this well,
you can actually drive
the car when we leave.
Oh, my gosh!
♪ Cubing meat softly
with your song ♪
BOTH:
♪ Cubing me softly ♪
♪ With his
wooooooords ♪
♪♪
[ Clock ticking ]
Uh, hi, I'm
Justin Warner,
and this is
"Triple-D."
Chef Ryan, tell us
what you got.
Hey, Warner, did you
start the show with out me?
I -- I would never.
Did he start the show
without me?
Warner.
Come on, I thought
we had --
You gotta watch yourself.
They're always nipping
at your heels.
The great chef,
Justin Warner.
Here we are.
Urban Chislic.
His idea.
I see now why.
The barbecued chislic
pork sandwich was awesome.
We brought the sweet,
and now, we're gonna
bring the heat.
Regret lamb burger
up in the window.
If you like heat and you want
to test your boundaries,
the Regret burgers
is a must.
It's a bonfire.
I'm gonna start
carving up
a little boneless
leg of lamb here.
Take just some of
the fat off,
'cause we're gonna grind that in
with some of the lamb.
You know why I think this is
gonna be exponentially better
than any other
lamb burger?
'Cause it's cubed.
Come on.
"Exponents"?
Everybody.
So, we're gonna make
our Sweet Hotness sauce.
Maple syrup, hot sauce,
brown sugar, salt and pepper.
Tighten it
with some slurry.
What's the rest of the
game plan over here?
We're gonna make our
Rack XXX sauce.
Start off with some of
that barbecue base
that we made earlier.
Then, we're gonna
add some
Carolina Reaper pepper
powder into that.
3 bucks --
dot your eye.
No way!
I wanna be in the rest
of the show, man!
Tighten it
with a little slurry.
Where are we at now?
We gotta make
an onion ring.
So, flour in the bowl.
Garlic salt,
some paprika,
onion powder, black pepper,
white pepper.
We have our dredge.
Now we're gonna make
our Bone Dust seasoning.
Kosher salt,
white pepper, chili powder,
Carolina Reaper pepper
in that as well.
[ Whistles ]
Little
sting-bada-bing, huh?
I start to quake in parts
I didn't know I could quake in.
Take our
panko breading.
Paprika, a little bit
of Bone Dust.
We're gonna
take our onions,
place them
in our egg wash.
A little dredge.
Another dunk!
And then, we're gonna
go into the "pain-ko."
Why did you do that?
Into the fryer.
Toast our bun up
a little bit.
Capicola?
Didn't see that coming.
Drizzled with
Sweet Hotness sauce.
Double patty smash.
Smoked habanero
jack cheese.
What is this?
Antacids for you.
Mmm!
[ Laughter ]
Where are those
jalapeños going?
Right on top of
the burger.
And then, this
delicious onion ring.
Look at that.
Is that how you normally
fill it up?
What?!
And then, you put a lid
on it so nobody knows.
All right, Justin.
Careful, it might
melt that knife.
Owwhh...
♪♪
[ Whistling tune ]
It is a little bit spicy.
I mean, I'll give
that a three.
On a scale of two!
But that lamb burger
is the thing I enjoy
the most about it.
It's nice warm heat.
Sub-Saharan.
Why are you
drinking that?
They just handed
it to me.
The medic did.
[ Laughter ]
It reminds me of the
combo that you get
with lamb
and harissa.
I'm getting some of that depth,
some of that earthiness.
That was it.
Let me help you out.
Come here.
Wait, is this
gonna explode?!
And you got
the Regret burger.
MAN: Juicy burgers.
They're terrific.
That crunch of that
onion ring --
the Sting Ring.
The "Sting Ring"?
The Sting Ring.
Lips are tingling.
Slurring the speech
a little.
Peach hab wings
in the window.
They have so many
different flavors.
It's unbelievable.
Come with a big appetite,
'cause you gotta eat a lot.
The whole experience
has been fantastic.
Chislic is the bomb.
Love that you take this
scratch-made attitude.
You're good
on your heat.
Called this the
Justin Warner-level,
but next time, make a
Fieri-level, would ya?
I will.
Well done.
Thank you, bro.
Justin?
One more to go?
What?!
[ Laughter ]
Up next in "Triple-D's"
50th state,
we're sticking to Sioux Falls
to grab legit Ethiopian.
You don't just
enjoy great food,
but you learn about
the culture.
From saucy chicken...
That's fantastic.
...to lights-out lentils.
I get mental for the lentil.
I gotta be honest.
♪♪
[ Car door slams ]
You know,
I gotta tell ya,
I think there might be
a little misconception
on "Diners, Drive-Ins, & Dives"
that everything we do
is pizza, tacos, fried chicken.
Don't get me wrong --
we do a lot of that --
but for me,
personally --
as a chef, as a guest
in a restaurant --
what do I like?
I love ethnic food.
I love learning
about the history,
the story, the culture,
the methods,
the ingredients.
So I'm here in
Sioux Falls, South Dakota,
and when I hear there's a joint
that's serving up
real-deal Ethiopian food,
you know I gotta check it out.
This is Lalibela.
♪♪
Lalibela [ Speaking Amharic ]
is ready.
I grew up in Ethiopia, and
this is like a taste of home.
Meat sambusa.
The flavors are robust.
A complex mix of spices.
GUY: Which was
all-new up here
When Mulageta
and Marta Endayehu
opened South Dakota's first
Ethiopian restaurant in 2003.
What are the
main spices?
We use curry...
Berbere is
the main one.
The main one.
It's finger meal.
We don't use fork.
You eat with
your hands.
Yes.
Good, 'cause I eat
with my hands anyways.
Oh, so it's going to
be easy for you.
I got this
figured out.
Yeah.
You eat with
the injera.
It absorbs
all of the flavors
of the dishes that are
put on top of it.
Without injera,
you don't eat anything.
We're not
having anything.
We're gonna use
three kind flour --
brown wheat...
Brown wheat.
And this is the teff
from Ethiopia.
Teff flour.
This is the starter.
From yesterday.
Yesterday.
Water.
And then, how long
does it need to set?
Overnight.
So it builds all
of the carbonation.
This is how we make.
Ethiopian crêpes.
And you have to
have the lid on it?
Yes.
[ Whistles ]
How pretty that is.
Okay, I want
you to try.
You did good.
Good job.
I think I made it
a little thick, though.
It is a beefy one.
It's not cooked very well.
That's why.
Yeah, I know it's
not cooked very well!
Right.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Delicious.
Little moist, tender,
but a bit of chew to it.
The tang from the starter
is outstanding.
What are we
making next?
Doro wot.
The doro wot
is a chicken dish.
You get the chicken
and the egg.
It's wonderful.
We do, first, butter.
Garlic.
GUY: That's a lot
of cardamom.
[ Laughs ]
Strong.
Mm-hmm.
MAN: [ Laughs]
Ginger.
Boil it.
Strain it.
I'm gonna do
the doro wot.
Onion, the oil,
garlic.
A lot of it.
One pound berbere.
That much berbere?
Tomato paste,
water, ginger.
Cardamom.
It is a very thick sauce.
Gonna put the chicken.
How long is this
gonna cook in here?
20 minutes.
At the end, we're gonna put
the hard boiled egg.
[ Laughs ]
♪♪
Little bit
of the butter?
Yes.
And what kind of cheese
is this, Chef?
You make that?
Yes.
So, it tastes a little
like ricotta.
Oh, I thought that was
a napkin roll-up.
[ Laughs ]
This is the injera.
I was gonna get my
silverware out of there.
Little salad.
Oh, right in
the center.
And cheese, potato,
carrot, and cabbage.
Full-blown meal we got
going here, folks.
Tear off
a piece, correct?
Grab some chicken,
little cheese.
♪♪
Mmm!
That's fantastic.
The sauce, it's rich.
It does have
a little spice.
Lot of garlic,
lot of onion,
little bit of chicken.
I like the little bit
of break that you get
from the nice
light cheese.
♪♪
But with this injera,
rip off a little piece,
grab a little chicken,
get down tonight.
♪ Get down tonight ♪
I mean, delicious.
A doro wot.
The chicken is
incredibly tender,
and it soaks up
all of the spices.
The sauce is what's really
getting at me right now.
I mean, it's like,
you could almost
put that sauce
on anything, right?
Yeah, pretty good.
In the middle of January
when it's way below zero,
to come in here and get
the warmth of the food
is something that's very
unique and special.
Miser key wot.
The miser key wot is a
spicy blend of lentils.
It really hits the spot.
"Miser key wot"?
"Key wot" is
hot red sauce.
We're using the lentils
instead of using the chicken.
Oh, yes.
Oil.
Onions, garlic,
and ginger --
The foundation
of Ethiopian food.
Yes.
Berbere.
A lot of it.
Tomato paste.
Put water.
And, of course,
the lentils.
And it's a split lentil.
Washed them
and soaked them.
Yes.
And how long is this
gonna cook, Chef?
About 45 minutes.
I get mental
for the lentil.
I gotta be honest.
When does the
cardamom go in?
When we're ready
to serve?
Yes.
That's the meat and potatoes
right there, folks.
A little bit of that
super butter.
Injera.              Injera.
It's a big tortilla.
I guess I got a big
family coming over.
That's quite the portion.
But I think it's gonna
rock the house.
♪♪
Delicious.
A lot of attention.
Great fresh spices.
It's a bit spicy.
You get all of the favorites
out of the berbere.
The lentils
remind me of beans.
They a little bit
of that same texture.
This concept right here
of scooping it up...
Pretty special.
Miser key wot.
Just incredibly
flavorful,
but not in a hot,
burn-your-mouth kind of way.
MAN: I live
120 miles away.
I come down at least
once a month.
They're exceptional.
A great chef that
knows how to do it
and understands
all the aspects.
You don't just
enjoy great food,
but you learn
about the culture.
Let's make the rest
of the menu.
Okay.
Get cracking.
Let me get my apron.
♪♪
Coming up
in Garretson...
Dude, I don't know
what's going on right now.
...a crazy cafe
making things their way.
This is a little bit of the
culinary Twilight Zone.
Like a cheesy
shrimp surprise...
I can't stop eating it.
...and greens
like I've never seen.
Those are lights-out greens
right there, I'm telling you.
♪♪
So, I'm here in
Garretson, South Dakota --
about a half hour outside
of Sioux Falls --
to check out a restaurant
where the chef --
Well, he was born
in northern California,
but he's got
strong southern roots.
He's got an
eclectic menu,
and he's got a unique style,
and he's doing things his way.
This is "O" So Good.
♪♪
Barbecue ribs
and a pan-fried walleye.
WOMAN: I think I've had
every dish on the menu.
Everything is
so flavorful.
And your bowl
of jambalaya.
WOMAN:
It's an amazing Southern flavor
that we just don't have
here in the Midwest.
FIERI: But Omar Thornton
is bringing it to South Dakota
straight out
of Northern California.
Where you getting Southern flair
out of Oakland?
My mom is from
Shreveport, Louisiana.
Alright. Let's go.
Jerk chicken
with collard greens.
You wouldn't think that
you could find jerk chicken
in South Dakota, but Omar
just knows how to make it.
Collard greens here
are better than my grandma's.
Sorry, Grandma.
What are we doing?
Marinade for our jerk chicken.
A little bit of buttermilk
there, I learned from my mom.
A little cayenne pepper.
A little?
That's a little, right?
Salt.
Mix that nice and good there.
Nice and good there?
Oh, my mom's
gonna love that one.
Is your mom
still in Shreveport?
Unfortunately,
she passed away.
Oh, so she's watching it
right now.
She's watching right now.
Theresa, what do you think
of that, "nice and good there"?
Probably gonna feel a pop
on the back of my head.
Yeah, you're gonna get a smack.
Alright, my friend,
what are we into?
Jerk rub.
Brown sugar, garlic,
onion powder, cayenne,
nutmeg, chipotle.
Chipotle.
Dash seasoning, cumin,
magic seasoning,
salt, pepper, ginger.
Paprika.
Chicken into the spice.
Go into the pan -- little bit
of oil, little bit of butter.
Pork belly, peppers,
jerk seasoning,
a little bit of water,
and we get it covered up.
Next up?
Mashed potatoes.
Skin on, boiled.
Butter, raw garlic,
heavy whipping cream, cheese.
Go into our mashing.
Look at the arm
on that guy.
Give it a little heat,
cook that garlic out, and next?
We're gonna make
our famous collard greens.
Bacon, black pepper.
Butter makes it
more better.
Onions, peppers,
carrots, celery,
house seasoning, water,
concentrated ham base.
You really are looking to do
Southern cooking, paprika.
And a lot of people
out here
do not have paprika
in their cupboard.
It's a good pepper flavor,
right?
Add in the collards,
red potatoes,
chili powder, garlic powder,
onion powder,
fresh chopped garlic.
Kitchen sink.
Spinach, a little bit
of our house seasoning,
more water.
Cover and let that
feel the love.
So we're gonna take
those mashed potatoes.
I don't know that I've
ever had jerk chicken
and mashed potatoes.
Welcome to the Midwest.
Our pork belly,
a little peppers and onions,
dried parsley, peppers.
And those
beautiful collards.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
That's how my wife looks at me
sometimes -- sideways.
Dude, I don't know
what's going on right now.
Just a little bit
of the culinary "Twilight Zone."
I've never seen collard greens
with potatoes in them.
Those are lights-out greens
right there, I'm telling you.
We load them up.
Thank you.
Now my mom's giving me a pat
on the back right now.
Wow! I don't know
if I call that jerk.
I call that delicious.
I get a little bit of jerk
and I get a little bit
of blackened
of panfried chicken.
But it works.
Well,
I'll tell you one thing.
I can't stop eating it.
What you're doing
hat got a ton of flavor.
What's the old motto
here on "Triple-D"?
If it's funky,
I'll find it.
You're welcome.
Putting down the jerk chicken.
It's just perfectly cooked.
Just the right amount
of seasoning.
Do you like
collard greens?
I had never had them before
until I had them here,
but they're amazing.
This is kind of like
the first car that you drove
for your driver's test
was a Ferrari.
FIERI: And while Omar's cooking
up his own style in the kitchen,
he and his wife, Renee,
are making sure
the rest of the joint
has its own funky vibe, as well.
-You got an open kitchen.
-Yes.
You got live music.
The whole thing has just got
an energy and an attitude.
MAN: I live in Sioux Falls.
It's a 35-minute drive for me.
But I'll come here
for three meals a day if I can.
We have a shrimp hot plate.
A cheesy shrimp dish
is a really good dish,
the way he cooks it up
and seasons it.
Have your taste buds ready.
It's great stuff.
What's it gonna be,
Chef?
Our shrimp hot plate.
Putting seafood
with cheese.
We are...
[ Laughs ]
We're gonna start
with our cornbread.
I can only imagine what
the cornbread's gonna be.
There we go.
So our regular
cornbread mix
and then we go with
sweet potato here, oil, eggs,
house seasoning, a little bit
of milk, roasted red peppers.
And then, of course, we got
to add a little bit of heat.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Cayenne?
Now we just know
that he's full-on crazy.
Mix that up, in the oven.
350, 20 minutes.
Next up?
A little bit of olive oil.
Butter.
Shrimp into the pan.
Cajun seasoning.
Go ahead
and get our cornbread
topped with butter
and brown sugar.
You hear the music?
[ Marching band plays ]
Got his own little marching band
going on in there right now.
Coming off the pan, Gouda,
cheddar, pepper Jack.
Into the salamander
for about two minutes.
We have a red chips, cornbread,
and we do fried kale here.
Take a little bit
of the red.
Parsley just to give it
a little bit of color.
And there's your
finished product, Chef.
♪♪
[ Laughs ]
Let me start off with saying
I'll eat this whole plate.
But it does not...
make any sense.
It's almost like
I'm eating shrimp poutine.
I got French fries.
The sauce is the cheese.
And then all of a sudden,
in the middle of this
crazy dream I'm having,
I get cornbread.
I almost could squeeze it,
and it would...
it would drip.
Shrimp are cooked
perfectly.
Potatoes are delicious.
Fried kale.
And the cornbread is the bomb.
Your shrimp
cheesy hot plate.
The first thing
you get is the cheese.
And then all of a sudden
you start feeling
a little tingle on your tongue,
and then your whole mouth
goes, "Wow."
You take a bite of cornbread.
It's like a cake.
Fried chicken breast
with a meatloaf.
There's nothing that holds
a candle to this place.
It's just love and soul.
Don't come in here with
any preconceived idea
of what you're gonna get.
I've only had two dishes
and I've been surprised
at both of them.
I can only imagine
what the rest of the menu is.
Nicely done, Chef.
Thank you.
You're gonna love it.
Well, that's it for this trip,
folks, but don't you worry.
There's funky joints
all over this country,
and I'll be looking
for you next time on...
ALL:
"Diners, Drive-Ins & Dives"!
[ Cheering ]
They don't consume
a lot of spice.
Why are you speaking
so loud?
I can't hear, Guy.
[ Laughs ]