People as me all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint
you checked out
in that one city when
you were doing DDD,
how they doin'?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
'cause DDD joints
have been blowin' up
and we're going back
to see what's cookin'.
Like on this trip.
All thriller, no filler.
A century-old sausage maker
in Portland, Oregon...
Look at 'em hotdog lasso
on the ranch at Flavortown.
...still stuffing
the family secrets.
This only says trouble for me.
Fantastic.
A meat and three at OKC...
[laughing]
-...that's good for the soul.
-Mmm.
♪ Mama Es, Mama Es
Mama Es ♪
♪ Will make will see ♪
[Guy] And in Florida...
I like that. That's good.
...a Jamaican joint
with all the island eats,
from soft dish to spicy hot.
Forty-five Scotch bonnets
in that batch of beef.
That's legit.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is Triple-D Nation.
So, the next time
you find yourself
in Portland, Oregon,
and you're cruising
on the southeast side
of Woodstock Boulevard,
and you look out the window
and you see some dude
grilling sausages,
you think, "Wait a second.
Didn't I see that joint
on Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives in 2009?"
-Show me a champion bite.
-[laughs] A champion bite.
Wow.
I'm back in town
and I got to check it out.
This is Otto's.
We try whenever we travel
to stop at places
that are on DDD.
So this was definitely
on our to-do list.
[man] If you're looking
for sausage and meat,
bockwurst and bratwurst
to barbecue,
it's the best in town.
They're just a great family
that really knows their
sausage and their meat pats.
[Guy] That's because the
Eichentopfs have been at it
for almost a century.
My grandfather came over
from Germany,
built this building in '37.
Here we go.
[Guy] And decades later,
Otto's grandson Jerry
is the sausage master,
running this place
with his wife Gretchen
and generation number four...
and five.
My daughter Heidi,
my daughter Bereka, Christie,
my granddaughter Krystin,
and my grandson Tanner.
All right, guys.
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay.
You two haven't aged.
[laughing]
You three got older.
Not older bad.
I have the funniest bit
of the three of you in the...
What's your favorite sausage?
-Hotdog.
Hotdog.
-Hotdogs.
-Wow.
-We'll make
old-fashioned wieners.
-Okay.
We use bull meat.
Like a big bull.
Nice and lean,
it's got a good sinew...
So the things we typically
don't like about bull meat,
that it is tough
and then it does have sinew.
Exact reason why
they made hotdogs out of.
And we're gonna go
with a little bit
of boneless picnic.
The bottom part
that has the bigger bone and
is more muscly, that's that.
Little bit of pork cheeks.
-Pork right here?
-Pork right there.
-And why that?
-It just has
a great flavor to it.
We'll add a little bit
of salt to that.
That's got a little nitrate
and a little bit of sugar.
Fire in the hole!
That's awesome.
Now, to keep it cold,
we're gonna add
a little bit of ice to that.
-Because it starts
to gum up, right?
-Right.
Okay, what's
the first seasoning?
We're gonna add
a little bit of black pepper,
-a little bit of coriander.
-Wow.
Celery salt,
brown mustard, paprika.
A little bit of ground mace.
[Guy] Mace, huh?
A little pork gel,
a little sweeter than
your back fat.
I was saying in the other
that we got good binding.
I think it was the first time
that we ever shot hotdogs
on Triple D.
Grab ourselves a casing,
natural sheep intestines.
[Guy] A little knot on
the end of it. Dig it.
-[whirring]
-Woah!
-And we're making sausages.
-Yes, we are.
-Would you like to try it?
-Oh, hey. You know I do.
I'll take my bling off
for this.
[Guy yelps]
-Can't you just make it
come out a little bit slower?
-I did.
Oh, I'm so not getting to
do this job, am I?
I'm going to be washing dishes
here forever.
So you just spin
every other one of them.
Skip one, spin one.
[Guy] Look at those things.
We got hotdog lasso on
the ranched flavor town.
So, what happens now?
We are going to
hang them on those sticks,
spread them around till
they get smoked
all the way around.
I am driving
the hot dog truck!
Into the smoker.
-Okay, 2 hours? How long?
-Two hours.
You want me to
stand here and guard?
I'm with you.
I just remembered
that experience of you
bringing the hotdogs out.
Holy Moly!
That is so awesome.
-How long in
the hot water for?
-Fifteen minutes.
Just to get the internal
temperature to 155.
Meet chiquita bananas.
-And then you put them
in the cold waters.
-Chill them off real quick.
So, this is done and
ready to rock?
-Done and ready to rock.
-Okay.
-That's a snap.
-Oh.
Tender, creamy, juicy.
Right to the grill.
Just enough to
give it a little mark.
I saw everything
that went in there.
That's as real as you can get.
You the man.
You folks are making
the legit grits.
What's the number one
selling sausage?
Still the same?
-[man] Hot dogs.
-[woman] And pepperonis.
Oh, the pepperoni here
is excellent.
We never have a problem
eating it all.
People love to get 10 stick,
20 sticks,
a hundred sticks.
Pork pig neck,
cayenne pepper,
ground pepper,
a little garlic,
red pepper flakes
and curing salt.
Now, we're gonna put it
in the stuffer.
-[Guy] In the Turbo Max 9000?
-In the Turbo Max 9000.
Probably not the exact words
but it's close.
[chuckling] This guy kills me.
Now we are going to take
these pepperoni sticks in
the smoke house for 2 hours.
Take them out, put them
in a hot water bath at
160 degrees for 1 hour.
And then, we will put them
in a cold water bath
to get their temperature down.
We'll take it out and
it's ready to eat.
I don't want to
like this, okay?
This only says,
"trouble" for me.
Fantastic.
How many of these
we make a week?
[laughing] A lot.
These are dynamites.
Here's your pepperoni sticks.
The pepperoni is
one of my favorite things.
Perfect amount of crunch.
When you bite into it,
you get a nice snap.
Not too spicy.
Smells really good when
they take it out of
the smoker too.
All right,
so give me the rundown.
Tell me where things are.
Seems like everything's
pretty much stayed
the same here.
Still the same volume?
or more volume from
back in the day?
We expected a big hit.
And all heck broke loose.
We couldn't make
sausages fast enough.
That's 11 years ago.
-Hasn't stopped since.
-That's great.
[narrator] And coming up,
time is really flying by...
Fifth generation actually
starting to work here?
-Yup.
-That's crazy.
[narrator] Plus, a sandwich
taking me way back.
My favorite thing,
since I was a little kid.
How I missed this last time,
it's all your fault.
[narrator] Back in 2009,
I went to this family-run
meat emporium for
a Triple D first.
One of the things
we've never seen,
something that
we all love and admire,
the kid pleasing,
grill loving,
old fashioned hotdog.
So that brings us here to
Portland, Oregon,
to the fourth generation
sausage kitchen, at Otto's.
So, who had the baby?
-How old is the baby now?
-Eleven.
-Do we have any other kids
working here yet?
-Yup.
-So, we have 5th generation
starting to work here?
-Yup.
-That's crazy.
I've never seen a
more close-knit family.
They're all involved,
all the time.
Everything they make
is wonderful.
They basically have
any kind of deli meat
that you'd want.
Everything from
the hard stuff to find
to just the basics.
Okay, pastrami.
-Give me the rundown here.
-We've got the bottom round
trimmed off a bit of the fat.
We're going to mix it in salt,
nitrate solution.
Take our pickling spice,
mustard seeds, peppers.
Some peppercorns,
you've got some herbs
in there, coriander.
How long are we gonna leave
this rub on there?
-Three weeks.
-Really?
-The curing process is done.
-We'll just rinse her off.
-[Guy] Over here.
-Then we're going to take
our coarse black pepper.
[Guy] You pack it
in there a little bit.
-It looks like
it's ready to go.
-Yeah.
[Guy] And now we're going to
put these in the smoker?
-They've been in there
overnight.
-Wow.
-Now, we're just gonna...
-Do you have to talk?
Just look at it for a second.
-Open up the hot tub.
Just lay it in there.
-For about 3 and a half hours.
[Guy] Wow, look at that.
-[Guy laughing]
-Think he's
running off with it.
-So you hand in the meat
and me off?
-Handing it off.
We're going to make
a pastrami sandwich for you.
-Do you like pastrami?
-Uh-huh.
-You like a lot of pastrami?
[Gretchen] This is
melt-in-your-mouth good.
There you are. Ready?
That is awesome.
That's killer pastrami.
All thriller, no filler.
Now we have
the Guy Fieri sandwich,
with rye bread,
mustard and pastrami.
It's a top seller.
Otto's has all kind of
sandwiches that are
homemade and delicious.
Orchard sandwich
is my favorite.
The Orchard is
the community sandwich
that the whole area loves.
This is what everybody loves,
so give me the rundown.
-What's in it?
-So, it's got honey mustard,
Granny Smith apples,
our hunter sausage.
The hunter sausage is
boneless bull meat,
pork cheeks, mustard powder,
paprika, fine pepper,
coriander, ground mace,
ground celery seed
and our curing salt.
We are going to add
some pork loins,
garlic powder and turn it on.
The hunter sausage is
a bigger sized salami
that we'll slice deli-style.
-We use havarti cheese...
-Was this one the menu when
I was here the last time?
-Yes.
-This has always been here?
-I missed this
the last time I was here?
-Uh-huh.
Okay, so I'm gonna tell you
something very funny
about this.
Let me take a bit first.
Outstanding sandwich.
All right,
since I was a little kid,
my favorite thing was to eat
sliced green apple
and salami.
So, the fact that you make a
sandwich with my favorite,
which is honey mustard,
and you put green apples and
the salami that you guys make,
the hunter sausage.
How'd I miss it the last time?
It's all your fault.
The sausage is amazing,
and you get plenty of it.
A little tang, a little sweet,
and a little tart of the meat,
that was just like
an instant hit with me.
The sausage is
my favorite part.
It's got that burst of flavors
but it's not too heavy.
And then the apple crunch
at the finish is delicious.
Every time I'm on
this side of the town,
I stock it up
and take it home.
Do you ever mail or send food
to California, to people
that've done shows here?
[woman] I guess we will now.
I mean, I don't know
where that came from?
For a while there,
every time around Christmas,
a little jerky package,
which got, somehow,
somebody lost my address.
I'm gonna get them there.
Oh, we're getting
our FedEx number organized
real quick before I leave.
[narrator] Coming up,
a soul food spot
in Oklahoma City.
Off the hook
in the culinary church.
[narrator] Feeding
their fans everything...
[woman] Oxtails.
[narrator] from head to toe.
-The hoof is the best.
-It is melt-in-your-mouth.
[narrator] Back in 2009,
I found myself
in a familiar spot.
Couple of years ago, when
we were cruising Triple D
through Oklahoma City,
we had a chance to
eat some killer barbecue
at this place called Leo's.
Now, believe it or not,
right across the intersection
from Leo's,
is another great place,
serving up 3 generations
of soul food.
And they're still dishing up
the same classics.
It's time to check out
Mama E's.
♪ Mama E's, Mama E's,
Mama E's ♪
♪ Will make you see ♪
Triple D showed everybody,
what a phenomenal
restaurant it is,
and if he didn't
know about it before,
he needs me on your list.
Mama E's is
one of the greatest
soul food restaurants
that you will ever find
in these United States.
This is Grandma
inside of a restaurant.
[Guy] And not
just Grandma, Mama too,
'cause owner and pastor,
Keith Patterson, named
this place
after his late mother, Evelyn.
-Now this is
your grandson, correct?
-That's my grandson.
Not only rockin' it here,
-but he's a pastor across
the street at the church.
-[Grandma] Oh, yes.
-Started across the street
in a little hut.
-Right
$50 and a waffle iron
-is what brought this business
to where it's at today.
-No.
-$50 and a waffle iron.
-That so beats my record.
When Guy was here
the last time,
he had pig feet.
I don't think he's
ever had a pig hoof.
-I don't know that I've
ever got down with the hoof.
-The hoof is the best.
-[laughing]
-Hmm. Oh, I got it.
That's one of our staples
in the community,
the black community.
We eat a lot of the pig feet.
-Gimme a high hoof.
-Yeah, high hoof. [laughs]
[hoots] So, anyhow,
water first.
The chicken base, onions,
-bell peppers, basil,
-A little basil.
chopped garlic,
cracked red peppers
Oh, I like this.
-Mama E's secret blend.
-You're not gonna
tell me what that is?
-Can't tell you what that is.
-Hang on a second.
Let me ask you
if this is what it is.
-[whispers]
-Mm-hmm.
-Aha!
-Right on the money.
He's good with knowing spices.
-[laughs]
-High hoof.
Black pepper,
added the vinegar to this.
Vinegar's gonna take
some of that swiny out.
-Wait, wait, wait...
-Did I say swiny? [laughs]
[Guy] Wrap it up.
Hour and a half.
Hour and a half. Pullin' 'em
out of the oven.
Pull that off of there.
[Guy] Make sure you'll get me
an al dente tape pig feet.
If you've never had pig feet,
you might not understand
pig feet, okay?
-So, that looks like a ratio
of, like, 50% fat, 50% meat.
-Fat and meat. That's it.
Mm, really good.
The flavor's money. But then,
the fat is like butter.
We still serve pig feet.
We serve 'em every Thursday,
and they sell great.
It melts in your mouth. Mm.
[upbeat music playing]
They have a lot
of different types of meat.
Pig feet, neck bones,
the fried chicken...
If you like to eat,
you will find something
that you will enjoy.
We have different entrees,
and those change out daily.
Thursday, we have pig feet.
Mainly on Fridays,
we do these oxtails.
And this is our take
on oxtails.
White pepper, seasoning salt,
soy sauce, a little garlic.
Get the flavor's all on there,
we marinate it real good.
Drop 'em into the hot butter,
allow them to get a sear.
You don't wanna cook 'em,
you just want
a nice sear on 'em.
If you cook them too fast,
they're gonna be tough.
We're gonna start now
with carrots, red onions,
celery, and white onions,
then we're gonna add green
bell peppers, minced garlic,
chicken base, beef base,
a little seasoning salt,
Italian seasoning,
wheat basil,
parsley, a little red wine...
Once you ger 'em
a little tender, you can add
just a little water,
that'll glaze your pan.
Now that our stock is ready,
we're gonna load it
on top of the oxtails,
come back with that wine,
then we're gonna add
your bay leaves.
Them we're gonna
cover it in water,
wrap them in foil,
and we're gonna let
the magic happen.
Now, we're gonna
show you the goodness.
After we finish,
we put that juice there.
And those are
oxtails at Mama E's.
[waitress] Here's
your oxtails with three sides
and a dinner roll.
The oxtails, man,
it was one of the most
absolute tender meat,
like, perfect cooked,
seasoned perfectly.
It's super juicy,
it just falls off the bone,
it's delicious.
Off the hook
in the culinary church.
[laughing]
[Keith] After Triple D,
we saw a lot more people
come in,
we went from
15 seats to 56 seats.
You know, when food is good,
it has to go national.
You heard my local boy.
You know, nobody knew me,
but now, hey, guess what?
This show took me to a status
where a lot of people come
and say, "Hey, I know you."
[Guy] And they know
his fried ribs.
They start out looking
like this and then,
they end up looking like that.
We can make 'em
marinade and the dredge.
And basically,
the same ingredients
go in both.
[man] We'll add the cumin,
the seasoning salt,
barbecue spice,
granulated garlic,
black pepper...
-Dig it. Into the
all-purpose flour.
-Mix all that up.
Then we have
the meat tenderizer,
Worcestershire,
a couple cups of water,
then we cut all of the ribs
we're gonna put 'em
in the marinade, we'll let 'em
sit for a while.
Now, they're ready
to do the dredge.
Comes three to an order.
When it's cooked,
it needs about 7-8 minutes,
and then, they'll be done,
ready to be plated up.
Here are your fried ribs.
[woman] It's not like
a normal rib
that you put
barbecue sauce on.
You really just taste
the flavor of the meat.
It's perfect.
These fried ribs
are succulent.
The moisture that
comes out of it.
and this is so soft.
I'm almost about to bite
into it again right now.
Mm.
Hey, Grandma,
what are you thinking?
Is he knockin' it out?
Oh, I'm so proud.
My heart is so big.
A year later, she passed.
Miss her every day,
and I know that her my mom
looking down at us
and proud of us.
[Guy] Comin' up in Florida...
The never-ending pot symphony.
A Jamaican joint
firin' on all cylinders.
-Super spicy?
-Give me super spicy.
This I how you get goin' on.
[exclaims]
[Guy] You ever find yourself
cruising around town,
thinkin',
Well, I want some
Jamaican food,
you know, like some
stewed oxtail
or maybe some curried goat.
Or better yet,
some stewed peas with pigtail
Thankfully, I found some
in a strip mall
in Miami, Florida,
back in 2008.
Mm.
And they're still there.
The line is just
a little longer.
You got to come
and check out this joint.
Jamaica Kitchen.
On point.
[man] I wasn't surprised
when this was featured
on Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives
because the food
is just so amazing.
[woman] It's Jamaican.
It's got flavor.
I'm always hyping
this place up.
I come from a background
of Chinese-Jamaican.
I think this is as authentic
as you get.
[Guy] It's as if Cheryl Chin
was born to make
this kind of food.
[Cheryl]
Three of my grandparents
are from China.
My own parents
were born in Jamaica
and the recipes has been
passed on for years.
Now that I look
at Jamaican food,
I see how many influences
actually really did come
from Chinese food.
Big kitchen.
How you doin', sir?
[Cheryl] When Triple D
came here,
this was probably
one of the first
ethnic restaurants
that they ever came to.
That was 12 years ago.
My husband still here.
I'm still here.
Alfred's still here?
Alfred is our main chef.
He's the early man.
He starts here
at 5:30 every morning.
So, Alfred, you're in charge?
They work hard. I mean,
this is hard to make
all this food.
When you come in.
If you like spicy,
if you don't like spicy,
there's a little bit
of everything
for everyone here.
I gotta tell you, Alfred,
this is the most unique
layout of food I've seen.
-[Alfred] Really?
-[Guy] Oh, yeah.
The never-ending
pot symphony.
[Cheryl] Pork and Ham choy.
Mm.
That's a pigtail.
Pigtail.
Very nice.
Oxtail stew?
This looks outstanding.
Mm.
That's sour.
We also have a combination,
curry goat and curry oxtail.
-We have curry oxtail?
-We do.
Mm.
This I could get goin' on.
Curry goat, oxtail,
jerk chicken, jerk pork.
Those are heavier dishes,
a bit heavier dishes,
and we also have lighter fare,
like the cabbage
and saltfish.
The cabbage and saltfish
is amazin'.
It's one of our favorite dish.
We'll start with garlic,
scotch bonnet pepper,
and butter.
Scallions, onions,
some tomatoes
and black pepper.
Now we're gonna
put in the saltfish.
We boil the cod twice
to get the salt out,
and then we shred it.
And now we're ready
for the cabbage.
Is this time?
Yeah, we're gonna
let this cook for another
four minutes,
and then it's ready to serve.
And this is our
cabbage and saltfish.
Full of flavor, it's creamy,
a little bit of richness.
It was very peppery,
and garlic was really complex.
[man] It's so authentic,
the food is so true
to Jamaican culture.
[man] Jamaican food
is a lot of spices
and flavors you've
never tasted before.
Jamaican food doesn't
have to be spicy,
but when it is,
it's so much better.
Don't be a wuss,
get a super spicy.
-Gimme super spicy!
-Super spicy.
That's got like
45 peppers in it.
That's fantastic.
And in the little
red dots mean?
-Four red dots
means super hot.
-Means trouble.
Mm.
Where was I on this...
I think Guy met his
match there with spicy.
45 scotch bonnets in that
batch of beef.
-[exhales]
-[Cheryl laughs]
Oh!
That's legit.
Mm.
[Cheryl] Cabbage and saltfish.
[man] I have no idea
how he found this place.
Wow.
I thought it was
our best kept secret,
but somehow Guy found it.
And, I mean, it's packed.
It's packed all the time,
but it's worth it.
You don't see this
every day on
Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives.
No.
Guy, sandwich...
[Guy] But that's what
I always say.
Enjoy.
[Guy] If it's funky,
we'll find it.
So we'll check in on more,
next time on Triple D Nation.
I've had tongue anyway
you can lick it.
Yeah.
Lamb's tongue, goat tongue,
beef tongue...
[Grandma]
You better rephrase that.
[Guy] Yeah,
that didn't sound...
[laughing]