You know, people are
asking me all the time.
"Hey, Guy, that one joint
you checked out
in that one city
when you were doing Triple-D.
How are they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
[Guy] Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning.
'Cause Triple-D joints
have been blowing up
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip.
Have you ever seen
Guy Fieri's
Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives?
[Guy] An old standby
in San Francisco...
All my boys in the crew
love the 23.
...still serving up
seafood with a scenic view.
This is you, Mac?
I'm impressed, kid.
-In Minnesota...
-Pasta Godfather.
[laughing]
...an Italian joint
stepping up
their pasta production...
I love this.
I'm getting one of these.
Mmm. Wow, that's good.
And way up in Wisconsin,
a neighborhood spot
with a name might not fit...
6'4" and you have
a place called Shorty's.
But the flavors are legit.
Ooey, gooey cheesiness
right there.
Familiar faces,
new places and more
off-the-hook flavors.
This is Triple-D Nation.
So let's talk about
how a lot of Triple-Ds
get started.
It usually involves
you sending us an email,
and then, us trying to
track the joints down.
But not this time.
Not in San Francisco
on the Embarcadero.
Now, this bad boy's
all mine.
That's because back in 2009,
this local landmark
was run by one of
my buddies' moms.
And now, she's finally
let him take the reins.
You gotta check out
Pier 23.
Pier 23's right on
the Embarcadero, which
makes it super accessible
to almost anywhere else
in the city.
This is an amazing
Triple-D location.
You feel like a regular
the first time that you
walk through the door.
I did see the Triple-D
episode, and it did a great
job of capturing the ambience.
[Guy] It's the vibe
that owner Flicka McGurrin
is sticking to,
ever since she bought
the waterfront spot
36 years ago.
We pretty much
don't change that much.
We're just happy
doing what we're doing.
Keep the music going,
keep the food honest,
fresh, delicious.
-That's it?
-That's it.
[Guy] I like the philosophy.
Hi, ladies,
how's everything?
[Guy] And it's a school
of thought she passed down
to her son, Mac.
All right, here we go.
So I wanna take
everybody back.
We shot Triple-D, seems like,
a million years ago.
We had great
Dungeness crab.
You can't beat that.
This, without question, is
one of my favorite things
about living in NorCal.
Al was the chef...
We get this great
Dungeness crab.
How are we gonna
prepare this bad boy?
-By boiling it with
a bit of salt, that's it.
-That's all she wrote.
-Now how long's this
gonna go down for, Al?
-About 18 minutes.
Cool thing about this
is after we cook this,
it's gonna turn
bright orange.
And then we'll pull it out.
We'll ice-bath it.
[Guy] To stop
the cooking process.
[whistles]
Look at the color on that.
Are you a body
or a leg man?
-[chuckling] Leg man, myself.
-Oh, really?
-Yeah.
-See, I'm a body guy.
-All right.
-[Guy whistles]
A little bit of olive oil,
get 'er started,
a little salt.
-[Guy] So you season the oil
a little bit.
-[Al] Little pepper.
Once it heats up,
little bit of garlic.
A little bit of crab.
So the crab's already cooked.
And now it's time to kind of
fortify it with flavor.
I wish you could
smell this right now. Oh!
[Al] Then you just give it
a little bit of a set.
[Guy] What we gonna
serve that with?
Sourdough bread.
Get 'er to the plate.
[sniffs] Whoa-ho!
Getting carried away there.
So you say that
you're a leg man.
Go ahead and spend
all day on those.
-[Al chuckles]
-[Guy] Me, I like
to get right in here
at that meat right there.
Mmm. That is just awesome.
It's got the lemon juice,
but it's also got some of
that great crab.
This is getting messy.
I mean, this isn't
for the timid.
They do a great crab
when it's in season.
When we can get
the whole crabs in,
people love it.
When it's Dungeness season,
which we have
a crazy Dungeness season
here in Northern California.
-When you do have it,
it goes nuts?
-Nuts.
[Al laughing]
Aren't you guys busy?
Don't you have anything
you wanna do?
[Al laughing]
Since then, you've taken over
as the chef.
But the food
continues to elevate.
We wanted to
go to the next chapter
of the business, you know.
So we got older
and we had all our fun times,
as you know.
It was like,
what are we gonna do next?
It's been around for decades.
But they've been
constantly improving it.
He's constantly creating
new food items.
I know the menu by heart,
pretty much, unless
they introduce something,
And I'm, like,
"That's what I'm getting".
[Mac] We got
a smoked cod rillette.
It's a terrine of smoked fish,
creamy goodness
and herbs.
It's one of my favorites.
-[Guy] Okay, so rillette...
-Spelling rillette
-is a challenge.
-Well, explaining
it to people.
I mean, how do the servers
explain it? What do they say?
-They call it tuna dip.
-Exactly!
-[Flicka laughing]
-And that's exactly
what I was gonna say.
-Smoked cod rillette.
-Thank you.
[Guy] Walk me through
how you make this.
[Mac] So we take our
fresh local lingcod,
and we smoke it
with applewood chips.
I'm a lingcod junkie,
just so you know.
I have a big lingcod issue.
[Mac] Once it's basically
cooked through and has
a nice smoky flavor to it,
then we build out
our rillette.
We add fresh herbs...
It has dill, scallion,
parsley and some sour cream.
Little bit of mayo,
and we give it some acidity
with lemon and lime juice.
And use a nice
extra virgin olive oil
to cap it off.
Here it is, the smoked
cod rillette with
our garlic crostini.
It's delicious.
It's creamy
and it's smoky,
and it's herbaceous.
It's got some acid,
it's got some olive oil,
and there's...
more smoked fish
than there is anything
Very elevated, very mature.
This is you, Mac?
[chuckles]
[mouth full] This is you?
I'm impressed, kid.
[man] Smoked cod rillette
in the window.
It's amazing. Smoky,
there's big chunks
of cod in it.
It's light,
but it's also very rich.
Yeah, it's just delicious.
I've never had it
anywhere else.
[woman] You put it on
the crunchy garlic toast bits,
and it's just an explosion
of flavor in your mouth.
Perfect appetizer
for two people.
And with a cocktail
or two, it's fabulous.
That's really a dynamite dish.
-Right on.
-Well done. All right, what
else are you bringing me?
[Guy] Coming up,
she's not one to brag...
Our chowder is the best
in the city.
[Guy]
...but she sure is right.
That's real good chowder.
Nice!
[Guy] It may have been 2009
when I went to
this seafood spot
right on the Embarcadero
in San Francisco for Triple-D.
But it wasn't my first
or last time at Pier 23.
My crew and I have been
hanging here for years.
I mean, we're talking
fresh seafood, live music,
a huge patio,
and you know what?
Good times!
It's just a really
great place to be.
Absolutely San Francisco.
It's a beautiful location
and you're missing out
if you don't stop in here.
Guy always felt like
this was one of his spots.
It was kind of special
in that sense.
All my boys in the crew
love the 23.
I made it in briefly...
Set up right here
in the sunshine?
To this day,
people come in,
"Where was Guy?
Where did he sit?
What did he eat?
We want to do
exactly what he did."
Have you ever seen
Guy Fieri's
Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives?
Yeah, I think I saw that once,
late night.
So you still do
the local favorites.
-You still do what we love.
-Crab and shrimp sandwich,
for sure.
-[man] Crab and shrimp melt.
-[Mac] The fish tacos,
-which you've had.
-I've had it
multiple times.
First thing in the morning,
we phone the fish guys, say,
"Okay, what do you got?"
-Fresh first,
and then recipe next.
-Exactly.
So we got some fresh
mahi-mahi.
We cut our fish
a little bit bigger,
about one-by-one.
-Ready to go for the saute.
-Dig it.
Bit of olive oil,
garlic, get that started.
And in goes the fish.
How many tacos
are you making there, captain?
-A couple.
-I like this.
-[Al] A little bit of onion.
-[Guy] That's pretty
straightforward.
Let the fish do the talking.
A little salt, bit of pepper.
Now we've got to get
our tortillas ready. Okay.
The reason we cut our fish
a little bit bigger is...
it doesn't overcook.
Cooks rare.
Give it a quick chop,
and then, what really
sets our tacos off
are the fresh corn relish
and the house slaw.
And the house slaw?
And you make
this slaw to order?
Yeah, diced carrots in a honey
coleslaw dressing.
Nice under-achieving.
A little bit of fish.
See how nice and rare
that is? A quick fold...
-Get the fold.
-Get them.
-[Al chuckles]
-Look at that.
Nice and tender in there.
I don't know that
I've ever had
a semi-rare fish taco,
but I will tell you,
that is the way to eat it.
It's a dynamite fish taco.
Mmm. I ate the whole thing.
I gotta go lay down.
Fish tacos? Oh, yeah.
Those are great!
I've had most of the dishes
on the menu.
Great ingredients,
always fresh, tons of seafood.
-[man] Octopus
and shrimp ceviche.
-Clam chowder in the window.
They have a great
clam chowder.
I really like it.
Okay, here's our
clam and fish chowder.
Our chowder is the best
in the city.
So what makes the
clam chowder so great?
It's not just clams.
Ours has fish in it,
lingcod...
How do you prepare that?
[Mac] When we start
the chowder, we saute
vegetables. Carrots, celery.
Once those cook down,
we add potatoes and herbs.
Our shrimp stock
that we make in-house.
White wine, then heavy cream.
It doesn't have
any flour in it.
What's the deal, then?
'Cause everybody makes chowder
with a little bit of flour.
-What do you guys
tighten it up with?
-Rice.
Wait, wait, wait.
So you puree the rice?
Yeah. We make a rice roux.
And then, once we get
all that cooking down,
we add our fresh clams.
We add fresh, local
lingcod for the fish,
which gives it nice flavor.
That chowder rocks.
This chowder's light.
I think that rice flour,
that ground-up rice roux
that you're putting in there
is keeping it from
becoming really tacky
and starchy and heavy.
-I definitely got fish,
I definitely got clams.
-Yeah.
It's got balance.
That's real-deal chowder.
Right on. Glad you like it.
I'm 100% ripping off
the rice deal, bro.
Nice!
I had the clam chowder.
Probably gonna gain
a lot of weight
now that I've found it.
There's a lot of seafood.
It's wonderful.
One of the most consistent
dishes there is on the menu
and that's one of the main
reasons I come back.
You can't walk into the 23
and not have a smile.
I mean, it's classic.
It's got history.
You're gonna love it.
It's just a fun place to be.
[Flicka] We're just trying
to consider ourselves
a little factory
that just keeps
manufacturing good times.
If that's not the tagline
on the bottom of a T-shirt,
I don't know what is.
If you don't know them,
you gotta meet them.
You gotta go to Pier 23.
The one and only
Flicka and Mac.
[Guy] Coming up
in Minnesota...
You wanna see what it'd be
like to go through the pizza
car wash in Flavortown?
[makes whooshing noises]
...an eatery covering
everything Italian.
[man] Twisted macaroni.
[Guy] From good luck charms...
Man, that is done right.
...to the chicken parm.
I come here
at least once a week
and have this for lunch.
Mmm!
On Triple-D, we hit
all kinds of joints.
Now, one of my favorites
is Italian.
There's Italian,
and then there's "Italian."
You know, the places that are
making their own meatballs,
their dough,
their fresh pasta,
their sauces.
Now the folks
north of the Twin Cities,
well, they're on point.
Since I was there in 2008,
they got more mouths to feed,
but they're still doing it
all in-house.
Here at this place,
Donatelli's.
Spaghetti pies coming up!
I think it was
a great find for Guy.
Such good food, and they've
been around for so long, you
want people to know about it.
Good food with great service,
you're gonna get both here.
When you come in
to Donatelli's, you really do
feel like you're getting
that family, Italian meal.
[Guy] Probably because
the food
is straight out of
Steve Donatelli's
family cookbook.
[Steve] My dad's Italian.
My dad's sister lived
right next-door to us.
The most wonderful cook
you'd ever wanna meet.
Basically, I learned how
good food was supposed
to taste.
[Guy] Right.
It is all handmade,
put together with
scratch ingredients.
The reason behind making
everything from scratch?
[Steve] Makes us different
from everybody else.
-Pasta Godfather.
-[laughs]
North of the Twin Cities.
[Guy] And no matter
who's back in the kitchen,
they're all on the same page.
When Guy was here
the last time,
we did the meatball sandwich.
[Guy] So, the meatball's
still nice and super juicy.
[Trish] We did
the spaghetti pie.
[Guy] Look at that,
creamy goodness.
Mmm.
Wow, that is rich.
Dynamite, man.
We actually did
the mostaccioli
with meat sauce.
This is when you know
it's legit.
First we're gonna add
our durum flour, semolina.
Let it mix for a minute.
Now, we're gonna add our eggs.
A little warm water.
Kind of like Medusa
the pasta machine.
I love this.
I'm getting one of these.
Oh, Lori's gonna
be pissed. when that's
on the counter at home.
Mmm.
Really good.
[man] That's the money
right there.
[Guy] That is the money.
-That's a mostaccioli.
-Yeah.
All of those start
with our red sauce.
This is a big hit here.
Everybody loves this.
Everybody loves it.
Six cans of tomato paste.
Add our puree.
This looks like
a splashing opportunity.
[man] Oh, yeah. Tomato paste.
Getting close.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Tomato juice.
Chicken and beef base.
Parmesan cheese, garlic salt,
black pepper,
basil and parsley.
Sauteed onions in oil.
And our water.
We usually let it simmer
about eight hours a day.
This gets used for everything.
We have lasagna, pasta.
The meat doesn't go in this?
No, we take this out,
put it in the meat.
Mmm, that's good.
[man] The red sauce
here is unique.
Don't think
I've tasted anything
like it anywhere else.
It's the same sauce that
they use on the chicken parm,
which is very good.
We've got a chicken parm
going up.
To prepare the chicken
for our chicken parm
we take a nice
boneless chicken breast,
we run it through
a meat tenderizer,
dip it in some egg,
then we dip it right in
some Italian bread crumbs.
We drop that chicken breast
in the fryer,
about three to four minutes.
Gets a little crispy.
We toss it on the flat top,
add some mozzarella
and some cheddar cheese,
melt it.
We take the spaghetti,
put a little red sauce in it.
Pop that chicken breast
right in the middle,
and put a little sauce
right around the edge.
Then we serve it with
a big piece of garlic toast.
Chicken parm in the window.
It's, like
the perfect trifecta,
with the pasta and the cheese
and the chicken.
It's an incredible dish.
It is crispy, and still,
it doesn't get soggy.
I come here
at least once a week
and have this for lunch.
It's fantastic.
[man] I bring my family
here, friends.
They all find something
that they like.
You don't have
to have just pasta.
There's all kinds of stuff.
You want to see what
it would be to go through
the pizza carwash
in Flavortown?
[makes whooshing noises]
[woman 1 laughs]
Heart Stopper pizza's up.
[man] Guy was talking
about the Heart Stopper pizza.
And I said,
"I gotta have that."
That's the only pizza
I get now.
Got a nice crunch to it.
See how thin that is.
It's a delicious pizza.
Mmm.
Wow, that's good.
Pizzas are fantastic.
[woman 2] The pasta
is also nice too.
You can tell
it's not your boxed pasta.
Twisted mac for you.
It's kind of like
your grandma's macaroni,
but it gives a modern flavor.
[Trish] First we start
with a gourmet
heavy whipping cream,
add a little processed cheese,
some butter, Swiss cheese,
spicy tomatoes with jalapenos,
some andouille sausage
just to give it a little kick.
Then we toss it
with some cavatappi
add more mozzarella
and cheddar cheese on the top
and we bake it.
Twisted mac 'n cheese
in the window.
It's really rich,
it's super creamy,
throw in some tomatoes there
to kind of give it
a citrus kick.
You can't go wrong
with the dish.
There's, like, heat,
there's the cheesy goodness.
It's just really sumptuous.
[Guy] I don't know
if you're allowed
to have more bling
than the host.
I mean, man,
that is done right.
[Steve] I started
my bling with an Italian
good luck charm.
In 2008, there was
this big economic downturn
and then Guy showed up.
It saved our business.
It has allowed us
to grow to the point
that we are today.
We have a footprint of about
9,000 square feet now.
And we do a lot of catering.
It's amazing.
[Guy] Coming up...
I was cruising down
Boring Avenue...
A neighborhood joint
in Superior, Wisconsin.
...hooked a right, right
onto Delicious Boulevard.
Headed straight
to Flavortown.
You navigated this into
a really dynamite sandwich.
[man] Thank you.
So it's July here in beautiful
Superior, Wisconsin,
right over the bridge
from Duluth, Minnesota.
You now, with the weather
the way it is around here
I'm told, "Spend as much time
indoors as you can."
So back in 2014,
I spent time in this joint,
smoking meat and making pies.
And they're still adding
new favorites from up north.
This is Shorty's Pizza
& Smoked Meat.
Gunslinger for the bar.
This Triple-D episode,
we're actually in it.
[woman] We were coming
to go for lunch and Guy's car
was out in front.
And I'm going,
"Hey, guess what?"
I'll tell folks I've coming
to Shorty's and they'll,
"Oh, gosh, I saw that on TV."
The name Shorty's,
do you know what it means?
I personally do not.
I have no clue either.
Why do you call it
Shorty's, by the way?
No one has been
able to answer.
Where did Shorty's come from?
You're far from short,
the building is enormous.
Apparently, it's a question
only Brian Noel can answer.
I just wanted to have a fun,
simple, easy name to remember.
And I know it sounds dumb,
'cause I'm 6'4".
But I wasn't thinking
of that, actually.
So, 6'4" and you got
a place called Shorty's.
When Triple-D first came
we'd only been open
about a year.
And it, you know,
gave us a great boost.
People come in,
and they still ask,
six years later, "What did
he eat? What did he eat?"
All right, let's get
into the hunter's chicken.
Okay. Red wine.
So we're making
a red wine reduction?
-Demi-glace.
-[Guy] Okay.
Gonna let that reduce down
to about a fourth
of what we started with.
-[Guy] All right.
-[man] Then, we're gonna
get the bacon grease,
so it melts down, gets hot.
The butter, the garlic,
shallots,
bacon, and a few mushrooms.
And let that reduce down.
I'm gonna go and add
the red wine
demi-glace reduction.
All we gotta do now
is season the chicken breast.
[Guy] What is that
we just put on there?
-This is a garlic-herb blend.
-Okay.
[man] Little bit of butter,
put it on the flat top.
Put a press on it.
We take provolone cheese,
put it over the top.
Put a cap
over the top of that.
Give a little shot of water
to melt that cheese down.
[Guy] There you go,
I like the method.
[man] And put it
on our grilled
cranberry wild rice bread.
Take our sauce...
And serve it.
If any one component
of this sandwich
wasn't there,
this would be
a pretty basic sandwich.
It's great flavor.
I was cruising down
Boring Avenue
hooked a right,
right onto
Delicious Boulevard.
You navigated this into
a really dynamite sandwich.
Thank you.
It's got a very wide variety
of menu items.
Lot of sandwiches.
The pizzas are really good.
[man] It's such a big menu,
you wanna have some entrees,
there's that.
If you wanna do something
a little more casual
and have some appetizers,
there's that.
Cheese and garlic crack bread,
you can't go wrong.
There's the crack bread.
[Brian] We start off
with a whole loaf of
sourdough bread.
Cut it into diamonds.
Take Wisconsin cheese
and we fill all the crevices.
We then cover it
with garlic butter,
top it with a little bit
of garlic seasoned salt,
finish it off
with a little bit
of shredded
Cheddar Jack cheese.
Bake that off.
And we'll garnish that
with a side of our marinara
sauce for dipping.
The marinara sauce
is the same sauce
as we use on our pizza.
Put the oil in.
Canola oil, onions,
crushed tomato,
basil, garlic, herbs, sugar,
salt, oregano.
Red chili flake.
Let this cook
for about an hour.
It's a very savory sauce,
perfect for this
kind of bread.
Here is your crack bread.
I can look to see
where there's the most cheese
and just dig that out.
You're not gonna get a piece
of bread that doesn't have
everything on it.
Oh, it's ooey, gooey,
cheesiness right there.
I get it every time that
I'm here, It's one of
my go-to appetizers.
The cheese bread is
our best-selling appetizer.
I have to say
I'm biased to the egg rolls.
I just love those egg rolls.
I really like
the Canadian egg rolls.
A Canadian-style egg roll,
we start off with
Napa cabbage,
shredded carrots,
garlic and ginger.
We saute our vegetables.
We then brown off
some ground pork,
we will add it
to the vegetables
and then we will add
the marinade.
We add it into
the egg roll wrapper
and then fry it
until it's golden-brown.
There's the Canadian-style
egg rolls.
That's unlike
any other egg roll
that you're gonna have.
It's crunchy,
but you got the veggies
and the meat in there.
Really good combo.
It's excellent.
I'll tell you something, man,
it's a great place.
Great pizza, scratch-made
food, good times, man.
-Thank you.
-Good times.
Hi, guys. How are we doing?
[Guy] That's what Triple-D
is all about.
Delicious.
I mean, this is dynamite.
Funky joints
treating their customers
to a good time.
Stopper's up, hot and ready.
[Guy] And the party's
not stopping anytime soon.
I'll catch you next time,
on Triple-D Nation.
[makes whooshing noises]
What is this?
It's a pizza cutter.
That's illegal in 49 states!
[laughter]