So when I come off the road
from doing triple D,
the first thing I wanna do
is to get home to my kitchen
and cook my food for my family
and after a few weeks,
I gotta be--
Dad, can we just...
I mean, please.
You could have rushed
on at least one time.
They start to revolt!
So, I came up with an idea.
How about we reach out
to some of our favorite chefs
and had them send us dinner.
-Huh?
-I like that idea.
[Guy] And I know
some triple D joints
who would love
to send it to us.
Their serious Stromboli
headed our way from Pinky G's
in Jackson, Wyoming.
This is dynamite.
A seafood feast from
the classic Marietta Diner
in Georgia.
Can't get it
in my face fast enough.
A real triple D, O.G.,
Mac & Ernies,
is sending
a not-your-everyday burger
from Tarpley, Texas.
Out of bounds.
That is so good!
[Guy] And for dessert,
a simple cinnamon roll,
rolled on out
of Colorado's LauerKrauts.
Ah, that's hot!
And on top of it all, they're
gonna videoconference in
to give us
the true triple D experience.
I have died a bit!
I tripped into crazy town,
which is right next
to flavor town.
Next door.
This is Triple D: Takeout.
And there's
a few more in the trunk.
Of course there is.
[music playing]
Alright, this is the cast
of characters we have today,
Hunter. Let's see here.
If we're gonna talk
about OG's and triple D,
it was a sheshed
and it was in Tarpley, Texas.
You are definitely
the official unofficial mayor.
[Naylene laughs]
The one and only
Naylene from Mac & Ernies.
How are you chef?
I'm great, Guy.
If you all love flavor town,
this guy and his restaurant
definitely had
something to do with it
when Gus drived the bus,
so we go to flavor town.
This is my buddy Gus
from Marietta Dinner
in Marietta, Georgia.
What's up, brother?
How are you?
You're looking good.
Robin from LauerKrauts
in Brighton, Colorado,
really introduced me
the reality
of what true sauerkraut is.
And then
in Jackson Hole, Wyoming,
Tom and Pinky G's.
He's got a great family,
he's got twins,
he's got all kinds of stories.
So, anyhow.
As you know
this is Triple D: Takeout.
We are not able to come back
and see you right now,
but we thought
the great idea would be...
[high pitched] Have'em
send us the food.
Have us send us the food.
[Tom mocking hunter]
Hey Hunter,
how're you doing buddy?
[Guy] Alright,
Rider on camera.
Now wanna remind everybody,
one of the four of you is
gonna get Best Dish tonight.
Considering that,
who wants to go first?
-Robin? LauerKrauts?
-I will.
This is probably gonna be
something fantastic
like a soup, or a stew,
or a burger with kraut.
Ho, ho, ho!
Oh yeah.
And when you make
real sauerkraut, you see
the way Robin does it,
I promise you,
you will have a whole new love
and appreciation
for sauerkraut.
You salt it,
and you start mashing it
by hand
and it starts to juice.
And how long is
the sauerkraut from that?
28 days.
That's killer kraut.
-Go ahead grab the box.
-All right.
I hope
everything made it okay.
Robin, what year did
we come into triple D there?
2010.
You're nine months pregnant?
-I am.
-Come down
and meet
the kraut burger baby.
Coming soon.
[Robin laughs]
This is the kraut baby.
This is Maximilian.
Hi.
Hey, Maximilian.
How're you doing, bud?
Seriously?
[Robin laughs]
[Guy] That is awesome!
Let's talk about
what we are making.
We are gonna make
our cinnamon rolls.
You make
a sauerkraut cinnamon roll?
This one is one dish that
does not have sauerkraut.
-Uh-oh.
-Sorry.
But you can add it.
You've got it there.
Oh, you said sauerkraut, fine.
I'm making cinnamon rolls.
I just wanted
to make sure that there was
some sauerkraut.
[Robin] Just get in there.
[Robin laughs]
Give me some of that.
Alright. I see
that you sent us the dough.
So, two of these
are one to one?
Yes, but you
can make a half batch.
Okay, listen. Does this
look like a half batch?
-No.
A badge and a half.
[Robin] You want
the butter nice and melted
so we can smear it
all over the bread dough.
I have to things of butter.
The other butter
is for the maple
cream cheese frosting.
How are we making that?
You'll need a mixer.
Nice mixer.
Yeah. Come on. You guys
expected anything different?
Does it make a vroom,
vroom sound?
Does it have an exhaust?
Does it have wheels?
So, butter down
and cream cheese.
Powder sugar now?
Just a do it slowly
so I don't have a
powder sugar storm.
Pour it fast. Let's see
the powder sugar storm.
Listen. Don't you know
that I am a rookie
at baking?
See! See!
Add the maple extract,
and the vanilla and the salt.
It smells good. Do you want
us to start rolling this out?
That'd be great.
I wonder if we even own
a rolling pin in this house.
-And toss it.
-Use a wine bottle.
Just sit on it.
Rider is running
to get a rolling pin.
This is pretty fun, Guy.
[Tom laughs]
Tom it was so nice
having you on the show.
-Alright.
-Thanks for tuning in.
-First time?
-Yeah, it is my first time,
actually.
I roll it like 24 by 36.
Whoa.
No, no.
You can leave there.
I doesn't need
to go on the sheet tray.
Robin, you didn't seem
like you would be
such a pain in his butt.
Yeah, thank you Naylene.
No, I'm so sorry.
I think you're
doing a great job, Guy.
Thank you very much, Gus.
That's why you get
to stay on the show.
Spread the butter evenly
over the whole thing.
Just try to leave
the very top edge of it
clean so you can seal it up
when you're done.
-Next step.
-Cinnamon.
So, it goes
everywhere, Hunter.
All over it.
Just keep the top edge clean.
The brown sugar is next.
Nuts?
[Robin] Nuts and raisins
as well.
That looks good.
And then I go back and forth
until it's nice and tight
and rolled up real pretty.
Can't you see
the Guy and Hunter bakery?
That is team work
if I've ever seen it.
Start pinching it
to seal it.
So, now cut it in half.
You're gonna go in halves
and then each one
of those halves go in thirds.
We get 12 out of it.
Bring the calculator, Guy.
Alright. There we go.
[Robin] Yeah.
Just put them there.
They get pretty good in size,
so you might need
two pans for that many.
You know what? We're
gonna have to make this work.
We're gotta do one pan.
Guy, two pans
is better than one.
Two pans!
[Robin laughs]
Alright. So, 50 minutes.
Let them proof.
When we come back,
we are gonna take this
and we're gonna smear that
on the top.
I actually warm
the frosting a little bit.
I dip them,
but you can smear them.
Oh, we weren't doing it
the right way.
We gotta do
both sheet trays, now.
We are going bigger
or going home.
That's right! You know
where actually we're going?
We are going to commercials.
Don't go anywhere.
We'll see you in a bit.
Who knows
who's coming back
and gonna do what else
they're gonna do.
I don't know.
See you in a bit.
We gotta make more of this,
because that is so...
-Do you wanna try?
-Yeah, I do.
Okay.
[Guy] So, welcome back.
Hunter and I have
just opened up our own bakery.
Yeah, no. Not right.
No, we called our friend Robin
in LauerKrauts.
So, we said "hey, we're
doing this really cool show
where you send us
all these fantastic dishes
you guys are working
on your restaurant.
We have cinnamon rolls
in a proofing right now,
but this right here
is a vanilla,
maple,
cream cheese, butter,
powder sugar...
I don't even know
if it's supposed to go
on the cinnamon roll, because
we're just gonna eat it
right off of the spatula
and the spoon.
So good.
While that's all happening,
let's talk
to our good friend Naylene
from Mac & Ernies.
We shot triple D there...
Many moons ago.
[Guy] We shot it
in Lou toolshed.
I think it's a shack.
[Guy] Shack. Okay,
so we're going with shack.
People came and ordered
out of the window.
This is the form
of drivethru here in Tarpley?
Yeah.
[Robin laughs]
We had fantastic
cabrito burgers.
100% ground cabrito
and I raise some goats.
Look at that!
[Naylene] It's a little
warzone with delight.
Naylene, what is on the menu?
So, I sent you
a New Zealand Red Deer Burger
with balsamic onions
and blue cheese
-with a sourdough bun.
-[Guy] Okay.
After Robin's ordeal
with rolling the dough
and mixing and stuff,
this is pretty easy.
I figured you might
need a little break.
[Guy] Thank you.
When she says
"Mac & Ernies Roadside",
it's really roadside.
It road hard.
We recycle.
Yes, you do!
Hunter, you need to show,
what you just pulled out
of that, to your dad.
Oh, my Gosh!
You actually have one now?
What happened
to the lid on this bad boy?
It got misplaced.
You're not supposed
to send it to me!
You're supposed to keep it!
I got an extra one
in the package.
If you would have it signed
and maybe hang it
on a little rope or something,
a little chord,
I would have...
-Genious!
-This had been
some culinary blink.
How're we doing this sister?
Talk to me.
Slice up those onions
about a quarter inch thick.
And this is
for the balsamic onions?
-[Naylene] Yes.
-[Guy] Okay.
So, tell me what's
going on in the world
of Mac & Ernies these days.
I bought a building
down the street.
We have indoor seating now.
An indoor Plum and Tooma?
Aha!
[Robin laughs]
Put the onions
in the pan with the butter.
Sautee those around
for about five,
six, seven minutes.
Alright.
So, while that's working,
can we see
if these cinnamon rolls
look good for you? Robin,
are we proofed enough?
They look great.
You can bake suckers.
350 for 15 to 20 minutes.
So, on this burger,
why the red stock?
Because it tastes
really good.
I don't think
I've ever had it.
I've never had it.
Tom, have you ever
had it up there in Jackson?
No. I'm gonna
make a visit here
and make it off a show,
if I'm still on the show.
Oh, Tom, I didn't even know
that you were still here.
Let me get the remote.
Tom, thanks a lot.
Let's say goodbye to Tom.
[all laugh]
Salt and pepper, the basics.
Yes, but put some
little seasoning cups
in here to mix together.
I know you're tired
after the cinnamon rolls.
[Robin laughs]
Granulated garlic,
onion powder,
fresh crushed black pepper.
Correct. Now just season
both sides of your patty.
It's 85% red deer
and 15% beef fat.
The red deer is super lean,
so I love that you put
some beef fat in there.
The onions are
starting to soften up.
There goes the chicken stock.
You see that cascading pour?
I'm doing my best work.
Now let that reduce
for just a couple of seconds.
Here it goes, the patties.
That's a good sizzle.
The reduced balsamic,
chopped up rosemary going in.
And another
little pinch of salt.
How are we treating
these buns, sister?
[Naylene] I just dry
toast them on the grill.
Okay.
If you wanna butter up mine,
I'm for that.
Hunter, there's
like eight minutes left
on the cinnamon rolls.
Okay. She might have stuck us
with making cinnamon rolls,
but the fact that you're
timing it in Colorado...
I'm impressed. I'm impressed.
Tom, better be ready.
Let's go.
On the bottom bun
go ahead and put
some of that lettuce down,
and slices of tomato.
Okay.
[music playing]
The onions and the balsamic.
That looks good.
Get your blue cheese.
We didn't see
any blue cheese.
How far is the supermarket?
Guy goes again.
Thanks for saving me, Guy.
There you go.
-Uhh!
-Yeah. Yeah.
There we go.
Oh, yum.
When he was at the restaurant
the first time,
Guy ate three
cabrito burgers.
I believe it.
Naylene!
[Naylene laughs]
As up without grade I thought
the cabrito burger was,
the same thing here
with this New Zealand venison.
The depth of flavor,
the richness is outstanding.
The mix of the 85/15
with the beef fat
and the venison is spot on,
and the compliment
of that the onion
and tang of the blue cheese
really counteracts with
the richness of the meat.
Great crunch
in the lettuce
and a little bit
of the tomato.
When I hoped that you were
gonna send me something
that was gonna
represent Mac & Ernies
like it should...
This is it.
-Well done.
-Good job Naylene.
Out of bounds.
That is so good.
We're gonna finish this up
and when we come back
our good buddy Tom
over there,
Pinky G's,
who is still with us.
Still here.
He's gonna show us how
to make the bun Stromboli.
See you in a bit.
-So good.
Welcome back, hanging out
at the Fieri house.
We're in the backyard,
cooking out
some of our favorite
triple D recipes
from some of our favorite
triple D chefs.
So, we have Gus
from Marietta Diner,
in Marietta, Georgia.
The OG herself,
Naylene at Mac & Ernies,
and coming up
shortly in a minute,
our buddy Tom at Pinky G's.
But, before we do that,
we have to talk
about cinnamon rolls.
We've been working
on these with Robin
from over there
at LauerKrauts...
Ah! That's hot.
[Gus laughs]
What you had told us
was to warm up this glaze
and to dip them in there.
Oh yeah, a fork's a good idea.
Careful.
That looks painful.
-It does look painful.
-Painfully good.
This is dynamite.
Good caramelization
of the sugar on the bottom.
Nice and airy.
It's not always sweet.
There's a good amount
of the cream cheese in there
for the tang of that.
Good balance
of the maple syrup
and the vanilla.
The walnuts and the raisins
you're making for me,
it really gives
them some texture.
Got a nutty flare to it.
[Hunter] It's nice.
-Amen. Well done!
-Thank you so much.
Dynamite cinnamon roll
means we gotta go
out dynamite pizza,
so we were
in Jackson Hole, Wyoming.
We heard
about this funky joint,
and then we met Tom.
Everybody knows you
for those big pies,
unique pies.
The Abe Froman.
Abe Froman,
the sausage king of Chicago
from Ferris
Bueller's Day Off?
Yes.
They got
a funky chicken pizza.
Can you do it?
There's one other person
I know the funky chicken
is one
of their favorite dances.
Let's get Aunt Polly
on the phone.
Hi, Aunt Polly!
Can you give me
a little funky chicken?
[Aunt Polly] How funky
is you chicken?
How lose is the goose?
[Guy laughs]
Thank you, Polly.
The box...
These are the Pinky G's pizza
boxes that you have taped?
Custom, baby.
And flip flops, because
I'd eat that on a flip flop.
That's it. There's one
for the whole family there,
-all right?
-Seriously?
One flip flop
for each person.
Here, Hunter, put yours on.
[all laugh]
Wait a second!
This is your company?
I'm making them.
They're cheap,
moldable flip flops.
These are dope!
[Tom] Those are
actually prototypes
and I want some feedback
on how they feel.
-Nice!
-You want some feedback?
He wants some feedback.
-Thank you.
What are we making, brother?
[Tom] We are doing
a Pepperoni Spicy
Italian Sausage Stromboli.
What's our game plan?
Let's make the marinara,
even though that's just
gonna be
a little dipping sauce.
-Okay.
-[Tom] Ground tomatoes,
peeled tomatoes.
[Guy] Sugar.
[Tom] Dried basil,
dried oregano.
[Guy] Garlic powder.
Here's a little
mushroom for you.
I've got the dough.
Turn it into, you know,
12-13-inch round pizza.
I did notice making
those cinnamon rolls
you handle dough
pretty well.
I was your warm-up.
Beautiful dough,
by the way.
I wanna start
with the pepperoni,
made here locally
from a friend
in Coal Vine and Swaren.
We're gonna envision
this pizza dough
into quarters.
From your chest out
put a halfway mark and just
above the halfway mark
do two or three
rows of pepperoni.
Good luck, Guy.
You thought
my thirds were tough!
Throw down
some mozzarella cheese
just over
the pepperoni, please.
Green peppers,
fresh chopped red onions.
Some mushrooms.
[Tom] And then
spicy Italian sausage.
-Okay.
-Take the top corners
and you're gonna wrap it
just over all the toppings
and kind of button it down
and now stretch that bottom
half a little longer,
roll it back.
Oh, dude. You're a pro.
That was professional.
Never made
Stromboli over here.
Yeah, I don't believe that.
[Guy] Score the top?
[Tom] Yeah. Put it
on the screen there,
because I don't want
the bottom to get baked.
Too charred. Got it.
-[Gus] Nice.
-There you go.
15 minutes in the oven at 550?
[Tom] Yeah, buddy.
Let me ask you, Tom.
You've got a buddy of mine
that always comes
in the restaurant.
This is our friend,
Simon McLaren.
He's been coming
to Pinky G's every day
since we've been open.
Here we go.
Now where's the chain?
You tell me these,
it's not the stunt double
for Diners,
Drivers, and Dives.
There's my brother!
How are you doing, man?
That's one of the best shows
we ever did.
He was a rock star.
I think he
was signing autographs
up and down the street there.
My favorite one was
with the funky chicken.
Oh, no.
I think you did
the funky chicken
better than Aunt Polly
does it.
-Thanks, Guy!
-All right.
[music playing]
[Guy] Hey I gotta tell
you something, man.
It's a bomb looking Stromboli.
Let's brush it
with the garlic infused
olive oil there.
Parmesan cheese.
Put some
of the marinara in there.
[Hunter] Oh, look at that.
Are you gonna go for it?
That just came out
of a 500-degree oven!
How are you doing
that right now?
[Guy] I love the marinara
dipping sauce.
I sure hope it cooled
it down a little bit, too.
Oh yeah.
I went right down
from 550 to 505.
[Tom and Robin laugh]
I was wondering the veggies
were kind of big,
but you know what happened
just went and soothed there
and cooked on that cauldron
of house made dough.
It's bathed in the oil
of the sausage
and the pepperoni.
They still got
a little bit of texture
but there are ton of flavor.
-Gangster, dude!
-That's amazing, dude!
I appreciate it.
Last but not least.
He drives a bus,
his name is Gus.
He's gonna take you
to flavor town.
See you in a bit.
All right, welcome back.
This is Triple D: Takeout.
We've had the venison burger,
the cinnamon roll,
classic Stromboli.
Next up is Marietta Diner.
I'm Uncle Gus.
I'm driving the bus
to the flavor town.
I would always
make the little joke
about flavor town.
But it wasn't until we
had Uncle Gus drive the bus.
I mean we should almost
have a plaque in the ground
that this is one the founding
restaurants of flavor town.
Gus in the bus. Now this was
the original Gus
who drove the bus
that went to flavor town,
but this is his uncle Gus,
and now has another diner
somewhere in New Jersey,
but my brother Gus here
has got the Marietta Diner,
has got a great
seafood joint as well.
Excuse me, Gus, what...
How many boxes did you ship?
I sent a little bit
of seafood, Guy.
Gus, we're gonna have a talk.
You can never
have enough seafood.
-Are you kidding me?
-[Gus] Our king crab legs.
All right,
my name's ridiculous.
What's yours?
Mmm... I think it's Gus.
Remember Gus gone wild?
I gotta leave, dude.
You gotta taste this.
One more.
-No.
-Oh, yeah.
Nice seeing you, Gus!
Hey, Guy!
Flight made Lobsters.
Wow!
I sent them first class.
[Gus laughs]
-Holy...
-It's the biggest lobster
you've all ever seen
and there's a case of them.
This is bribery, baby.
[Gus] This is
the takeout version
of the flavor town bus.
No way!
There's stuff in there, too.
Gus, we own plates
at our house.
Wait a second! I know
what the plates are for!
My dad.
[plates break]
Hey!
Opa! Welcome, Guy Fieri!
Opa!
There he goes!
[Guy laughs out loud]
Got plates everywhere!
Out of control.
My son George
wants to say hello.
Opa!
Hey! Hey! Opa!
[Naylene] Way to go, Guy!
I have died a bit!
I tripped into crazy town,
which is right
next to flavor town.
Next door.
Whoa! Oh, he's breaking more
plates. Go! You gotta go!
What's
with the broken plates?
It's papa George's M.O.
Anybody has a birthday,
he just breaks plates.
It's part
of the Greek culture.
Gus,
what are we making?
We are making a Marietta Fish
Market Style Bouillabaisse.
[Guy] I'm scared
of this much food.
It's not a sprint,
it's a marathon.
What are we starting with?
I have some regular sized
lobster tails there for you.
I take it out of the shell?
[Gus] Yes, please.
[music playing]
But don't separate it
from the shell.
Got it, got it, got it.
I only did that one.
Okay.
[Gus laughs]
Roll the camera, actually.
[rewind sound]
[Guy] Heat up the pan
with some oil.
Dust the lobster tail,
and the scallops, and shrimp.
[Guy] Okay. So, some flour.
[Gus] And the fish, too.
I sent some grouper.
Start dropping these in.
Everything
but the shrimp right now.
Because the shrimp
cooks a little faster.
When are we making the sauce?
Gus, we're making
it right in there after
we cook up all the seafood?
-Yes.
-What are we gonna start with?
Some butter.
Well, you only said
a pound of butter.
Is that gonna be enough, Gus?
Ah, yeah.
[Naylene laughs]
Just a little cube of butter
and you can put
the shrimp in.
-Okay.
-And then add
some chopped onions.
[Guy] Onions are
going down, boss.
You gotta let that cook
just for a few more minutes.
The shrimps are done.
Okay. We are gonna
strain the oil now.
Add the butter,
some minced garlic,
chopped fresh basil.
Okay, now we're gonna
add our seafood back in.
Add a little salt.
White pepper, black pepper,
granulated garlic,
cajun seasoning.
All right, now we're
gonna add our white wine.
The OG brandy.
Is this brandy really
called Original Gangster?
That Ice radio
was a coincidence.
Shot for the dish,
shot for you.
Whoa! There you go!
[all cheering]
One for the dish,
lemon juice.
Diced fresh tomatoes,
some chopped clams
and clam juice.
A little more.
A little more juice.
Please.
Thank you, thank you.
[Guy] Marinara sauce.
A little more. A little more,
please. I'm sorry.
Sorry. Sorry.
You can never
have enough sauce.
Scampi sauce.
[Guy] What's
in the scampi sauce, Gus?
[Gus] Garlic, butter,
white wine, lemon juice,
onion powder,
granulated garlic,
pepper, gravy,
diced pimentos, and scallions.
Now we're gonna add
the clams and mussels, please.
There's more seafood
in here than we have
at the aquarium down the road.
Oh, we forgot the bread.
We gotta dip in the sauce.
There's some bread inside.
Oh, that's delicious!
At least helps you forget
the lobster tail, right?
Oh, we've got
another costumer.
[Hunter whistles]
[Robin chuckles]
Sourdough bread.
Put a little olive oil on it.
Oh, you know, we didn't get
the king crab, yet.
[Gus] Take the crab legs out
and chop up the king crab.
[Guy] Look at this thing.
Hey, they made me one,
too, Guy.
So we can have
kind of lunch together.
Oh, you're having one, too?
Yeah, of course.
Wow!
Over the top.
Can't get it in my face
fast enough.
[music playing]
It's outrageous.
I love
the little bit of flour
we put on the seafood.
It gives a little
more texture.
Seafood super tender.
Nothing's overcooked.
And it really
helps that sauce.
When we added
in chopped clam juice.
It took the whole seafood
flavor to the next level.
I would drink that as a soup.
Wow! It just got so much
complexity to it.
I just hope you have enough.
Enough?
[Naylene laughs]
Today has been outrageous.
The dishes are dynamite,
but we gotta figure out
who's gonna get Best Dish.
Remember, it doesn't
get you cash or prizes.
It's just a bit
of bragging, right?
So, hold on a second.
[tense music playing]
I know I got
the biggest dish, right?
Folks, we have a tie.
Oh!
So I gotta give it up
to two of the OG's.
To Naylene at Mac & Ernies.
You get it for the minimalist
delicious awesome burger
and we gotta give it
to Gus from Marietta Diner,
because Gus, this is
the most ridiculous thing
I've ever seen.
Thank you.
But everybody:
fantastic dishes.
Thank you so much.
-See you guys next week!
-Adios!
Adios!
"Adios" is my line.
Okay. Hasta luego.
I got nephew George,
my son George's in the house.
Watch yourself.
[dishes breaking]
Got plates everywhere!
Out of control.
[all laugh]
[man] Opa!