So when I come off the road
from doing Triple D,
the first thing I wanna do
is get home to my kitchen
and cook my food
for my family.
And after a few weeks,
I gotta be--
Dad, can we just, please,
go to a restaurant
at least one time?
They start to revolt.
So I came up with the idea,
how about we reach out
to some of our favorite chefs
and have them
send us dinner, huh?
I like that idea.
[Guy] And I know
some Triple D joints
that would love
to send it to us.
There is the barbecue
from Baby Blues
in Venice, California.
Outstanding, seriously.
The folks at Otto's Sausage
are showing me
how they've been doing it
in Portland
for four generations.
-That didn't come out too bad.
-Looks awesome to me.
[Guy] The wild man
from Paradise Burger Co.
in Phoenix
is sending
all kinds of surprises.
We have hit a new level today.
And coming
from one of my favorite
go-to spots
right here in Santa Rosa,
spicy shrimp,
La Texanita style.
-That is delicious.
-It's fantastic, Chef.
And on top of it all,
they're gonna
video-conference in
to give us the true
Triple D experience.
This is Triple D Takeout.
-And there's a few more
in the trunk.
-Of course, there is.
All right, Hunter,
you are gonna love
this line-up.
First, our buddy Bret
at Paradise Valley Burger
in Phoenix.
-Are you at home?
-Yeah, man. Just rocking
and rolling over here.
[Guy] Christie and Jerry
up at Otto's in Portland.
And I'm glad
that you're here today
'cause I'm out of beef jerky.
I get a beef jerky shipment
every month.
Sister Alma
right down the street
at La Texanita.
But she doesn't have
her signature
bleached blond hair.
We both get our hair done
by the same guy.
It's too hard to keep it up.
And then last but not least,
my buddy Rick
at Baby Blues BBQ.
Where do we find you
right now, bud?
I'm in Venice Beach right now.
You guys know my son Hunter.
And my son Ryder is over here
running the camera.
I've asked you to send me
some of your favorite
new recipes
and we'll cook them.
At the end of this,
someone will get
the award of Best Dish.
All right,
let's get things kicked off.
Let's start with La Texanita.
-Alma, what year
did we do Triple D?
-2009.
I think it was
one of the first times
that Hunter
was really on Triple D.
Hunter and I have been going
to this place for years.
And one thing
we're always jonesing for...
-The famous Carne Asada
at La Texanita.
-Yes, that one.
I've been asking
for this recipe
since I've been coming here
for the last five years.
Finally, I give you
the recipe.
Shh.
Alma, give me the rundown.
What are we making?
[Alma] Camarones a la Diabla.
Spicy shrimp.
How do we wanna start this?
First, we're gonna make
the salsa a la Diabla sauce.
[Guy] So the roasted tomatoes
go in.
A little bit of salt
and chipotles.
-Chipotles in adobo.
-Use like three or four.
When I go hang out
with Sister Alma,
it's not three or four,
it's three or fourteen.
[chuckles]
-[Alma] Onions.
-[Guy] And the garlic?
Only two pieces of the garlic.
Now there is a orange juice.
Shake it.
-Me or...
-Yeah, you have to shake
your booty.
When you're chopping,
you have to shake your booty.
-That's part of cooking it?
-Yeah.
[Alma] Add
the Mexican chilies.
-Chili de arbol. All of them?
-Only six.
Hunter,
get some tortillas going.
I'll take this
and go to the blender.
Ryder, get over here.
Alma, do you want
any texture to this?
-Make it into a puree.
-Got it.
Talk amongst yourselves.
I'll be right back.
I wanna try this dish
they're making, Alma.
Oh, this looks good.
Ooh, that's got some heat.
Now what are these shrimps
been marinated in?
Chopped garlic, oil,
the sauce, the...
It is hard to me for say it.
-Worcestershire sauce.
-That one.
-The old washer-sister sauce.
-There you go.
We're gonna put on the pan
the butter.
How long
do these marinate for?
We did it yesterday
for you today.
I've got the shrimp
working in the pan.
They're just turning
translucent.
[Alma] The next step
is gonna be only the onions.
Now the bell peppers.
I see a package
of ketchup here.
What's that all about?
You have to add
the ketchup too.
-Ketchup?
-Really?
-Ketchup. Yeah.
-Wow.
That will make the sauce
a little bit sweet.
-What am I into now?
-We have to add
the salsa a la Diabla.
-[Guy] How much?
-[Alma] Just half of it.
-I think you got it.
-No.
-Smells fantastic.
-It does.
I think it's coming
right through the TV.
And we're ready
to put this together.
-[Alma] Side of rice.
-Avocado on the lettuce?
-Tomatoes on the side.
-[Guy] Couple of limes.
Hunter, did you
make yourself a bite?
-No, I thought
we were sharing.
-No, no, we're not sharing.
-This is--
-I thought
it's father and son.
No, this is dad's plate.
[Hunter] If you had told me
there was ketchup
in Mexican food,
I would not have believed you.
That is delicious.
-[Guy] You don't taste
the ketchup at all.
-[Hunter] Mm-mm.
Those veggies
are still so crisp.
That shrimp
is so tender though.
-The sauce is a combo
of sweet and heat.
-Mm-hmm.
Having this little salad
on the side
where you're able
to cool yourself down
because there is a little bit
of heat on the back of that.
-It's fantastic, chef.
Thank you.
-Nice.
-Thank you. Thank you.
-Well done.
Nice job.
Ooh.
So it's really hard
to follow somebody
that's a 2009 Triple D OG.
That's unless
you're a 2007
Triple D original OG.
This is Baby Blues BBQ.
This is kind of like
pulled pork meets
au jus French dip.
-That's right.
-Just keep working. I'll eat.
Whoa, you sent us a lot.
Made in... [laughs]
No, you didn't.
When I first met Rick,
and back then, he had
a partner named Danny,
and they're mixing
their barbecue sauce.
And here they are
with their magical
bucket system.
And... [humming]
[all laughing]
And I called it
the dueling buckets,
and it says right here,
"Made in the dueling buckets."
-That's awesome.
-Well done.
All right, buddy.
Walk me through this.
[Rick] We're gonna do
a couple of our appetizers.
The Suicide King with tri-tip
and hush puppies.
-How are we doing it?
-There's some cornbread there.
-That needs to be warmed up.
-Got it.
And then you're gonna
make coleslaw too.
You got mayo.
-Brown sugar.
-[Rick] Dijon mustard.
-[Hunter] Buttermilk?
-Yep. Apple cider vinegar.
-I don't see ACV.
-It's like a liquid.
-Oh, is it?
-Oh!
-Yeah.
-I was looking for a block
of apple cider vinegar.
I'm like, "Where did that go?"
You mean the thing that says
"One of two for the coleslaw."
-Yes.
-Oh.
-[Guy] Horseradish.
-[Rick] Celery seed.
-All of it? [whistles]
-Yup. All of it.
-Cayenne.
-[Rick] Kosher salt.
Poppy seeds. Add pepper.
[Guy] So while
he's mixing that up
and adds in cabbage,
tell me about the tri-tip.
We marinate the tri-tip
with garlic, cilantro, tamari,
washer-sister sauce.
Oh, you could smell
the smoke on it right there.
-I smoked it for two hours.
-I thought you were putting...
-[laughing]
-He fell for it.
Tri-tip is on there
getting some color.
Let's make a remoulade.
It's gonna go
on top of everything.
-Lime juice.
-[Rick] Mayonnaise.
A little triple egg sauce.
-Yeah, that's scary.
-[high-pitched]
I think it's really smooth.
Little bit heat.
Some molasses too.
-Hunter, you wanna get
the hush puppies started?
-Yeah, yeah.
-Flour and
baking soda into a bowl?
-With the cornbread mix.
And there there should be
some cheddar jack blend.
-That's a lot of cheese
in there, buddy.
-Cheese adds flavor.
Profound.
-What temperature
you want that oil at?
-[Rick] 350.
[Rick] Those hush puppies
about three minutes,
and the outside will get
golden brown and crispy.
[Guy] Hunter's working
the hush puppies.
We've got the smoked
marinated tri-tip.
That's on the grill,
and the cornbread
is in the oven.
When we come back,
we're gonna put this together
and whoever knows what else.
Triple D Takeout
will see you in a bit.
-Which two do you want?
-Which two?
I made these actually.
They're mine.
Welcome back.
Triple D Takeout.
Hanging out in the backyard,
and Hunter and I,
well, we're cooking up
Baby Blues BBQ
in Venice Beach.
And our buddy Rick
has sent us an appetizer
he calls the Suicide King.
We got a smoked
marinated tri-tip,
and I assume you want it
on the bias like this?
-Oh, yeah, that's perfect.
-Hey, hey, hey.
-What? I'm just--
-I didn't say.
I'm the one slicing.
[Guy] Look at that beautiful
smoke ring on that.
That cornbread's a bomb.
What do you smoke with?
[Rick] Hickory,
white oak, apple.
Wow. Delicious.
[Guy] Little barbecue sauce
on this.
North Carolina style.
Little bit of remoulade.
[Guy] A little bit
of the cotija.
[Rick] A little slaw
on the side.
Couple of hush puppies.
What goes on with this
honey butter you sent me?
[Rick] It's honey in butter
with a little cinnamon
and vanilla.
[Hunter] Oh, yeah.
[Guy] Tri-tip, I think,
is one of the greatest cuts.
And in this dish
in particular, mmm,
we're talking lights out.
Takes smoke really well.
-Nice and tender.
-Oh, yeah.
The barbecue sauce
and the remoulade...
go perfectly.
You know,
you get the creaminess,
you get the acidity
coming through from that
Carolina barbecue sauce.
[Hunter] And the sweetness
from the cornbread
mixing it in.
And the hush puppies,
the cheese to flour ratio
was crazy.
Kind of gooey in the middle.
I eat much more of this,
I'll be gooey in the middle.
Whoo! And that honey butter
to top it off,
that's a treat right there.
-Outstanding.
-Seriously.
All right, folks.
If you like burgers, I got
a crazy buddy named Bret.
He's down in Arizona.
And this,
ladies and gentlemen,
is Paradise Valley Burger.
Your burger
interpretive dance,
what would it look like?
Start with the nose plug,
work its way down.
-That's where it's at.
-Slowly switch.
-And some ice. There we go.
-Line dance.
Country Fried Burger.
It takes the regular
everyday burger
to another level.
Well, I gotta tell you,
Bret...
-I'm sorry. Who's in the back?
-Who?
[screams]
Oh, I'm so sorry.
I have no idea
how this man got in here.
[laughs]
Conquering
all hungry appetites,
it's Burger Man.
This is Brian.
He was actually
the first employee I hired
and he's still with me
ten years later.
Brian, how much money
do you owe Bret?
-I mean, what happened?
-If you're in trouble,
blink twice.
[laughing]
[Guy] How many boxes
did you send home?
Two large boxes
and like a medium box.
-No, no, they're all
very large boxes.
-They're all large boxes.
[laughs]
-Does this say Doughitos?
-Doughitos.
-You make these?
-Yes, sir.
Our pizzas take,
like, 25 minutes to cook,
so I set them
in the dining room
so they could eat it
like bread while they're...
-Actually, those are
really good Doughitos.
-Thank you, sir.
Cheeseburger drink rafts.
Very nice. Then, fantastic.
-Not only did you send me...
-It's duct-taped.
...some of Sammy Hagar's
tequila from his old company
which I'm now in business
with the new company,
but you drank half of it,
and then you send to me,
and you duct-taped
the top on it.
Yeah, pretty much exactly
what happened. Yup.
-It's a full-blown pizza.
-He sent a pizza?
I threw a pizza in there.
Hey, we're making burgers.
But who wants pizza?
Oh, wait, there's a letter.
Enclosed you'll find some info
on how to prepare
the Cinco Diablo
from Paradise Valley Burger
in Phoenix, Arizona.
Anybody should be able
to get this. [laughs]
-That was my favorite one.
-[laughing]
We have hit a new level today.
What are we making?
[Bret] So we're doing
the Cinco Diablo
five chili burger.
Two different dimensions
for you guys to make.
The Fresno chili pesto.
Then I have a jalapeno ranch
you guys can rock and roll on.
Let's start
with the Fresno chili pesto.
So I have Fresno chilies
that are roasted right here.
[Bret] Basil, olive oil,
parmesan,
-peanut butter.
-Wait, wait, wait.
Peanut butter, really?
Yes, sir, and a little bit of
salt and pepper of course,
and then the roasted red bell
peppers. That should be on
the money right there.
-What can we start on next?
-The pickled serrano chilies
we like.
I got sliced serrano chilies
over here,
hook it up with some of
the tequila, about half a cup,
and then freestyle some
sugar in there.
Freestyle? Okay. Freestyling
the sugar.
[Bret] Some cumin.
Squeeze a lime up in there.
Fresno pesto is done,
which is gorgeous by the way.
-What's the next step?
-Beer batter up the
poblano pepper.
Flour and beer, super simple.
Take the roasted green
chilly there,
I like to salt them a little
bit first and then flour
and then batter.
-Okay.
-Finally, Chef, will be the
jalapeno ranch.
We're gonna take the
heavy cream, you got
your jalapenos.
-All the mayo.
-And then granulated
onion, bread and garlic.
-Light salt pepper.
-And then this gets pureed up?
[Bret] Yes, sir.
[Guy] Hunter's got his batter,
he can start frying.
Toast nice and crispy.
Alright, brother, I'm done
with the jalapeno ranch,
don't go anywhere,
Paradise Valley Burger,
one in a million.
We got burgers coming up.
Welcome back,
Triple D in the backyard.
We're right in the middle
of it folks, making this
Cinco Diablo...
-What is it called again,
Bret?
-Cinco Diablo.
[Guy] From our buddy, Bret,
at Paradise Valley Burger.
Hunter just took these
roasted poblanos,
then out them in a nice
beer batter. Are we ready
to make the burger yet, bro?
Rock and roll, man.
Take our squared bun,
little bit of butter
get those on the flat top and
get our patties rocking,
it's a two two-ounce patties.
-Season them with?
-Salt and pepper, I like a lot
of lettuce on the bottom bun
-to stop from a soggy burger.
-Burger's over.
[Bret] A little bit of the
light jalapeno ranch,
chipotle bacon is...
bacon just rubbed in
chipotle, backed off,
so it's got a little blackened
vibe going on with it.
And then a little bit more
ranch, so that the poblanos
sticks to the ranch.
-Beautiful.
Fresno chili pesto.
-Now avocado?
-[Bret] Kinda fan it out.
-We're having some very big
height challenge issues here.
Oh!
And then a few of the serrano
chilies and then a nice
cilantro garnish,
and that is it.
I... the diameter of this...
Nice. Good form gentlemen.
-Hold on.
The poblanos are hot.
-[all laughing]
That ranch cools it down.
The Fresno chilly pesto,
that's a screamer
right there, bro.
Delicious meat, I love the fry
and crunch from the poblano.
The chipotle on the bacon and
brother, you are without
question, the real deal.
-Well done. Your man's
bowing in the back.
-[all applauding]
The next place we're gonna
check out, Hunter,
has the deli case the size
of Burger Man's energy
and attitude.
It's up in Portland, Oregon.
Every time I go there,
I come to visit the place.
You're gonna love it.
This is Otto's.
Holy moly, it's like
meat Disneyland. Whoa!
-And we're making sausages.
-Yes we are.
-Whoa, Can't you just make it
come a little bit slower?
-I did.
Christie, when was it?
You were still in high school
when I was there.
I think it was, like, 2008.
[Guy] How many family members
work there?
[Jerry] Mom and Dad, the three
daughters and two
of their husbands.
[Guy] I want to see
what you sent us,
I know this is got
so much history
and so much background.
How long has this all been
going?
We're gonna be pushing a
100 years here in about
an year and a half.
-What are we gonna make?
-A South African boerewors
and apple chicken sausage.
We have our nice new
grinder out here, that
we've never used.
So, let's start off with
the boerewors first.
-What've we got?
-[Jerry] Beef chuck.
I think you're gonna have to
dice it up a little bit to get
through your grinder.
You see what I don't have is
the size machinery that they
have there at Otto's.
Whoa! That's the biggest
buffalo chopper I've ever
seen. Fire in the hole!
That's awesome.
It's quite the production.
I've got all the beef and
pork loin.
-Season it now in a bowl.
-Peppers in. Salt's going in.
Allspice.
-[Hunter] Brown sugar. Cloves.
-Coriander, nutmeg.
And red wine vinegar.
-Hunter?
-Yep.
Impressive, Guy.
-Where's the recipe come from?
-This guy was from
South Africa,
James Collier, and he brought
in packages of boerewors
seasoning
and wanted me to make it,
it was delicious and so we
came up with our own recipe.
And right on the top of
this meat?
That put it in a bowl so you
can mix it together and
not lose too much.
See, Hunter, that's why
they're making sausage,
and we're standing here acting
like we're making sausage.
-There you go, okay, let's see
how this starts working.
-Oh, yeah.
You wanna keep the meat
flowing through you grinder
because that's what
cools your plate.
-We're rookies, Jerry.
-We deal with a 100 pounds,
you only got five pounds.
-Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
-[Jerry laughing]
-[Hunter] We're gonna
case this?
-Yes.
-Jer, which size am I wanting?
-You're gonna want the
smaller horn.
Okay, you're gonna have to get
more water in there.
You're gonna need a good
slurry you what to
go through it.
It's gotta slide on easy,
otherwise it's not gonna come
off easy. You're getting it.
And I don't need to tie this
off, right? I need to let
my air come through?
You got that right.
See, Jer, I paid attention a
little bit when we did this.
Okay, here we go.
Just put it all on the top.
We're learning here as we go,
we're trying to work
as a team, Jer.
-I'm starting to get a full
cased one now.
-That's beautiful.
I'm not saying that
Hunter and I are
doing it any Otto style...
-We're not pros.
-But I think for our
maiden voyage
on our little countertop unit,
-that didn't come out too bad.
-Looks awesome to me.
Let's just saute it in the pan
with little oil, get a nice
brown to it.
So, one sausage down,
but don't go anywhere,
we're gonna cook this,
-we're gonna get the grinder
cleaned up, that's your job.
-No, no.
We're gonna make chicken apple
sausage, see you in a bit.
-Alright, now I'll watch this,
you go...
-No, no, no. I'm already here.
-Go clean, go clean. Alright.
-I got the pan,
I put in there.
Welcome back, Triple D
in the backyard.
We're doing a little takeout,
we got some of our favorite
Triple D chefs from
around the country.
We went to Paradise Valley and
had a fantastic burger, we've
been right down the street
here in northern California,
with our sister Alma,
at La Texanita.
Then we go to our buddy, Rick,
of Baby Blues barbeque,
and right now folks,
our friends at Otto's, up at
Portland, Oregon.
-We're making sausage.
-High five.
Yeah.
Okay, so now we're into
chicken apple sausage.
We cut up all the breast
and all the thigh.
We got to cut those two apples
up and de-core 'em,
leave the skin on.
Ground ginger, going in,
cinnamon... niminim.
Chicken apple salt, or
this is just salt.
-Just salt.
-I think it's just salt.
I didn't know, I mean,
maybe you have
special salt up there.
We got some fresh cracked
black pepper, onion, this is
coriander going in right here.
And a little nutmeg.
Is there a liquid that's
going into this?
No it'll be plenty moist.
Hunter, I think you could've
used a bigger bowl.
-I...
-We're just learning
that now, Jerry.
This is a learning process,
okay?
It sure likes it here when
it's nice and easy chicken
to run through it and
a couple of apple chunks.
[Jerry] We're gonna use
the same port casing.
Hunter, I cased it for
you, son.
Thank you, that's... You're
a good father. Ready to roll?
-[Guy] Let's give her a shot.
-We're rocking and
rolling now.
-You got to do this.
-Wait, wait, wait.
-Got to do that.
-Wait, wait.
I have to check the sausage.
We've African boerewors
cooking here low and slow.
I don't know how to do it,
do I just hold it?
-Nice job, Hunter.
-There we go. Now are these
supposed to be linked?
Right. Just use your
fingertips.
-Nice and easy, that's what
we're looking for, right?
-[Jerry] Looks beautiful.
[Christie] Put them in a
160 degree water bath
for 30 minutes.
Since it's chicken,
you want a nice thorough cook
and water transfers the heat
so much better than
just the pan.
[Guy] Once you're done,
bring them out put them
in a pan,
and this is the African
boerewors sausage, a toasted
bun, look at that, huh?
-[Hunter] Love it.
-[Guy] How do these
get plated up?
With Onion add some
Dusseldorf mustard.
-Is Dusseldorf blow the
top of your head off mustard?
-No.
Okay, so this is top round
pork loin, a variety
of spices.
Wait, wait, wait, you're
taking a bite without me?
What I like in particular
about this, is I like
funky flavors.
I want that red wine vinegar
in there, you know, I want
that tang.
I want that funk of the
coriander, of the allspice.
-Cloves, all that.
-It has that,
"Oh, my goodness,
I'm a big meal inside of
a little package."
[Hunter] It's delicious.
That Dusseldorf mustard,
my new fav.
We're also making chicken
apple and going with this is
the potato salad.
-What's in the potato salad?
-[Christie] Otto's bacon...
-Because, of course you make
your own bacon, right.
-Of course.
Onion, apple cider vinegar,
beef broth, black pepper,
add some Maggi seasoning.
-Delicious.
-Now, on the chicken apple...
what you get there is a little
bit of sweet, a good amount of
cinnamon and nutmeg.
-It's tender, there's enough
fat in there it's not dry.
-Right.
A lot of apple, I think
leaving the peel on the
apple's the real key.
-The kind of spiced apple now
with all the spices there.
-It is.
Fantastic. Everybody straight
across the board from Mexican
to burgers to barbeques
to sausages...
Rockstar, awesome job.
Thank you very much.
Hunter and I now have to come
up with, who sent the
best package.
There's no cash prizes,
it's just bragging rights.
Hopefully we get down and
visit all you guys.
Oh, I'm definitely coming for
that sausage, bro. I'm coming
for that barbeque.
We're coming. Yeah.
Alright folks, listen, all the
dishes were dynamite,
but folks
winner winner Triple D
takeout dinner goes to...
-Paradise Valley Burger, our
buddy Bret, and Burger Man.
-[all applauding]
Nicely done, you guys,
thank you so much.
-Adios. What's your line?
Good bye.
-Adios, how about that?
If you're wearing that,
you have to do the dance.
-Don't you think he has
to do the dance?
-Do the dance.
-I thought we were friends.
-[all laughing]
-Let's get it.
-Okay, hold on.
-Two, one, two, three, four.
There you go.
-[all laughing]
That's how we kick it off
on a Friday.