You know, people are asking me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy. That one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing Triple-D,
how'd they do it?"
You know, I don't know,
we should check it out.
Over the years, I've seen
and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out, it was only
the beginning,
because Triple-D joints
have been blowing up
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip.
We're wheeling...
I have to pull over,
I don't have a choice.
Dealing...
Gordy's makes the best Coneys,
believe me.
And taking it to go.
Maybe get us a pizza box.
Order of rings for you.
There's a classic car hop
in Cloquet, Minnesota...
You think about
the all-American drive-in,
that's the kind of burger
they're talking about.
A Mexican-Filipino mashup
moving around San Francisco...
There we go. Now you're
getting taco truck on me.
It's Flavortown for sure.
And in Kihei, Hawaii...
Beautiful.
The boys and I
are crashing a pizza cart...
-There's the stencil.
-Is it, really?
Catalina island-inspired pie.
Watch out. You're not going
to look the same in your
bathing suit.
Familiar faces, new places
and more off the hook flavors.
This is Triple-D Nation .
The Hawaiian islands
may cover a lot of ground,
but you can't throw a stone
without hitting
a Triple-D joint.
And after Hunter, Jules and I
hit up a new place on Maui,
we found ourselves
face to face
with an old one.
That Outrigger Pizza joint,
it looks a little familiar,
doesn't it?
Now, we shot Outrigger Pizza
in 2016, but it was by a park
down at the water.
You can't get pizza that good
in most restaurants.
I'm doing it right here
on the trailer.
-I don't think that's
the same place.
-Are you sure?
-Actually it might be.
-Let's go check it out.
This is Outrigger Pizza.
-Aloha.
-It's the number one
pizza place ever.
If you want something unique,
you want something great,
you come to Outrigger.
Supreme pizza.
I saw that Guy has actually
been here because I saw
the stencil.
So I knew it was legit.
There's the stencil.
-Is it, really?
-There is the stencil.
I threw that up in 2016,
when I found Kevin Laut
and his mobile pizza oven
parked in a pretty epic spot.
Look at the environment.
How high-stress is this?
-Sheesh.
-It's why I moved here.
Now it's Hunter and
my nephew Jules' turn.
Although the scenery
isn't exactly the same.
-We were in Lahaina
last time, on the beach.
-Lahaina.
-On the beach in Lahaina.
-Now we're in a parking lot.
-Is this a normal hang?
-Yeah, this is every day.
You know, you're cruising
down the road
and you just can't miss
that big yellow cart.
-I love the rig, man.
Who built the pizza oven?
-I did.
-Did you, really?
-Yeah.
-Last time we tried
a Kajlua...
-The Lilikoi Pork.
-The Lilikoi Pork, right.
-Number one seller by far.
-It's the true Hawaiian pizza.
-Got it.
-Lilikoi, what is Lilikoi?
-Lilikoi is a passion fruit.
-Okay, first we're
gonna make pizza dough.
-Yep.
Hang on a second.
Where's the mixer?
No mixer, it's all by hand.
-Seriously?
-Yeah.
-I add my yeast to the water.
-Okay.
-And my sugar.
-Fantastic.
-Five pounds...
-I don't want you to
take any offense,
but I'm gonna
stand on this side
when you pour the flour.
That's the side where
the wind's gonna go.
Okay, fantastic,
I'll be right over there.
Unbleached flour,
bleached flour, semolina,
and now we're gonna take out
four pounds to add that to our
second phase of the dough.
There you go.
-Water.
-So what'd you do today?
Watched a guy make dough.
For his pizza cart
at the park by the water with
some weird contraption.
Danish whisk.
-You Danish?
-No.
-So we're gonna add our
activated yeast and water.
-Okay.
-So we'll wait two hours
for this to poof.
-Oh.
-To do what?
-Rise.
-Good.
-Now that we've let
the dough rise,
we're gonna reintroduce
our four pounds of flour.
Hawaiian sea salt.
-Alright, so that's together.
-Two hours later, we're gonna
knead the dough.
And into our plastic bag,
and then refrigeration.
Let it rest for two days.
And we're gonna do
a garlic aioli base,
a little bit of garlic,
the pork, Maui sweet onions,
sweet bell peppers.
Mozzarella cheese,
a little bit of Romano.
Well, that oven's hot, buddy.
They only take about
90 seconds to cook.
That is a gorgeous
looking pie, dude.
We'll do some fresh parmesan.
And here's our specialty,
the Lilikoi.
Beautiful pizza.
It's dynamite.
The crust is...
Too legit to quit.
Really dynamite pizza.
How's business been?
Just like you said,
business is gonna double.
-I might need a mixer.
-Right?
-Yeah.
-Did you finally
go with a mixer?
I got a big 60-quart mixer
to help me along my way.
-It's been great.
-I love it.
Well, what do you got,
what's new?
-The Maui onion.
-Okay.
Which is a garlic aioli,
Maui sweet onions,
rosemary, truffle salt.
-I love it.
-This is gonna be
our garlic aioli base,
which is mayonnaise,
garlic and a hint of lemon.
We're gonna press out
one of our handmade doughs.
Our garlic aioli.
Little extra garlic for you.
Mozzarella cheese.
Maui sweet onions.
And then just
a touch of rosemary.
Ready to go in the oven.
Add a little bit
of truffle salt.
Maui sweet onion.
-Yes.
-Beautiful.
That's money.
-The rosemary...
-Yeah.
-On top of this.
-Isn't it dynamite?
-I just kind of wanted
a simple pizza.
-It is.
-Something light.
-Most importantly,
it's really in balance.
You've got not
too much of anything.
I mean, I remember this
from when we had it
six years ago.
What I like is that
you're not heavy handed
with your ingredients.
It's not supposed to be
the gooey cheese stretching
off into the sunset,
it's supposed to be a balance
between all the flavors
to where you can
taste everything.
-Balanced, delicious...
-Awesome.
I love the Maui sweet onion,
the crust is awesome.
It's a great white sauce
pizza, it's amazing.
It's crispy, it's fast,
it's delicious.
It's a Yahtzee every time.
But it's not the only
game he's got.
Because coming up...
This dude does not stop.
It's home run...
It is crispy,
it is perfectly cooked.
After home run.
It's amazing!
Hunter, Jules and I
are at Outrigger,
a pizza cart I first found
on the sand in Lahaina.
The rig looks like it's been
rode hard, bro.
-Oh my God, you have no clue.
-How many years has it been,
six, five?
2016. My son was actually born
the day the show aired.
Comes, helps me make pizzas,
helps me with the dough.
-That's awesome.
-That's really cool.
Kevin, local legend
of the pizza game out here.
He's got a great
personality, just a lot of fun
to be around,
it's a really nice
laidback vibe.
Driving by, you could smell
the kiawe wood fire oven,
I have to pull over,
I don't have a choice.
-Alright, what are we
gonna make next?
-Italian sausage.
-You guys are making almost
everything from scratch?
-Yes.
We're gonna make
some red sauce.
Go ahead, I'm standing
over here because
I'm in light blue...
You might get red.
I can already tell you
that tomato sauce is gonna
make a mess.
Our ground tomatoes,
granulated garlic,
one teaspoon of basil,
one teaspoon of thyme,
oregano, black pepper,
salt, teaspoon of cinnamon,
nutmeg, and then we're gonna
mix it here.
We made dough by hand
and now you're gonna
use an electric mixer?
Buddy, you just
don't make sense.
One cup of olive oil.
Give it a little
bit of flavor.
Tomato sauce,
ground sausage,
Maui sweet onions,
mushrooms and some
green peppers.
Mozzarella, Romano.
-Back into the oven.
-90 seconds.
There you go.
Fresh parmesan again.
A little bit of truffle salt.
Hear the crunch?
Look how thin that is.
Nice crust, a little char.
-Really nice job.
-Thank you.
Dynamite. I'm impressed.
-Any new plans?
-I have a plan to put
another pizza oven,
but we'll just put it
on the side here because
we're just so busy.
-It just cranks.
-It's unreal.
How many pies are we talking?
-Last night, I think, we made
156 pizzas.
-Whoa.
It's always busy here,
but after Triple-D
it gets crazy.
It definitely hit the mark,
great pizza,
I love the mushroom.
White cheddar mushroom
is delicious.
White cheddar mushroom pizza.
Get to stretching
some dough here.
Looking for a 10,
11 inch pizza.
And it has
the garlic aioli base,
this is just our garlic.
We're gonna do some mozzarella
cheese, white cheddar,
and mushrooms.
And it's gonna go into our
700-degree oven.
Slice them up,
add some truffle salt.
White cheddar mushroom pizza.
-White cheddar mushroom.
-I love it. Thank you.
-You're welcome.
-Beautiful.
-Enjoy.
-Look at that crust.
It is thin, it is crispy,
it is perfectly cooked.
Well done.
Delicious.
White cheddar mushroom
is actually my favorite.
When it comes out of the oven,
it's got that
thin crust crunch.
It's amazing.
Watch out. You're not
gonna look the same
in your bathing suit.
I've got to tell you, bro,
I am so... This is actually
a fantastic spot.
And I can see why you're doing
156 pizzas in a night.
-Thank you.
-Well deserved, buddy.
-This is money.
-You helped out,
thanks, I appreciate it.
-I think you need to get
yourself another oven.
-Yes, I do.
-And maybe get us a pizza box.
-Yeah.
Coming up,
in Cloquet, Minnesota
a drive-in, whose
old school ways...
We've always said, "What's
working, don't screw it up."
...are drawing in
fresh crowds.
I love Gordy's shakes.
I mean, here's one of
the things I love about
this show.
It's finding the joints that
have been doing it old school
for generations.
So here we are, about
20 miles south of
Duluth, Minnesota
off Interstate 35 in
a lumber town called Cloquet.
These folks have been rocking
over 11 and a half million
burger patties
since they opened in 1960.
And with another decade
under their belt,
the third generation
has stepped up to the plate.
Hey, guys, how are
we doing today?
And here's the kicker, they're
only open six months
out of the year.
This is Gordy's Hi-Hat.
Three double cheese
and a Coney ready.
This is a great place
for Triple-D to come to.
I have to say, it's really
kind of my happy place.
I've got your three Coneys
and onion rings.
After watching Triple-D,
I made a point to come to
Gordy's Hi-Hat.
It's unique and it's
one of a kind.
[Guy] Just like the man
who started it,
Gordy Lundquist,
who opened this joint
with his wife Marilyn
back in 1960.
By the time I rolled around
50 years later,
their son Dan was in charge.
When you thought about
starting this,
did you think it would turn
into this?
Never, especially when
Dan took over, he had more
ideas than I did,
my ideas were getting
a little old.
I've been coming
to Gordy's for 57 years.
We used to come up
here for lunch.
You could get a 19 cent burger
and 19 cent fries and
a dime coke.
What's the number one
selling item on the menu?
Double cheeseburgers
with Marilyn on the grill,
my mom.
The burgers are off the hook.
-I heard that you run this
better than anybody.
-I do.
I'm the oldest, fastest
fry cook in the United States
and a TV star, you know.
-How many times do you
flip them?
-Just a couple times.
I will put a bun on
as they want them,
if they don't
want mustard
or whatever else.
-What about those onions?
-Put some onions on.
-Do you like
your cheese melted?
-Please.
We always melt the cheese.
Couple of pickles...
It's all built right on there.
It's all built on there,
and then I just
put it on the bun.
Bun tops are toasted and
we put it into the container.
-This is the number
one seller?
-Number one best seller.
Look at all that juice.
When you think about the
all-American drive-in,
that's the kind of burger
they're talking about.
Can I help you?
My dad's 92, my mom's up there
too, and I won't tell you
what her age is,
but they're slowing down
a little bit.
You can't handle something
like this when you get
in your 90s.
Now I'm passing on to my son
Sever, who is ready for
another generation
of doing the same old thing.
My dad's been here for
his whole life
and I basically have
been here for mine.
Our double cheeseburger
has always been our
number one seller,
it's been a staple
for 60 plus years.
But the Coney dog's
a very close second.
Our dealership used to order
sometimes 50 or 60 Coneys
at a crack at Tuesdays.
-As in, a Coney Island dog?
-A Coney Island dog.
We're all the way up here
in Minnesota. How do you
know what a Coney is?
Gordy's makes the best Coneys,
believe me.
Coney dogs have been
on the menu since
we opened in 1960.
The recipe has not changed.
We make our sauce
in house every day.
We start here with some
choice ground beef,
we'll get this
on the grill here.
We'll mix in all of
our spices.
Chili powder, some
black pepper,
garlic salt,
onion powder, little
cayenne kicker,
I'll add a little water
on top just to help
mix these spices in,
put it in a pot to simmer.
We're gonna cook
some Coney wieners.
You've got a nice crispy coat
on them here.
Now our dogs are on the grill,
yellow mustard, wiener on,
hot Coney sauce,
freshly chopped onions,
and you're ready to serve.
Three Coneys up.
It's like a chili dog,
but it does not have beans.
A lot of ground beef.
They're the best.
The sauce that they put
on top of it is to die for.
Top it with the onions,
best there is.
The Coney dogs are great.
I love the onion rings.
-I do onion rings every day.
-It's a big onion.
You go after it.
The grease is at about 375.
We just serve
them with catsup.
-With what?
-Catsup.
I think that means "ketchup".
That's a really good
onion ring.
Mmm.
You want something
that Guy had?
Double cheese, onion rings,
blackberry shake.
[Guy] Blackberry
and raspberry.
Let me just
help you out with that.
Take vanilla soft serve
ice-cream with
a high butterfat,
make sure it's a rich,
creamy ice-cream.
Big, whole blackberries.
Put it in the blender.
With a little whipped cream.
Blackberry shake, ready to go.
Got three shakes for you.
You got it, bud?
I love Gordy's shakes.
It's nice and creamy.
And berries, yummy.
It always tastes fresh.
It's always, you know,
thick, tough to suck
through a straw.
Can't beat it.
[Guy] But you're
not gonna find them
all year round.
Why do you close six months
out of the year?
[Dan] It works, you know.
We've always said,
what's working
don't screw it up
and the novelty
of opening every year
is a big thing.
I'm usually trying
to get down here
as soon as they open up
and try to get here
as many times as I can
before they close in the fall.
What a great institution.
You guys have been
taking care of these folks
for a long time.
-Thank you.
-Nice to meet you.
-An honor to have you here.
-Thank you.
[Guy] Up next,
in San Francisco...
Wow. That pork has got
so much flavor...
...a food truck
is branching out...
It's a big meal,
but you won't
be disappointed.
...and planting roots.
Not Asian, not Mexican.
-Just Senor Sisig.
-For sure.
So I'm here at San Francisco,
in the SoMa district,
South of Market,
to look for a food truck.
You never know where they're
gonna be, so you gotta check
'em out on their website.
Now, I hear these guys
are doing
a cross between Filipino
and Latin-American cuisine.
It's like a Filipino burrito
fusion spot, a taco truck
-that you gotta check it out.
-You make it so easy
to understand.
[Guy] And after I track
this one down in 2013,
they exploded all over
the Bay area.
This is Senor Sisig.
This is Pork Sisig Fries.
They have a cult following
in San Francisco,
so everybody
knows Senor Sisig.
What does Sisig stand for?
I saw them, like, hey,
those guys were on Triple D,
that's actually well deserved.
It's flavor town for sure.
[Guy] And the guys
taking you on that trip,
that would be Gil Payumo
and Evan Kidera.
So whose idea was
this festivity here
of the truck?
I wanted to be on the streets
with mobile food,
came to my friend
who is a chef.
Had you worked
at a food truck before?
No.
-Had you driven
a food truck before?
-Never.
Having Guy come through,
you know, he's a Bay area guy,
so, you know, we kinda
just got along right away.
Good looking out.
-Right on.
-Take care of business.
[Gil] Two pork Sisig Tacos...
What does Sisig stand for?
Sisig is a traditional
Filipino dish.
-Is this what you grew up
eating when you were a kid?
-Yeah.
Not everyone knows
what Sisig is
and I think that was
a good way to put us
on the map.
Give me the low down.
First, we're gonna start off
with the pork shoulder,
sliced up, quarter inch, thin.
We got some
soy sauce over here
and sugarcane vinegar,
pineapple juice.
Got our minced garlic,
some bay leaves,
some white sugar,
black pepper and
we got some salt.
Mix it up a little bit
and we're just gonna
cover it up.
[Guy] You let this marinate
and then how are we gonna
cook it?
[Gil] We're gonna basically
char grill it then we chop it.
There we go.
Now you're getting
taco truck on me.
We're gonna throw it
in the marinade.
That's gonna go
to the flat top?
[Gil] Sisig goes
on the tortillas,
diced onions on there,
iceberg lettuce
and cabbage mixture,
cilantro cream sauce,
a little jalapeno
and two limes.
[Guy] So you really did mix
the two cultures?
[Gil] Yeah.
Wow.
That pork has got
so much flavor.
-Salty, spicy goodness.
Nicely done.
-Yeah. Right on, my friend.
Two Pork Sisig Tacos.
Sisig is delicious
and you can get it done
many different ways.
The pork is the main seller
here people come for,
but there's variations
of protein or the meat
that you can have.
Here's your Pork Sisig Nachos.
It could be pork,
it could be chicken,
they can be made with tofu.
I have a Whole
Barnyard Burrito
and a Pork Sisig Cali-changas.
Thank you.
I'm having their
Whole Barnyard Burrito today.
It has all four Sisigs.
Pork Sisig, Chicken Sisig,
Tocino, tofu.
So the Chicken Sisig
and Pork Sisig
are made the same.
Now, we're gonna start off
prepping our Tocino,
which is a sweet
Filipino pork.
First, we're gonna be making
our marinade pineapple juice.
We got some sugarcane vinegar,
granulated sugar, salt,
beet food coloring
and also red food coloring.
This helps identify
the Tocino that is sweet.
Now we're gonna be taking
the pork shoulders,
it's gonna marinate
over 48 hours
and it's ready to go on
the flat top and grill it up.
Now we're gonna be
sauteing our tofu,
throwing down the onions,
then we got
our chopped jalapenos,
some granulated garlic,
black pepper and some salt.
We're gonna saute this
for about two-three minutes.
Add my tofu with
a sweet chili glaze.
For our Barnyard Burrito,
fries right in the middle,
two ounces of each protein,
Pork Sisig, Chicken Sisig,
the Tocino, our Sisig tofu.
Next we're gonna take
our fried egg,
fresh jalapenos,
shredded cheese on top,
guacamole, sour cream,
Pico de Gallo.
There you go.
Your Barnyard Burrito.
I have
a Whole Barnyard burrito.
It is super flavorful,
it's very colorful.
You're gonna wanna
come back for more
every time you have it.
That Sisig flavor,
it's really tasty.
It's a well balanced
sort of savory and sweet.
It's a big meal,
but you won't be disappointed.
If you've earned it,
if you want something
a little heavier...
-If you've earned it.
After Triple D aired,
you know, I mean,
we definitely got
a good response.
-You have two trucks now?
-Two trucks.
Two trucks?
How many you gonna get?
[Gil] We've grown
to five trucks
and we also have
two brick and mortars.
This has really just been
a dream come true for us.
[Evan] I got
a Chicken Crunch-a-Dilla.
I got you.
Whenever we see
the Senor Sisig truck,
it's usually a truck
that we hit up first.
The service is always the same
and they give the people
what they want.
[Gil] Adobo Buffalo Wings.
What can you describe
the spice as, the flavor as?
I couldn't nail it
as Filipino,
and I couldn't really
hit it as Mexican.
It's in its own category.
Infused.
Confused infused, I like it.
-Thank you very much.
Enjoy.
-Thank you.
Not too sweet, not too spicy.
Not Asian, not Mexican,
just Senor Sisig.
-Yeah. Right on, my friend.
-Nicely done.
Hot fudge shake, Coney,
double cheeseburger
and some fries.
Listen, there is nothing
I like better
than checking in
on Triple D chefs,
taking the opportunity
and running with it.
-There you go.
-Yeah.
Two tortillas on a flat top.
We'll catch up with
more faces and places,
next time on Triple D Nation.
What do you do during
the holidays?
-I sell Christmas trees.
-You sell Christmas trees.
On Maui.
How many Christmas trees
do you sell in a year?
480.
480. How many did you order?
481.