So when I come off the road
from doing DDD,
the first thing I wanna do
is get home to my kitchen
and cook my food
for my family.
-And after a few weeks,
I gotta be...
-Dad, can we just...
I mean, please,
go to a restaurant
-at least one time.
-They start to revolt.
So I came up with the idea.
How about we reach out
to some of our favorite chefs
and have them send us dinner,
-huh?
-I like that idea.
[Guy] And I know
some DDD joints
that would love
to send it to us.
We've got a southern feast
out of Des Moines, Iowa.
Thanks to my buddy Mike
at Flying Mango.
Keep crushing it, bro.
Seafood that's gotta be
real deal
since it's coming from
San Francisco's Pier 23.
You're not going
to regular fish taco land.
My friend, Jazz,
at Jitlada in Los Angeles
is blowing up the heat
with her authentic Thai.
This is like a freight train
coming into flavor town
with no brakes.
And Super Duper Weenie
is sending
a Cincinnati chilidog
all the way from Connecticut.
My mouth is watering right now
just getting into this.
And on top of it all,
they're gonna
video conference in
to give us the true
DDD experience.
This is DDD Takeout.
And there's a few more
in the trunk.
[Hunter] Of course, there is.
[upbeat music playing]
All right, Hunter, you are
going to love today's lineup.
We have got superstars
in all ends of the spectrum
of food.
First, my buddy Mac
down at Pier 23
in San Francisco.
What year did we
shoot you?
-2008.
-[Guy] You're looking good.
Now, all the way out
in Connecticut,
our buddy Gary
from Super Duper Weenie,
are you before or after 2008?
We were 2008 as well.
[Guy] Then it would go
to Flying Mango,
our buddy, Mike,
how are you, bud?
I am living the dream
right here
in Des Moines, Iowa.
-[Guy] What year
did we shoot you?
-October of 2014.
[Guy] Then we got our sister
from another mister,
Jazz, from Jitlada
in Los Angeles.
And her daughter, Sirine,
the best Thai.
Some of my favorite
in the world.
How long ago was that?
Two years ago.
[Guy] Seems like
it was two days ago.
So anyhow, here's my son,
Hunter,
here's my son, Ryder.
What we asked you
to send us
is maybe one
of your all-time favorites
that we haven't tried.
Maybe something new
that you're working on
that we really got
to experience.
Now, I wanna remind everybody
that someone's gonna win
no cash or prizes,
but is gonna get best dish
tonight.
We got a little Southern,
we got a little
California seafood,
we got amazing Thai,
and we got hotdogs.
Not hotdogs
like you would expect
and that's what we should
jump right into.
If you're gonna call
your joint
Super Duper Weenie,
you better bring it.
And these guys did.
Got a California,
one New York.
So you're
the big weenie here.
What is the number one
seller?
Our New Englander style.
I think you had that
when you came here.
Bacon, sauerkraut,
mustard,
sweet relish,
chopped onions.
Hmm. Where's that been
all my life?
People wanna have
a gourmet hotdog experience.
-For sure.
-So, is that what you sent me?
I sent you
Cincinnati style chili,
which is one of the most
unusual chilies
I've ever tasted
and/or created
that has cinnamon,
cumin, allspice.
Believe it or not,
cocoa powder.
I know.
Look at that.
-Is it Christmas?
-[Gary] There you go.
We're gonna start
with the meat first.
[Gary] Yes, sir.
Read the label.
Chuck sirloin
and love.
Aw, that's sweet.
[Guy] Hunter's
working on that.
-What can I do?
-You could slowly start
cooking some hotdogs
if you like.
[Guy] Who makes
the hotdog for you?
A company out in
New Haven, Connecticut,
called Hummel Brothers
and that is a
natural-casing hotdog.
Beef and pork
as they should be.
I don't want
any shaming going on
that I bit in
to a cold hotdog,
like you haven't done it.
Nobody's in the house.
[laughs]
Slide out
the deli drawer.
Here's the thing about it.
The casing,
right when I bit into it,
little snap.
And when those cook,
it's even gonna get better.
All right. We got a lot
of ground beef to cook down.
[Gary] Yeah,
I gave you plenty.
There should be
onions and garlic.
You want the onions to get
a little translucent.
[Guy] You sent me enough here
for probably 50 people.
[Gary] Oh, easily.
I knew that there was
trouble coming.
Jazz, you're last today
-by the way.
-Uh-oh.
Because if I had you
on the show first,
there would be
no more show. Okay?
Because I know what you're
gonna do, Jazz.
So onions and garlic are in.
I would start,
uh, adding your spices.
-[Guy] Chili powder.
-[Gary] There you go.
[Guy] Now, wait a second,
that much cocoa powder?
-[Gary] Yup.
-I'm cocoa for cocoa powder.
[Hunter] That's a lot
of cocoa powder now.
That is a lot
of cocoa powder.
Cider vinegar,
the allspice,
cayenne, salt.
-That much cinnamon?
-Yes, sir.
[Guy] Dude,
I don't doubt you.
I mean, you are crazy
and what you guys do is crazy,
but do you still sell
my DDD dog?
Once in a while,
I get a call for it.
It was the most
ridiculous thing.
Bacon, little cheese,
chili,
dollop of slaw,
sprinkle with some onions,
sweet left, hot right.
Now, talk about that.
Hmm, dude,
that's dynamite.
Is that killer or what?
-That was a big dog.
-[laughs]
That's awesome.
When does the Worcestershire
go in?
[Gary] You could put
that in now.
How long do you guys
typically let it simmer?
Probably about
30 to 45 minutes.
You're gonna throw
that bottle of water in.
[Guy] Tomato sauce go down,
let this stew.
Tell me the deal
with the fries.
[Gary] It's a Norwis potato.
Blanched for about
two and a half minutes,
and then when you plunge
those back in that hot oil,
they're gonna crisp up
beautifully.
What do we do with the buns?
[Gary] Yeah, just butter
them up and face down.
[Guy] And then we'll put
this thing together.
So don't go anywhere.
It's DDD Takeout.
We're hanging out at the house
with our favorite DDD chefs.
You're gonna love this dish.
We'll see you in a bit.
[rock music playing]
[Guy] Welcome back.
DDD Takeout.
Hunter and I, well,
we're jumping into things
with one of our favorites,
and that is a hotdog.
Not any hotdog, but it's
a Super Duper Weenie hotdog
out of Connecticut.
Our buddy, Gary,
sent us all the goods.
Are we calling this
Cincinnati?
Cincinnati.
[Guy] So I got these hotdogs
that you have especially
made for you,
and then go straight
with the chili right up top.
[Gary] Yup. Ladle it
right on there,
nice good amount.
-Lots of shredded cheddar.
-[Gary] Onions on top.
[Guy] Hunter's got the fries
with a little bit of salt.
-Yup.
-That looks great.
My mouth is watering right
now just getting into this.
[Sirine] Our mouths are
watering watching.
Ryder.
Get this shot.
-[Gary] Oh.
-[Jazz] Yummy.
[laughs]
[Guy] I wanna make sure
this pot of gold
doesn't burn
right now, Gary.
I mean, the chili is
great, man. It really is.
That allspice there
is just super key.
And I've never had it
with a cocoa powder.
There's a lot of depth.
We've never had chili
like this.
The bun's great,
the dog is dynamite.
That snap in the dog.
It's no mushy hotdog.
Delicious.
Loved the chopped onion.
Fries are fantastic.
I gotta say my favorite part
is when you're eating
a hotdog
and everything
kind of falling off.
Now, you've got yourself
some chili cheese fries.
Only recommendation I have.
Send a beach towel.
-[laughs]
-Okay?
-Out of the park.
-Thank you.
Close to the park is
our next visit.
To Francisco,
where the Giants play.
And my buddy, Mac, is
doing it right.
This is Pier 23.
My crew and I have been
hanging here for years.
I mean, we're talking
fresh seafood,
live music, a huge patio,
and you know what,
good times.
This is getting messy.
I mean, this isn't
for the timid.
-Hmm.
-[laughs]
The locals love you,
the tourists love you.
My great buddy,
Eric Lindell
played there several times.
Right.
[Mike] Well, on a side note,
Eric Lindell's band
has played here
in my Flying Mango.
-Oh, I love it.
-Take a look what that is.
So that's the whole lingcod
we sent out to you.
-Oh.
-Wow.
Wait a second,
you just sent a fish?
-That's a greenling.
-[Mac] Yeah.
A, where did you get
a greenling cod?
B, what are we making?
And C, gosh, you're awesome.
[Mac] We get it locally
for our fish tacos,
which we're
gonna be making today.
And we also have
crab cakes.
[Guy] Oh, you sent
crab cakes also?
Yeah, buddy, come on.
What's the game plan here?
I was hoping we'd do
the fish tacos.
Let's start off
with the batter. Flour.
[Mac] Light beer
that I sent up there.
Do you want to bloom
this yeast?
[Mac] Yeah.
In the beer.
-Yeast in.
-[Mac] That's it.
[Guy] Here's our
consistency, buddy.
-Is that what
we're looking for?
-Yup, that looks great.
-[Guy] What are we doing now?
-[Mac] We wanna make
our charred jalapeno
and cucumber salsa.
So char the jalapenos
right on the burner?
-[Mac] Yup.
-[Guy] Hunter's got that.
-Can I start the crab cakes?
-You can, yeah.
Mix some mayo,
house-made devil juice.
-Oh, that's good.
-I need that.
[Mac] Lemon zest
and some lemon juice,
scallion, and some
chopped parsley.
Nice.
Good on cooking.
Just not pretty looks, Jazz.
Hunter, those are
charring up?
Trying, one fell
in the hole,
-it's gone forever.
-Let me show you
a little trick.
[Hunter] Oh, look at that.
Way easier.
So we're gonna put
some panko in there.
[Guy] Just enough
to hold it together.
Dungeness crab,
which we're known for
up here in
Northern California.
[Mac] Use some
of the crab meat
and some egg whites
into a paste.
That's gonna be
the binder for it.
Professional.
I know.
This is like my workout.
Keep going. You can have
an extra hotdog.
-[laughter]
-All right. In this mix?
[Mac] Yeah, so we wanna get
the rest of the crab in there.
[Guy] Folding these over.
Light and gentle.
And you still got
really nice big pieces
of leg meat of crab
right there.
Next?
Make the jalapeno
cucumber salsa.
[Guy] And this is what goes
on these lingcod
-fish tacos?
-Correct.
[Guy] We've got
the charred jalapenos,
chopped cucumber.
[Mac] Shallot
and chopped cilantro.
And a little touch
of some salt
and that's all she wrote.
Hunter's warming up
the beans.
Over to the crab cakes.
Put down a little bit
of panko.
He's gloving up.
[Guy] What size, Mac?
Little smaller than
a baseball?
Yeah, that looks good
right there.
[Guy] Hunter's gonna get
into battering that fish now.
Anything special
on the tortillas, Mac?
Just warm them up.
[Hunter] I could definitely
use a beer right about now.
-[Mac] Yeah, me too.
-[Gary] Me three.
-[Jazz] Me four.
-[Mike] All in.
[Guy] Mac, tell me how we're
plating this crab cake.
[Mac] We have
a mustard crema
-smeared across the plate.
-Smear.
[Mac] Crab cakes are
gonna go on that,
mixed greens on the side
with the vinaigrette.
[Guy] Radishes, fennel,
some crunchy papitas.
Boy, I like where this
little salad just went, dude.
I hit a little
lemon zest on top.
Take a look at that.
Mac, you approve?
Absolutely.
[Guy] I put these things
together
about as delicate
as you can imagine.
Ryder, get in here
for this shot.
When I push this
with my fork, watch.
It falls apart.
It's all crab
and just enough ingredients
-to hold it together.
-Yup.
-[Guy] Delicious, bro.
-[Hunter] Amazing.
Just enough acid on there
to balance it out.
-I mean, amazing.
-Here's the thing, Mac.
I'm super serious
about this.
-You can taste the crab.
-That's the Dungeness.
You can taste the sea.
Outstanding.
All right, Hunter,
let's do these tacos.
Two tortillas
[Mac] A little bit
of black beans,
piece of fish on top.
Put a good amount of
the miso aioli on there.
Do the jalapeno,
cucumber salsa, avocado.
Gorgeous.
[Mac] People come back
for this dish all the time.
That fish is
so airy and soft.
-Overwhelms you.
-You're not going
to regular
fish taco land.
You take a hard left.
-Yeah.
-Okay? And you end up
right off the coast
of Mexico
on your way to Hawaii
because of the miso factor.
Fantastic job,
my friend.
-Well done.
-[Mac] Right on.
This is just two
out of four.
Up next, our buddy,
out of Des Moines, Iowa,
Flying Mango,
don't go anywhere.
We are in for it.
[rock music playing]
Welcome back.
DDD Takeout.
It should be called
DDD tap out.
[bell rings]
I mean, you just wanna
sit in a chair.
[Guy] We had our buddy
from Super Duper Weenie
bring us
a Cincinnati dog.
Then we go to my buddy Mac
with fish tacos,
and then crab cakes.
Up next, our buddy Mike
from Flying Mango,
Des Moines, Iowa.
Is it the dad
from Family Ties?
-[woman] Yes.
-[man] Yeah.
[Guy] That's exactly
who it is.
We did ribs, we did catfish.
About as real-deal
as they come, son.
-Thank you.
-Well played.
What's on the menu
today?
[Mike] We're doing
shrimp Pontchartrain.
[Guy] Tell me the inspiration
behind the dish.
[Mike] Me spending
a lot of time in the South
as a very young dude
from the Midwest.
[Guy] You named the dish
after the Lake in Louisiana.
-[Mike] Yes.
-[Guy] And you were saying
earlier, our buddy,
Eric Lindell,
he's played at your place.
Yeah. Uh, actually Eric's
a friend of mine.
[Guy] Hang on a second.
Let's see if we can get
my buddy Lindell
on here.
Eric, say hi to everybody.
-[Eric] Yeah, baby.
-We're doing a show
Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives Takeout.
And I've got two
of our buddies
that are buddies of yours.
I got Mac from Pier 23
and I got Mike
from Flying Mango.
We're all having
a big Eric Lindell
appreciation moment,
so we had to call you.
[Eric] I love y'all, man.
Be safe out there.
Don't let them get you.
All right.
Talk to you soon, bro.
That was great.
Let's get into
this dish, chef.
[Mike] Get a little
skillet going.
Let's sweat some onion
and garlic in the butter.
When collard greens
are good cold,
you know they're good.
Y'all know that's not
part of the recipe.
That's just because
I know you like them.
Oh, no, no, no.
-Listen...
-He just wants to snack.
-I just snack it.
-Well, you're probably hungry
after just three hotdogs,
four tacos,
and two crab cakes.
No, no, no. Not when it comes
to collard greens.
[Mike] Collards are one
of the things we did
when you were here
in '14.
I'd eat those greens
till my head falls off.
Oh, this was
a nice little gift.
Okay.
Onions have sweated out.
[Mike] Deglaze that
with a little chardonnay.
Throw those lemon halves
in there.
-[Guy] Cayenne...
-Thyme.
-[Guy] Little paprika?
-[Mike] Yeah.
[Hunter] A lot of paprika.
-[Guy] Chicken stock now?
-[Mike] Yup.
Add the cream and bring it
back to a boil.
Reduce the heat and simmer
that for about 10 minutes,
remove the lemons,
and then season
with the salt and pepper.
There's a good amount
of cayenne, by the way.
Yeah. I want you
to remember it.
Thicken it with
a little cornstarch
and add the crawfish tails.
[Guy] Now, I got shrimp here,
we're not gonna cook these
ahead of time.
We're gonna drop
these in the sauce
-to finish, correct?
-[Mike] Yup. That's correct.
[Guy] It's gonna like almost
poach the shrimp
and it's gonna
make it super tender.
Now, how are we
serving this up?
Are we a bowl,
are we a plate,
are we a trough?
I'd go with
a bowl-shaped trough.
[Guy] You wanna rice this up?
[Hunter] Yes.
Those greens are
so tender.
Hmm, look at those
beautiful shrimp
and all those tails.
I'm around that stuff
all day.
And that looks good to me.
[Guy] Ha ha.
The right amount
of heat, man.
That little cayenne kiss
you gave.
[Hunter] Little kick.
Love the thyme.
The crawfish,
there's that
traditional Louisiana
crawfish flavor
that you're getting
from it.
And then the shrimp
are mega tender.
And there's a whole contrast
of textures and flavors
in here.
[Guy] It's a delicious dish.
You keep crushing it, bro.
-Well done.
-[Mike] Thank you, man.
[Guy] Dynamite.
At this point in time,
we should say good night,
but we can't.
-[Hunter] Ugh, dude.
-[Guy] Because she
is standing by.
She is the queen
of Thai food.
She runs the show in LA.
She runs the show
on Guy's Grocery Games.
We're talking about
my sister Jazz.
And this is Jitlada.
-What is this?
-This is galangal,
it's one of the famous herbs
-when people get cold...
-[Guy] Yeah?
...like Ryan Gosling,
when he gets sick...
-Ryan Gosling is her boy.
-I can't believe it's taken...
[man] He eats here.
Do like Ryan more than Guy?
[laughter]
Um, so exciting to see you.
And I'm not even
Ryan Gosling.
[laughs]
[Guy] Sirine, how long have
you been working
-with your mom?
-[Sirine] Um, my whole life.
But, like,
just on the side.
She's my side gig.
All right, Jazz,
what are we making?
[Jazz] Beef Salad.
[Guy] Beef salad and...
[Jazz] Spicy Basil Chicken.
That is the bomb.
Jazz is now officially
your L.A. Mom.
A hundred percent of
the proceeds of that T-shirt
goes to three
different charities.
I think it's awesome, Jazz.
Let's start with the salad.
Okay.
Slice the beef.
[Guy] Slice the beef.
Okay. Thin slice.
[Jazz] You have to marinate
the beef with fish sauce.
-[Guy] Fish sauce?
-[Jazz] And the oyster sauce.
Use half of that.
Half of the oyster sauce.
[Jazz] One tablespoon
of soy sauce.
One tablespoon of sugar.
-Uh-oh, Guy.
-No. Don't say, "Oh, Guy."
[Jazz laughs]
Pepper.
[Guy] How long is
this gonna marinate, Jazz?
[Jazz] Like couple
of minutes.
I'm gonna put it
on the grill.
When the meat comes off,
it's gonna go in this bowl.
What goes in this bowl?
[Jazz] White onion,
chopped chili.
[Guy] All of this?
Two tablespoon.
[Sirine] One tablespoon
of shrimp paste.
-How much sugar?
-[Jazz] Just only, um...
-[Sirine] One tablespoon?
-[Jazz] No, teaspoon.
And then how much
fish sauce?
[Jazz] One tablespoon.
[Sirine] One tablespoon
of fish sauce.
-One and a half limes.
-[Guy] Got it.
Meat goes in the bowl,
correct?
-[Jazz] Yes, sir.
-[Sirine] Yes.
-And then cut the tomatoes.
-[Guy] Cucumber?
[Jazz] Very thin like pico.
[Sirine] Throw it in
with the meat.
Squeeze the meat
and the sauce together,
as well as the, uh,
vegetables.
[Guy] Beautiful salad.
And how do you want
the lettuce cut?
Cut like square.
[Sirine] And it's basically
the bed of the meat.
Okay.
Now, scallions?
[Jazz] Yeah.
On top and cilantro.
That was easy.
[Guy] Look at that, huh?
Watch out 'cause there's
a tremendous amount
of the Thai chili.
Which Miss Funny-Funny
thought
-it would be awesome.
-[Hunter] Oh, boy.
-Oops.
-[Gary] So hungry right now.
This is cruel punishment.
Whoo!
That's spicy, Jazz.
It's not bad.
It's a good amount of kick.
-It's healthy.
-No. This is...
This is my kind of Thai,
to have the cooked
and the raw together.
Fresh veggies, skirt steak,
quick sear on the...
on the hot grill,
with the raw dressing.
It's delicious.
I mean, like...
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Well, I got to tell you
something.
Everybody, you did
a fantastic job.
-Wait, what are you doing?
-Well, I'm saying goodbye.
-I'm gonna tell everybody
this has been wonderful.
-We have more time.
-We don't have more time.
-We do.
All right. Well, stick around
for one more dish.
DDD Takeout.
-We'll see you in a bit.
-Can you do one more?
For Jazz, I can do one more,
but I'll have this.
Uh, you go to commercial.
[upbeat music playing]
[Guy] Welcome back.
We are in the final moments
of Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives Takeout.
And Hunter and I,
well, we've had
Cincinnati chili hotdogs,
dynamite fish tacos.
We went straight to Louisiana
through Des Moines, Iowa,
and got ourselves
some Pontchartrain over rice.
And then we've ended up
in LA at Jitlada.
We're hanging out with
the one and only Chef Jazz
and her daughter, Sirine,
and the salad was awesome.
All right, Jazz,
what's our final dish?
[Jazz] The spicy
basil chicken.
So I got the chicken
right here.
[Jazz] I need you to have
chili and garlic.
[Guy] I found the garlic.
And how many serranos?
Make it three.
Jazz, were gringos
from Northern California.
You can handle the heat.
-I'm terrified.
-[Guy] Okay, here we go.
-What else?
-The Thai chili
I chopped
for you already.
[Guy] Thai chilies are
going in too?
Jazz, I don't think
you're being nice.
-[Hunter laughs]
-You know me.
-[Guy] Oh, dude, that's hot.
-Oh, my God.
It just ate the enamel
off my teeth.
What else are
we gonna add to that?
[Jazz] The ground chicken.
[Guy] Ground chicken goes in.
Whoa.
Don't scream.
What did you say,
quit crying?
She said don't scream.
Yeah, I don't see
a lot of dishes
that call for three
full serranos,
seeds, and ribs.
I'm over here
scrubbing my hands
to get it all off.
I'll be right back.
[Sirine] Don't touch
your face.
All right. What sauces
are we gonna add to this?
[Jazz] Oyster sauce,
half of that.
[Hunter] Okay. So you said
half the oyster sauce.
I'm back.
I'm ready for surgery.
How much fish sauce?
One tablespoon of
fish sauce.
[Guy] Oh, one tablespoon,
Jazz.
Tablespoon of
light soy sauce.
-[Guy] Okay.
-[Jazz] One full...
tablespoon of sugar.
Now, you guys know
how to cook Thai food.
One tablespoon
of everything.
[laughter]
[Jazz] Then bell pepper.
-Black pepper.
-[Guy] How much?
-One tablespoon.
-[Hunter] One tablespoon.
-[Mike] Why do you ask?
-[Sirine] Did you have to ask?
The last thing is the basil.
-[Guy] You grow this basil?
-[Jazz] Yes, sir.
-[Guy] The Sri Lanka
lime leaves.
-[Jazz] Oh, yes.
Smell it.
They're from my garden.
I love it. It's very...
It's very nice.
[Jazz] That's it.
I got to tell you,
it smells delicious.
It looks fantastic.
You might not have a chance
to make it to these places,
but you do have a chance
to bring these flavors
to your house.
-Look at these colors.
-That looks delicious.
[Guy] And hitting
the basil into that.
One tablespoon,
how it taste?
Did you just say
one tablespoon,
how does it taste?
Oh, Hunter, Hunter,
I don't know
if it hit you yet.
It's coming.
[Jazz] Yummy.
Delicious.
Yeah, yummy delicious.
It really is delicious.
This is like a freight train
coming into flavor town
with no brakes.
Going right by the terminal.
-My tongue...
-[Guy] Uh-huh.
...immediately lost feeling.
I've... Yeah.
[Sirine] Good thing
you guys had that last.
Can you guys just look
at that beautiful,
like, meatball of chicken
with the basil
grown in her garden?
Can you guys just see that?
-[Mac] Yum.
-[Gary] Yeah. Thanks.
-[laughter]
-Thanks.
[Hunter] It really is
absolutely dynamite.
And I mean that in two ways.
[Guy] The chicken is
awesome for this,
it's light, but there's
tons of flavor.
-[Hunter] Tons.
-[Guy] Outstanding.
Like blow the doors off it
outstanding.
Everybody, today,
thank you so much.
-[Hunter] You guys killed it.
-Here's the difficult part.
Someone's gonna win
no cash or prizes,
but is gonna get
the best delivery of the day.
So just hold tight.
Hunter and I are gonna have
a little talk.
Jazz, you guys are great.
[Jazz] Thank you so much.
You have to come by.
We are family.
-[Hunter] Okay.
-Well, folks,
this is difficult,
but all I'm gonna
tell you right now,
it's gonna go
to winner winner
DDD Takeout Dinner
Jitlada.
Congratulations, Jazz.
-You win.
-[Sirine] Yay.
[Jazz] Thank you, Guy.
[Guy] Everybody, fantastic.
And everyone at home,
you got to check
these joints out.
You know where to find them.
You go to foodnetwork.com.
You can get all the info.
We'll see you guys next week
in the backyard.
[Hunter] I'm going to take
a nap.
Bye-bye.
I'm gonna eat
the rest of this.
You said add more serrano?
Yes, sir.
-No, you didn't.
-[Hunter] What?
What do you... What...
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
-[laughter]
-[Hunter] This is terrifying.
-[Guy] It is terrifying.
-[Hunter] I'm so scared.
[laughter]