You know, people are
asking me all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint
you checked out
in that one city
when you were doing Triple-D,
how are they doin'?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out
it was only the beginning
'cause Triple-D joints
have been blowing up
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip.
We're taking a walk
back in time
and just down the street.
The stuff
that you're looking for,
it might be
right in your backyard.
Like at this hot spot
close to my hood.
Specials off the hook.
I'm not trying
to take your line.
Serving up Italian dishes...
Eggplant parmesan!
...close to my heart.
I have a weakness
for chicken marsala.
It's delicious.
And a dive in Minneapolis...
Great dog. Nice snap.
...getting inspiration
from their neighbor.
Now, do you
make that yourself
-or does that come--
-No. From Chicago.
Plus,
this classic Philly diner...
[man] We don't make crepes.
We make crepes
in Philadelphia.
...that's still
a neighborhood institution.
Why did they name
the street after you?
I like the way you think.
Familiar faces, new places
and more off-the-hook flavors.
This is Triple-D Nation!
You just gotta
love San Fran.
I mean, all the great
restaurants that are owned
by real characters.
Like this place, Rocco's.
Now, it's owned
by a dude named Don Dial.
Everybody calls him Double-D.
So, I thought
it would just be perfect
that he should be
on Triple-D.
And back in 2009,
I don't think
either of us thought
it would lead
to a double feature,
but here we are again.
This is Rocco's Cafe.
[man]
I saw Rocco's on Triple-D,
and we've been coming here
ever since.
It's almost like
watching a show
with the fire going up
and the food going.
Ruby! Eggplant parmesan.
Pick up.
Seeing Don on Triple-D,
I mean,
that was pretty special.
because he's really good
to his customers
and cooks great food
for everybody.
[woman] It's like family.
It gives you that feel,
like you're at home,
like Grandma's
home-cooked food.
[Guy]
Except for owner Don Dial.
It was Grandpa's!
Because his grandfather,
Rocco, owned an Italian joint
for 30 years.
Are these some of his recipes?
Use some of his recipes.
And a name like Rocco's,
why call it Don?
Call it Rocco's.
[Guy]
What do your buddies call you?
Double-D.
-Do they call you Double-D?
-Yeah.
That's a great name.
Great to have you.
How many years has it been
since we shot Triple-D?
Uh, 11 years ago.
I think right after
we shot there,
I was telling
my mom and dad, Jim and Pene,
I said, "I went to this place
in San Francisco
and this chef
cooks on a line
right in front of you,
and he made the best
linguine and clams."
And my mom says, she goes,
"Well, I love
linguine and clams.
I think we'll go tomorrow."
All right, Don Juan, Double-D.
Okay, so now we're clams?
[Don] Clams and linguini
in a white sauce.
Give me the tour, brother.
-[Don] Big garlic.
-[Guy whistles]
-[Don] Baby whole clams.
-All of 'em?
All of 'em.
[Guy]
Is this a platter for nine?
Fresh clams.
So, the baby wholes
with the juice
is the big flavor.
-These are kinda like
for show.
-Right.
Then we add some white wine.
Half and half.
Then we add
some butter, okay?
[Guy]
It's better with butter.
Pepper, basil.
We let this bad boy reduce.
[Guy] The great technique
on the clam
before it's been cooked,
we tap it on the shell.
It should close up
a little bit
-'cause it's still alive.
-Right. That's true.
[Guy] But then, when you do
cook the clams,
if the clam shell
doesn't open up,
well, then you probably
shouldn't eat that one.
-And they're popping open
as you see.
-[Guy] They are.
They look-- Wow. It's like,
"Take a look at me."
They're on cue.
Clams go around the plate.
Our sauce right on top.
Parmesan cheese,
little parsley on it.
Mmm.
Look at the ratio
of clams to pasta.
Shovel that in my pocket.
-[Don] There you go.
-Huh?
I could do that.
I will, for sure,
steal that recipe.
You can have it.
And that was the beginning
of the Triple-D,
Double-D, Rocco affair.
And how have
things been since?
Everything's been great since.
You know, it's just been
taking off and it's been fun.
I change the menu
and specials all the time.
So, I keep people,
you know, interested.
Did you bring me
something delicious to eat?
[Don] Chicken marsala.
I have a weakness
for chicken marsala.
I'll be very honest with you.
Any thyme?
I'm a big thyme guy.
No, there is no thyme
in there actually.
I don't put thyme in it.
-Really?
-Nope. I don't have time.
[clock ticking]
[timer dings]
See, here's the thing,
my secret.
Here's my opinion
of chicken marsala.
Okay, we're not
gonna tell anybody.
We're gonna keep this
between us. Right.
I don't flour it.
I put Italian bread crumbs.
-Really?
-Yes.
I'm not getting
a graininess
that you would get
from a bread crumb.
[Don] What you want
is to cook that chicken
in the bread crumbs
and the olive oil,
but you just want
lightly brown.
Then we add our garlic,
fresh mushroom,
fresh chopped tomato,
fresh basil,
a pinch of black pepper,
our Marsala wine.
Pull the chicken breast
and put it on top.
We can reduce it
without burning our chicken.
We add our little
half and half,
and it blends so good
with the Marsala wine.
I make chicken marsala
all the time with thyme.
But I don't use any
half and half.
I mount it with butter
when I'm done.
-There's no butter in there--
-No butter.
No butter,
but the half and half,
it's just to bring
the richness together.
What it does, it makes it
nice and silky.
[Don] Then we add
our homemade chicken broth.
Just a touch of marinara.
And we let
this bad boy reduce.
And it just makes
a really nice marsala sauce.
It's delicious.
-Are you sure?
-No, I'm not kidding you.
It's delicious.
[man] It's just thin slices
of this moist, tender chicken.
You can really taste
the sweetness
from the Marsala sauce.
I love the mushrooms
and the bite
from the tomatoes.
It just all melds together
in this wonderful bite.
[woman] It has a beautiful
sherry taste,
which I really enjoy.
That's one of my favorites.
And the mushrooms
and the sauce.
You just can't beat it.
Now, we are a big
chicken marsala family.
I don't want
my kids to see it.
I don't want them
coming out comparing.
But coming up,
it's not my kids
that are crashing the party.
If I'm gonna have Double-D
from Rocco's,
I should have Rocco's
from Triple-D.
And the dishes
just keep coming.
Double-D's,
a lot of Piccata.
It's delicious.
[Guy] Back in 2009,
I met the Double-D,
Don Dial,
who has an Italian joint
not far from where I live.
This is the funny thing
about it for me.
You know, living here
in the wine country,
I don't make it to
San Francisco as often as
people would expect,
and going down
to your place--
And again, this was at
the beginning of Triple-D.
And we come in
and we meet you.
And I thought, man,
I've been coming down
to this city for so long,
I've driven by here
a million times,
and this is what's
going on.
And that was the example
we've always said
to people about Triple-D
is the stuff that
you're looking for,
you don't have to go
all over the country for it.
-No.
-It might be
right in your backyard.
Well, that's what
we're hoping for. Exactly.
-[Guy] Are you always here?
-[Don] I'm always here.
-[Guy] Really?
-Yeah.
-So when I come back in...
-Yes.
-...you're gonna be here?
-[Don] Right.
[Guy] Good.
Are you still
doing it?
-Oh, yeah. I'm still doing it.
-All the time?
I'm on the line.
Yep, I'm on the line
still busting it.
You look lean
and mean, dude.
-I don't think so.
-You look like you've
been staying in training.
I think you got
a trick camera.
Is that what it is?
[distorted]
A trick camera? If we do,
can we use it on me?
All right, so give me
the update on Rocco's
since we were there
11 years ago.
[Don] We have remodeled
the whole restaurant.
[Guy] Really?
[Don] It's just been
an amazing ride.
But this is the thing
that I love about it
is that it's
a neighborhood joint.
Still, traditionally,
is it Italian base, still?
[Don] The whole thing
is old school,
Italian-American food.
And then specials
off the hook.
I'm not trying
to take your line.
You just did
take my line.
[man]
I've had everything here
'cause I've been
coming here for so long.
Everything is delicious.
[woman] I like
the grilled polenta
topped with
a garlicky marinara.
That's killer.
Is the rest of the food
gonna be like this?
You're gonna eat today.
[woman] I love
the Chicken Piccata.
It has lemon and tanginess.
One of my favorites.
Mmm. I could have
a Piccata sandwich,
Piccata salad.
-[Don laughs]
-Piccata on a stick.
Double-D's,
a lot of Piccata.
-That's awesome.
That's awesome.
-That's marketing, baby.
All right,
what else you got for me?
[Don] Eggplant Parmesan.
[Guy] Okay,
walk me through it.
[Don] Well, you have
a fresh eggplant.
That's the number one thing.
Cut like
a half inch thick.
We trim the skin off.
So now we take
our sliced eggplant
and put 'em in
our egg wash.
Bread crumb, flour?
No flour,
no bread crumb.
-An egg.
-Just an egg.
Eggplant.
Let me ask Rocco DiSpirito.
-Rocco. Where is he?
-He knows.
Rocco, I want
to introduce you--
I figure if I'm gonna have
Double-D from Rocco's,
I should have Rocco's
from Triple-D.
Eggplant Parmesan.
-No flour?
-Flour, eggs, bread crumbs.
Have you ever heard it
with just egg?
Just egg? Sure.
Yeah, that's a different
style of breading, yup.
[Don] This is the style
my family cooks
where they're from.
We lightly brown it.
We add fresh garlic,
fresh chopped basil.
Pour the wine
over the garlic.
Now we add our
marinara sauce
and we turn 'em over
and add our fresh-sliced
provolone cheese,
grated Parmesan
and fresh parsley.
We let it simmer.
We will cover it.
Little fresh Parmesan
right on top.
So get a little
bite here, Rocco.
-Want me to taste?
-Yes.
It's delicious.
-It's fantastic, right?
-It's fantastic.
[Guy] You know
what it is for me?
Really good ingredients
and dynamite
tomato sauce.
You could still taste
the eggplant,
-which is really nice.
-Yeah.
[woman] The eggplant
is thickly sliced,
super fresh,
drenched in marinara sauce,
and it's super garlicky
and just full of flavor.
It's perfect.
This is like
the perfect balance
of just like
firm and tender
and just kind of breaks
when you put
your fork into it.
Just really homey.
Delicious. You keep doing
what you're doing.
You can feel the--
your passion.
-My passion's there, man.
-Your love, your care.
Now stop using
my name, okay? Thanks.
[all laughing]
[Guy] Coming up...
That is a Chicago dog.
[Guy] ...a hot dog stand
in Minneapolis.
Didn't give much heat.
Mmm, there's a little heat.
Ooh.
Still feeding the masses.
You definitely are
a culinary gangster.
I'm a hot dog hustler.
I like that.
I'm close to the corner
of Cedar and Riverside
near downtown Minneapolis.
Now, this joint,
it's not a diner.
It's not a drive-in.
There's no argument.
This one's a dive,
the Wienery, run by a dude
that's making hot dogs
and hamburgers
his own unique way.
I'm here every day.
[Guy] It was 2008
when I first met him.
Ta-da!
And, yeah, he's still there.
This is the Wienery.
Got a West Bank burger
and a Chicago Dog.
The Wienery has just
got a great menu there.
Dogs, burgers...
It's a pretty chill spot.
Good energy, good people.
Every time I come here,
I see smiles.
I first came here
when Triple-D first came,
been coming here ever since.
Cool spot
and friendly guys here.
Yeah!
I enjoy coming here
and talking to 'em.
[Guy]
And the feeling's mutual.
In fact, owner Pat Starr
loves his customers so much,
he's keeping tabs on 'em.
How many people
do you run tabs for?
Well, I just say
financing's available.
The deer,
that was a food trade.
Think it was a breakfast.
The marlin,
two Philly cheesesteaks.
So, pawnshop-slash-Wienery.
Let's make a deal.
It's a community,
and there's characters,
and they all have
different levels of income
and abilities to pay.
I've bought many cars
with hot dogs
and food credits.
[laughs]
How much is that?
Uh, let's see.
You got money.
Probably three bucks.
[both laugh]
What if I'm light
on change today?
You have to tell me
before you order.
We'll go easy on the cheese.
[laughs]
I have a Chicago
hot dog joint,
and Guy of course
had one of my
Chicago hot dogs.
Let's do a Chicago Dog.
All right,
we got the dogs hot.
Don't want them
sitting and boiling away.
That's a no-no.
I'm gonna get
your ingredients together.
And you cut
everything to order?
I'm game on everything.
Get that hot dog
in a steamed bun,
tomato wedge.
Onions go next.
Some of that special
unique green relish.
[Guy] Now,
what's that all about?
That's a Chicago product.
It's got to be that way
if you want a Chicago Dog.
Couple of sport peppers,
-celery salt, mustard,
that is a Chicago Dog.
-[Fieri] Mmm.
Great dog. Nice snap.
The veggies are fresh.
They're good!
-[Fieri] Where are you from?
-[man] Chicago.
-How did this stack up
in the world of Chicago Dogs?
-Very good.
I have, of course, my Vienna
beef dogs, my Chicago-style
poppy seed buns...
but one of the great things
from Chicago food
is their giardiniera.
So, we have a hot dog
that's made...
just to kind of showcase
the giardiniera flavor.
[Starr] Mr. Sunshine up!
I ordered up the Mr. Sunshine
dog -- giardiniera and cheese.
Simple.
That's what I love.
A Vienna Beef Dog is just
boiled, and it's delicious
that way.
For the poppy seed buns,
you want to steam them.
We have a steamer
right here on the grill.
Let that sit for a little bit.
One of the keys
to the Sunshine is getting
the cheese on right away.
So, you use the heat
from the hot dog
to melt the cheese.
If you like spicy giardiniera,
this hot dog's for you.
Shredded up vegetables
in oil base.
-[Fieri] Now, do you make
that yourself or does that--
-No. From Chicago.
[Fieri] From Chicago.
[man] I got a Mr. Sunshine.
It's a good quality dog,
does have a nice snap,
and the peppers had
a good spice to them,
and all the flavors
went together well.
It's just nice and simple,
tastes good and fresh.
You feeling dogs,
they got dogs.
Feeling burgers,
they got burgers.
-Let's do the Selamu.
-[Starr] Yeah. All right!
We put a little bit
of garlic, a little bit
of habaneros.
[Fieri] And again,
we're gonna cut everything
to order?
[Starr] Absolutely,
and all burgers are
hand-formed.
Get it all mixed in there.
Angus beef, about
a third of a pound, usually.
Nice and flat.
I like it flat, get nice
and done in the middle.
-[Fieri] Ah!
-[Starr] Now, do you want
cheese on here?
-[Fieri] Oh, yes, please!
-[Starr] All right. Think you
want lettuce and tomato?
-Let's do lettuce and tomato.
-Yeah.
Voila! Le burger.
Got the garlic.
Didn't get much heat.
Mmm, there's a little heat.
Ooh.
Sure you didn't get
the Scotch Bonnets?
Good burger!
[woman] The Selamu
Burger's great.
It's got a lot of heat to it,
but now they're serving it
with coleslaw,
and it's called
the West Bank Burger.
It's got the garlic
and the hot peppers, same as
a Selamu burger.
We got the meat done,
and now we're ready
for our homemade slaw.
The key to the coleslaw
is the texture...
real fine, really makes
a difference.
Put this in a bowl with some
onions, a little celery salt,
black pepper.
One of my big secrets!
Shake it. [laughs]
And our last ingredient...
mayonnaise.
Our burger's ready!
Here's our West Bank Burger.
I got a West Bank Burger up!
I love the onions
and the spiciness of it,
and the coleslaw really cools
off everything.
Coleslaw at The Wienery
is like your mom's coleslaw,
except even better.
[man] One thing I love about
The Wienery is that...
you're driving
down the street, you see
this beautiful walk-up window,
it's like, "Ooh! What's going
on there?"
You know what I'm doing?
I'm hooking up all my friends
with delicious meals
every day, and I keep it cheap
'cause they're all broke.
-[Fieri] You definitely are
a culinary gangster.
-I'm a hot dog hustler.
You're a hot dog hustler.
I like that.
[narrator] And coming up...
So bad for you,
but tastes so, so good.
[narrator] ...a diner
still serving classic
Philly food...
Mmm, that's delicious!
[narrator] ...breakfast,
lunch, and dinner!
If a customer wants
to eat day or night,
he knows he can come
to The Dining Car.
In the world of 24/7,
when the sun's coming up,
it means the end
of a late night,
or the beginning
of an early morning,
and either way,
you're gonna need some grub.
The folks here at The Dining
Car in Philadelphia,
well, they've got you covered.
And since I was here in 2007,
not much has changed.
It's still run by
the same family with
the same chef behind the line.
And it's still
the talk of the town.
This is The Dining Car.
[woman]
Tennessee brisket sandwich?
It was really amazing to see
The Dining Car on Triple-D.
-[Fieri] Five days a week?
-[man] Five days.
[woman 2] It's nice to see
them getting that reward
for all the hard work
that they do.
[man] It's home-style cooking.
You can taste the love
in this food.
Apple walnut going up!
[man 2] They run this as
a family business,
and I feel like part
of that family as a customer.
[Fieri] Everybody
wants to be a member
of the Morrison family...
Hi! How are you today?
...who started their Diner
dynasty when Joe opened
the doors in '61.
Why 24 hours?
My philosophy is that
if a customer wants to eat
day or night,
he knows he can come
to The Dining Car.
Here you are, ladies.
My dad and Guy hit it off.
It was nice for him
in his 90s
to have someone else
be excited about
what he built.
You're doing
traditional diner fare...
-handmade.
-[Joe] That's correct.
Okay, guys,
table two going out.
-Nice to meet you.
-Okay.
[Guy] Sadly,
Joe passed away in 2018,
but not much else
has changed,
-because his daughter Nancy...
-How you doing?
-How you doing today?
-Great.
...and chef Larry Thum...
Two brisket sandwiches
going up.
...are still keeping
the lights on day and night.
Now, how long
have you been here?
Thirty-two years.
What, you start
when you were ten?
-Yeah, something like that.
-[Guy] I like it.
We wanted to
showcase the fact that
we're more than
just a diner.
This is one of the first menus
that we've ever come across
that we've seen crepes.
[French accent] Or crepes.
-How do you say it?
-[French accent] Crepes.
We don't make crepes.
We make crepes
in Philadelphia. [laughs]
Let's get our crepe on.
-So six eggs
and six extra yolks.
-Right.
-Some milk.
-Three cups of flour.
[Larry] Exactly.
-Clarified butter.
I'd rather have a little
extra butter in 'em.
And you're gonna put in two
ladles full of crepe batter.
With that mush butter,
I'm a little gnarly
about flipping.
I mean, I didn't bring
the fire protection suit.
We do wear... We do wear
some of our crepes sometimes.
Bring it up and over.
-That's how it goes.
-Yeah.
-No.
-Okay.
He, actually didn't
want to get his sandals...
-Ready?
-Looking good.
Wonderful. Oh, that's
a nice-looking omelet there.
Yeah. [laughs]
This is crazy crepe.
It's crazy crepe!
Now what? Sliced ham.
Natural cure cheddar cheese.
Fresh-cooked spinach.
And then you're gonna
roll 'em up.
This is how I
roll sushi, too.
This is called Supreme Sauce.
That's correct.
A little bit of mushrooms.
That's all.
Mmm.
We tried to take crepes
and make comfort food
out of them.
Welcome to comfort crepe.
That's delicious.
[woman] Crepes Florentine.
I haven't tasted anything
that good since I was
in Paris having crepes.
You know, I've had pretty much
everything that Chef Larry
can put out here.
You can get just about
anything you really want.
Anything breakfast you want.
[Larry]
I need one side of pancakes.
Apple walnut going up.
This is the Apple Walnut
French toast,
and it's dynamite.
Apple Walnut French toast
is one of our signature items.
We make it with our
very own Apple bread that
we bake here from scratch.
We're going to cut
our homemade Apple bread,
then we're going to dip it
in French toast batter.
Now they're ready to
go on the griddle.
We have to cut a hole
in each one.
This is
the cream cheese stuffing.
Cream cheese, walnuts, sugar.
It's gonna go in the middle
of the French toast.
[sizzling]
French toast is done.
Now we're gonna top it
with cinnamon sugar
and then powdered sugar.
We're gonna finish it
with some maple syrup.
This is our Apple Walnut
French toast.
Apple Walnut
stuffed French toast.
The walnut cream cheese
filling, it has almost
a buttery type flavor to it.
And it goes really well
with cinnamon and sugar.
So it just reminds me of home.
-It's like a second home,
isn't it?
-That's exactly right.
It was a lot of fun
to be able to show Guy
the things that, you know,
you can get here,
in Philly you can't get
anywhere else.
-What's that?
-That is Scrapple.
What is the main
basis of it?
Well...
I don't like when
anybody starts with
"Well..."
It's all different parts of
the pig, and he thought
that was kind of crazy.
Do you eat it?
-I love it.
-Yeah.
So bad for you, but tastes
so, so good.
Chipped beef.
My dad talked about it
when I was a kid
About having it
in the military,
having it in Navy.
It's gotten a bad rap,
but not when it's made right.
Not when it's made here.
[Larry] Chicken Croquettes.
[chuckles]
Bro, that is rich and big.
Since Guy, Chicken Croquettes,
it is our number one
selling dish.
The Chicken Croquettes
are one of my favorites.
They have all your
regular Philly favorites.
[man] Cheesesteak going down.
They also do
your usual diner fare.
You don't get better
than the Car.
Honestly.
If you want down-home,
home cooking,
you come to the Car.
You proud of your daughters
and you son?
-Oh...
-You happy how they're doing?
-They're doing
a good job?
-They're great.
[Nancy] My dad always said
he was proud of us.
You know,
he had a little diner,
and we grew it
into the Dining Car.
We also have
the Apple Walnut Cafe.
You know,
we couldn't be more thrilled.
Why did they name
the street after you then?
I like the way you think.
Pick up,
Linguini Prawns gamberoni.
[Guy] These guys put
so much of themselves
into their joints.
I'm just glad that the nation
is taking notice.
This place is off the hook.
Zachtacular Mexican style.
[Guy] But those
aren't the only ones.
We'll check in on more
diners, drive-ins and dives
next time on Triple D Nation.
-[man] Yeah!
-[cheering]
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
[laughing]
You know where they're
going in that, don't you?
They're going to Flavortown.