You know, people
are asking me all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint you
checked out in that one city
when you were doing Triple D,
how are they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
[engine revving]
[Guy] Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning
because Triple D joints
have been blowing up
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip.
It's an international
flavor fest.
From Africa.
I wanna get a slip and slide
in flavor town
-and run Charmoula through it.
-[laughs]
-[Guy] To Italy.
-[man] Order up.
[Guy] And everywhere
in between.
I call that
the "bibimbap blessing."
[Guy] In San Francisco,
a Triple G
and Triple D Superstar...
-Chef, nice to have you back.
-Yeah. Yeah.
[Guy] Is now a Triple Threat.
You wanna make another?
-Make a hundred of them.
-[laughs]
I'll sleep here.
A Duluth diner
serving fresh ingredients.
I mean, this is meat
and potato country.
Right from their planters
to your plate.
You sure have a knack
for pulling it off
and making it tasty.
And an Italian spot
in Minneapolis.
This, ladies and gentlemen,
is a hot rod I don't own yet.
Still cranking out,
scratch made pasta
and porchetta.
No more laughing, no more fun.
The pasta coma has begun.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more
off the hook flavors,
this is Triple D Nation.
So I'm here on the southeast
side of San Francisco
in an area known
as the Bayview District
just like I was in 2016
when I went to check out
a chef
who had already proven
himself on Triple G twice.
-Chef, nice to have you back.
-Yeah. Yeah.
[Guy] And he's still creating
his signature
Ethiopian dishes
with a twist.
This is Radio Africa
& Kitchen.
Grilled Flank Steak.
Radio Africa is one
of my favorite place
in the whole city.
Good fresh fusion
African foods.
Vegetable [indistinct]
on the window.
It's an international
experience.
It feels like each dish
tells a story.
[Guy] And what a story it is.
29 years ago,
we walked out of Ethiopia.
You literally walked?
Walked out of it,
that's right.
Three weeks to Sudan and then,
the United States.
-How old were you?
-19.
[Guy] And fortunately for us,
Eskender Aseged
brought his cookbook with him.
Eskender definitely brings
his Ethiopian roots
to the table.
He really is a local superstar
as well as I think
kind of an international star.
[indistinct chatter]
-Nice to see you, buddy.
-Nice to see you, too.
So Radio Africa & Kitchen
in San Francisco,
-how long ago we shoot that?
-2000...
-2016.
-One of our first
Triple G competitors
from Guy's Grocery Games,
then became a member
of the Triple D family.
Now, that you're a big
TV star.
And now, you're here
on Triple D Nation.
That's history.
Maybe not big,
but it's history.
So what are we starting
with first?
Ethiopian style
chicken jambalaya.
[Guy] So you're taking
Louisiana and going right
-over to Ethiopia?
-That's right.
-We debone the chicken thighs.
-[Guy] All right.
[Eskender] And then, we take
also the chicken tenderloin.
That's gonna be
cooked separately.
We're gonna make a marinade,
salt and pepper, fresh thyme,
fresh oregano, pomegranate,
and a little bit of olive oil.
I got to be honest, Chef,
I didn't see you move this
fast in Guy's Grocery Games.
No, I was paying attention to
what other chefs were making.
So we have this on top
of the chicken thighs
and the tenderloin.
And then we marinate overnight
or for a couple of hours.
[Guy] So how are we gonna cook
the chicken thighs?
[Eskender] Grill it lightly
like about 10 minutes each.
[Guy] Got it.
[Eskender] Now, we're gonna
cook up our chicken tenders.
What would this dish be
called in Ethiopia?
Chicken Wot, W-O-T.
-[voices] Wot?
-I don't think Chicken Wot
-sells on the menu.
-Absolutely.
-As well as Chicken Jambalaya.
Next we're gonna add
the chicken thighs.
-[Guy] Tomatoes.
-Basmati and brown wild rice.
And then,
add a little sea salt,
kale, Swiss chard,
the spinach.
There you are.
You remember Troy Johnson?
Was he a judge
when you were...
-[Eskender] Yeah. Mmm-hmm.
-...when you were cooking?
Troy Johnson would say,
"Do you think
it was a good idea to put
the barberry on the chicken?"
-Absolutely.
-"Well, it was.
-It was a great idea."
-[laughs]
-[laughter]
You're welcome, Troy.
Give me a little rundown
what's been happening
-in the restaurant.
-We're trying new dishes,
how can we improve,
what do people like.
Smoked Trout Bacala.
-[Eskender] Beluga lentils.
-So what do we got?
This is Ethiopian style
Grilled Flank Steak
with Chermoula.
-Please explain this to me.
-[Eskender] We got a nice cut
of lean flank steak.
We're gonna make a marinade
with freshly crushed garlic,
lemon juice, a little bit
of chopped parsley,
pepper, salt, olive oil,
and chopped shallots.
Make sure it touch
every surface.
Cook our flank steak
to a medium rare.
And this Chermoula sauce...
Is this our Chermoula here
that we make?
-[Eskender] Exactly.
-[Guy] Okay.
-Chermoula sauce.
-That's right.
We have chopped parsley
over here,
cilantro, garlic, cumin,
and coriander.
The cayenne is gonna be
just a little pinch over here.
So we have olive oil,
lemon juice,
of course salt and pepper.
And we'll put this
in a blender.
-[blender whirring]
-Good idea, take the lid off.
Your ears all right?
-What?
-[laughs]
I wanna get a slip and slide
in flavor town
and run Charmoula through it.
[laughs]
Flank steak
is cooked perfectly.
The oil works as a medium
so it kind of allows it
to coat
and really get silky
over the top of it.
Your base is salty,
little bit of heat,
little bit of warmth spice,
good amount of acid.
I don't know if you can
put that in a bottle.
We actually do.
Grilled Flank Steak.
The meat is really fresh,
cooked perfectly.
The herbs you can really feel
and smell on top
and everything goes
really well together.
You know,
when you see a movie,
I don't wanna go see
the sequel because...
Well, the sequel is not
gonna be as good
as the original movie.
Well, that's kind
of where I'm at right now.
But the follow up
doesn't disappoint.
It's an influence of Ethiopia,
Spain, and Portugal.
That's outstanding.
-Saffron prawns.
-We'll be back.
-Yeah, yeah.
-See you in a minute.
[Guy] Welcome back.
We're in San Francisco
hanging out at a Triple G,
Triple D legend.
This is my buddy, Eskender.
And we are at
Radio Africa & Kitchen.
We're back in 2016,
I may have over indulged.
I'm just trying to get one in
before this ends.
You wanna make another?
-Make a hundred of them.
-[laughs]
I'll sleep here.
You can't keep this guy down.
He literally
walked out of Ethiopia.
-A little run, too.
-A little running as well
to go to a better life.
Ethiopian is your foundation
of where you came from.
But Radio Africa
is kind of like
a melting pot of flavors.
-Absolutely.
-What else are we gonna do?
This is the Saffron Prawns
with cauliflower,
smoked trout bacala
and vegetables.
It's an influence of Ethiopia,
Spain, and Portugal.
Ethiopia, Spain, and Portugal.
-Yeah. You...
-Yeah, it just...
-They also border each other.
-Exactly. We're neighbors.
What I did was here's
the Saffron Prawns quickly
sauteed with just
a sprinkle of barberry.
We have shelled
and deveined prawns over here.
-And we have...
-"Divined prawns,"
I don't know
if you ever had them.
-They're deveined and divined.
-Deveined, that's right.
Now, we're gonna make
a marinate saffron.
A little chili flakes,
tiny bit of salt,
ground pepper,
a little bit
of chopped parsley over here.
Garlic, a drop of olive oil
right here,
a squeeze of lemon, mix this.
[Guy] Let that go
for a couple hours.
You wanna just
like barely cook.
[Guy] Nothing worse
than overcooked.
Exactly.
We drizzle a little bit
of Zhug.
It's parsley, cilantro,
lemon juice,
salt and pepper,
a little bit of garlic.
Tender, not overly seasoned,
-delicious.
-Saffron Prawns.
I can definitely taste
the fresh herbs,
which Eskender uses a lot of,
and they're perfectly
sauteed,
so they're not
at least overcooked.
That's outstanding.
But I'm not kidding you,
this little move that you did
with the cauliflower
and the trout, and the way
you put that together
could be center
and played by itself.
We cook blanched cauliflower
and we flavor
with the smoked trout.
We add parsley, caper, garlic,
tomato confit,
and of course
being an African restaurant,
chili flakes goes everywhere,
green olive oil,
and mash it together.
[Guy] It's a cauliflower
smoked trout croquette.
-Yeah, exactly. Right.
-But it's not fried.
Or did you finish in the...
Oh, you baked it, yeah.
It's baked in the oven, yeah.
It's fantastic.
The trout bacala,
it's a little bit
like mashed potatoes.
It has a little bit
of a smoky flavor,
which is really nice.
It's just very comforting.
[man] I thought the flavors
went well together.
Eskender puts together
really subtle combinations.
And so, one thing
never overpowers the other.
Everything works really,
really well together.
-Saffron Prawns coming up.
-[Guy] I think it's time
we got to get you back
on Triple G.
Yeah, absolutely, why not?
Why not?
Okay. Why not go from Triple G
to Triple D to Triple D Nation
-back to Triple G?
-That sounds good.
-Awesome. Thank you.
-Appreciate it.
Thank you very much, Guy,
always.
Delicious.
Coming up in Minneapolis.
Fire it up.
An Italian joint
that's all the rage.
[woman] It's perfection
on a plate.
[Guy] With pretty much
every age.
Super, duper, duper,
duper, duper big.
What else do you want?
[upbeat music playing]
You know,
one of the coolest cats I know
in this world is our director
photography for Diners,
Drive-Ins and Dives,
a guy named Anthony Rodriguez.
Now, we call him Chico.
He's the one
that's shooting it right now.
He lives in Minneapolis.
Back in 2012,
he insisted I check out
this Italian joint
his whole family
gave two thumbs up.
So what makes it so good?
The sauce, the pasta,
it's perfection on a plate.
[Guy] And it's still
their go-to joint.
They just have three
to choose from these days.
This is Broders'
Cucina Italiana.
[man] I happen to be
in Broders'
and all of a sudden
here comes Guy.
[Guy] Italian food
is like this in Minneapolis?
This is the Italian food,
yeah.
-This is the staple.
-That's when Triple D came.
Things just exploded.
It was busy all the time.
In first grade,
my dad brought me to Broders'.
-[Guy] How is it?
-Super, duper, duper,
duper, duper big.
-[scoffs]
-[giggles]
-What else do you want?
-I said you have to go
to this place
that had New York style
Italian food.
This is one of the first
I've had
on the show or anywhere.
This is the closest stuff
I grew up with in Brooklyn.
[Guy] That's thanks
to Molly Broder
and her late husband, Tom,
who opened up back in '82.
Eventually, their three sons,
Charlie, Danny, and Thomas
joined in.
30 years ago is this what
you think was gonna happen?
-[Molly] No.
-[laughter]
I told them to be
good students
and become scientist
or, you know...
-They are scientists.
-[laughter]
We were so proud to showcase
what we do.
[Guy]
This, ladies and gentlemen,
is a hot rod I don't own yet.
How do you sleep in bed
with it?
-Just like this.
-Like this?
Yeah.
It was a really great moment
when he showed
his excitement
for that pasta machine.
That machine is the
life blood of our business.
[clangs]
Now we can commence.
So we start with durum flour.
Tender, but with a good chew.
Fire it up.
[Thomas] Whole eggs,
a little bit of water.
We mix that up
for about 10 minutes.
Your roller set in there.
You open the door here.
It's gonna come out.
-We're gonna roll it again.
-We're gonna roll again.
-[Guy] Whoa.
-With a little semolina,
that'll keep it
nice and loose.
And you're ready to go
to portion...
Yes.
We're gonna portion it up.
After we were on air,
the machine wasn't big enough
to keep up.
We quickly realized
that we needed
a bigger machine.
Take us to the Broders' line.
[Thomas] Go ahead
and drop our pasta.
We're making Bolognese.
[Guy] Okay. Pasta is ready.
-Nested fettuccini.
-[Thomas] Yup.
Now, they will head
over the flame.
Over that grana padano.
[Guy] This is fantastic.
No more laughing, no more fun.
The pasta coma has begun.
[laughing]
Housemade egg noodles,
they're widely fresh.
[woman] I really, really like
how the noodles
they, kind of, melt
in your mouth.
All the freshness
of that yummy pasta,
you feel like you're in Italy
eating it.
Whether it's
a stuffed tortellini, ravioli.
The lasagna is amazing.
[Danny] Lasagna siciliana
for table 10.
Starting
with our fresh pasta.
Ricotta mix, fresh ricotta,
parsley, three whole eggs,
we'll just mix this around
until it's really well
and corporate.
Put a little bit
of the sugo betti
right on top
of the ricotta here.
Spread it as even may
as you can.
Get a little sausage.
Nice imported
grana padano cheese,
mozzarella,
and that's what the first
layer looks like here.
We're gonna do
a total of five,
and then, the last layer
is just sauce and cheese.
We'll go in a 350 degree oven
for 20 minutes
that we rotate,
another 20 minutes.
We cut this up and we take
some of that sugo betti
right over the top,
a little bit of grana padano
and some fresh chopped
parsley.
The lasagna siciliana.
[woman] It is fresh.
The tomato sauce
is just so tangy,
it's so light.
It's just delicious. [laughs]
[upbeat music playing]
Your passion
and your enthusiasm
for the food is outstanding.
I'm surprised you got
50 of these joints.
[laughter]
There are three restaurants
at Broders' now,
Broders' Cucina,
Broders' Pasta and Terzo,
those are all located on
the same intersection here.
They built an empire here
on 50th.
[Guy] It's been
really exciting to see,
I mean, the food here
is to die for
-every time you come in.
-I always get the calabrian,
one of my favorite
sandwiches in town.
And we get
the focaccia sandwiches to go
and they're always great.
[Danny] And so with
the dry seasonings here
to mix the black peppercorn,
fennel seed,
rosemary,
a little fresh garlic,
a little Dijon mustard
adds a really nice bite.
We put fennel fronds
in the bottom of the pan,
then we take just the tops
of the fennel fronds,
sprinkle over the top.
So now we're gonna start
by wrapping up the shoulder
so that belly
that can really wrap around.
We're gonna come by
with some white wine,
and then, put it
in a 220 degree oven
for at least 12 hours.
Now we're ready to assemble
our calabrian pepper
focaccia sandwich.
We got a nice toast
on the ciabatta bun,
calabrian pepper aioli,
and then,
calabrian chili paste,
egg yolk, lemon juice,
Canola oil.
Put a healthy amount on there,
fresh pork,
and then, we top with it slaw,
gonna slice in half
and there is the calabrian
focaccia sandwich
here at Terzo.
The aioli and the slaw
really balanced out
the richness and savory
quality of the pork,
they just give it
a little bite, a little lift,
it's perfectly balanced.
It is the most intense
flavored pork
you could imagine.
And when you take
a bite of it,
it is like being intoxicated.
When Anthony told me
about this, he said,
"I'm really telling you,
you're gonna flip out."
I didn't think
he define flip out enough.
-There's a new definition.
-Oh, that's sweet.
[Guy] Coming up.
As the Mayor of Duluth,
I welcome
the Mayor Flavor Time.
[Guy] A diner in Duluth
dish out everything
from classics.
That is comfort food 101.
To Korean.
Bibimbap order up.
[Guy] Primetime my friend.
Primetime.
[upbeat music playing]
I'm here in Duluth, Minnesota
in the Lincoln Park
neighborhood,
it's now and up
and coming area
and home to a restaurant
that that left corporal world
to do his own gig.
And that decision paid off.
Mmm-hmm.
[Guy] Because since
I was there 2010,
he's taking over
the neighborhood.
This is Duluth Grill.
[Emily]
As the Mayor of Duluth,
I welcome
the Mayor Flavor Time.
Hmm. Thank you.
Wow.
I saw the Triple D episode
years ago
and there's time
in the kitchen,
whipping up the food,
making it look easy.
I just love the food.
This is a hometown treasure.
[Guy]
And home to owner Tom Hanson
who's whipping up
scratch made recipes
next to his son Louie.
And when Tom opened
this joint
he set his sights high.
I said Louie,
"If the food network called,
what do you wanna do, open up
a free package product
or tell him that we used
everything from scratch."
[Louie] It was probably
two years after that,
the food network called.
They'd like to feature
our bison hot rolls.
Start it with a simple Rub,
black pepper,
celery seed, salt...
-Granulated garlic.
Just gonna stir that around.
That now is ready.
Let's put some MiraPLY
in the bottom.
-[Guy] For the pan.
-[Tom] Carrots, onions,
and celery.
Now, we'll add the Bison,
we're gonna pierce the roast,
a little psycho into this.
Now, we'll add
some minced garlic,
we're gonna get this rub
evenly spread.
Do you want the rest
of your plaw?
[Tom] Yup.
This gonna cover the top.
We let this marinate for about
five hours to overnight,
we're gonna add...
Put a half a gallon
of water here.
Just it covers a little bit
on the sides.
Then we'll wrap it in foil,
and it's ready to go
in the oven.
300, 325 for about five hours?
Yup. It should be done.
We'll take the roast
out of the pan
and strain the liquid
for the gravy.
The bison is just rested long
enough now for us to cut it.
Got a crispy outside crust,
nice tender inside.
-[Guy] Dude, that fall apart.
-[Tom] It falls apart.
That goes like that
with the vegetables,
the super gravy,
label it right over.
Hmm. That is comfort food 101.
Really nice texture.
Not only really tender
but has a real beef flavor.
You sure have a knack
for pulling it off
and making it tasty man.
We had a lot of fun
cooking side-by-side with Guy.
[laughter]
[woman]
They have many great options,
lunch, dinner, pie,
anything you want.
[man] The menu
is kind of modern now
and there's more
organic foods,
they're growing food
in the parking lot.
[Guy] Up here in Duluth,
I mean,
this is main potato country.
Over 10 years ago,
we started this idea
that we would have gardens
on our property
and they've really given us
charge to go hyper local
and get super fresh
ingredients
in every dish.
Bibimbap, order up.
Bibimbap, fabulous.
Bibimbap is a very
traditional Korean dish
which we've kind of given
a Minnesota flair.
It's combination of all these
fresh sauteed ingredients,
the rice is grilled crisp,
there's
the pork burger patty,
gonna take a local beef
and a local pork
and our marinate to it,
combination of ginger,
garlic, fish sauce,
sesame oil, oyster sauce,
sriracha, liquid aminos,
rice wine, and vinegar.
This marinate is blended in
to form a patty
and we'll grill that.
There's the fermented kimchi,
its napa cabbage,
red cabbage, and carrot
with about to seven
to 14 day fermentation.
The marinated kale,
it's a marinade of ginger,
olive oil, aminos,
rice wine, vinegar,
lemon juice,
and sesame oil.
We massage the kale
and let it marinade
for at least 24 hours,
and then, grill it.
And then, we're gonna garnish
the dish with peppers,
pickled onions.
Grill sauteed mushrooms,
avocado,
Korean barbeque sauce,
eggs, soy aioli,
and green onion
with cilantro and wine.
Bibimbap, order up.
[man] It's got
a little bit of sweet,
a little bit of tangy,
a little bit spice in there
with the beef and pork combo
and the wild rice,
it's such an amazing dish.
I always like something
that's kind of spicy,
salty with that perfect
equilibrium,
I called that
bibimbap blessing.
[laughs]
We come here
seven days a week.
-No you don't.
-It's true.
She's got the cleanest oven
in town.
I bet you she does.
[Tom] Since the show,
we were able to open
two new restaurants,
the OMC Smokehouse
and Cork Town Deli and Brews.
This neighborhood
is kind of in transition,
so he felt, he could open
some restaurants
and help get back.
[Tom] Since those two
restaurants have opened
20 new businesses have opened
right on that same block.
-Curry Steak.
-[Emily] To see the work
that Tom and his family
are doing
in this neighborhood,
in the city,
it's really incredible.
Primetime my friend.
-Primetime.
-Thank you.
Two porketta balls all day.
[Guy] But if this place
didn't live up to the hype...
-[woman] Enjoy.
-Thank you.
[Guy] ...we probably
wouldn't be here
-in the first place.
-[man] Order up.
[Guy] Or for round two.
But those are not the only
one folks, don't worry,
we got more to cover
next on Triple D Nation.
The next thing
is we're gonna mix
-the barberry mix.
-Barberry.
Isn't that a nice shop
that my wife shops at?
-Yes.
-So you just ground up
one of her purses
and threw it in there.
Let's make a dish
called coach.
-[Eskender laughs]
-[Guy] Love it.
Love it.