So when I come off
the road from doing DDD
the first thing I wanna do
get home to my kitchen
and cook my food
for my family.
And after a few weeks,
I got to be...
Dad, can we just...
I mean, please,
we'll go to restaurant
at least one time.
They start to revolt.
So I came up with the idea,
"How about we reach out
to some of our favorite chefs
and had them
send us dinner, huh?"
I like that idea.
[Guy] And I know
some DDD joints,
that would love
to send it to us.
There's gangster Gorditas
coming from Tacos Chiwas
in Phoenix.
[man] That is a little
of pocket of de-lightness
right there.
[Guy] Korean fried
chicken straight out
at Denver's Dae Gee.
I can't get it in
my mouth fast enough.
A steak specialty
from Kenny and Ziggy's
classic deli down
in Houston.
Outstanding, dude.
And heading here
from Knoxville, Tennessee,
meatballs and pies
from the decades old
Pizza Palace Drive-in.
We are going supreme, baby.
And on top of it all,
they're gonna video
conference in to give us
the true DDD experience.
This is DDD take out.
And there's a few more
in the trunk.
Of course there is.
[upbeat music playing]
Wait till you see
this cast of characters,
I mean, we are going OG.
We're not gonna start
with oldest OG
of the whole thing.
We're gonna start off
with Nadia at Tacos Chiwas.
Chef, how are doing?
Doing great.
How are you?
[Guy] I love it, Hunter,
the way she does tacos
is not the everyday
ordinary way
that you would expect.
Next up, my buddy
Joe from DAE GEE.
Joe, do you have red
hair going?
You can't barely see it
in the background.
I'm blending right in,
right?
[Guy] There you go.
Now, we're gonna go
to the one and only
Jewish deli all the way
in Houston, Texas, our buddy
from Kenny and Ziggy's,
-what's up brother?
-I'm doing okay.
Now, ladies and gentleman,
this guy is an OG of OG,
although, I think
that he might be a vampire
or something
because he doesn't age.
He did the show
when we've started,
our buddy Charlie
at Pizza Palace.
-How are you buddy?
-I'm doing great Guy,
-good to see you.
-So the show
DDD Takeout,
we call you,
we ask for takeout,
you send it to us,
and then, Hunter and I
try not to eat everything
as it comes out
of the package.
-It's a tough job we have.
-Sweaty.
But we get through it.
I wanna remind everybody,
one of the four of you
is gonna get
best dish tonight.
-Zig, will do you first.
-Okay.
[Guy] This is real deal
old school Jewish Deli.
I have a full Yiddish
dictionary over here.
-Yeah.
-[Guy] You've been the Macher?
-[Ziggy] Macher.
-[Guy] Macher?
-Right.
-The big-shot around here.
-This is called
the Zellagabetsky.
I guess I could just sit there
and whittle away at it.
Here is my sandwich.
What does your sign
say behind Zig,
"We schlep nationwide."
[laughs] Yeah.
Talking about schlepping,
here comes Hunter.
I sent you corned beef
and pastrami,
I send you the whole
dish.
Am I gonna pull a Jewish
grandmother out of here?
-[laughs]
-All right. That's it.
Show is over.
We're gonna go to commercial.
The Matzah Ball soup
just showed up,
I'm heating this up
right now.
Okay. [laughs]
[Guy] I'm still trying
to find the dish
-that we're making Hunter.
-I think it's right here.
[Ziggy] We're making
a Romanian skirt steak.
[Guy] Give us the rundown
on the marinate.
We're gonna put some
white wine in there,
vegetable oil, tamari.
Today or tamari?
-Tamari.
-[laughter]
Fresh squeezed OJ,
fresh squeezed lemon,
give it a good shot of A1
and a shot
of Worchester sauce.
Where did this recipe
come from, Zig?
My grandfather
was in the business
and I learned everything
from him.
I love this.
We got some garlic,
chopped garlic in there,
chopped onion, black pepper
and red pepper flakes,
-chopped parsley.
-I could turn this
-into a soup right now.
-[Ziggy laughs]
-I'll take a shot of that.
-[laughs]
I'd put on anything,
I mean,
I could put that on
your old shoe.
[Ziggy] You're gonna
pour that on those
beautiful prime skirt
steaks.
When these marinate
at restaurant,
you let them go
for how many days?
Three days.
I sent you some
already marinated
because, you know,
we don't have time
to wait three days.
You set me in that food
that I can survive
on Gilligan's Island
by myself for three days.
Absolutely. That was...
[Guy] Are these gonna
go onto the grill now?
Of course.
Cook it to your liking.
[Guy] The skirt steak
is one of my favorite
-pieces of meat.
-[Ziggy] Hunter can get
dredge for the onions,
we're gonna put
some plain flour in there,
granulated garlic,
Hungarian paprika,
the black pepper, and then,
some season and salt.
Hunter, while you're there,
you can put
the carrot soufflé
in oven to warm up.
The sliced onions,
you're gonna dredge.
[Guy] Okay. While
he is doing that, Zig.
[Ziggy] We're gonna do
the Jewish chimichurri sauce.
-[laughs]
-Were making
-Jewish chimichurri?
-Yes, basically.
[laughs] Put some schmaltz
in this.
-Some what?
-Chicken schmaltz.
[Guy] It's the chicken fat.
If you haven't cooked
with chicken fat,
you're not living my friend.
No, you're not.
And then, we're gonna add
-the garlic.
-[Guy] Red chili.
[Ziggy] Pinch of salt,
the chopped parsley.
[Guy] I love this
because this is blooming,
and a lot of times with
the chimichurri is not cooked.
All right.
I'm gonna drop these onions.
[Guy] Drop them
like they're Hot.
-Drop them like they're hot.
-Thank you.
[Ziggy] Some apple sauce
and sour cream for the latkes.
[Guy] Gonna salt
this when they come out?
[Ziggy] Yes.
Give it a little...
[speaks Yiddish]
[Guy] Gorgeous.
Zig, take a look at this,
-you like that?
-Those looked beautiful.
Okay. So fry up a couple
of those latkes.
Yeah. This is torture
for those of us at home.
[Hunter] Don't overfeed
yourself in the first round.
[Guy] I know it's
the first round, Hunter,
don't talk to me
when I'm getting ready
to get into my matzah ball.
I used chicken feet that
give it such a good flavor.
You know, how you go on
some on those plans now
where they're gonna mail
you bacon of the month.
I want matzah ball
of the week.
We can do a subscription
if you want,
not a problem. [laughs]
Let's put it together,
let's schmear.
-Schmear?
-The Jewish chimichurri sauce
all over that skirt steak.
Beautiful. On top of that,
those onion strings.
-[Guy] Got it.
-Yeah. Don't be bashful.
On the side,
two of the latkes, and then,
take a nice thick slice
of that carrot soufflé.
What's in a carrot soufflé?
[Ziggy] Carrot,
onion, egg whites,
-and a little matzah meal.
-Delicious.
[Ziggy] Yes.
[Guy] The flavors
are fantastic,
the caramelizing
of the meat,
so it's nice
and sweet and then, boom,
you cut it,
you cut it with that...
With that schmaltz,
the parsley, and the garlic,
and the chili flake,
then you give the nice crunch
with the latkes,
the potato still,
inside of it.
And then, the soufflé
is nice and light,
and delicate.
-Outstanding, dude.
-Thank you.
-I can vouch for that.
-You all said it
-to each other?
-[All] Yes.
[Guy] Well, listen folks,
this is just the beginning,
don't go anywhere,
there's great food coming up.
All right, Hunter.
You start cleaning up,
I'm gonna take a brief
break and enjoy this.
Welcome back.
It's a DDD Takeout.
We're hanging out
at the Fieri house
in the backyard.
And of course,
we've invited some of our
favorite triple D chefs.
We just had our buddy Zig,
from Kenny and Ziggy's
in Houston, Texas sent us
the whole 500 item menu.
-[Hunter] The entire menu.
-[laughs]
[Guy] But let's go to
Denver right now,
to this place
is called Dae Gee.
Where you can go get
this pig out festival
of all you can eat,
Korean delicacies,
you cook there
at your table.
Joe has this rockin'
red Mohawk, normally,
you know, I'm the only
guy in the show...
-Yeah.
-...with the real lid.
I mean, I... I'mma put
a bag on my head up.
Don't say anything.
So you got a guy
with a lot of energy,
a lot of attitude,
a lot of enthusiasm,
and unbelievable flavors,
he can bulgogi anything.
What is bulgogi mean?
Bul means fire
and the gogi means meat.
-Fire meat?
-[Joe] Yeah. Typically
you take a lettuce wrap,
put a little bit
of the meat that you like,
some of the sides.
Whole point is to pig out.
Hmm. If you're gonna have
a haircut like that,
-you better back it up.
-Yeah. Absolutely.
-Good job, buddy.
-All right, man.
What are we making today?
Oh, we got Korean
fried chicken
with a mango gaucho sauce.
Oh, Korean fried chicken.
Finger licking, finger
licking, finger licking good.
You set your grandmother
in the box.
-[laughs]
-Soju.
[Joe] Kind of a Korean spirit.
Soju just put
a little bit in?
Yeah.
Soju need two bottles,
all right?
-[laughs]
-Okay.
You said soju two bottles,
there's 14.
Oh, yeah.
Every flavor.
-Oink Ale?
-[Joe] Tivoli Brewery
here in Denver, Colorado
brews it for us,
it pairs with all
of our chicken wings.
What makes Korean fried
chicken different
from regular fried chicken?
[Joe] It's the spice.
It's the kick that you get
-in the end.
-So let's the wings
and we're gonna make
the Dae Gee sauce
to marinate it in.
Have Hunter puree
the onions, the apple.
-[Guy] We need that in a bowl?
-[Joe] Yeah. In a bowl.
Ground garlic,
ground ginger in the bowl,
a little bit of soju
in there,
-black pepper in there.
-Salt?
Yeah. Pineapples.
-Puree this?
-[Joe] Yes.
Put it in the bowl
and mix it up.
Did you get the, uh,
soy sauce?
And water in there also.
So chicken wings in,
at the restaurant
this will go 24 hours?
-Yes, sir.
-Is there one location
-or 17 now?
-We have five locations.
-Under-achiever.
-[laughter]
[Joe] So we got
the mango gaucho sauce,
puree those fresh mangoes,
and some of those,
uh, Korean red peppers,
corn syrup, garlic.
Hunter, if you wanna
get some of those lemons,
squeeze those into there.
Tell me about this batter
that we're making
for the chicken wings?
[Joe] There's a fry
and a pancake batter mix,
so it's a one to one,
six ounces of water.
Six ounces of water.
Fantastic.
And this supposed to be
about the texture
-of tempura batter?
-Yes, exactly.
Keep on adding water
until it gets creamy.
-Chef, is this, uh...
-Oh, perfect.
[Guy] The sauce has made.
We've got
the wings marinating.
I mean, there's a lot
still going on here, right?
-[Joe] Yeah. Yeah. Yup. Yup.
-[Guy] Okay.
So here's what we're gonna do,
we're gonna take
a commercial. We got
to clean some this up.
We got to let these wings
marinate a little bit longer,
get our fryer all ready,
we're gonna come back.
We are making Dae Gee
from Denver Korean
fried chicken.
You can't miss this.
-Well see you in a bit.
-I am so excited.
I know you are and you only
get one chicken wing.
[upbeat music playing]
Welcome back.
DDD Takeout hanging out here
at the backyard
of Fieri house.
We have a bunch
of heavy hitters
with Nadia at Tacos Chiwas,
Charlie at Pizza Palace,
Zig from Kenny and Ziggy's.
And we brought in
some funky food,
we're talking about Dae Gee
out of Denver, Colorado.
-Oh, yeah.
-[Guy] Korean barbecue.
And what Hunter and I
are in to right now
is making some
Korean fried chicken.
So a marinated wing nice
and crunchy
with mango gaucho sauce.
[whistles] Little spice.
Little spice.
You also sent along
some fermented onions
and jalapeno,
my new middle name.
-[laughter]
-Some kimchee,
-you also make in-house.
-[Joe] Yes.
[Guy] Pickled daikon
and little roasted
-sesame seed on top?
-That's it, man.
Masterpiece. Oh, yeah.
-Are we able to try them?
-There you go, Nadia.
-Eat some.
-[Guy] I don't understand it.
I got my own too.
You stealing my thunder.
Oy vey ist mir,
that's hot.
-So good.
-I can't get in my mouth
fast enough. I mean,
it's light and crunchy.
It's like a hard tempura.
You can even send those
to folks pare baked
or pare fried, where they
could do it in home.
[Hunter]
These are really money.
Super crunchy.
Not too hot.
-Great little sweetness to it.
-[Guy] And all of these
little accompaniments,
fermented onions and jalapeno,
the pickled radish,
the kimchi is real deal legit.
Now, you got the whole
show drinking.
What has happened to our show?
Oh, my goodness.
All right, Joe.
Fantastic job. Hunter and I
have a little clean up to do
but you got to check
this out.
This is a husband and wife
team that are doing
tacos their way. They're
from Chihuahua, Mexico.
This is Tacos Chiwas.
What is Chihuahuan food?
How would you describe it?
[Armando] Chihuahua
is land-logged so,
it has a lot to do
with proteins.
-Barbacoa tacos.
-[Guy] Well, that's a bunch
-of chili to our bowl.
-[Nadia] Do you like spicy?
-Come on.
-[Nadia] Yeah?
That's not at all.
-Uh, what's up, brother?
-[Armando] Hey, guys.
[Guy] Look at that cutie
right there.
-What's her name?
-Paloma.
What's been happening
at the restaurant
-since we were there last?
-[Nadia] We opened up
-two more locations.
-Three restaurants and a baby?
You have your hands full.
-They sent a whole cooler.
-[Guy] I always recommend
that you just send
the whole cooler itself.
-Yeah.
-Peace, love and Tacos Chiwas,
-huh?
-[man] Nice.
-[Guy] Thank you.
-So, we're gonna be making
-rajas con queso gordita.
-Oh, that's what I what
usually say every morning is,
rajas con queso gorditas.
So, rajas is gonna be onions,
cream
and stripped chili
in our gordita.
Nadia,
how you wanna start this?
So, we're gonna start
with the gorditas.
Flour, baking soda, salt.
We wanna disperse
the shortening throughout,
-correct?
-[Nadia] That's correct.
Add water with milk
and you wanna go slowly.
Not too slow.
Speed it up a little bit.
[Guy] So, typically
ball these up, chef?
-About this big?
-Yeah. Yeah.
And then let them rest
24 hours
-and then we're good to go?
-Yeah.
Where do you wanna start next?
So, let's start
on the rajas.
[Guy] Raw onions and serranos,
right here.
[Nadia] You're gonna
saute them,
it's a vegetarian gordita.
Salt and pepper.
A pinch of cumin.
So, we're gonna have
to blend some cream cheese
-with water.
-[Guy] Gorgeous.
Anaheims and poblano
that have roasted,
seeded de-veined
and skinned.
[Nadia] Let's add a little bit
of asadero cheese.
We get it all the way
from Juarez, Chihuahua.
It tastes like a really
super big creamy jack.
What can I do to get
started on these, uh,
on these beans?
Pour lard and let it melt.
While Hunter is working that,
can I get some
-tortillas going?
-Yeah.
Roll these, hand pound them,
what's the game plan?
If you have
a tortilla press.
You go watch that,
I'll go find it.
Oh, so we're gonna take
a short break.
We'll be right back
with you.
-That's perfect.
-Okay. Awesome. What next?
[Nadia] The chorizo and bacon.
-[Guy] Into the lard?
-[Nadia] Correct. Yeah.
[Guy] Okay. Hey,
that vegetarian thing's out
-the window, folks.
-[Nadia] That chorizo
-we make in-house.
-[Guy] So, white onion,
garlic, gorgeous. Can I add
my hotdogs now, chef?
-[Nadia] Yes.
-[Guy] And now, what? Ham?
-That's correct.
-[Guy] I don't know
what you call this dish
but right now,
-this is meat lover's delight.
-This is a staple
and all-Mexican parties.
You can never go wrong
-with piccolo charro.
-Charros?
-What does charros mean?
-It's like a Mexican cowboy,
-a charro.
-[Guy] Got it. Got it.
And the next thing
we'll be to add what?
-[Nadia] Pinto beans.
-[Guys] What did you cook
-these beans in?
-[Nadia] Water, white onion,
salt and garlic.
Add water.
Let them boil
for about five minutes.
All right.
So, the refried going down.
Did you put the chicharron
to finish out
the rijo la charros.
We forgot the main ingredient.
So, the crunchy
chicharron...
Before you taste that
before you put it in there
-to make sure it okay.
-Hmm.
-Yeah.
-[Guy] And the last thing
-is the cilantro?
-[Nadia] Correct.
-[Guy] Oh, it's gorgeous.
-How are those gorditas
-looking, good?
-[Guy] Looking great.
Hunter with a mad
knife skills.
[Nadia] Smear a little bit
of the re-fried beans
-inside the gordita.
-Okay.
[Nadia] And then,
you're gonna put the rajas.
Are we going generous?
Go big or go home.
And then, you're gonna finish
it with the queso asadero.
[Guy] And then the beans?
Chicharrons and hotdogs.
When did my day
get so good?
Yeah. That looks great.
[Hunter] You're starting
without me. I mean,
I thought we're
doing this together.
-That's good.
-[Guy] Sister,
I'm telling you what.
These beans
with the 95 different
pieces of meat,
you put in there.
It's a meal within itself.
And the chicharron,
you're happy
when you find
that little nugget.
[Hunter] Dad, there's a little
pocket of the lightness
-right there.
-[Guy] It's everything
you love in a chili relleno
but not fried
and the roast
of the peppers, fantastic.
The cream cheese adds
that real nice tang.
[Hunter] I also love like
that creaminess at the end
of it too
from the asadero.
I'm gonna tell you something.
This is...
This is enough, okay?
We're just gonna call
quits right here.
Except for the fact
that you get one
of the DDD OGs
from season one.
We'll be back.
Don't go anywhere.
You're gonna love
this last piece.
Seriously. I'm gonna have
to go for a walk.
[upbeat music playing]
Welcome back.
DDD in the backyard doing
a little takeout.
I'm telling you what, Hunter?
-How are you feeling?
-Full.
[Guy] Well, the show that
had ended with Tacos Chiwas.
Ziggy almost took us out
from getting
at Ziggy's in Houston.
And I'll tell you what,
Dae Gee in Denver,
Joe is not nice either.
So, we were basically ready
to say goodnight, folks.
Thanks for tuning in.
But we can't give up
on a funky drive-in
pizza place
called Pizza Palace.
I had never seen
anything of the like.
[Charlie] On opening day
in 1961,
they we're lining up
out the door
because this is the first
experience with pizza
that many people
in Knoxville had.
-No.
-Pizza was not available
-at that time.
-Now, Hunter. I went there
when we first started DDD.
First season,
they took a gamble
and let some guy come in
with tattoos
and bleached blond hair
and hang out
-in Knoxville, Tennessee.
-What is in the tomato-base?
[Charlie] I can't tell
to you all of these things.
-I would have to kill you.
-Is it... It's...
You'd have to kill me?
So, you probably add
some oregano, and some basil.
Just be glad you got this far.
Just be happy that I'm in
the inner sanctum?
-That's it.
-[Guy] Wow.
Charlie, how are things?
We're keeping it real
with the one location.
Still got the push button
at the drive up
where people come
and order the pizza?
[Charlie] We had it replace
the one
-that you saw originally.
-[Guy] Whoa, whoa.
Whoa, whoa. Whoa, whoa.
Whoa, whoa.
-[Hunter] I have three more.
-[Guy] Boxes?
Yeah.
Oh, you did it.
-Yeah.
-That's what's called
-a curve tray.
-[Guy] That's about
as old-school as it gets.
I mean, right on the window.
Happy birthday?
Today is my birthday, buddy.
No, it's not.
Hang on a second.
Oh, there you go, Nadia.
Today is Smokie's birthday.
How perfect is that?
You wanna wear that?
-Not so much.
-Happy birthday, man.
-Thank you very much.
-Oh, yeah.
Figured you'd like
to have something like that
-for your outdoor oven.
-[Hunter] That is sick.
Why can't I have that
as a belt buckle?
Looks like a weapon
from Game of Thrones.
We're gonna make
a meatball sandwich.
We're gonna have a pizza
with whatever topping
you want on it.
And then we're gonna bread
some onion rings
and fry those up.
These onions rings
are the bomb.
Pizza and onion rings?
That's right.
Because it's to the baseline.
Walk me through these
onion rings.
You want four bowls,
egg wash, flour,
egg wash, breading.
Use one hand dry,
one hand wet.
I know the old one hand dry...
[Guy] Oh, we had the old wet
and dry hand around here.
[Charlie] Put pressure on it.
Pack them on.
There you go.
Otherwise, when you fry it,
it won't hold up.
So, what is in this
meatball mixture?
[Charlie] Chopped
browns of beef,
bread crumbs, onions,
celery, peppers, eggs,
salt, pepper and a little
crushed red pepper.
I'm just gonna shallow fry
on these meatballs?
-[Charlie] Yes.
-Heat these meat sauce up?
Walk me through it again.
I didn't tell you then.
I'm not telling you now.
-God! Charlie.
-So, that's homemade
-meat sauce.
-Let's talk about the pizza.
I see the dough here.
Nice and light.
Let's see how your toss is.
-There you go.
-[Guy] Meat sauce, pizza
-mozzarella shredded.
-And we're old-school
-toppings. Sausage,
peppers.
-Olives.
-[Charlie] Ham.
-Ground beef.
Looks like
you've seasoned this.
Yeah. We got some of salt,
garlic powder
-and a little bit of oregano.
-[Guy] Roasted mushrooms.
Well, we saute those up
with a little bit of onion,
seasoned them up,
adds another dimension
-of flavor on that pizza.
-I've loaded this up.
We are going supreme, baby.
-Look at that.
-I think, that's just
-about right.
-[Guy] All right.
What are we gonna do
with these hoagie rolls?
[Charlie] Cut the hoagie
in half,
put the meatballs on it
with a little sauce
and parmesan cheese.
There you go.
[Hunter] That is an OG
meatball sandwich right there.
The amount of flavor
inside of the meatball
is way over the top.
Super tender.
And the meat sauce again,
it's so nice to get back
and have a reunion with it.
Delicious. But don't worry,
there's more.
All right, Dad.
Onion rings are done.
-How's that pizza?
-[Guy] Check that out.
-Not bad at all.
-[Guy] A little salt on those,
Hunter. Coming out.
Look at, Charlie.
You tell me.
I mean, that one Hunter
took a bite out of,
but you tell me
that's not the right crisp
-and not the right crunch.
-Well done.
-Golden brown.
-Oh, the right ratio
of crunchy batter
to awesome onion,
fantastic.
Let's dig into it.
House made crust.
Nice slice of pie.
Reminds me of pizza
as little kid.
-Old school.
-Not too fancy in quality.
Handmade,
scratch made, homemade.
-[Hunter] Mmm-hmm.
-[Guy] It's a dynamite
piece of pizza.
I applaud you all.
-Job well done.
-Thank you.
[Guy] And thank you
for destroying any workout
program that I had
planned for later.
-Thank you, Guy.
-But Hunter and I
have to do
the hard work right now
of who is going to get
the best dish.
Will you just hold on
a second?
We'll be over here conferring.
I got to tell you.
You guys are all topnotch
-in my book.
-Everything was great.
Thank you so much
for all the food.
Well, folks.
I am gonna be honest with you.
Hunter and I could not come
to an equal decision
on this but I'mma
tell you what,
gorditas, Asian food,
Jewish deli,
pizza, I mean, we hit all
of the major food groups,
correct?
But right now,
we're gonna go best DDD
to go today is winner,
winner OG DDD
pizza dinner.
Congratulations, Charlie.
-Pizza Palace.
-Nice.
Nice, Charlie.
Awesome job. Everybody,
thank you so much.
And don't you guys
forget at home,
these places are open
and they are ready
to send you these
fantastic DDD dishes
and we'll see you next week.
Back here, DDD.
Adios.
[Hunter] Nice.
[Guy] There you go.
That's my kind of goods.