Hey I'm Guy Fieri
and do you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun.
I'm on my way to flavor town.
This is Diners,
Drive-Ins and Dives.
This trip,
we're packing everything in.
This whole thing
is going in the taco?
From pasta...
Delicious, really good.
...to potatoes.
Smash it,
throw it in there
when the chicken's cooking.
Things are
getting fishy in Florida
with my buddy Vanilla Ice.
[Rob]
That's delicious.
This tops Pop's?
[laughing]
There's a mix up of
flavors and more ahead.
DJ Stupid Birthday.
That's it. I quit.
I have to go home.
And in Marathon Key...
If it's funky, we'll find it.
...classic comfort food
gone off the rails.
Kinda like
running in the dark.
Naked.
Running
in the dark naked.
That's all
right here, right now
on Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives.
[theme music playing]
Man, 1968 Camaro 502?
[Guy]
I told you I'd let you drive
if you bring me
to a place that's the bomb.
Now where are we exactly?
-We're in Palm Beach...
-Okay.
...and this is Dixie Highway.
Not quite as famous as the A1A
but it does run the same way
but about a block that way.
And what kind
of food are we going for?
[Rob] Ecuadorian food.
This is your kinda joint?
That's right.
This is Cholo Soy.
[Hunter] Let me out.
[knocking]
Come on, Hunter.
Sucks when
you lose a bet, huh?
Choclo con Queso.
Let's go, let's go.
[man]
This place is amazing.
Like a little hidden gem.
I had this for the first time
and I was like,
"What is this?"
[Guy] You would know
if you grew up in Ecuador.
Like chef Clay Carnes' wife
Gabby did.
Tempura fish tacos.
We moved to her hometown.
-My dad's from Ecuador.
-Right, I knew that.
So you go to Ecuador.
And were
you cooking down there?
Yeah, yeah, I was cooking
in Ecuador for a few years.
When we
came back I was like,
"Oh, you know
what we could do?"
I mean,
I think of taco joints,
I think of everything
except Ecuadorian.
Steak tacos
ready to go.
It's the next level,
it's a separation from
any other
traditional taco shop.
[Clayton]
Tacos working, guacs down,
check me out,
how's my fish looking?
Fish tacos.
Those are one of my go to's.
Perfect amount
of flakiness and crisp.
[man] The sauce that
they top it off with
is a passion fruit like aioli,
amazing.
What are we making?
Tempura fish tacos.
That's one of the reasons
I brought Rob down.
He's a aquatarian.
-[laughing]
-Huh? Huh?
He eats out of the waters
and vegetables.
And nothing on the hoof.
[Clayton] We've got
some yellowtail here.
Man, those are pretty fish.
Fillet it. We're gonna
make the tempura batter,
-you said it's...
-Like a mix of cornstarch,
flour, a splash
of soy sauce,
and a Mexican style lager.
We're just gonna
dredge a little bit
in some cornstarch
and then we're gonna
put it in our batter.
-[Guy] Fry these up.
-[Clayton] 350 degree oil.
What's on top of this?
Pickled pineapple salsa.
Got vinegar here,
a lot of it.
Sugar, salt,
bring that to a boil.
[Guy] Just to dissolve it.
[Clayton] Fresh pineapple.
This is something unique.
[Clayton]
Onion, red bell pepper.
We got the hot
pickling liquid.
[Guy]
Then you put ice in it?
We want this liquid to be cold
cause if we put it in here
we're gonna have mush.
I'd eat a salad
just with that.
-[Rob] Yeah.
-[Guy] Next.
Let's do the Cholo sauce.
It's a secret sauce.
-Don't tell anybody.
You guys have an audience?
-Keep this quiet.
We got a base of mayo,
some Aji Amarillo,
which is like a
Peruvian chili paste,
and passion fruit puree.
Mmm.
-Get that tang.
-Different.
Get the tortillas rolling?
[Clayton] We get them
delivered twice daily
from a local tortillaria.
We've got
our fish that's fried.
So I get to split
one of the two tacos--
No, it looks like he's making
you your own taco now.
When Hunter co-hosts with me
he just gets a nibble.
Did I hear that
he's getting his own taco?
-No.
-Okay, that's not fair.
-Hey, what?
-[laughing]
[Clayton] We're gonna put
a little bit of guac there.
This whole thing
is going in the taco?
[Clayton] That's it, brother.
Pickled pineapple salsa.
[Guy] Pickled onions.
Cholo sauce, scallions,
cilantro and radish.
[Guy] Way over the top.
Hit it with the lime for sure.
Lime is on time
now I'm gonna get mine.
[reggae music playing]
-That's delicious.
Lot of flavors popping out.
-Yeah, right?
The more you chew,
you get the warmth in there.
-Yeah.
-You get the cold in there.
And you taste a
little bit of everything
as you go.
Yo, just keep talking
I never get to just eat.
I always
have to talk about it.
[laughing]
The fish,
and the tempura batter,
is excellent.
We've got soft,
and tender, and crunchy.
And then you get that
creamy, subtle
delicious vegetable fat
from the avocado.
It's more than a taco.
It's dynamite.
[Clayton]
Fish tacos going down, guys.
This is one of the best
fish tacos I've ever had.
What I like best about it
is the pineapple,
cause that really pops.
Choclo goin' to Fransisco.
How do you
describe the food to people?
It's not Mexican,
it's not Cuban,
it's Ecuadorian.
South Florida on a plate.
All right, guys,
I got one order of
Rock Shrimp Ceviche up
ready to go.
We get the Rock Shrimp Ceviche
every single time.
It's super citrusy
and super tangy
and delicious.
What's on the menu now?
It's ceviche de camaron.
We're gonna actually
poach this shrimp.
Bring some water to a boil,
dump the salt in.
A few peppercorns
and lime juice.
Fresh gulf rock shrimp
and turn that thing off.
Let it cook
for about 45 seconds
to a minute and a half.
Put it in the ice bath.
This little quick poach
that he did to it,
they don't lose
that real fresh flavor
and texture.
-Next step.
-Pickled pepper.
It's a cool touch in there
when you get a grip
of that pepper.
You gotta get a grip
so you don't slip.
-Ah, yeah.
-Yeah.
Yellow and red bell peppers,
little jalapeno for some heat.
And the brine,
same vinegar
that we had before.
We're gonna put that aside.
We want as much time
as we can on this.
-Put it together.
-We got our fresh shrimp,
add the pickled peppers,
shaved red onion,
cilantro and scallions,
a dash of ketchup,
oranges, some lime in there,
healthy amount of salt.
This is an ice cold bowl.
It's getting really icy here.
[laughing]
[Clayton]
So here's our ceviche
accompanied by your
plantain chips.
Going right in.
[Clayton] Open sesame man.
Boom!
[chuckling]
This shrimp is not overcooked.
The crunch
of the red onion, money.
The pickle of the bell pepper,
the cilantro,
the green onion, boom boom!
And then the fresh citrus.
This is one of the most tender
well balanced ceviches
I've ever had.
Every week, we've had
ceviche in the house.
Hate to say it, Pops,
but this tops it all.
This tops Pop's?
[laughing]
And here's your
shrimp ceviche.
It's amazing.
From the quality
of the shrimp,
everything is just fresh.
When you're
talking about balance,
having the onions so thin
so that they can't
dominate anything else.
When I was 16 years old,
I was an
exchange student in France.
Three other kids
were Americans.
And they all spoke
really good French.
And then there was me.
But the guy
that spoke the best French
was a guy named Marty Nolan,
and his wife Rosalind.
What do you think?
This is phenomenal.
Go ahead
and drop those pork bellies.
I come here
embarrassingly often.
[man]
People hanging out together
make a
nice little night out of it.
Hey, guys.
[Guy] If you're telling me
this is a good representation
of Ecuadorian food,
I wanna book a ticket
tomorrow.
Delicious,
good job, bro.
-Chef, out of the park, man.
-Yes, sir.
Watch out
for both these guys, huh?
Hey, watch out.
[Guy] Up next,
in Moorhead, Minnesota...
Scratchmeat pasta
and poutine...
[man]
Then we cut it by hand...
-Sharp hand.
-Yeah.
...scores some major points.
[man] House spinach pesto
for the win.
For the win.
I'm here in
Moorhead, Minnesota
which is right on the border
of Fargo, North Dakota.
I'm here to check out a joint
where they've
got a great story.
You know, to get
into the restaurant business
as an owner,
it take a lot of time,
a lot of money,
a lot of energy.
And one
of the great ways to do it
is when one of the owners
sells to the employees.
That's right, the employees
were working there
and now they own the joint.
This is Rustica
Eatery and Tavern.
Buttermilk fried chicken
going down.
Rustica is a wonderful place.
Spanish style meatballs.
They take really simple things
and add certain flavors to it
that make it unique.
[Guy] They call it
American food
with a European twist.
And by "they" I mean
Anna Weisenburger
and Chef Micah Leitel
who went from employees
to owners of the joint.
So the restaurant
was up and running,
owners wanted out,
and they said,
"Boom, here's turnkey.
Pay us for it."
-Yeah.
-I had to open
quite a few restaurants
before they ever started
looking this nice.
You got the
bar concept on one side
and the dining
establishment over here.
You can find something
that'll hit your taste buds
no matter what.
Pasta chorizo up.
Their pasta
feels like home.
So what
are we making first, chef?
Are we doing pasta?
For the pasta chorizo dish,
oil, water,
egg yolk, flour, kosher salt.
Let this mix up 10-15 minutes,
let it rest an hour.
Knead it,
put it through the sheeter
then we cut it by hand.
-Sharp hand.
-Yeah.
So now
we have to mix up the chorizo.
80-20 ground pork.
Paprika, smoked paprika,
dry oregano, cinnamon, cumin,
salt and pepper.
And then over here
on out wet...
Sherry vinegar, water,
Worcestershire sauce
and some minced garlic.
Put the wet in,
and then the dry.
-[Guy] On to the sheet tray.
-375 for roughly 15 minutes.
-Next step?
-Make the house tomato sauce.
Oil, onions,
salt and pepper, basil.
Chef on your stress level,
one to ten,
where are we right now?
I'm always at an 11.
Just like a duck,
cool on top
but he just paddling
like a mother
underneath the water.
[Micah] Oregano, garlic.
[Guy] Deglaze
with a little red wine.
And then we'll add in
our diced canned tomato.
Chili flakes, white sugar,
balsamic vinegar,
tomato paste,
then we'll blend it up.
Let's build it.
Shallots, garlic, chorizo,
deglaze with red wine.
House tomato sauce,
chicken stock,
roasted garlic, some cream.
Fresh pasta going in.
Salt and pepper.
[Guy]
Where did you learn to cook?
I started at a nursing home.
I worked my way up to
full-fledged lunch lady.
Don't see that
on everyday resumes.
[Micah]
Mount it with a little butter.
Fresh moz,
house spinach pesto,
and toasted bread
for the win.
For the win.
[chuckling]
I like this
crown of the pesto.
I am a big chorizo fan.
This eats like
Mexican chorizo, being loose,
but it tastes like
Spanish chorizo
because of the paprika
and the smoked paprika.
The pasta is nice and tender.
Delicious.
-Oh, good.
-I mean really good.
Got a pasta chorizo.
That pasta, it's dense.
Yet it melts in your mouth.
The chorizo's distinct,
and you can feather that pesto
into every bite.
It's really quite lovely.
Two pizzas,
Haole, Decoy.
[Guy]
What else do you do for fun,
besides
work here all the time?
Before I really
got serious about cooking,
I was DJing
all the time.
Scratching on the turntables.
What was your DJ name?
DJ Stupid Birthday.
[laughing]
That's it. I quit.
I have to go home.
But he's really getting funky
when we come back.
Bacon on the poutine.
I think everybody should
try their poutine.
[woman]
The bacon, the braised beef
everything is amazing
but I could just
pour more and more
gravy on it.
That's all right here,
right now,
on Diners, Drive-Ins
and Dives
-with DJ Stupid Birthday.
-Yeah.
Stay tuned. Shout out.
How did you come up
with DJ Stupid Birthday?
Came to me in a vision.
[Guy] Triple D's parked in
Moorhead, Minnesota
at Rustica
in one of the towns
oldest spots.
The building
was originally built in 1898.
-Okay.
-And it's been
a plethora of things.
[Guy] But now, it's all about
fresh takes
on classic dishes.
Poutine, going up.
Unlike traditional poutine,
it has fingerling potatoes.
The meat is like a roast.
Comfort food at its finest.
All right, chef.
Into one gigantic cut of beef.
[Micah] This is chuck shoulder
for our fingerling poutine.
-We're gonna braise all this?
-Yeah.
First we
gotta whack it into hunks.
[Guy] Wouldn't it be
a great arcade game?
Old Butcher Whack a Chunk.
Prime rib, boom! You're down.
Fillet, ding!
[Micah] Give it a good amount
of salt and pepper,
sear it
in a pan over high heat.
[Guy]
We'll hit all four sides?
Set up our braising pan.
Oregano, thyme, bay leaf,
add in the seared meat.
-You're sear-ious.
-I'm sear-ious.
Mirepoix, whole garlic cloves,
salt, tomato guts.
-Another fine culinary term.
-Red wine, chicken stock.
[Guy] And a lot
of red chili flakes.
We call it chili-braised beef.
[Guy] And how long
are we gonna roast that off?
-At least four hours.
-[Micah] At least.
-Shredding it up tender,
but not completely mushed.
-Correct.
Strain the jus, reduce it,
pour it over
the shredded meat.
[Guy] What are we doing
past this?
[Micah] We'll make some beef
gravy to serve on the side.
-Gravy goes on the side?
-Oh, yeah.
-Give you the pleasure
of pouring it over the top.
-Give me the... [laughs]
You, too, are a winner.
We got blended oil,
onions, oregano, thyme,
tomato paste, salt and pepper,
red wine to de-glaze.
Naturally.
Nice facial from that.
[Micah] Chicken stock,
beef base, balsamic vinegar,
chili flakes.
Tamari, but have it today.
Simmer, stain, add the roux
and it's finished.
-Last but not least, what?
-Fingerling potatoes.
-[Guy] Okay.
-Get them fried, crispy.
And why not just regular
french fries to make this?
Why be normal?
We put the chili beef
over the top
-with my own cheese.
-Hoo-da?
It's a cow's milk cheese
covered in paprika rind.
Move that to the salamander,
transfer it to
a serving plate.
Little parsley, bacon,
roasted garlic
and then the gravy.
Before today,
I'd never had a dish
made by DJ Super Birthday.
[laughs]
This right here...
I don't even know
if calling it poutine
is the right thing to do
because it's a very
elevated poutine.
Going to a regular
french fry potato
would have been simple.
You take it and mix it up.
Get it?
And throw in the fingerlings,
which is the royalty
of potatoes.
And then you make the gravy
that you really take some time
and energy to do.
This dish has got
a lot more sophistication
than you would find
in most poutines.
That is dynamite.
Poutine hitting the window.
The meat is rich, it's tender.
Gravy brings me back to home.
Folks tell me
you are the mayor.
I've been a fan of Rustica
for many years.
It brings a whole
new flavor to town.
-Did he just say
"flavor town"?
-[laughs]
Is this the mayor's subtle way
of trying to get me
out of office?
Scallops going up.
I love this place?
It's nice to have a place
to come where
I don't have to be picky.
Everything's perfect.
-Ladies and gentlemen,
DJ SB.
-[laughs]
[Guy] Coming up...
A culinary staple
in Marathon, Key...
And yet there's more, folks.
Serving up smash hits.
Briny, salty, herby.
It's really good.
I mean, it's really good.
So, I'm here in Marathon,
Florida, down in the Keys.
And you know what?
I know how you feel.
You're driving though
a tourist area like this,
and you got
all these restaurants
jumping out at you.
And you don't want
to play restaurant roulette.
No, you're on vacation.
You only get to eat out
a few times.
And that's why
you got Triple D.
I'm out here finding
the joints for you.
You're gonna dig this.
Herbie's Bar & Chowder House.
We got a whole-fry yellowtail.
There's no other place
here in the Keys
that I can get a better meal.
You know you're gonna
get kicked out of some joints
for saying that, now.
-It won't be the first time.
-[woman laughs]
Tuna tacos for you.
Hidden gem all day long.
It's one of those
mom and pop places.
[Guy] And the mom and pop here
are Shirley and Peter DeMaras,
who became empty nesters,
moved to Peter's home town
and bought this
Marathon Key landmark
that first opened in 1945.
This is like
the quintessential
postcard experience
of driving down the freeway,
and all of a sudden
you see this little hut,
and you're like,
"Boy, I bet you
that's a cool place."
It's an original
Florida shack,
is what they used to call it.
Food is always fresh,
always amazing.
Local style fish,
but a lot of stuff
you don't see everywhere else.
We have the chicken
smash potato.
The chicken and smash
is excellent.
It's two whole
chicken breasts, fried,
a baked potato
that he smashes,
and then it's topped
with this awesome
white gravy. I love it.
So, let's talk about
this chicken... Smash chicken.
-Chicken and smash.
We're gonna make the brine.
-Okay.
-[Peter] Water.
-Brown sugar.
[Peter] Kosher salt,
orange concentrate.
Orange concentrate?
Okay, I like it.
-[Peter] Lemon juice, ginger.
-Got it.
-A sea salt blend.
-Red chili flakes,
-little granulated garlic,
yada-yada-yada.
-Yep.
Rosemary, fresh thyme,
fresh sage.
Simmer for 15, 20 minutes.
-And how long
is this gonna brine?
-Overnight.
-What's our next step?
-Making a Buffalo sauce.
-Regular old Buffalo sauce
isn't good enough?
-Nope.
Hot sauce, the reaper sauce.
It's also another
style of wing sauce.
White pepper, chili,
cumin, ginger,
mustard, cayenne, turmeric.
[Guy] There you go
with that concentrated
orange juice again.
-And the butter.
-Okay. So, standard wing sauce
just completely freaked out
by you to the next level.
-Pretty much.
-Good talk.
[Peter] We have our buttermilk
and the Buffalo sauce
that we just made.
-[Guy] So, this goes in,
brines for another day?
-Yep.
-Next up.
-Caramelized onion
cream sauce.
When I come down to the beach,
hang out at the Keys,
I always like to have a nice
caramelized onion cream sauce.
It always says
bathing suit weather.
Put a speedo on,
you got the chain.
Why not? Let's roll.
[both chuckling]
Clarified butter, salad oil,
onions, sea salt blend,
-white pepper, garlic...
-And de-glaze
with a little white wine?
[Peter] Cream,
little bit of cream cheese.
And let that reduce.
[Guy] So, when can we eat?
-Tomorrow?
-Ooh, good watch.
-[Peter chuckles]
-Right past the freckle, huh?
-[Peter] We got to make
the chicken flour.
-Got it.
AP flour, basil, oregano,
cumin, thyme, ginger.
-Guess what?
-Garlic?
-White pepper.
-White pepper. Oh!
How did I miss that?
He teed it up.
-[Peter] Rub sage...
-Chili powder.
[Peter] Mustard, cumin,
coriander, parsley, paprika.
-Are we missing
salt there, or...
-Thank you.
So, now the chicken comes out
of that to high-gluten flour,
into an egg wash, into this,
and then we go to the fryer.
And all we do is just take
a regular baked potato,
smash it, throw it in there
when the chicken is cooking.
That's it. Top 'em with
the green beans, our chicken,
onion cream sauce,
scallions on top.
Bon appetit.
That chicken
is layered with flavor.
And it soaks up that brine
so it's super juicy.
And the caramelized onion
anti-Speedo gravy
is the piece de resistance.
I mean, that's what ties
this whole thing together.
But you got briny,
salty, herby,
a little bit of spice in it,
crunchy chicken.
Served on a luxurious potato.
This is a "stick to your ribs"
kind of a meal.
And it's really done
with real culinary process.
-Well done.
-Glad you like it.
Chicken and smash potato.
The breading is wonderful.
His fried chicken
is moist and crunchy
and perfect.
So, I grew up here,
and Herbie's was a staple.
The family environment
that we have here
is second to none.
Everything on the menu
is amazing.
[Peter] Cheeseburger
and para-fries.
Cheeseburger and para-fries
is basically a mound
of french fries
with a cheese burger on top
and extra cheese curds
that come from Wisconsin.
It melts in your mouth.
Okay, first step of this
cheeseburger and...
Para-fries.
We're gonna make a remoulade.
Garlic going in, horseradish,
roasted red peppers.
Add a little bit of
pickle juice, mustard, mayo.
-[Guy] Cajun blackened spice.
-A little cayenne.
-[Guy] A dash of hot sauce.
-A dash of hot sauce.
Just a dash. Now we're gonna
take it to another level.
-And it's gonna
be called the...
-Hack sauce.
So, more mayonnaise...
-Pickle relish.
You said there was
a beer cheese sauce?
The beer cheese sauce
is very much like our
caramelized onion cream sauce.
-From there we add...
-Mexican lager,
American pale ale,
cheddar cheese, provolone,
Havarti, American cheese,
seasoned salt.
-Final steps?
-We got the burger going,
little white pepper.
You and your white pepper.
[Peter] Some cheese, fries.
Lay the burger down on it.
Lettuce, tomatoes,
onion, pickles.
-[Guy] And cheese curds.
-Cheese curds.
And yet, there's more, folks.
[Peter] The beer cheese
that we made earlier,
the hack sauce on top.
[Guy]
Patty is cooked perfectly,
little caramelization to it.
I like the American cheese
on top. It's silky and melty.
All the crustifiation
from the veggies is perfect.
Where do you get
a little ridiculous?
Like, over the top
and, like, you know,
-running in the dark...
-Naked.
Running in the dark naked
is the cheese curds.
-It's really good.
I mean, it's really good.
-Glad you like it.
Cheeseburger and para-fries.
Got nice flavor,
nice juiciness to it.
The whole combo
works really well.
Spicy clam chowder.
Herbie's is the best.
This is what
Triple D's all about.
If it's funky, we'll find it.
-Nice job.
-Thank you.
That's it for this week.
But don't you worry,
I'll be looking for more
joints all over this country.
I'll see you next week on
Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives.
Hey, this is the Ice Man,
and I kick like Jackie Chan.
And here we are
in the 561, man.
This is Triple D.
Get it how you live it
with me.
[Guy laughs]
-[Vanilla Ice laughs]
-That was awesome.