You know, people ask me
all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint
you checked out
in that one city,
when you were doing
Triple-D, how they doing?"
You know, I don't know.
We should check it out.
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning.
'Cause Triple-D
joints have been blowing up,
and we're going back
to see what's cooking.
Like on this trip,
straight from the sea.
You really do got
the fresh tuna
all the way through.
And stuffed with cheese.
-It goes in like this?
-[Mike] Yeah.
[Guy] Look at that.
There's a shrimp
and pizza mash-up
in Marathon Key.
This is the kind of thing,
for me,
I'd come back
for in a heartbeat.
Grilled up goodness
in Philadelphia.
You take something simple
and you push up
another level.
Outrageous.
And in Saint Paul,
Minnesota...
I'd come back
and hang out with you.
Mmm. Mmm.
...we're three-peating
these stuffed burgers...
I got a hunch on this one.
...and out-of-bounds apps.
Here we go.
Little pickles and peppers.
This place rocks.
-Whoo.
-[laughing]
-Well, you can feed
the whole Fieri family.
-Feed everyone.
[Guy] Familiar faces,
new places,
and more
off-the-hook flavors.
This is Triple-D Nation.
All right, Hunter. We're here
to check out a joint
where this husband and wife
lost their restaurant
in Hurricane Irma.
-[Hunter] Oh, that's terrible.
-Yeah.
What, that little place
right there?
No, Hunter.
That's the gift shop
-for the restaurant.
It's right here.
-Oh, okay.
It's kind of like
a chain restaurant, right?
-[Guy] Why?
'Cause it's by a hotel?
-[Hunter] Yeah.
-[Guy] Nah, the locals say
it's the real deal.
-[Hunter] Oh.
This is Sparky's Landing.
Sparky's oysters.
[woman] We love Sparky's.
It's like coming
to a friend's house
that knows how to cook.
Plating, tuna club.
Lots of options
on the menu.
Everything from local foods
to wood-fire burned pizzas.
Really diverse,
but everything's amazing.
[Guy] That's what
I kept hearing
over and over again.
So, even though this joint
wasn't on Triple-D,
Hunter and I had to come
check it out.
It's a landmark here
in the Keys for sure.
[Guy] Started by Matt
and Carolyn Anthony
back in 2006.
All right.
Give me the run down.
Have you guys always
been in the restaurant
business or...
-Pretty much on and off.
-Off and on.
Where did you
learn to cook?
Picked it up over the years.
We like to play
in the kitchen.
Special up,
fire and ice, all day.
Let's go.
[Guy] But this wasn't
the original
Sparky's Landing.
No. The original Sparky's
was down there,
maybe 100 yards.
And you guys got
washed down here or--
[Matt] We got washed
and lost the building.
They had one
prior to Hurricane Irma,
just down the street.
So, this is the new
and improved
Sparky's Landing here.
[Matt] The people who
had this didn't want to
reopen it and run it again.
It was good for us.
This is about as good
as they come.
They found a bigger
and better spot.
It just has an atmosphere
that makes you feel like
you're on vacation
when you live here.
-What type of menu?
-[Matt] A little bit
of everything.
We used to have
flat breads over there.
Now we've inherited this
beautiful wood-fired oven.
-The oven was here when
you guys took over for this?
-[Matt] Yes.
Wood fired.
No conveyor belts here.
Some of their greatest dishes
come out of
that wood-fire oven.
We love their shrimp
and bacon pizza.
-Shrimp and bacon pizza.
-All right.
It's always our
go-to pizza here.
[Matt] Inspired by
just a simple barbecued
bacon-wrapped shrimp,
little bit of basil
and I took it
a little bit further.
[Guy] Tell me
about the crust.
It's a thin-crust
we make daily.
We use active yeast,
double zero flour,
salt, little bit of sugar
and little bit of olive oil.
Let it rise a little bit,
portion it up,
and assemble
the pizza to order.
We make our own sauce.
We use
San Marzano tomatoes,
basil, oregano,
garlic salt, coarse salt,
black pepper.
Give it a good blend.
Spread it out.
We shred our own
mozzarella cheese,
red onions, diced tomatoes.
Roasted garlic.
[Matt] We roast those here.
And our sustainable shrimp.
We cook off our own bacon
and chop it up.
We usually run
around 850, 900.
All right. Here she comes,
out of the oven.
Little fresh basil.
Shredded parmesan.
Shrimp and bacon pizza.
-[Hunter] You can't beat that.
-Shrimp's cooked perfectly.
Pizza's cooked dynamite.
The ingredients
are in balance.
So, really nice.
The Keys are known
for their Key West
pink shrimp
and they're
juicy and delicious
on the wood-fire oven pizza.
That's just charred perfectly.
[man] You don't find
this type of ingredients
on any other pizzas.
And they make
their own dough here
and they've a wood-fired oven.
Great crispy crust,
fresh ingredients.
It's amazing.
-I see you have a hotel
right in front of you.
-Yeah.
[Guy] Then you have
all these docks that
people can come up to.
[Carolyn] Yeah,
they come by boat.
-They don't have fun at all.
-[Carolyn laughing]
[Matt] Eight hundred
plus people
through here a day.
-Here? Really?
-Yeah. A day.
It's a hold on and go.
Hold on and go
is an understatement.
[man] Come by boat,
come by car.
Food is always fabulous.
Mozzarella prosciutto pizza.
Besides the pizza,
what do people go,
"Oh, when you go
to Sparky's,
-you gotta have the..."
-Tuna club.
-[Guy] Tuna club.
-Yes.
-You're nodding back there.
-Yeah, absolutely.
-Okay, that is the real deal.
-[man 2] It is.
Tuna club.
Up in the window.
[Matt] We use
sushi-grade tuna.
Little black pepper, salt.
We're gonna go
right into the pan.
About two minutes
on each side.
Just sear enough to get
the flavor to open up.
Get that off there.
Slice this one up.
This is already chilled
and ready to go.
Mmm!
[Guy] In what level
of panini machine
are you working
that you're getting
the bread down to this
wafer cracker crust?
Well, we do the bread
separate before we
start assembling.
Sourdough bread,
little bit of oil.
I just love how sturdy it is
and how everything just
goes out the back when you
bite down on it, you know?
[Matt] The aioli is
a lemon-basil aioli.
Ingredients are raw eggs,
roasted garlic and mustard.
And start blending
all that up.
Drizzle in our olive oil.
Canola oil, fresh basil.
Salt, black pepper,
lemon juice.
Tuna on two layers.
Roma tomatoes,
apple-smoked bacon.
Arugula, top with
the final piece.
Cut it up.
And there you have it,
our tuna club.
That's a tuna club
right there.
[Guy] When you think
about clubs, you definitely
don't think fresh.
You know, I thought it
was gonna be like
a canned tuna, you know.
-That's what we get a lot.
-It's the perfect way
to execute it.
Because then you're not
warming up the tuna.
I like the hot and cold.
You got a little bit of warm,
little bit cold,
-back and forth.
-Exactly.
And you really do get
the fresh tuna
all the way through.
-Yeah.
-Great.
[waitress] Tuna club.
The tuna is ahi grade.
It's so amazing.
Really crisp and clean.
It's like, every food
group right here.
It's a perfect mix.
They put that
apple wood-smoked
bacon on there.
They have got this
basil pesto mayo
that they make in-house.
It's the best tuna club
I've ever had.
Phenomenal. I was told
by couple of different people
that you were making
scratch-made food.
-It's dynamite.
-[Hunter] Yeah.
Sushi, pizza, sandwiches,
I mean, that's, uh...
-You can feed the whole
Fieri family.
-Yeah, feed everyone.
[Guy] Up next...
You fry your wallet,
it tastes good, right?
-There's me
losing my show.
-[all laughing]
[Guy] A neighborhood
hangout in Philly...
Grilled cheese
with pepperoni jam.
...daring to be different.
Fried peanut butter
and jelly.
I think we've just taken
a trip to flavor town.
[all laughing]
Triple-D is here
in South Philly to go to this
-funky little Tap Room.
You're just gonna--
-Wait, wait, wait, wait.
I said you could drive
the car. This isn't
Diner's, Drive-ins and Dives
on wrap.
But it definitely felt
like that.
Back when my buddy
Marc Summers tagged along
with this neighborhood bar
back in 2013.
Fat burger
going to the bar.
[Guy] These days
there's a new face
behind the line.
But they're still putting
a spin on the old classics.
We're here to check out
the South Philadelphia
Tap Room.
-Yeah, man. Check it out.
-Come on.
I come here so much
that I was
on that original episode.
You know, you're gonna come,
you're gonna have
some great food,
great times and great drinks.
I'll just keep coming.
[man] It's my favorite bar
in the neighborhood.
I don't live
in this neighborhood,
but I come here for this bar.
[Guy] That's what owner
John Longacre
was banking on,
when he opened the place
in 2003.
-This is like where it's at?
-It really is.
I mean, this is
as South Philly as it gets.
As we grew,
the neighborhood grew
and it kind of
just grew up around us.
It's, uh, really welcoming,
really open.
All your neighbors,
all your friends come here.
[Guy] Which is
why I rolled up
with a friend of my own.
-You know Marc Summers.
-I do.
-Extraordinaire.
-Since Double Dare.
You know what?
Marc lives here
in Philly, so...
I thought he would be
the perfect guy
to bring down
to South Philadelphia
to try the Tap Room.
So, Chef Scott,
what're you gonna make us?
My signature dish,
a fried peanut butter
and jelly sandwich.
You fry your wallet,
it tastes good, right?
-How bad could that be?
-See, there's me
losing my show.
-This is awesome.
-[all laughing]
I'll be over here.
You guys just
go right ahead.
So we're gonna
start with making
the French toast batter.
We have eggs,
fresh ground nutmeg, salt,
-black pepper.
-Really?
Vanilla extract, cinnamon.
Just whisk that
in a little bit.
Some sugar. Heavy cream.
Some whole milk.
Okay. [claps]
Peanut butter and jelly.
White bread, peanut butter,
and then strawberry preserves.
-[Guy] Okay, PB&J
is made.
-[Scott] Yeah.
So now we're
gonna just dip it
in the French toast batter.
What's this concoction
here of dust?
Ground Frosted Flakes.
Just pulsed
in a food processor.
Just on both sides.
Nice and crusted.
Oh, man, right.
How bad can that be?
Well, you get this
and you get
a free Spanx shirt.
[all laughing]
So how long on that side
are you frying it?
[Scott] Two to three minutes.
Bon appetit.
You go first.
Oh, my. [whistles]
Mmm.
I love that.
Take something simple.
Push up another level.
Outrageous.
-Corn Flake topping...
-[Scott laughs]
...is the piece de resistance.
Frosted Flakes. Corn Flakes
would almost make it healthy.
Do we look like
we're on some health tour?
[woman] It's not your typical
bar food. It's definitely
different ingredients,
spins on classics.
[Guy] And Chef
Doreen Demarco
is the fresh face
in the kitchen,
bucking that traditional
bar food.
Like, the grilled cheese
isn't your typical
mom's grilled cheese.
It's a really good spin
on a classic thing.
[waiter] Grilled cheese
with pepperoni jam.
Making pepperoni jam.
So olive oil.
Red onions, roasted peppers.
Hot cherry peppers.
Once that's in the pot,
we're gonna go in
with our pepperoni.
Brown sugar. Dried oregano.
Apple cider vinegar.
Cook it down.
Let your sugars break down
and caramelize.
It's gonna turn it into
a nice jam consistency.
It's gonna be perfect
for that grilled cheese.
Start off with
our garlic butter.
Get that toasted off,
going in with mild provolone,
Cooper sharp
and yellow cheddar cheese.
Get the cheese all
nice and melty
and really gooey.
Once that's done,
going in
with the pepperoni jam.
Wouldn't be the best
grilled cheese in Philadelphia
if it didn't have
the tomato lager soup.
Start with a little bit
of oil in the pot.
Onions. Jalapenos.
Garlic, plum tomatoes.
Sugar. Little bit of salt.
Our oldest German lager.
Bring this up to a simmer.
Finish it off with some butter
and ready to serve.
Grilled cheese,
tomato lager soup.
Grilled cheese
with pepperoni jam
and tomato lager soup.
[man 2] It's like
a pepperoni pizza
sandwich almost.
Buttery, delicious,
soup that goes with it,
perfect sweetness,
cut the heat
of the pepperoni.
It's just an amazing
grilled cheese. Delicious.
[bell chiming]
Understanding
what our customers want is
probably the most
important thing.
And Doreen is...
She's got her finger
on the pulse.
Grilled pork chop,
macerated fruit.
You're gonna get
some things that you
can't find anywhere else.
You can expect really
great out-of-the-box food.
-Three grilled cheese,
all day, ready to plate.
-[waiter] Enjoy.
This is a place that
people got to check out.
-You're gonna get a lot
of folks coming to see you.
-[John] Thank you.
We opened another place
the American Sardine Bar
about eight blocks north.
And a couple of years later,
we opened Second District
brewery,
couple of blocks that way.
So, yeah, we've a whole little
network down here.
-Can I say something?
-Please go ahead.
I think we have just
taken a trip to flavor town.
[both laughing]
[Guy] Coming up,
it's Saint Paul.
Guy's Big Bite.
Enjoy it.
[Guy] A local joint
with the bomb burgers.
Let's try the Matt Birk,
the Lodge burger.
[Guy] We're coming back for...
The gnocchi super supreme
double-decker cheeseburger
in special sauce.
...three times.
And a bacon cheeseburger.
Mmm, that's a tasty burger.
Back in 2007,
one of the first places
we shot Triple-D
here in Saint Paul, Minnesota,
was at the Nook.
You remember?
Two local boys take over
this long-standing
burger bar joint.
And you guys
loved the place.
Well, then what happens?
Tragedy.
The place burns down.
But they picked themselves up
by their bootstraps,
opened a second joint
and they're still
stuffing burgers
all these years later.
This is the new
and improved Nook.
Guy's Big Bite.
Enjoy it.
I saw the initial episode
of Triple-D.
Black sear, up.
[man] Really showcased
everything that was
so good about
why I come here.
This place rocks.
Flamin' hot curds up.
[woman 1]
It's very homey in here,
definitely a nook.
[woman 2] And this place
has been around
here since 1936.
Long before my time.
[Guy] And long before owners
Ted Casper and Mike Runyon
were around, too.
When we took over this place,
we were 20 years old.
I mean,
we were really young.
What did you guys think
you were gonna do
with your lives?
Weight lifter.
[laughs hysterically]
Ted and I have been doing this
obviously for 20 years now.
The first Diners and Drive-Ins
was like,
what, 15 years ago?
It was absolutely fantastic.
What's the specialty
of the house?
The juicy.
You fold up
a piece of cheese
and stuff it inside
of the burger.
-That's like a thing
around here?
-Yeah.
The stuffed burger,
you know, that's
the Minnesota staple.
[Guy] Look at that.
That is juicy.
Dude, I'm telling you.
That's a tasty burger.
Is this the
number-one seller?
That's the
number-one seller.
Yeah.
We've got
a few different options,
stuffed with different cheese.
Let's try the Matt Birk.
The Lodge burger.
[Mike] Have you ever heard
of the whole story like,
Guy comes in and orders
everything on the menu.
The gnocchi super supreme
-double-decker cheeseburger
in special sauce.
-[Mike] Yeah.
And a bacon cheeseburger.
[bell dings]
He literally did it.
-Mmm. Oh.
-[Ted laughs]
-Look at that.
-It's big bite.
Mmm-hmm. Mmm!
Hmm. Look at that thing.
That is a ton
of flavor.
[Mike laughing]
[man] If you're coming here,
get yourself a burger.
But definitely,
don't sleep on the apps.
All right. Kissing booth.
We got the Irish fries.
I had the flaming hot
cheese curds.
They look pretty intimidating.
Flaming hot cheese curds.
So we got our dry mix
for our beer batter.
This is our extra pale ale.
Local, Minnesota.
Food coloring.
The red pops. It signifies
that this is gonna be
a hotter dish.
We got these cheese curds.
They're like buffalo
cheese curd spice.
Pinch of flour.
These are
our ghost peppers.
Toss that around.
All right.
Now we'll batter them up.
Coat them well.
And they're ready
to be dropped.
We serve that
with the local spicy honey.
These are our flaming hot
cheese curds.
Flaming hot cheese curds.
[man] It's got that
very subdued hot
on the front end
and then,
on the back end,
that upper cut is coming.
Very nice
one-two punch.
Good heat. It kind of hits you
after a couple of seconds.
-It's like bam.
-Yeah.
So how is Nookie
at lunch?
-It's really good.
-Really?
There's numerous people
that come in on the daily
and they're always like,
"Hey, we're a big
Guy follower. We go
to all of his restaurants."
-[Guy laughing]
-[Matt] Where's my wallet?
People from all over
the country are finding us
easily now.
Enjoy, you guys.
[Guy] But a game changer
almost made that impossible.
That was devastating.
[Guy] Before coming back
even bigger.
What's this monster?
Mmm!
Two kinds of cheese.
That's gotta be a hit.
Anywhere I go
around the country,
I really like to get
my hands on what
the locals like to eat.
Up here in Minnesota,
it's what they call
stuffed burgers.
And I had one
back in 2008
at the Nook
in Saint Paul.
-You know what I'll say
I like about that?
-What's that?
-Everything.
-[Mike] Cool.
[Guy] But in December of 2010,
an electric fire almost
wiped out the whole thing.
It was devastating.
It was a hard go.
So, is it over?
No, it ain't over.
It ain't over until
Casper and Runyon
say it's over.
And when I
came back in 2011,
it definitely wasn't over.
So, you rebuilt the whole
entire place?
Yeah, the bar's
the original bar,
back bar's the original bar.
What the firefighters
did is they came through
the whole place,
took the pictures off the wall
before they started chopping
and spraying.
So a lot of what you see
on the wall today
is stuff from
the original bar,
which is great.
It gives me goosebumps
that you say that.
Guy made a special effort
to come out and revisit us
after we got it reopened.
It really felt like,
you know, he cared.
[Guy] All right. So,
give me the rundown.
What do we got?
-[Mike] That's the
Guy's Big Bite right there.
-It's the Guy's Big Bite.
That's the burger
we came up with,
when we heard the news
he might be coming
to visit us a second time.
So we got
our heads together
and said, "What's one
of our best sellers
right now?"
And that's
the Paul Molitor burger
which is a Juicy Lucy
stuffed with pepper
jack cheese.
-[Guy] And it goes
in like this?
-[Mike] Mmm-hmm.
-Like that?
-That.
-Wow.
-You gotta kind of
ball it up though.
Squeeze.
It's a work out...
in every cheese.
We decided to enhance
that with...
what's better than
a little meat on top of meat.
So we threw
some roast beef
on top of there.
[Mike] And bacon.
'Cause who
doesn't like bacon?
-Yeah, Meat with meat
and meat.
-Yeah.
[Ted] We added
the cheddar jack
combination to resemble
the hair.
You know, right on top.
[both laughing]
I gotta hunch
on this one.
That Italian beef
on there, man.
Two kinds of cheese.
Stuffed burger.
That's gotta be a hit.
[waiter] Guy's Big Bite.
[man] The Guy's
Big Bite burger,
it's got the molten hot
cheese in the center.
It's got a ton of flavor.
[Ted] Yeah,
the Guy's Big Bite?
-It's got its own following.
-Yeah, yeah. For sure.
[Mike] There's a million other
things that we're constantly
adding. You know there's--
-A million?
-Well.
You know, every month
we have burgers of the month
that come out,
appetizers of the month,
that we try out new things.
[waiter] Pickles and peppers.
Dynamite. It's a good
light addition
for an appetizer.
[waiter] Pickles and peppers.
What we do here is,
we'll start with
our pickle planks.
Some peppers.
Add a little bit of flour
in there.
Little bit of Cajun seasoning.
That's the Minnesota kick.
I'm adding the beer batter.
And then we will
just kind of mix
with our hands here.
Then we'll fry it
for couple of minutes
and we should be golden.
We'll plate them all up.
Those are the Nook's
pickles and peppers.
Here we go.
Little pickle and peppers.
[woman] Love a fried pickle.
So having the peppers
in there too
is like a nice twist.
There were
pickle and peppers.
Now they're gone.
[chuckles]
-Were you guys best buddies
before this started?
-[Ted] Oldest buddies.
There's a picture of us
in our diapers.
[Mike] I think
we're very thankful
we have each other.
That's pretty hard to have,
you know,
two friends have come together
and made something out of it.
And with our success,
we were able to open
a second location
with more space.
Got your food here.
These guys
do a phenomenal job
in the kitchen,
both this place
and Shamrocks.
Flamin' hot curds are up.
Is there a fireman's discount
on December 14?
December 14th,
all firefighters eat for free.
We kind of lost
our beloved Nook.
When the firefighters
come back on that day,
they eat for free.
-What do the regulars say?
-You know, they miss
the diveyness of the old Nook.
-But--
-Well, you two
are still here.
That's divey enough, right?
I'd come back
and hang out with you.
We can drop this thing
down a few notches.
-Grilled pork chop.
-Bacon-wrapped scallops.
So, you got
anything else for us?
But these
aren't the only places
I got to get back to.
We got a long list
to get through, next time
on Triple-D Nation.
Right here, on Diners,
Drive-ins and Dives.
[all laughing]
[laughing] Oh, God.
-He did it like
a WWE wrestler.
-[all laughing]
All right. Next up.