You know, people were
asking me all the time,
"Hey, Guy, that one joint
you checked out
in that one city
when you were doing Triple-D,
how they doin'?"
You know, I don't know,
we should check it out.
Over the years,
I've seen and tasted it all.
This is ridiculous, dude.
But it turns out,
it was only the beginning,
'cause Triple-D joints
have been blowing up
and we're going back to see
what's cooking.
Like on this trip...
Something old.
All day long, girl.
And something new.
The world is going
to know about us.
There's a vegan version
of Creole classics
in Oakland.
-Now, okra's no jokra.
-[laughs]
Hearty home cooking
in Pennsylvania.
People gonna come down here
looking for these.
And in Miami...
-I've been invited late
to this one.
-[all laughing]
A never before seen
Haitian joint's
got me pikliz by the pound.
I can get it in my mouth
fast enough.
Familiar faces, new places,
and more off the hook flavors.
This is Triple-D Nation.
So, every time I roll
into Miami,
it's the South Beach
Food & Wine Festival.
It's to go visit
my buddy Marcus'
new restaurant Red Rooster,
I called Patrick,
now this is the dude
that owns Bogosse,
those fantastic shirts
that I'm always wearing.
Well, he's that guy,
and he's our Haitian
connection,
the bomb food,
where are we going?
-Kasa Champet.
-You're gonna love this.
-Where's my shirt?
-[all laughing]
Seafood legume, ready.
[woman] You can't have
Haitian food anywhere else
in town
as authentic and as good
as Kasa Champet's.
The flavors are so different
from every other kind
of ethnic foods
that there are around here.
[man] It feels like
you're in Haiti,
when you're here.
I love it.
-You're a Haitian food fan?
-Yes.
Okay, I'm a Haitian food fan,
and this is my Haitian food
connection
because I can't typically,
one, I don't know where
I'm going,
and two, I don't know
how to order off the menu.
So, I always call Patrick.
Well, now I can call
Gerline Brutus,
and just because
she didn't start out
on Triple-D,
doesn't mean
her Haitian flavors
shouldn't be recognized.
[woman] It's a good thing
that Guy came here
because we do want to share.
[laughs]
Now, the world is going
to know about us.
-How are you doing?
-How are you?
Nice to see you.
Gerline's been feeding
her loyal customers
since 2005.
Hi, guys, how are you?
Giving her daughter
Jessie Julmice, plenty of time
to learn the ropes.
[Guy] What does the name mean?
Kasa is house
and then the Champet in Haiti,
we always have
Champet party.
-Hmm, I haven't been
in any Champet party.
-Yes.
-Did you get the invitation?
-I didn't get the champet.
-I don't even what
Champet party.
-Champet party...
-Yes.
-is, like, you know,
they do it, like,
from Thursday to Sunday.
All day, all night.
-I've been invited late
to this one.
-[all laughing]
The Haitian culture,
on the weekends,
they like to gather
for entertainment, for food.
So, what are we going
to try on the menu today?
We must have Griot.
[Jessie] And here
is your Griot.
I love the griot.
The griot is a staple
Haitian dish, it's fried pork.
To make the griot,
first thing we do,
we have to wash the pork
with salt, vinegar,
fresh squeezed lime,
sour orange juice.
We're going to mix it up,
wash it with water,
strain it.
Now, it's ready to season
with our epis.
The epis is a mix
of fresh ingredients,
Italian parsley, green pepper,
red pepper, fresh garlic,
yellow pepper, white onion,
green onion,
scotch bonnet, hot pepper,
seasoned salt.
We're gonna mix that up.
We're going to mix it
with our pork.
Now, it's ready to boil,
we're going to add thyme
and parsley,
when it's done boiling,
we're going to fry
our pork for five minutes,
and it's going to be nice
and crispy.
Griot in the window,
ready to go.
-And this is the griot?
-The famous griot.
[Guy] The fried pork.
It's like the national dish
of Haiti.
Haitian food
is flavorful, spicy,
it's food that feeds the soul.
Oh, this is so good.
The pork is tender,
everything's seasoned
correctly.
The griot is fantastic,
but the pikliz, mmm,
that's lights out.
Pikliz is a sweet,
kind of spicy slaw,
we put this on everything.
[Gerline] Now, we're going
to make the pikliz, cabbage
and carrot,
seasoned salt,
sour orange juice, salt,
blended scotch bonnet pepper,
give it the nice heat,
green, yellow pepper,
white onions,
a lot of vinegar to make
the pikliz juicy.
Add the lime juice.
Now we're going to mix it up.
What the pikliz does,
it breaks everything down,
because there's heat there,
but the vinegar
kind of makes it light.
-You get that, like...
-[Marcus] That bite.
-Mmm.
-[Patrick] That little kick.
-[Guy] Pikliz should be
in a jar.
I want to have that to go,
I want to two gallons of it.
It's tangy, it's a little bit
sweet, but it's unique
to the Haitian cuisine.
Dynamite.
And what's this one?
That's chicken.
[Patrick] Poulet en sauce,
they call it.
-[Guy] That's really good.
-So tender, you know.
First thing we do
for the chicken,
we wash it with citrus,
we're gonna add
the citrus, garlic, moyo,
our homemade epis,
mix it together,
the chicken is boiled
fried, for five minutes,
and then we're gonna put it
in the gravy.
Chop onions, green pepper,
red pepper, marinara sauce,
stir it for, like, one minute.
Now, we're gonna add
the chicken, already fried,
coat the chicken
with all the gravy,
add water, boil.
Buttered pepper,
thyme and parsley,
let it simmer,
it's ready to plate.
The poulet en sauce is ready.
-You got to try the chicken
with the sauce.
-It's tasty, right?
-Tender?
-So good.
I can't get it my mouth
fast enough.
[Jessie] Lamb sauce.
[woman] Thank you.
It's flavorful, sizzling,
well fried,
it's a hallmark dish
for the Haitian community.
The chicken is ready,
I need two pikliz.
And I need more plantains,
please.
[Guy] I mean,
it's all dynamite.
I'm not kidding ya.
I think Gerline is really,
really going to be happy
to know that.
What I want to know is,
can I get,
can I get it delivered?
[all laughing]
-Coming up.
-I can't
-make her sweat in here.
-[laughs]
-A surprising spot
in Oakland.
-Huh?
Nobody?
Great Bayou classics,
with a twist.
This food makes you feel good.
So, I think on Triple-D
by now, you come to expect
the unexpected.
So, I'm here in Oakland,
California in an area known
as Jack London Square,
so, what am I here
to check out? Wait for it,
wait for it, wait for it,
exactly what
you're not expecting,
a vegan joint.
And since I was there
in 2016,
It's only gotten more
surprising,
with ghost kitchens haunting
the whole city.
Steak burger with fries.
This is Souley Vegan.
So, I have a jambalaya
for you.
I grew up eating soul food
and to be able to get it
still as a vegan is amazing,
you don't miss the meat
at all.
All the food is super healthy,
but very satisfying
and hearty at the same time.
[Tamearra] Okra gumbo up.
[man] Kind of fun seeing
Guy Fieri's picture up
on the wall,
it kind of gives
that little stamp of approval.
[Guy] That's something owner
Tamearra Dyson
definitely deserved.
How did this all start?
I turned vegan at 17
and started cooking
at about 18 years old,
I just want to introduce
vegan food to people
in a way that they can just
understand it.
Now my sister Morgan
was a vegetarian, vegan,
and so this is something
that's near and dear
to my heart.
-Excellent.
-So, when I heard about
your place.
-[Tamearra] Yes.
-When I heard that
this was going on.
-[laughs]
-So close to home.
Um, I said,
I gotta come see it.
[Tamearra] The fact
that we are 100% plant based,
and, Guy, he was so open
to, you know, come here
and explore what we do
and then love it.
He's my brother.
-Yeah.
-Well done, girl.
Hey, y'all.
Oh, boy, let's talk about
some okra.
So, I am going to make
my spices first
-which I call love spice.
-Okay.
[laughs]
Granulated garlic.
Sea salt.
-Sea love.
-[laughs]
-Black pepper. [laughs]
-Hot love.
-And paprika.
-I got nothing to say.
So, we're just using this
as the base
for my okra gumbo.
-Got it.
-Okra gumbo is a staple
in Louisiana,
and so I just love
to put my own
little vegan funk on it.
Red and green bell pepper.
[Guy] Would you put
that many peppers
and onions in a dish?
-[laughs]
-You had me at hello.
[Tamearra] Sea salt.
-Coarse black pepper.
-"Coarse" you do.
Cayenne.
So, now I'm gonna add
my okra.
Now, okra's no jokra.
[laughs]
[Tamearra] Corn, seaweed,
love spice.
Love spice.
Tomatoes.
-[laughs]
-The whole scam here,
pork chops are going in now.
-Andouille sausage next.
-[laughs]
[Tamearra] This is marinated,
seasoned tofu.
Now, how long is this going
to cook down?
Thirty to 45 minutes.
We serve that with?
-Basmati rice.
He just kind of chewed
for a while and I was like,
"How is it?"
I can't make her sweat
any longer.
-[laughs]
-I can't make her sweat
anymore.
You did a great job.
There's a tremendous amount
of flavor, you've got...
Good heat.
-All day long, girl.
-Right on.
Thank you. [chuckles]
[man] We pretty much tried
everything on the menu,
like, twice or three times
at least.
[Tamearra] Sample platter up.
Gator bites, table 24.
I love the gator bites,
those are actually
our favorite.
In Louisiana,
gator is huge.
My family is Louisiana Creole,
so I wanted to do a play
on Gator bites,
so we're calling these,
"Deez Ain't Gator Bites,"
we have our base,
onions, sea salt,
some minced garlic, jalapenos,
black pepper and cayenne,
some of our love spice,
cilantro, tomato puree,
garlic powder,
we're going to go ahead
and blend it up.
Drop a few teaspoons
in our bowl,
add our vital wheat gluten.
-Your who?
-Vital wheat gluten,
it's the protein
of whole wheat.
-That's what I thought it was.
-[laughs]
I'm gonna add a little bit
of our broth,
knead this for a little while,
then we're going to break
this off into little chunks,
we're going to bake them off
and then after they're done,
we're going to coat them
in our wet and our dry batter,
along with some mushrooms
and these are going to fry up
for about two
to three minutes,
and then they're going
to be ready to serve.
Deez ain't gator bites.
It's just a different texture,
it's the crunch and the depth
and all my favorite things.
Hey, y'all.
Super flavorful,
you feel very satisfied
after eating it.
-You got another one?
-I do.
-You have another trick?
It's not even a trick,
but she's fooling everyone.
I've never had a real po' boy.
Never had a real po' boy?
Oh, this should be good.
We'll be back right
after these messages.
Welcome back, hanging out here
in Oakland, California
at Souley Vegan,
I know everybody sees me
on Triple-D and they say,
"Oh, that Guy that eats
a bunch of nachos,"
I like my nachos.
But, this food
makes you feel good.
And so does Tamearra's story.
I was in the medical field,
and I worked in
the industry department.
Whoa, whoa,
wait, wait, wait.
-[laughs]
-Wait, wait, wait.
We kinda just slid by that...
probably bad pun.
I mean, I can see
where the end trail is.
-Uh-huh.
-Um...
[laughs]
Huh? Nobody?
That's fantastic.
So you leave
the medical field?
Left the medical field,
I started selling food
-at the farmers' market.
-Single mom at the time?
Yeah.
To quit a really good job
in the medical field...
-Yeah.
-...to go sell food
at an open market,
to come and take an abandoned
restaurant building
and to do it all
at a very young age,
when it's meant to be,
it's meant to be.
Oh, absolutely.
[Tamearra] It's pretty amazing
that Triple-D is here again,
after it aired, we just got
so many phone calls,
"We love what you do
and we're proud of you."
Here's your po' boy and fries.
It was pretty amazing to see
the feedback,
definitely, the po' boy,
people were just kind
of going crazy over that.
Have you ever had a po' boy?
I've never had a real po' boy.
Never had a real po' boy?
Oh, this should be good.
[laughs]
So first, we're gonna make
the seitan,
vital wheat gluten flour.
Liquid amino acid,
blended seaweed.
-Okay.
-Fresh garlic, love spice.
Form this into a ball.
Now does this need
to set up, cure, marinade?
-Yeah.
-Amalgamate?
[Tamearra] It boils
for about 45 minutes
to an hour,
we're gonna cut these
into cubes.
There's some texture there.
We're gonna dredge it,
wet batter first.
[Guy] What's in
the wet batter?
Um, bleached flour,
love spice, water,
and then we have
the dry batter which
is flour and cornmeal.
-We're gonna fry this off?
-That's right.
Now, what are we gonna
make 'em?
Vegan mayo.
-Great.
-So we're starting
with silken tofu,
coarse black pepper,
yellow mustard,
granulated garlic,
sea salt and put it in the
refrigerator overnight...
-Okay.
-...for it to set.
-Po' boy time.
-All right, so I have
my Dutch Crunch bread
that I've toasted and then
I have my vegan mayo,
mustard, tomatoes,
shredded lettuce.
-I like it.
-And then I have my seitan.
A little bit more mayo,
squeeze a little lemon juice.
It weighs about 10 pounds.
I don't know exactly
what po' boy I'm having,
but there's no question
that's a po' boy.
[Tamearra] Po' boy
with fries up.
Everything is always
very fresh
and vibrant flavors,
a lot of variety among
the flavors of the dishes.
And this jambalaya is great.
Two jambalayas up.
We are going to go ahead
and add some oil,
because we're gonna
saute onions,
red and green bell pepper,
celery, fresh garlic,
black pepper and cayenne,
cilantro
and there's some love.
Gonna mix that in really well
and add our tomato puree,
garlic powder, basmati rice.
After it's ready to go,
we're just going to top it
with our unbattered
and unfried gator bites.
So this is
our Jazzn' Jambalaya.
It's got a really rich
peppery flavor, not too spicy.
-It's just right.
-It's delicious.
Just because it's not meat
doesn't mean you can't have...
real food.
Since, Guy, you know,
has approved it, so to speak,
we definitely gained a lot
of longtime customers,
and even share with us,
"You know, I first came
to this restaurant
after I saw it on Triple-D."
In 2020, I've ventured out
into that territory
of ghost kitchen,
and so it's pickup
and delivery only,
including this location,
we'll have six locations.
[man] It's great to see
that Souley Vegan is,
you know,
taking the show
on the road
and, and opening up
and then exposing
other communities
to this wonderful food.
The profile of what
you're doing for vegan food.
-Mm-hmm.
-You're the real deal.
-[laughs]
-I mean look at you,
and now Food Network's here.
-And now Food Network is here.
-O-M-G.
-Huh?
-[laughs]
Up next, right outside
of Pittsburgh.
I would break my keto
for this pasta.
A neighborhood joint,
pushing pierogis and pasta
and knocking it out
of the park.
-[exclaims]
-[laughs]
He wows the crowd.
When you're looking for
a great neighborhood bar,
well, you're probably looking
for a place that's been there
for a while,
so here we are
in Blawnox, Pennsylvania.
Well, back in 2008,
I found this old school bar
cooking down home
Pittsburgh staples.
And people are still
flocking in for comfort food.
At the Starlite Lounge.
Pierogi Plattner,
one of each.
The ambience here,
it's welcoming,
it's not pretentious,
it's wonderful.
People come and they want
to come back.
I come over once or twice
or even three times a week.
I do come for two things,
good food and Moondog.
[Guy] AKA Ron Esser.
Why do they call you Moondog?
I actually used to play music
for a living
and that was my stage name.
He has another name,
"Lionhead."
I could actually do
a killer version
of the Lion
from The Wizard of Oz.
-[imitates Lion]
-[laughs]
He wows the crowd.
He's just a special guy
and he represents Pittsburgh,
friendly and welcoming.
So, what are we making?
Chicken Diablo.
Who made the recipe?
The devil, I guess. [laughs]
This is the cast
of characters?
Peppers, some onions,
get the chicken going,
I grow these peppers
and then I can 'em.
[Guy] Yellow peppers.
[Ron] Just a little bit
of marinara.
-Sriracha.
-Do you want some
of that in yours?
Just add a little taste
of it in there.
Just cut it up a little bit,
throw it in,
-throw a little pasta
in there.
-Wow.
-That's a portion, huh?
-That's good.
Look at that.
Now, we add
a little parmesan cheese
on top.
Hmm.
The pepper and the chicken
and the spice really go
together great.
When you work in a kitchen,
you're like an artist.
Well, you know,
the chef paints
his masterpiece
upon the canvas of the plate.
That's right.
You know, you can only make
the same painting
so many times,
then you have to come up
with a new idea.
With the Diablo, we used
a lot of different,
fresh ingredients.
All I want to do
is find more of those peppers.
We took it to the next level
with our new creation.
Here's your shrimp cavatappi,
enjoy.
I have shrimp cavatappi,
It's delicious.
I would break my keto
for this pasta.
Add a little olive oil,
shrimp, salt,
some white pepper,
garlic, shallots, mushrooms,
fresh spinach, tomatoes,
red peppers,
and our feta cream sauce
which is basically
roasted red pepper soup
with feta cheese added to it.
So, now we add
our cavatappi,
put it in the bowl,
now we add our shrimp, basil,
and then top it
with some parmesan cheese.
Shrimp cavatappi.
The tomatoes and the shrimp,
it's a perfect combination,
it's not too spicy
and the flavor just pops.
It's creamy, it's delicious,
just enough spice
comfortable level,
but not enough where you have
to drink all your beer.
It's a very colorful dish.
You're a very colorful guy,
Moondog.
When Triple-D came
the first time,
they said we were gonna
get busy.
They didn't say
we were gonna get crushed,
but, hey, man,
it's a blessing.
We saw the pierogis
on the episode
and decided to stop in.
I think one of the things
that's interesting about
is pierogis,
that you're handmaking those.
That might be
a Pittsburgh thing,
I don't know.
So I get a glob
of this mixture,
now I get some
more flour down.
-Looking pretty good
at this point.
-It looks beautiful.
-Is it gonna be
a pierogi party?
-Yeah.
[Guy] Now what happens
to 'em now?
[Ron] We boil them for about
five minutes.
Pretty enormous.
[Ron] These are real pierogis.
There you go, look at that.
Hmm, I'm tellin' you that
is about simple goodness
right there.
We still have them
and they're great.
They love them.
But you better get ready.
People gonna come down here
looking for these.
It's comfort food.
That's part of Pittsburgh.
Pittsburgh style food,
I would say is very hearty,
very filling.
It's just home cooked,
it's Pittsburgh food.
Here's your meatloaf, Sarah.
Today, I got the meatloaf,
it's always excellent.
You start with
ground meat, eggs,
so we get it nice and gushy.
Gushy as a culinary term.
So, then we add salt
and pepper,
marjoram, mustard,
thyme, bread crumbs,
some onions,
and you just mix all
this up,
we're going to press it
in the pan, so we form it,
and then we're going
to turn it over,
put it on a sheet tray,
then we add ketchup
and bay leaves,
we're going to bake this
for about an hour at 325,
and then cut about
three nice pieces,
some gravy over top.
And there, you have
our wonderful meatloaf dinner.
[woman] It's juicy,
it's thick.
I don't even want to say
it's as good as mom's
'cause it's probably better.
[man] It tastes like
home cooked meatballs.
I would say
it's a very rich flavor.
I have had most of the dishes
that they serve here,
and this is one
of my favorites.
[man 2] I have so much food
in this place.
You get the bang
for your buck.
I'll tell you this, Moondog.
It's not what I would
expect to find at a lounge.
If you're gonna cook,
you might as well
do it, right?
-Go big or go gnome.
-Right.
Dirty Cajun fries,
table 54.
And that, ladies and gentlemen
is what makes up
the Triple-D nation.
-Enjoy.
-Thank you.
And I can't wait to see
what other places
have been up to.
-Cheers.
-Cheers, guys.
We'll catch you next time.
If I called it my love spice,
there would be a whole,
big problem with that,
but when you're cute,
and you can go,
"I call it love spice."
But not if I called it
love spice.
If I called it love spice,
"Oh, he's a weirdo."