We had such potential,
such promise.
But we squandered our gifts,
our intelligence.
Our blind pursuit
of technology
only sped us
quicker to our doom.
Our world is ending.
But life must go on.
Wait! I'm a friend.
Yes, I always hoped.
Aha!
So much thought.
The details... Carved wood.
Molded copper.
You can't speak.
Uh-huh.
Come with me.
Here.
Stop!
Somethings in this world
are better left where they lie.
But if you know
where to look,
these ruins are
full of riches.
Friend?
Wait, wait.
Almost there.
Friend.
Friend?
What's this?
You found it!
He's...
He's always drawing this.
Are... Are we alone?
No, no.
Go.
Get in the can. Go on.
Here, kitty, kitty.
Why don't you finish
what you started, with me?
It's all right, I'm not going
to hurt you.
You're safe now.
Where am I?
With us. I never expected
to see an other one.
There, that should hold.
If 2 were here, he would have
done a better job.
I wonder where
he's gone to.
I was with him.
2? Where? Out there?
What was he...
Keeping secrets from me, I see.
I was coming
to tell you.
What's this?
I... I found him
in the emptiness.
What were you
doing out there?
I...
You'll lead the beast straight back to us!
But...
How many times have I told you?
The beast. That's what took 2!
If we hurry, we can save him.
If the beast took him,
that's the end of it.
But he was still alive.
No! We have rules!
Our new guest
seems confused.
Perhaps I can help you
achieve some clarity.
It didn't kill him?
Quiet!
Hey.
Hold on.
When we woke in this world,
it was chaos.
Man and machine attacked each other
with fire and metal.
Look out behind you!
I found others.
There's a path ahead.
Follow me.
The gas killed everything.
I led us here
to sanctuary.
And here we waited
for the war to end.
Slowly the world
became silent.
The only thing that remains now
is the beast.
So we stay hidden.
And we wait for it,
too, to sleep.
But where did it come from?
Why is it hunting us?
Questions like
that are pointless.
We need to protect ourselves,
keep ourselves out of danger.
Too many of us have
already been lost.
But he isn't lost.
Why aren't you listening to me?
2 chose his own path!
I suggest you avoid
making the same mistake.
Go to the watchtower
and take our guest with you.
This was the first thing
we built together.
We can still go after him.
Us? But he could be
anywhere out there.
That's where it took him.
Out towards those three tall shapes.
Oh, no.
We can't, not there.
We have rules.
Why do you
listen to 1?
A group must have a leader.
But what if he's wrong?
Come with me.
I can't do it alone.
I...
I... I can't.
But wouldn’t he
have come for you?
I...
Wait.
We're going to
need a map.
Actually, I don't mind
having one eye. It's easier for me.
Allows me to concentrate
on just one thing at a time, you know?
Why was he out here alone?
Where's this tunnel?
I don't know!
Wait!
We should go back!
We can't.
The beast.
It's too dark.
We can use that.
Wait.
2 would be impressed.
We'll find him.
You know,
you're just like him.
You forget to
remember to be scared.
Can I wait here?
Oh.
Why would it
bring him here?
Two!
I knew you would come.
I thought...
Seven!?
I don't believe it!
You've come back!
I never left. You finally decided
to join the fight.
You dropped this.
Where've you been hiding?
Rusty, hacked-together,
shoddy pile of...
We did it. We did it.
Remarkable. I never thought...
Wait!
What are you doing?
We don't know what it is!
Oh!
No! Two!
Whoa!
Jump!
Hurry! Quick!
What are you waiting for?
Keep up! Come on!
I knew we shouldn’t have come!
Why? Why did you do that?
I didn't know! I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
What were you thinking?
What is it going to do?
I know where we
can find answers.
Is this what it was like?
Keep up!
Oh! They've been here?
The whole time?
Twins.
They've been hiding here.
Lost in the past.
Looking for answers.
Oh!
They're cataloging.
Whoa!
We need your help.
We awakened something.
No. I awakened something.
Something terrible.
That's it!
Today, the Chancellor
presented the latest advancement
of technological
wizardry to the public.
Comrades, today dawns a new era.
Let us praise
this new technology.
Welcome to the age
of the Machine!
It will create new machines
in its own image!
Machines of peace
that will usher in
a glorious new era
of wealth and prosperity
for the state!
Residents are advised to
pause for a public address.
Science has turned its
sinister hands against us.
People of our mighty state,
join me in repelling
the iron fist of the Machine.
But the thing
that woke it,
it was round and imprinted
with strange shapes.
The shapes corresponded.
It fit perfectly into the Machine
as if it were made for it.
That's what 6
always draws!
6?
2 collected his drawings.
He was always
studying them.
I have to see them.
What? Go back to 1?
So he can lock us away
while this nightmare awakens?
Never.
Where did he put them?
Uh... They're here somewhere.
Uh...
Here. Here. Here they are.
Right?
You awakened what?
You fools! I warned you!
He warned you.
Now you've put us all
in unimaginable peril.
And may I ask,
did you manage to save 2?
Of course not!
By following
this witless folly,
you've endangered
everything we work for!
Why was 2 sent out
to begin with?
I sent him to scout.
That doesn't
make any sense.
You don't send
the oldest out to...
Look, we need to figure out
what's going on.
The source, the source...
Go back to the source.
This is it. This is what
awakened the Machine.
What do you know
about this?
Ah, You can't be trusted.
I won't allow you to endanger us further.
Subjugate them!
Sub... What?
You illiterate cretin!
Take their belongings!
Hey!
You're nothing
but a coward.
How dare you challenge me!
I, who kept everyone
safe all these years.
Ever since you got here,
everything has been unraveling.
You're a curse, a fool,
guided by pointless queries!
And you are a blind man
guided by fear!
Sometimes fear is
the appropriate response.
Whoa!
Quick!
9!
Go!
Nine!
Keep going! I'll find a way down!
Come on!
Let me try that again.
Oh!
The cable! Cut it!
Grab on!
Grab those wires!
Your cape!
Let it go!
I can't!
Do it now!
Well, you owe me a cape.
Oh.
There will be more,
won't there?
It's not safe here.
Stand lookout.
I'll search out
a safer retreat.
Oh!
Ah!
Ooh!
Oh!
Oh.
What? What is it?
The source.
The thing that
woke the Machine.
Go back. Go back.
Back to where?
Dark science.
What good does this
useless rubbish do us? Forget it!
You know something.
What do you know?
I know enough to leave
their ancient evils to molder.
Look what they've left us with.
Leave it be, I say!
But you,
always asking questions!
So many pointless questions!
Probing. Pushing. Like 2!
He always had to know too much!
I was right! You did send him
out to die!
He was old. He was weak!
Sometimes one must be sacrificed
for the good of many.
You coward!
Seven!
Your path takes us
to catastrophe.
We have to go back.
Back? Where?
To the first room
where I woke.
Hmm?
Can't he see his way
only brings trouble?
I mean, what good
comes from his path?
I know what we need.
I... I know what's right.
No.
No, no. It can't be!
No! No!
No!
Find her!
Don't look in the eyes!
Five!
Seven!
Nine!
No!
We have to go after them!
What? 8? Where's...
Where's 8?
That thing has them! It's taking them
back to the Machine!
Then it's too late.
We... We have to
get out of here.
We must try to find
another safe place.
No more hiding. We're going
after them! All of us.
Need I remind you of the outcome
of your last heroic venture?
I can't let this
happen to them.
I'm going in.
I'm coming with you.
No. I need you here.
If I don't make it back,
destroy it.
Wait! How?
So then, let's hear it.
What's your brilliant scheme?
We’ll need a full barrel.
Hey! Over here!
Where are they?
It's been too long.
We have to do it now.
No! They need more time.
Help me pull it down!
They're coming!
Help! Help!
No! Not yet!
Let go, you fool!
Five!
We're coming!
Now!
Good riddance.
It's done.
Sound.
Thank you.
Hmm.
The Machine!
Everybody, the Machine!
Run away!
No! No!
There's nothing we can do!
No! No! No!
No!
They... They've
been trapped!
To the bridge!
No! They're trapped!
They're trapped inside!
Six, come on!
Get off the bridge!
No! Stop!
You mustn't destroy it!
Get away, Six!
Don't destroy it!
They're trapped!
They're inside!
Run!
Jump!
Go back to the first room!
He'll show you the source.
It must be destroyed.
No. No, we can't!
Didn't you hear him?
They're trapped inside.
We can still save them.
What? How?
We have to find the source.
It holds the answer.
We need to destroy it.
But there's still a chance!
We're out of time.
Nine, they're gone.
You're wrong.
Nine...
Let him go.
Greetings, Nine.
It had such promise,
my Great Machine.
It was meant to be
an instrument of progress,
of creation.
That was the agreement
our Chancellor failed to honor.
Though the fault is
hardly his alone to bear.
The Machine was born
purely of my intellect,
which I now know
was not enough.
My creation was hopelessly flawed
and indeed dangerous,
for it lacked the human soul
and could be easily corrupted
by those who controlled it.
That is why I'm
making each of you.
You are all that's
left of humanity.
You are all
the pieces of my soul.
Together, you and this device
shall protect the future.
Look closely and
remember what you see.
Fire!
Quickly!
I now know the truth!
The Scientist!
It's the Scientist.
He's the source!
He gave us his soul.
We are him.
Load the cannon!
Stop! You’ll destroy
the talisman!
It's too late!
Quick. Quick, get in.
We need to take the talisman
from the Machine.
It can be used against it.
I'll lure it to me,
and then you'll have a chance.
No. Nine, don't do this.
What if you're wrong?
I'll show you how to use it.
It'll be okay.
This is the sequence.
No!
Please, we can't
do this with out you.
They all died
because of me.
I started this and
now I need to finish it.
They left us nothing.
Nothing.
Why do we have to
right their wrongs?
Sometimes,
one must be sacrificed.
No!
You did it!
No, I didn't.
Not yet.
They're free now.
What happens next?
I'm not sure, exactly.
But this world is ours now.
It's what we make of it.