(Rattling)
(Humming)
(Electronic chittering)
(Clacking)
(Distorted computer noises)
(Noises stop)
(Chattering, indistinct)
The food is terrible. Worst
shit I've ever seen, man.
Parker: What you say? You
got any biscuits over there?
Ripley: I keep seeing corn bread.
- I am cold.
- Still with us, Brett?
- Right.
- Oh, I feel dead.
Anybody ever tell you
you look dead, man?
(Mouthing words)
Parker: Oh, yeah, right.
Now, I just forgot something, man.
Uh, before we dock,
I think we oughta discuss
the bonus situation.
- Right.
- Brett and I, we think we oughta
- We deserve full shares, right, baby?
- Right. You see, Mr. Parker and I...
feel that the bonus situation has
never been on, uh, an equitable level.
Well, you'll get what you're
contracted for like everybody else.
Yes, but everybody else gets more than us.
(Monitor beeping)
Dallas, Mother wants to talk to you.
Huh? Yeah, I saw it. Yellow
light's for my eyes only.
Okay, get dressed, huh?
- Parker, come on.
- Can I finish my coffee? Thank you.
It's the only thing good on this ship.
(Chattering continues)
(Buzzes)
(Beeping)
(Clacking)
(Electronic chittering)
Dallas: Morning, Mother.
(Beeping, whirring)
(Voice over radio, indistinct)
- Right.
- Okay.
Plug us in.
Thank you.
Where's Earth?
Well you should know.
It's not our system.
Scan.
(Sighs)
(Whispering) I can't believe this.
Contact Traffic Control.
Ripley: This is commercial towing
vehicle Nostromo out of the Solomons.
Registration number:
1-8-0-niner-2-4-6-0-niner.
Calling Antarctica Traffic
Control. Can you read me? Over.
Commercial towing vehicle
Nostromo out of the Solomons,
registration number...
Ripley: Nothing.
Kane: Keep trying.
Ripley: Calling Antarctica Traffic Control.
Do you read me, Antarctica? Over.
I found it. Just short of Zeta II Reticuli.
(Ripley continues on radio)
- We haven't reached the outer rim yet.
- That's hard to believe.
Lambert: What the hell
are we doing out here?
I don't know. What the hell
are you talking about?
- That's not our system.
- I know that.
(Loud rumbling) Parker: Listen, you ever
notice how they never come down here?
I mean, this is where
the work is, right?
Well, it's the same damn reason
we get a half share to their one.
Our time is their time.
That's the way they see it.
Parker: No, but-Listen, man.
Brett: Same old shit, man.
Parker: I think I know why they
don't come down here.
It's because of you. You
don't have no personality.
Parker: Wonder what they want now.
What's going on down here?
Um, you happen to be in my seat.
Can I have it?
- Yes, of course.
- Thank you
Ash: I'm sorry.
(Wiping)
Parker: What's happenin' now, baby?
Well, some of you may have
figured out we're not home yet.
- We're only halfway there.
- What?
Mother's interrupted the
course of our journey.
- Why?
- Yeah.
She's programmed to do that should
certain conditions arise. They have.
Ripley: Like what?
- It seems she has...
intercepted a transmission
of unknown origin.
- She got us up to check it out.
- A transmission? Out here?
Dallas: Yeah.
- What kind of a transmission?
Acoustical beacon. It repeats
at intervals of 12 seconds.
- S.O.S.?
- I don't know.
Human?
Unknown.
Brett: So what?
Kane: We are obligated
under section eight
I hate to bring this up, but, uh,
this is a commercial
ship, not a rescue ship.
- Right.
- And it's not in my contract
to do this kind of duty.
And what about the money?
If you wanna give me some money,
I'll be happy to oblige.
- Man's right.
Dallas: Parker...
- Let's go over the bonus situation...
- Can we... Can...
- Sorry, can I say something?
- Let's talk about the bonus situation.
There is a clause in the contract
which specifically states...
any systematized transmission indicating
a possible intelligent origin
- must be investigated.
- I don't wanna hear it.
- We don't know if it's intelligent.
- I wanna go home and party.
Parker, will you just
listen to the man?
On penalty of total
forfeiture of shares.
No money.
You got that?
- (Chuckling) Well, yeah.
- All right, we're going in.
Yeah. We're goin' in, aren't we?
(Clears throat) Can we
all hear that, Lambert?
(Beeping)
(Electronic pulsing)
(Pulsing continues)
(Scoffs)
Good God.
Doesn't sound like any
radio signal I've heard.
- Maybe it's a voice.
- Well, we'll soon know.
Can you hone in on that?
What was the, uh, position?
6550-99.
(Beeping)
(Clacking)
(Beeping) All right.
It found the quadrant.
Ascension: Six minutes, 20 seconds.
Declination: 39 degrees, two seconds.
Okay. Put that on the screen for me.
(Computer beeping and whirring)
Lambert: All right.
Well, that's it.
It's a planetoid.
1200 kilometers.
Kane: It's tiny.
Dallas: Any rotation?
(Beeping)
Lambert: About two hours.
What about gravity?
Point eight-six.
You can walk on it.
(Lambert over radio)
Approaching orbital apogee.
Mark 12, 11
Equatorial orbit nailed.
Lambert: Nine, eight
seconds on descent.
Kane: Grids energized. Fields focused.
Lambert: Five. Four
(Dallas, indistinct)
- D.O.R.'s on line.
- How's the status on the lifters?
Give me an A.C. pressure reading.
Forty-eight seconds and counting.
(Ripley over radio) SR-1 stable.
Prepare to disengage from platform.
Lambert: Mark, 20 seconds. Eighteen, 17
Twelve, 11, 10,
nine, eight, seven,
six, five, four,
three, two, one, lock.
Disengage.
Ripley: Umbilicus clear.
Money's safe. Let's take her down.
Parker: Nine, eight, seven
Kane: Roll 92 degrees port yaw.
Ripley: Prime to port.
Ripley: Prime ventral. Prime dorsal.
Kane: Down a degree.
Lambert: 39,000 meters.
(Dallas over radio, indistinct)
Ripley: Turbulence.
(Voices over radio continue)
Locked and floating. You can drop
us anytime now. We'll catch you.
Inertial damping's going off. Hold on,
people. There's gonna be a little bump.
(Metal creaking loudly)
What the hell was that?
Pressure drop in intake three.
Must've lost a shield.
Let's go with it.
(Voices over radio continue)
Mm...
Dropping off now.
Still dropping.
Here we are. We've got it.
Take her down.
(Ripley over radio)
Approaching perigee...
Navigation lights on.
Ash: We've got 5-3 still out.
No problem. Just down 11%.
Grid status okay.
Lambert: Nine,
eight, seven, six,
five, four, three,
two, one.
Kill drive engines.
(Loud crunching sounds)
(Alarm blaring)
Dallas: What the hell happened?
(Additional alarm sounds)
(Hissing sounds)
(First alarm silences)
Somebody give me a straight answer!
Is the hull breached?
I don't see anything.
We've still got pressure.
Hit the screen.
(Loud hissing and roaring)
(Wind howling)
(Parker over radio)
Secondary load sharing unit...
is out.
Three to four cells are gone.
- Is that it?
- No, hold on, uh,
We can't fix it out here anyway,
and, uh, we need to reroute
a couple of these ducts,
wouldn't you say, uh, Brett?
Dry dock time.
Dry dock. Tell her
we need to dry-dock.
Look, we couldn't fix it out here anyway.
We gotta reroute all these ducts,
and in order to do that
we've got to dry-dock.
(Sighs)
What else?
(Parker over radio)
Some fragments kicked up,
and we've got to clean it all
out and repressurize it.
(Ripley over radio) How
long before we're functional?
- Look, what is- What-
- It's 17 hours, tell her.
- At least 25 hours.
- Yeah.
Ripley: Get started on the floor panel.
I'll be right down.
What the hell's she comin' down here for?
She better stay the fuck out
of my way, I'll tell you that.
I'd like to see what she's
gonna do when she gets here.
Parker: Shit.
(Wind howling)
Dallas: Any response yet?
Ash: No. Absolutely nothing.
Except the same transmission
every 12 seconds.
All the other channels are dead.
(Clicks switch)
Kick on the floods.
- We can't go anywhere in this.
- Mmm.
Well, Mother says the sun's
coming up in 20 minutes.
- How far are we from the source of transmission?
- Uh, northeast.
Just under 2,000 meters.
Walking distance?
(Laughs)
Well
- Can you give me an atmospheric?
- Yes.
Ash: Oh.
It's almost primordial.
There's inert nitrogen,
high concentration of carbon
dioxide crystals, methane.
I'm working on the trace elements.
- Anything else?
- Yes.
It's...
rock, lava base,
and deep cold.
- Well below the line.
- Mm-hmm.
Kane: I'll volunteer to be
in the first group to go out.
Dallas: Yeah, that figures.
You too, Lambert.
- Swell.
Dallas: Better break out the weapons.
(Wind howling)
Lambert: I can't see a goddamn thing.
Dallas: Ash, are you receiving?
(Voices over radio, indistinct)
(Mouths words)
Ash: Good contact on my board.
(Dallas over monitor) Clear and free.
Keep the line open. Let's go.
Hey, Ripley.
Hey, Ripley, I wanna ask you a question.
If they find what they're lookin' for out
there, does that mean we get full shares?
Don't worry, Parker, yeah. You'll
get whatever's coming to you.
Look, I'm not gonna
do any more work...
- till we get this straightened out.
- Brett,
- you're guaranteed by law to get a share.
Parker: What?
- Why don't you just fuck off.
- What?
Brett: What'd you say, Rip?
If you have any trouble,
I'll be on the bridge.
Parker: Hey, Ripley, come back here!
(Chuckling)
- Son of a bitch.
- What's the matter?
Lambert: Can't see a goddamn thing.
Kane: Quit griping.
- I like griping.
Dallas: Come on. Knock it off.
(Clacking)
(Ominous silence)
(Quiet hissing)
(Respirators hissing)
Ash, can you see this?
Yes, I can.
I've never seen anything like it.
Dallas: Very bizarre.
(Heartbeat pounding)
(Suit electronics beeping)
Kane: You said it.
Dallas (Breathing heavily):
All right.
Moving on to second... position.
Lambert: What is it?
Let's get out of here.
Kane: We've got this far.
We must go on.
We have to go on.
Will you say that again? Shit.
Shhhhit.
Dallas: Ash, as you can see,
it's kind of hard to describe.
I'm going back to the console.
(Voices continue over monitor, distorted)
(Dallas, faint) Seems to be solid.
To walk- You can on it.
(Dallas continues, voice distorted)
Approaching the entrance...
(Dallas continues, indistinct)
Dallas?
(Respirators hissing)
Kane: Come on down here.
Something different down here.
I don't know what it is, but...
See if we can get up that wall. If we
can get up that wall, we can find out.
Amazing.
Dallas: Alien life-form.
Looks like it's been dead a long time.
Fossilized.
Looks like it's grown
out of the chair.
Huh...
Bones are bent outward,
like he exploded from inside.
Lambert: Wonder what happened
to the rest of the crew.
Let's get the hell out of here.
Hey, Dallas, Lambert,
come on over here.
Come on.
- What do you got?
- See what you make of this.
(Clicks switch)
Ash.
That transmission- Mother's
deciphered part of it.
- It doesn't look like an S.O.S.
- What is it, then?
Well, I- it looks
like a warning.
- I'm gonna go out after them.
- What's the point?
I mean, by the time it
takes to get there, you'll...
they'll know if it's a
warning or not, yes?
(Clicks switch)
(Exhales deeply)
(Wind howling lightly)
(Winch motor whirring)
Dallas: You okay down there?
Dallas: Can you see anything?
Kane: Uh... a cave.
A ca- a cave of some sort.
But I...
Well, I don't know, but it's like
the goddamn tropics in here.
(Whispering)
What the hell is this?
The cave is completely enclosed,
and it's full of...
leathery objects, like...
eggs or something.
(High-pitched humming)
There's a layer of mist...
(High-pitched tone)
just covering the eggs
that reacts when broken.
(Dallas over radio)
Kane? You all right?
I'm okay. All right.
I'm okay. I just slipped.
Appears to be completely sealed.
(Hisses)
Wait a minute, there's movement.
It seems to have life.
Organic life.
(Creaking sound)
(Screeching)
(Wind howling)
(Wind intensity increases)
(Wind howling loudly)
(Computer clacking)
(Dallas over radio) You there, Ripley?
- I'm right here.
(Beeping)
Okay, Ripley, I'm at the
inner lock hatch now.
(Ripley) Right.
(Decontamination sprayers hissing)
- Ripley. We're clean. Let us in.
- Right here.
- What happened to Kane?
- Something has attached itself to him.
We have to get him to
the infirmary right away.
What kind of thing, I need
- a clear definition.
- An organism! Open the hatch.
Wait a minute. If we let it in,
the ship could be infected.
You know the quarantine procedure-
24 hours for decontamination.
He could die in 24 hours.
Open the hatch.
Listen to me. If we break
quarantine, we could all die.
Look, would you open the goddamn
hatch? We have to get him inside.
No. I can't do that.
And if you were in my
position, you'd do the same.
Ripley, this is an order.
Open that hatch right now.
- Do you hear me?
- Yes.
Ripley, this is an order!
Do you hear me?
Yes, I read you. The answer is negative.
Inner hatch opened.
(Whirring)
(Helmet cracks open)
My God.
(Tail tightening)
What the hell is that?
Jesus Christ.
What is that, man?
Hey, how the hell is he breathing?
Is he still alive or what?
Why don't you guys freeze him?
How come they don't freeze him?
What's going on in there?
- What the fuck is going on?
- You bitch!
Jesus Christ! Hey! Hey!
- You would've left us out there.
- Break it up.
Dallas: Ripley, when I give
an order, I expect to be obeyed.
- Even if it's against the law?
- You're goddamn right!
Maybe she has a point, you know.
Who the hell knows what that thing is?
How are we gonna get that off him?
- How are we gonna get it off?
- Now just a minute, just a minute,
I'm gonna get some instruments here.
My God.
(Mumbling)
Right. I'll make an incision here.
- Try and remove one of the digitals from...
- You're gonna do what?
(Clearly) Finger. I'm gonna try and
get his finger off. Just a minute.
(Continues, indistinct)
No, that's not...
It's tearing his scalp!
(Ash) I know!
It's not coming off without
tearing his face off with it.
We'll have to take a
look at him inside. Right!
How come they don't freeze him?
(Parker shouting) How come
you guys don't freeze him?
All right, you can take your mask off.
What's it got down his throat?
I would suggest it's
feeding him oxygen.
Paralyzes him,
puts him in a coma,
then keeps him alive.
Now what the hell is that?
- Well, we gotta get it off of him.
- Just a minute,
just a minute.
I mean, let's not be too hasty.
We don't know anything about...
it.
Now, we're assuming it's feeding
him oxygen. If we remove it,
it could kill him.
I'm willing to take that chance.
Let's cut it off him now.
- You'll take responsibility?
- Yes, yes,
I'll take responsibility.
Now, get him out of there.
Dallas: Where do you wanna do this?
We'll make an incision just
below the knuckle there.
- Right here.
- Stand by.
(Whirring)
Ash: Good God!
Dallas: That crap's gonna
eat through the hull.
That thing's gonna eat through
the goddamn hull. Come on!
Brett: What's going on?
This way.
Next deck.
(Sizzling)
Parker: There it is.
Don't get under it!
Don't get under it.
Looks like it's stopping.
Take a look at this, man. Yeah.
Brett, give me- what do you got, a
pen there? Give it to me, quick.
Come on! Come on!
Brett: Don't get any on your arm.
(Melted material glops)
It stopped.
Don't see anything like that
except, uh, molecular acid.
It must be using it for blood.
It's got a wonderful defense mechanism.
You don't dare kill it.
What about Kane?
- Here's your pen back.
- Brett: What do we do now?
Leave Kane to Ash. You get back to work.
Well, what...
(Electrical crackling)
Okay.
Try it.
(Motor cranking)
Damn it. I thought sure that was it.
Try it again.
(Cranking)
I feel like I've been
in this place a month.
We shouldn't have landed in
this place in the first place.
Shouldn't have landed on
this damn ball, I know that.
Well, the sooner we patch this
thing up and get out of here,
the sooner we can go home.
This place gives me the creeps.
Ripley: That's amazing. What is it?
Ah, yes, it is. Um...
I don't know yet.
(Grunts)
Did you want something?
Yes. I, uh...
I'd like to have a little talk.
How's, uh, how's Kane?
He's holding. No changes.
And, uh, our guest?
- Well...
- Hmm?
Well, as I said, I'm still...
collating, actually, but, uh,
I have confirmed that he's got an outer
layer of protein polysaccharides.
He has a funny habit of
shedding his cells...
and replacing them with...
polarized silicon,
which gives him a
prolonged resistance...
to adverse environmental conditions.
Is that enough for you?
That's plenty. What
does it mean?
(Pen clatters on table)
Please don't do that. Thank you.
I'm sorry.
(Ash breathes deeply)
Well, it's an interesting
combination of elements,
making him a...
tough little son of a bitch.
And you let him in.
I was obeying a direct order, remember?
Ash, when Dallas and
Kane are off the ship,
I'm senior officer.
Oh, yes. I forgot.
You also forgot the science
division's basic quarantine law.
- No, that I didn't forget.
- Oh, I see, you just broke it.
Huh?
Look, what would you have
done with Kane? Hmm?
You knew his only chance of
survival was to get him in here.
Unfortunately, by uh,
breaking quarantine,
you risk everybody's life.
Maybe I should've left him outside.
Maybe I've jeopardized the rest of us,
but it was a risk I was willing to take.
That's a pretty big risk...
for a science officer.
It's, uh, not exactly out
of the manual, is it?
I do take my responsibilities
as seriously as you, you know.
You do your job...
and let me do mine, yes?
(Wind swirling)
♪ (Classical)
Ripley: Where's Dallas?
Ash: In the shuttle.
♪ (Continues)
(Beep)
(Clicks switch)
Dallas...
Ash: I think you should
have a look at Kane.
Why?
Something's happened.
Serious?
Interesting.
(Clicks switch)
(Music stops)
Ripley, meet me in the
infirmary right away.
Ripley: Where is it?
Ash: Well, I don't know.
I mean, we ought
to try and find it.
Dallas: Yeah, let's check it.
(Slow breaths)
Dallas, please be careful.
(Loud crash)
Oh!!
Sorry.
(Quietly) No, not in
the corner! Psst.
Have one of these.
Just in case.
Kane? Dallas?
(Screams)
You okay?
I didn't see it.
Was it in the overhead?
- What? It was up there somewhere.
- My God.
Dallas: Cover up the damn thing, will ya?
Ash: No, wait a minute...
That's alive!
That's a reflex action.
Well, we've gotta have a look at this.
Excuse me.
Ash: Seems dead enough.
Ripley: Well, good. Let's get rid of it.
(Scoffs) Ripley...
for God's sake,
this is the first time
that we've encountered
a species like this.
It has to go back. All sorts
of tests have to be made.
Ash, are you kidding?
This thing bled acid.
Who knows what it's gonna
do when it's dead.
Think it's safe to assume
it isn't a zombie.
Dallas, it has to go back.
Well, I'd soon...
as not burn it at the stake, but
you're the science officer,
it's your decision, Ash.
Dallas!
How come I've got to change my
mind? The decision's been made.
I'm not trying to change your mind,
Dallas. I just want you to listen,
Will you listen to-
(Groans)
Just tell me how you can leave
that kind of decision to him.
Look, I just run the ship.
Anything that has to do with the science
division, Ash has the final word.
- How does that happen?
- It happens, my dear,
because that's what the
company wants to happen.
Since when is that standard procedure?
Standard procedure is to do what
the hell they tell you to do.
What's happening with
the repairs? How's it going?
They're pretty much finished now.
Why the hell didn't you tell me so?
Well, because there's
still some things left to do.
Like what?
Well, we're blind on
'B' and 'C' decks.
- The reserve power system's blown-
- Ah, now that's a bunch of horseshit,
We can take off without that.
Yeah, we can. You think
that's a good idea?
Look, I just wanna get the
hell out of here, all right?
(Engines roaring)
Dust in the intakes again.
Number two's overheating.
Spit on it for two minutes,
would you, for Christ's sake?
Ripley: We're hot.
We're getting hotter.
Engine room, red clip status?
- One kilometer on ascension.
Ripley: Engage artificial gravity.
- Engaged.
- I'm altering the vector... now.
Dallas: Inhibit C.N.G. control.
- Struts retract.
Parker: Struts retracted.
Lambert: Max stress to fifth overload.
Dallas: Ease it back.
Dallas: She's great. Beautiful.
Walk in the park!
When we fix something,
we stay fixed, don't we, Brett baby?
Brett: Right.
Parker: What I think we
should do is just freeze him.
I mean he's got a disease,
why don't we stop it where it is?
He can always get to a doctor
when we get back home.
Right.
Whenever he says anything, you say
"right", Brett. You know that?
Right.
(Sighs)
Parker, what do you think? Your staff
just follows you around, says "right".
- Just like a regular parrot.
- Yeah. Shape up.
- What are you, some kind of parrot?
- Right.
Oh come on. Knock it off! Kane's
gonna have to go into quarantine
- That's it.
- Yes, and so will we.
Well, how about a little
something to lower your spirits?
Thrill me, will you, please?
Well, according to my calculations,
based on time spent getting
to and from the planet
Just give me the short version.
- How far to Earth?
- Ten months.
- Oh, God.
- Right.
(Intercom buzzes)
Yes.
Ash: Dallas, I think you
should come and see Kane.
Has his condition changed?
It's simpler if you'd
just come and see him.
Ripley: We're on our way.
Right.
(Laughter)
Lambert: How are you doing?
- (Coughs) Thank you.
- How you doin'?
Um, terrific. Next silly question.
(Laughing)
Oh, thank you.
Do you remember
anything about the planet?
What's the last thing
you do remember?
Huh?
(Sighs)
I remember some...
horrible dream about...
smothering, and...
And-anyway, where are we?
- Right here. (Laughs)
- We're on our way home.
Yeah, back to the old freezerinos.
(Everyone chuckling)
Could I have something to
eat before we go back?
I-I need something myself.
Yeah, right. One more meal
before bedtime. I'm buyin'.
- Hey, that's a break.
- Big time.
(Chattering)
(Parker) What happened...
What happened to this guy...
(Chattering continues)
(Heartbeat sounding)
The first thing that I'm
gonna do when I get back...
is to get some decent food.
I can dig it, man. Let me tell you,
I've eaten worse food than this,
- but then I've tasted better, you know what
I'm sayin'? - The other one over there.
Well, you pound down the stuff
like there's no tomorrow.
I'd rather be eatin' something else,
but, uh, right now I'll stick with the food.
Kane: Well, at least you
know what it's made of.
No, man, I don't wanna talk
about what it's made of.
- I'm eatin' this just to-
(Gagging)
What's the matter?
- The food ain't that bad, baby.
- What's wrong, Kane?
(Gagging, retching)
Are you choking?
What's wrong?
(Coughing, gasping)
What? What?
- This is serious.
- Kane, what's the matter?
(Gagging, gasping)
It's okay!
Hold him down! Hold him
Ash: Get the spoon in!
(Groaning)
Damn it!
- Get it into his mouth!
- I'm trying!
(Screaming)
(Agonized scream)
(Lambert screams)
(Agonized grunts)
(Bones breaking)
(Screeching)
(Screaming)
Lambert: Oh, my God! Oh! (Crying)
No! Don't touch it!
Don't touch it!
(Screeching)
(Dishes clatter)
Brett: Dallas?
Dallas?
- Yeah.
- Anything?
No. You?
Nothing.
- You see anything?
- No.
(Loud clank)
Dallas: Inner hatch sealed.
Anybody wanna say anything?
(Air rushing)
This is just an ordinary
prod, like a cattle prod.
It's got a portable battery.
It's insulated all the way
here, all the way up to here.
Just make damn sure nobody puts
their hand on the end of it.
(Loud arcing)
It shouldn't damage the little bastard,
unless its skin's thinner than ours.
But it will give him
a little incentive.
Now we just have to find it.
I've taken care of that. I've
designed this tracking device.
You just set it to search for
a moving object, like so.
Hasn't got much of a range, but when
you get within a certain distance,
it'll start to give off a signal.
What's it key on?
Micro changes in air density.
Give me a demo.
(Whirring) See?
Again. (Whirring)
Got ya.
Two teams. Ash...
Lambert and I,
Ripley, you take Parker and Brett.
Now, anyone see this thing,
you catch it in the net...
that Parker's holding on his lap.
Parker, I don't want any
heroics out of you, all right?
Catch it, put it in the
air lock, get rid of it.
Now, channels are open on all decks.
I want you to communicate, keep
in touch at all times, all right?
Let's go.
Ripley: I thought you
fixed 12 module.
Brett: We did.
I don't understand it.
Parker: The circuits must have burned out.
- What do we got here?
- Dammit, hold your light over here, would ya?
Yeah, that's it.
- I don't know if this is gonna work.
- RIght
If I could just put this-
put this in there.
- Right.
- Oh, damn it.
Brett: Check the insulation.
Parker: Oh, shit!
(Electricity sputtering)
(Tracking device whirring)
Brett: Steady.
- According to this, it's within five meters.
(Indistinct whispering)
Ripley: Micro changes
in air density, my ass.
(Equipment beeping)
It's within five meters.
Parker: Be careful.
(Beeping continues)
Ripley: Christ.
Parker: Don't do that.
- Don't creep up on me with that thing.
Ripley: You guys, stick together.
(Click)
(Beeping stops)
(Tracker twittering)
- Don't fail me now.
Parker: What?
- What is it?
- Parker, Brett, it's in this locker!
Where?
Brett: Here, take this.
Get over there and get the net.
- Get it?
- I got it. I got it. I got it.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
All right, Parker. When I say.
All right. Now.
Easy.
(Hissing)
(All chattering)
- Wait! Don't let him go!
What the hell are
you doing, man?
It's the cat.
(Laughing)
Hey, look, now. We had to bag it, man.
Now we might pick it up
on the tracker again.
- I'll-I'll-I'll-
- Go and get it, man.
All right. You get him.
We'll go on.
(Sighs)
(Scoffs)
Here, kitty!
Here, kitty, kitty!
Enough of that kitty crap.
Jones?
Jonesy?
Here, Jonesy.
(Meowing)
(Cat meows)
Jonesy?
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
(Meowing)
Here, Jonesy.
(Whispering) Jonesy?
(Faint meowing)
Here, kitty, kitty.
(Panicked meowing)
- Shh.. No, don't...
(Shoes clanking on deck)
(Liquid splashing)
(Chains clinking)
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
Here, Jonesy.
Jonesy.
Kitty, kitty.
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
Jonesy?
Hey. Hey. Come on, Jonesy.
Come on, baby. That's a kitty.
That's a kitty. Come on, baby.
- That's a kitty.
- (Hisses)
Hey, hey. I'm not gonna hurt you.
Come on.
(Snarling)
(Creature hissing)
(Screaming)
Brett!
Parker: Brett!
(Shuddering breath)
Whatever it was, it
was- it was big and
You're sure it took him
into the air shaft?
Disappeared into one
of the cooling ducts.
No question, it's-it's using
the air ducts to move around.
Could he want Brett alive?
- What?
- Could Brett be alive?
No. I mean, I don't think so.
Well, this air shaft may
work to our advantage.
Here it leads up to and comes
out in the main air lock.
All right. There's only one
big opening along the way.
We can cover that up, and then we...
drive it into the air lock
and zap it into outer space.
This son of a bitch is huge!
- I mean, it's like a man, it-it's big!
- Kane's son.
Come on, Ash, I mean, science
department should be able to help us.
What can we do to drive it?
Yes, well, it's adapted remarkably
well to our atmosphere,
considering its nutritional requirements.
The only thing we don't
know about is temperature.
Okay. What about temperature?
What happens if we change it?
Let's try it.
I mean, most animals
retreat from fire. Yes?
Fire, yeah. Parker, can you rig...
three or four incinerator units?
Give me about 20 minutes.
I'll do it.
- Who gets to go into the vent?
- I do.
No. You and Ash...
take the main air lock.
Parker, Lambert, you cover up
that maintenance opening, please.
Lambert: Right.
(Beeping)
Dallas: I'm at the first junction.
Dallas, I'm right here.
- Parker?
- Yeah?
(Dallas over radio)
Lambert...
We're in position. I'm just
trying to get a reading here.
- The air lock is open.
- Okay, Ripley.
Ready.
(Hatch grinding shut)
Dallas: I'm moving up.
All right. I've got a reading on you now.
(Tracker beeping)
Uh, open the hatch to
the third junction.
(Hatch grinds open)
(Beeping)
(Beeping continues)
Dallas: Okay, I'm through.
- Ripley?
- Yes.
Close all the hatches behind me.
I'm moving on.
(Hatch grinds shut)
(Hatch grinding shut)
Lambert: Dallas, hold it a minute.
I mean, I think I got it.
- Yes, I've got it.
Dallas: Where?
Lambert: It's somewhere around
the third junction.
Okay, moving on.
It is right around there. Now, Dallas,
you're gonna have to be careful.
All right. I've reached...
the third junction,
and I'm going down.
(Sensors beeping)
(Beeping)
The hell's the matter with that box?
Dallas, you're gonna have to hold
your position for a minute. I-
I've lost the signal.
What? You sure?
Look, look around. Are you
sure that it's not there?
I mean, It's got to be
around there somewhere.
Dallas: Check that out, Lambert.
You may be getting interference.
Lambert: Dallas, are you
sure there's no sign of it?
I mean, it is there.
(Flames whooshing)
It's gotta be around there.
Dallas?
God, what is happening?
All right.
Uh, am I-am I clear, Lambert?
I wanna get the hell out of here.
(Beeping)
Lambert: Oh, God. It's
moving right towards you.
Uh...
Move! Get out of there!
Behind you! Move!
Dallas! Move, Dallas!
Move, Dallas!
Get out! (Sobbing)
No, not that way, the other way!
(Screeching)
(Shrill feedback)
Dallas?
- No.
- Take it easy.
Parker: Dallas?
(Static on radio)
We found this laying there.
No blood...
No Dallas.
Nothing.
(Slams flamethrower down)
How come I don't hear anybody saying
- nothing around this place?
- I'm thinking.
Unless somebody has got a better idea,
we'll proceed with Dallas' plan.
What? And end up like the others?
Ohh. No, you're out of your mind.
- Got a better idea?
- Yes. I say that we abandon this ship.
We get the shuttle and just
get the hell out of here.
We take our chances
and just hope that...
- somebody picks us up.
- Lambert.
- The shuttle won't take four.
- Then why don't we draw straws and...
I'm not drawin' any straws. I'm for
killing that goddamn thing right now.
Ripley: Okay.
Well, let's talk about killing it.
(Parker grumbling)
We know it's using the air shafts-Will
you listen to me, Parker?
- Shut up!
- Let's hear it.
Let's hear it.
It's using the air shafts.
- We don't know that.
- That's the only way.
We'll move in pairs.
We'll go step by step...
and cut off every bulkhead
and every vent...
until we have it cornered, and then
we'll blow it the fuck out into space.
Is that acceptable to you?
- If it means killing it, it's acceptable to me.
- Obviously it means killing it.
But we have to stick together.
- How are our weapons?
- The weapons are fine.
- This one needs... refueling.
- Will you get it, please?
- Ash, go with him.
- No, no. I can manage, Ash.
Don't follow me.
Ash?
Any suggestions from you or Mother?
No, we're still collating.
(Laughs) You're what?
You're still collating?
I find that hard to believe.
- What would you like me to do?
- Just what you've been doing, Ash.
Nothing. I've got
access to Mother now,
and I'll get my own
answers, thank you.
All right.
(Clicking, beeping)
(Whirring)
(Keyboard beeping)
(Clacking)
There is an explanation for this, you know.
Is there really? I don't wanna
hear your goddamn explanation!
(Sobbing) I want-I want
(Sobbing) I want-I w...
Parker. Lambert?
Ash, open the door.
Ash.
Will you open the door?
- Let me by, Ash.
(Giggling)
(Screams)
Oh! (Grunts)
(Jingling)
- Yaah!
(Groans)
(Muffled shouts)
(Ash jibbering)
What the hell are you doing?
(Muffled shouting continues)
Aah!
Get her up. Get her up. Get her up.
(Chittering)
Android! He's an android!
(Screeching)
Jesus!
Parker: It's a robot.
Ash is a goddamn robot!
God!
Parker: Oh! Get off me-Oh!
Holy shit!
Help! Help me get this
fucking thing off!
(Screaming)
Aah!
God! Jesus! Oh, God! Oh, God!
Parker: How come the company
sent us a goddamn robot?
Ripley: All I can think
of is they must've
wanted the alien for
their weapons division.
He's been protecting it right along.
Parker, will you plug it in?
Parker: Umm... I don't know why...
- Because he may know how to kill it.
Ripley: Ash, can you hear me?
Ash?
(Distorted voice)
Yes, I can hear you.
- What was your special order?
- You read it. I thought it was clear.
- What was it?
- Bring back life-form.
Priority one. All other
priorities rescinded.
The damn company! What about
our lives, you son of a bitch?
I repeat: All other
priorities are rescinded.
Ripley: How do we kill it, Ash?
There's got to be a way of
killing it. How-How do we do it?
You can't.
That's bullshit!
- You still don't
understand what you're
dealing with, do you?
A perfect organism.
Its structural perfection is
matched only by its hostility.
You admire it.
I admire its purity.
A survivor...
unclouded by conscience,
remorse or delusions of morality.
Parker: Look, I-I've
heard enough of this,
and I'm asking you to pull the plug.
Ash: Last word.
- What?
I can't lie to you about
your chances, but...
you have my sympathies.
We're gonna blow up the ship.
We'll take our chances in the shuttle.
Blow up the ship. Good.
Come on.
When we throw the switches,
how long before the ship blows?
- Ten minutes.
- No bullshit.
If we ain't outta
here in ten minutes,
we won't need no rocket
to fly through space.
We're gonna need coolant for
the air support system.
You two go down, get all
the coolant you can carry.
I'll get the shuttle ready.
I'll give you about...
about seven minutes.
Come back up here. I'll
shut the switches off,
and we'll blow this
fucker off into space.
Okay. All right. Come on.
Ready? Take care of yourself.
Seven minutes.
(Throwing switches)
(Parker on speaker) Take it easy.
(Meowing on speaker)
Jones.
(Cylinders hiss)
Jones?
Okay, check the bottles.
- How you doin'?
- Fine.
Kitty.
(Tapping fingers)
(Parker on speaker)
Okay. Go ahead.
Jones?
Psst! Psst! Psst! Psst! Kitty,
kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
Come here, Jones. Come here.
Jones?
Come here, boy.
Come here.
Nice kitty.
Jones?
(Rattling) Jones?
Come here. Come here, sweetheart.
Jones.
Jones? Jones?
Jones?
(Snarls)
(Gasps)
Jones! Goddamn it!
Now I got you.
Here, sweetie. Nice kitty.
(Gasps)
- Oh, my God.
Parker: Get out of the way.
Lambert: I can't get out of the way!
Get out of the way, Lambert!
It's gonna kill us!
I can't!
- Lambert, for Christ's sake, get out of the way!
- Parker? Lambert?
Get out of the way, Lambert!
Parker? Lambert?
Lambert? Parker?
(Lambert sobbing)
Get outta the room!
(Screaming)
(Lambert screaming)
Lambert: Oh, God! (Parker whimpering)
(Alien roaring)
(Lambert screaming)
(Scream stops abruptly)
Parker?
(Shuddering)
(Ripley grunting)
(Alarm beeping)
(Breathing heavily)
(Hatch screeches open)
(Mother) Danger. The emergency
destruct system... (Alarm sounding)
is now activated.
The ship will detonate in T-minus...
ten minutes.
The option to override
automatic detonation...
expires in T-minus five minutes.
(Alarm continues)
(Coolant hissing)
(Mother, distant) The option to
override automatic detonation...
expires in T-minus... (inaudible)
(Groaning)
(Gasps)
- Oh
Dallas.
(Moaning)
Brett.
(Gasping)
Oh.
Dallas: Kill me.
(Moaning)
- Kill me!
(Alarm continues)
(Breathing heavily)
(Gasps, grunts)
(Grunting, breathing heavily)
(Breathing heavily)
(Mother) The option to
override automatic detonation...
expires in T-minus...
three minutes.
(Mother) The option to override...
automatic detonation expires...
in T-minus one minute.
(Horn blaring)
Twenty-nine, 28, 27,
26, 25, 24,
23, 22,
21, 20 seconds.
Nineteen, 18,
17, 16,
15, 14, 13,
12, 11, 10 seconds.
Nine, eight, seven,
(Gasps)
Six, five, four,
- Come on!
- Three, two, one.
(Siren whooping) (Mother) The option
to override detonation procedure...
has now expired.
Mother? I've turned the
cooling unit back on.
Mother!
(Mother) The ship will
automatically destruct...
in T-minus five minutes.
You bitch!
(Screams)
Goddamn it!
(Steam gushing)
Jonesy.
(Distant explosions roaring)
(Explosions nearing)
(Gasping)
You now have one minute
to abandon ship.
The ship will automatically destruct...
in T-minus one minute.
(Mooring clamps bang loudly)
T-minus 30 seconds.
Twenty-nine, 28,
27, 26,
(Engines ignite)
25, 24,
(Beeping)
23, 22, 21,
20 seconds.
Nineteen, 18,
17, 16,
15, 14, 13,
12, 11, 10 seconds.
(Rapid beeping)
Nine, eight, seven,
six, five,
- four, three, two, one.
- (Steady beep)
(Tremendous roaring explosion)
(Roaring explosion)
(Nuclear explosion)
I got you,
you son of a bitch.
(Meows)
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
It's all right.
Shh, shh, shh.
(Meows)
Shh, shh, shh. It's all right.
(Meows, growls) All right.
It's nice to see you too.
(Jonesy hisses)
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
It's okay.
(Jonesy growling)
(Screams)
(Gasping)
(Air seal hisses)
Come on. Come on.
♪ You are ♪
♪ My lucky star ♪
♪ You... are my ♪
♪ Lucky star ♪
♪ You ♪
Lucky, lucky, lucky,
lucky, lucky.
Okay.
(Inhales)
Well, come on.
♪ You are ♪
♪ My lucky star ♪
♪ You ♪
(Screeching)
- ♪ You are my lucky star ♪
♪ You are my lucky star ♪
♪ You are my lucky ♪
(Mumbling)
(Screeching)
Oh, my God.
My-My lucky-
(Breathing heavily)
♪ You... are my ♪
(Gasping)
♪ You are my ♪
♪ Lucky ♪
(Gasping)
(Screaming)
(Screeching)
(Engine roars to life)
(Engine blasting loudly)
Ripley: Final report of the
commercial starship Nostromo.
Third officer reporting.
The other members of the crew
Kane, Lambert,
Parker, Brett,
Ash and Captain Dallas- are dead.
Cargo and ship destroyed.
I should reach the frontier
in about six weeks.
With a little luck, the
network will pick me up.
This is Ripley, last
survivor of the Nostromo,
signing off.
Come on, cat.