BOTH:
Bye, L.A.!
Here we go.
AMANDA:
My friends are morons.
You better be careful or you might end up
in the Tower of London.
Criminal.
Ta-da!
But it's gonna be you.
- Forget the plane.
- This is backwards, by the way.
[WOMAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN
OVER PA]
CHRIS: And here in front of us,
we have the beautiful...
- ...Danube River.
NATALIE: Uh!
We're doing Prague.
Hi, Paul! We're at the Tower of London!
Here we come, Kiev.
We're coming to see you, Paul.
[PAUL CHUCKLES]
PAUL:
You guys are ridiculous.
- Dude, it was so much fun, man.
- Yeah, I can imagine.
- Hey, ladies! You wanna put your stuff away?
AMANDA: Some place you got here, Paul.
PAUL: I'm never leaving. Best place ever.
Ain't it right, Chris?
- I got it, it's fine.
- I got it, I insist.
- Where are we sleeping?
- I told you, I put a pillow on the patio for you.
[MOCKINGLY] "I told you,
I put a pillow on the patio for you."
PAUL: You're sleeping in my room!
Where do you think?
CHRIS: Great. Some chick still sleeping in there?
PAUL: Quite possibly.
I hope you cleaned those sheets.
Or burned them.
PAUL:
I heard that!
CHRIS:
So, Kiev, huh?
PAUL:
Kiev, baby!
I thought for sure your ADD
would have kicked in by now.
Dude, I'm telling you, man.
I don't think I'm leaving.
I love it here!
The chicks, they're fucking amazing.
They absolutely love Americans
and they are completely fucking insane.
Yeah, well, they have to be
if they want anything to do with you.
- So, Amanda.
- Yeah, okay.
- What? Chris! Come on.
- I knew this was coming.
Rob literally broke up with her three weeks
before we were supposed to come here...
...and Natalie had to drag her ass
onto the airplane.
PAUL:
Perfect! Look at her.
She's lonely, she's in Europe.
- You're a sick son-of-a-bitch.
- I'm not sick, dude!
Would you stop?
- Heh. Do I have a shot with her?
- No, you don't. Zero.
No? All right. Fine.
[CHUCKLES]
- I'll leave it alone.
- Thank you.
What about you and Natalie?
You guys going good?
- It's creepy when you look at me like that, dude.
- Hold this.
Are you serious? Are you serious?
Yeah, dude!
I haven't asked her yet.
I'm gonna propose in Moscow.
- Does she have any idea?
- I hope not.
- What about Amanda?
- No.
That's awesome, dude.
[TECHNO MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS]
PAUL:
Unbelievable. A fucking riot.
Oh, man, thank you so much.
This was such a good night.
Yeah, it was.
Told you, man. Okay!
Save it for the apartment. Get a room!
Go to town, we're in Europe!
Don't listen to him.
- Whoa! You all right?
- Hello! Thank you, good save.
Watch out!
These cobblestones, they'll get you.
Thank you for being a good host.
We've had a lot of fun.
My pleasure.
You enjoying yourself in Kiev?
I am. Yeah, it's a beautiful little city.
Yeah, it's great.
Wait till Moscow.
Wait until you get to Moscow.
You believe me?
Mm. I don't know.
Do you trust me?
I don't trust you in those heels.
CHRIS: Paul. Hands off!
PAUL: Sorry.
[AMANDA LAUGHS]
AMANDA: You're trouble.
PAUL: I am trouble!
I can't promise what's gonna happen
at the end of the road, but-- Don't fall.
Those stairs are slippery.
NATALIE: Please, lock your door tonight.
I don't trust him.
- Christopher.
- Yeah.
- You are visiting your brother in Kiev.
- Yeah, well, I had to chase you down.
I didn't know when you booked this trip,
it was a one-way ticket.
I miss you, buddy.
Yeah, I miss you too, man.
It's good to see you.
- How are things back home? Good?
- Yeah, things are great.
Mom's worried sick, of course.
You know how she is.
You spoken to Dad?
No, I, uh... No.
- You should call him.
- I know I should.
- Paul, which way should we go?
PAUL: Left.
[THUGS SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
Hey, hey, hey, we don't want
any trouble, seriously.
[SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN]
AMANDA: Come on.
- Don't touch me.
- Good night.
- Have a good night.
Good night. Bye-bye.
Come on, come on, come on.
Fucking losers.
CHRIS: Nice.
PAUL: Real friendly people here.
Don't worry about it.
We got a big day tomorrow.
AMANDA: Okay, I'm assuming that this is
the breakfast menu? But I don't know.
Excuse me, is this the--?
CHRIS: Yeah, she hasn't had her coffee yet.
- Wow.
Where's Paul?
He's supposed to help us with this.
I don't know, I just want something greasy.
Can you just point out
something greasy, please?
You need the Hangover Special.
Amanda, I want to apologize
for Paul's behavior last night.
Oh, please. He's fine.
I mean, I know the type, you know?
Just all talk.
Yeah, well, with him,
it's not always just talk.
I can handle him,
I'm not too worried about it.
And I'm sure,
deep down in there...
- Very, very deep down.
- ...somewhere...
...he's a good guy, you know?
It's just an act, that's all.
I mean, he's related to you, baby,
and you turned out all right.
- That's true.
AMANDA: Yeah, you're okay.
That's true. Just let me know
if I need to kick his ass for you.
- Thanks, dude, I appreciate-- Hello!
- Morning, children. How are you doing?
Fantastic. So I know I said
we're going to Moscow.
AMANDA:
Mm-hm.
But I'm gonna ask you a question,
and I want an answer.
The answer is already no.
You guys ever heard of Chernobyl?
- Yeah.
Isn't that where
the nuclear disaster happened?
Yes. I met this really cool guy,
Uri, who's a, uh...
Have you heard of extreme tourism?
- Uh, somehow, I haven't, no.
- You guys see where this is going, right?
We're going to Moscow,
as we talked about.
PAUL:
Chris? Can I please finish?
So, there's this place called Pripyat. It's a
town right next to Chernobyl. Uri, who is...
[IN RUSSIAN ACCENT]
...very excited to take us there...
[IN NORMAL VOICE] ...is an extreme tour guide.
He's gonna show us this city...
...that was abandoned overnight.
Literally. They had no time to take anything.
Factories, schools, stores, homes,
apartments, everything's still there.
Imagine the photo shoot
you can have there, Amanda?
Yeah. But-- Okay, I hear that, but it's--
Radiation levels or something,
it's probably pretty dangerous, right?
No. We'll only be there for a day. A few hours,
see some cool shit and then we split.
- How are we gonna get there?
PAUL: Uri's gonna take us.
- He's got a van.
- A van?
- Yeah.
- He has a van?
He has a van!
Okay. Aside from the sketchy van situation...
...and if you promise that this tour is safe...
...I think it could be kind of cool.
- That's what I'm talking about.
- You're kidding.
No. I mean-- I don't know. He's right.
We're in Europe, we might as well see as
much as we possibly can while we're here.
I don't know.
- Tell me you don't want to meet Uri.
- I don't want to meet Uri.
How can you say that?
You haven't even met him yet.
We'll take some pictures,
explore a bit, and then we'll be on our way.
Just as planned. Right?
I don't like that he's rubbing off on you.
- He's definitely not rubbing off.
- You're incredible, you know that?
All right, let's just settle this
by a show of hands, please?
Who's coming with Paul to Chernobyl?
Yeah!
You're kidding me, right?
You guys are so weak.
All right, kids! Welcome to
Uri's Extreme Travel. Let's do it.
CHRIS: Uri's Extreme Travel.
- Uri!
[URI SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN]
What's up, buddy?
- How are you?
URI: Good morning.
- Come in! Welcome, welcome.
- All right, man! The gang is all here.
- This is my little brother Chris.
CHRIS: How you doing?
PAUL:
His girlfriend Natalie. The lovely Amanda.
- Guys, this is Uri.
AMANDA: Hi.
Hello.
I was telling them about our little adventure
today and Chris got parental, as usual.
So I figured you'd give him a little
peace of mind before he pisses his pants.
You're feeling nervous?
No, I'm not. I'm not nervous.
It's a nice shop you got here,
it's very professional.
Thank you. It's all mine.
- It's all yours, huh?
AMANDA: Yeah, very nice.
- Yes, it's all mine.
CHRIS: Well, what are you, ex-military?
URI:
Yes, Special Forces.
What does it matter
if he's a fucking magician, dude?
- I'm just asking a fucking question.
- Okay. Uri, what's the plan for today?
URI:
Well, this is a very well organized tour.
I've been taking special adventurous
tourists for a while now...
...so you should feel very, how do you say?
- Special?
URI: Special, I like that.
Okay, so imagine, you have big city
and no one's there. All to yourself.
NATALIE:
Is it safe?
Of course it's safe.
This is not my first rodeo, Natalika.
- So sorry we're late!
- Well, now we're here.
Hey. You guys with the special tour, yeah?
ALL: Yeah!
- I'm Michael, this is my Viking Zoe.
CHRIS: How you doing? I'm Chris.
Nice to meet you.
What's up, man? I'm Paul.
Nice to meet you, buddy.
URI: Okay, we go!
MICHAEL: We go now.
- Come, come.
MICHAEL: All right.
CHRIS: Sweet.
MICHAEL: We didn't keep you waiting?
PAUL: No. You guys are fine.
MICHAEL: That's all I told you, go with the plan.
PAUL: So, tell me, what's up with
the whole "Viking" thing?
ZOE: He calls me that all the time.
I'm from Norway, so...
And he's my Australian surfer dude.
MICHAEL:
All right, let's rock 'n' roll!
CHRIS:
Yes.
[PAUL CHUCKLES]
Yeah, buddy!
AMANDA: Are you kidding?
CHRIS: Wow.
That's what we're riding in?
- Might as well just... roll with it.
URI: Put your bags in the back.
PAUL:
Whoo!
MICHAEL: First time, mate?
- Pripyat? Yeah. How about you guys?
Yeah. Someone said it's pretty fantastic.
Yeah, I heard it's pretty awesome.
- You two sweethearts mooning?
PAUL: "Mooning"?
AMANDA: We what?
- Honeymooning.
Yeah, actually, we are honeymooning.
We're just friends. Barely.
- Ouch.
MICHAEL: You're cute.
- Are you guys?
- Oh, yeah, we're timeless.
No. A month.
You guys have only been together a month?
God bless.
- Wow.
- These two are practically married.
URI: We go.
PAUL: Shotgun!
AMANDA:
Thank you.
URI:
Anybody gets hungry, I have beef jerky.
Pripyat is two hours from here,
and Chernobyl is not far from there.
MICHAEL: Good time!
NATALIE: What exactly happened in Chernobyl?
The Chernobyl disaster was a result
of failed systems tests.
It caused sudden power surge.
And reactor number four
became one with the air.
NATALIE:
One with the air?
- Vaporized.
CHRIS: It exploded.
[SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN]
I'm sorry, what does that mean?
Nature has reclaimed its rightful home.
[CHUCKLES]
URI:
Here we are.
Welcome to Pripyat.
Photo.
URI:
We're now entering exclusion zone.
CHRIS:
How long is it safe to be here?
URI: It's very safe.
We'll only be in Pripyat for two hours.
What is this place? Is it like a checkpoint?
CHRIS:
Looks like it.
Why would there be a checkpoint
at an abandoned town?
MICHAEL:
Tourists.
URI:
Okay.
- Let me do the talking.
PAUL: Oh, you think?
Put your cameras away.
AMANDA:
Yeah, got it.
MICHAEL: Tough guys.
- Yeah. These guys look pretty serious.
MICHAEL:
Yeah.
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
I don't know what they're saying,
but this guy is saying no.
PAUL:
Look at this guy.
AMANDA:
What do you think is going on?
ZOE: Ohh. Scary!
CHRIS: God, look at that guy. He's huge.
MICHAEL:
Make sure he doesn't see me.
- How's that?
ZOE: Criminal soul.
MICHAEL:
Do I look like one of them?
Uh, he is not letting us in today.
There's maintenance going on.
Maintenance work? I thought you said
this place was abandoned.
It is unusual.
Usually, they let me know in advance
if something like this is going to happen.
Wait, I thought you said everything
was gonna be taken care of.
We paid for this tour, bro.
I know, I know.
Don't worry.
There's more than one way into Pripyat.
PAUL:
Make it happen.
AMANDA: It's so bizarre,
I don't see any birds or anything.
This must be Uri's special entrance.
Paul, this looks fucking sketchy, man.
Stop being a pussy. We came all this way,
enjoy yourself, all right?
It's called being sensible.
This is not right, you guys.
We're gonna end up
in a Ukrainian jail or something.
MICHAEL:
Ahh! Come on, just think of it as an adventure.
ZOE:
It's okay.
- This is the awesomest.
PAUL: Really?
[MICHAEL CHUCKLES]
Okay, no problem.
Today we have Pripyat to ourselves.
CHRIS:
Sweet.
AMANDA:
All right.
URI:
Here we go.
AMANDA:
I was not expecting a lake out here.
URI:
And there is Pripyat.
Home to the workers and families
of Chernobyl.
AMANDA:
Wow.
CHRIS:
It's incredible.
URI:
Hold on! This is going to be a little bumpy.
A little bumpy.
ZOE:
Oh, you're not gonna--
[ALL LAUGHING]
URI:
And down we go!
And up!
ZOE:
Oh, my God!
When are you putting seatbelts
in this thing?
- Jesus.
NATALIE: Or barf-bags.
ZOE:
Ridiculous.
Okay. Now, I want to show you
something in water.
PAUL:
He wants to show us something in water.
ZOE:
Thank you.
MICHAEL:
After you.
URI: Stay close behind me.
- Like we're gonna go anywhere.
- Paul?
- Yeah?
I want you to tell me if you see
something moving in water. Okay?
Okay...
AMANDA:
You don't want to get your booties wet.
[URI YELLS]
PAUL:
Give me your hand! Give me your hand!
You okay? You okay, mate?
[LAUGHS]
MICHAEL:
Funny, bugger.
- Are you fucking kidding me?
NATALIE: He's a fucking comedian.
- It's jerky.
- Jerky, you jerk.
Can we go?
- Fucking got me!
- Yeah. He got me, too.
AMANDA:
Oh, shit!
MICHAEL:
It was a joke.
AMANDA:
Sorry about that.
Come have look at this.
PAUL:
Is this another joke?
URI:
No. No, come.
PAUL:
Holy cow.
URI: Don't get too close.
PAUL: Why? It's dead.
NATALIE: It's disgusting.
MICHAEL: Look at the chompers on him.
PAUL:
What is that thing?
MICHAEL: Touch it, mate.
PAUL: Whoa!
[NATALIE SCREAMS
& CHRIS LAUGHS]
Who's the pussy now, huh?
- Can we go? This is disgusting.
PAUL: Keep it up.
CHRIS:
Can we go? That's disgusting.
MICHAEL: That's awesome.
- And moving on.
MICHAEL:
See its teeth? It's cool, huh?
ZOE:
Oh, my God.
Did you just make a rhyme, Uri?
URI: Yes.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Make small joke.
- Not to worry.
- Here is Uri.
CHRIS: So, Uri, how long has this place
been abandoned?
URI: It's been 25 years. Only recently
have radiation levels gone down.
Man, this is crazy. It's creepy as fuck.
URI: We are back on main road.
It's only way in and out of Pripyat.
Yeah, except for your shortcut, right?
This is where the families of the workers
in Chernobyl lived.
MICHAEL:
Wow.
- See?
MICHAEL: Yeah.
- These were all full at one point.
URI: Yes. Very sad.
50,000 people, families, just left.
- Okay, hold on. Little bump, little bump.
MICHAEL: Oh, wow.
[NATALIE GIGGLES]
- The Ferris.
ZOE: Bumper cars?
- All right. We're here.
MICHAEL: I used to love those things.
Wow!
PAUL:
Still want to go home, Chris?
CHRIS:
I'm happy we're here. Thanks.
MICHAEL: There we go. Brotherly love.
PAUL: You're welcome.
[CHATTERING]
Whoa.
CHRIS:
Guys, look at this.
Man.
Okay, everyone.
Stay near me and you'll be safe.
I have Geiger counter. It will let us know
if the radiation levels are high.
That's good.
[BEEPING]
URI:
Levels are good.
Can you guys imagine this, like,
full with kids? Like... playing?
It's really sad, actually.
PAUL:
They had no idea.
AMANDA:
Wow.
I mean, this is just unbelievable.
NATALIE:
I have never seen anything like this.
AMANDA: It's like they were getting ready
for a carnival or something.
URI: They were preparing for "May Day,"
the celebration of Spring.
Never happened.
Okay, let's go. This way.
Can we get a photo?
Uri, you want to take it? A photo.
- Hey, guys?
CHRIS: All right. Quick photo.
And new friends.
URI:
Okay.
Good.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
MICHAEL:
It's so American.
[PAUL CHUCKLES]
ZOE:
In a way it's like...
There was life, and it just...
Hey, you hear that?
Silence.
AMANDA:
It's like nature really has taken over.
One last thing.
ZOE:
Are we going in?
URI:
Yes.
[ZOE GASPS]
MICHAEL: What is it, babe?
Whoa, Zoe. Hey, babe, it's okay.
They usually don't come so close to town.
Must have been starving.
MICHAEL:
I reckon he's right.
Come in.
NATALIE: That's disgusting.
MICHAEL: That's the VIP entrance. Treatment.
[MICHAEL CHUCKLES]
PAUL: Poor guy.
NATALIE: Are there any other animals here?
Unlikely. Especially during the day.
Just you. Heh.
[GROUP CHATTERS]
Stop it.
Here's one of a thousand apartments
that were abandoned.
MICHAEL:
Cool.
The people were not even given five minutes
to collect their personal possessions.
You can't take that. It's contaminated.
I was just look-- Spot the convict.
Cheers, man.
It's contaminated.
For a while, people came here
and they looted through these buildings.
They took these things,
sold them on black market.
People who bought them got sick...
...not knowing they were contaminated
by radiation.
Sorry, I was just--
Come, let's have a look.
ZOE:
But it's okay to be here and breathe?
URI:
Yes, yes.
We're not here long enough
to get exposure.
Chernobyl Reactor Number Four.
Where the disaster happened.
PAUL: That's pretty close.
- Have you been inside?
No. You can only go inside
with radiation suit.
Only for short period of time.
Here, take picture.
MICHAEL: Take a nice, romantic photo?
ZOE: All right, all right.
MICHAEL:
Hey, I wasn't gonna...
ZOE: Yeah, he was.
NATALIE: This is going on the fridge.
- That's a metaphor here, by the way, guys.
PAUL: Do tell.
MICHAEL: That's beautiful.
CHRIS: Our love is just exploding.
AMANDA:
Oh, God.
[ALL LAUGHING]
PAUL: The one good thing about the radiation
is that I'll probably finally grow a penis.
MICHAEL:
These guys are funny.
ZOE:
I know, I know.
MICHAEL: Can you beat that kiss?
ZOE: What?
[GROUP CHATTERS INDISTINCTLY]
We should go now.
It's going to get dark soon,
we should get back to van before then.
[CRASHING]
CHRIS:
What the fuck was that?
MICHAEL: Right, it's gonna be a trick.
- Shh!
[CLATTERING]
[WHISPERS]
Stay.
CHRIS [WHISPERS]: What the fuck is it?
AMANDA: Shh, shh.
Holy shit! Go!
CHRIS [IN NORMAL VOICE]: Jesus!
PAUL: Motherfucker!
AMANDA:
Oh, my God!
CHRIS:
Holy shit!
URI [IN NORMAL VOICE]: Is everyone okay?
CHRIS: Don't fucking stand there!
URI:
Let's go, move, move, move!
CHRIS:
Go!
MICHAEL: Fuck! What the fuck was that?
URI: Go, go.
MICHAEL:
A bear? A fucking brown bear? Oh, Jesus!
ZOE: What is a bear doing here?
NATALIE: Let's get the fuck out of here.
MICHAEL: Jeez.
AMANDA: Watch out for that.
PAUL:
Oh, fuck!
MICHAEL: Okay.
PAUL: Holy shit.
NATALIE: Can we just get the fuck out of here?
AMANDA: Yeah.
- Thanks for that.
- Yeah. Don't mention it.
Told you it'd be exciting, didn't I?
Yeah, almost getting mauled to death by
a radioactive bear from hell? Pretty exciting.
Anybody else have a story like this?
NATALIE: Funny.
AMANDA: You okay?
Anyone get a photo?
- A photo. This guy.
- Jesus.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
PAUL:
Bear! Bear, bear! I'm kidding.
ZOE:
That's bad.
So, Uri, all the animals,
they stay in the woods, huh?
It's very unusual.
I've been doing this for five years.
- I've never seen anything like this.
- Kind of chilly out here, huh?
A dog, a wolf. But a bear, very odd.
It was exciting, right?
- Yeah, mate.
- No extra charge for bear attack.
Say goodbye to Pripyat.
- Ciao.
- Yeah, ciao-ciao.
Hey, Christopher?
Moscow! Thank you.
MICHAEL: I'll have to get your e-mail, eh?
- Yeah, for sure, dude.
- Catch up again? I'll be back to Kiev.
- Done, dude.
It was a blast.
Turn the heater on, buddy.
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
Pump it.
Give it some gas. Give it some gas.
What's up, is there gas in there?
Yes. Half a tank.
Is it the starter, mate?
Has this happened before?
CHRIS: I don't suppose you guys
have AAA out here?
ZOE:
Do you have reception?
MICHAEL: I haven't had reception all day, guys.
There's no kind of reception out here.
- Look, look.
- What the fuck does that--?
What the fuck could've done that, mate?
That's fucking been chewed on.
NATALIE:
Wait, what's happening?
ZOE:
What's going on?
- The wires have been destroyed.
- Chewed on.
What do you mean chewed on?
What kind of--? What, by what? An animal?
What kind of animal chews on car parts?
Are you sure we're out here alone?
Yes. You heard the soldiers this morning,
this place is off-limits.
We are here alone.
CHRIS:
What the fuck is it, Michael?
MICHAEL: That's the sparkplug leads,
been chewed on...
- Can you call someone?
- ...by a raccoon, a rat, or some animal.
NATALIE:
But how would an animal get in here?
MICHAEL:
Under the car. Through the engine.
AMANDA: Underneath?
MICHAEL: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
AMANDA: He said there aren't any around here
and all of a sudden--
CHRIS:
I don't know.
Guys! Let's just shut up and let him--
We're trying to--
[STATIC OVER WALKIE TALKIE]
Fuck me.
MICHAEL:
Uh...
Uri?
What's the plan, mate?
Hey, big fella? What's the plan?
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
ZOE:
I'm so hungry I could die.
PAUL:
Well, this is great.
Gotta hand it to you.
Some fucking tour, mister.
URI:
This is not my fault.
PAUL:
Oh, really? Not your fault?
Because last time I checked,
you were the one that drove us out here.
NATALIE: If it weren't for you,
we wouldn't be here either.
PAUL: I'm sorry to try and show you guys
some fun while you're out here visiting me.
CHRIS:
Oh, yeah. Lot of fun.
PAUL:
Hey, Chris.
All right, you know what? Relax.
- We're fine.
- We're fucking stranded out here.
And don't tell me to relax.
I swear to God, this is the last time
I listen to one of your dumb fucking ideas.
You know what, Chris?
Your fucking whining isn't helping right now.
NATALIE: He's got every right to be pissed.
AMANDA: Okay, guys. Hey, Uri.
Someone has to know
we're out here, right?
I work alone.
[PAUL CHUCKLES]
PAUL:
Fucking great.
So, tell me, Uri.
What are our options right now?
We stay in van.
NATALIE: Are we safe here?
URI: Yes, we're safe.
We close windows, lock doors.
In morning, I fix van, we drive up.
Or we all walk back to checkpoint.
CHRIS:
Wait, wait, I'm sorry.
Are you suggesting that we spend
the night here?
Okay, guys. I'm sorry, but we're gonna
have to hike out of here, all right?
Uri, how far to the checkpoint?
It's 20 kilometers.
PAUL:
That's like 12, 13 miles.
Exactly. We can hike that.
No, no, not at night!
- It is not safe.
- Shh, shh, shh! Be quiet!
[CREATURE SCREAMS]
CHRIS:
What the fuck was that?
ZOE: Are there people here?
- It's impossible.
MICHAEL:
Shh.
It sounds like a baby.
What is that?
- It's not a baby.
- Then what the fuck is it, Uri?
Whoa. What's with the gun, man?
- You have problem?
- Yeah. What's with the fucking gun?
You should all be glad I have this.
Everyone stay here.
- A gun?
- Where is he going?
ZOE:
Do you trust him?
PAUL: Do you want to go out there with him?
MICHAEL: Easy, brother.
ZOE:
I don't know, it's just that the...
MICHAEL:
Stay here. He'll come back.
PAUL: Chris, what the fuck--?
AMANDA: Where's he going?
PAUL: Chris, I'm coming with you.
- No, I don't want you to come with me.
Just sit in the car and think of another way
you can fuck this up even further.
I swear to God, Paul, it's a fucking hazard
having you as a brother.
NATALIE:
Chris!
ZOE: What's he gonna do?
MICHAEL: I don't know, babe.
NATALIE: Where is he going?
CHRIS: Uri, wait up!
NATALIE:
I can't see him. Can you guys see him?
Oh, God.
[GUNFIRE]
PAUL:
Chris!
- Chris! Chris!
NATALIE: Chris, no!
Oh, my God! Chris, no!
Can you guys see anything?
- Can you see them?
ZOE: I don't know. I can't see.
NATALIE:
Chris!
ZOE:
Michael, can you see?
[NATALE WHIMPERS AND PANTS]
PAUL: Open the door! Get him in, get him in!
Get him in, get him in!
[ALL SCREAMING]
Oh, my God! Oh, my God, Chris!
MICHAEL: Okay, look at me. Breathe, buddy.
Chris, mate, keep breathing.
- Fuck!
MICHAEL: Chris, what happened?!
I don't fucking know!
There were a lot of them!
Where's Uri? Where's Uri?
Chris. Chris, what happened to Uri?
They got him! They fucking got him!
What fucking got Uri?
Just breathe, baby!
MICHAEL: Hold him, hold him.
ZOE: Don't look!
MICHAEL:
Fucking first aid!
PAUL: Where's the first aid kit? He's cut.
MICHAEL: I don't know, check in here.
That's fucking fishing tackle!
Fuck!
Holy shit!
What the fuck--?
Stay away from the windows!
[BARKING AND GROWLING]
Fuck off!
Hey, everyone away
from the fucking windows!
Stay away from the windows.
Chris. Chris, look at me, buddy.
Look at me, buddy.
It's gonna be all right, brother.
Look at me, okay? Stay with me, all right?
- Get me the fuck out of here!
- I'm gonna get you home.
Chris, I'm gonna get you out of here.
Chris, look at me, look at me.
I'm gonna get you out.
What the fuck is with the lights?
MICHAEL: Just relax. The battery's dying.
The fucking car battery is dying.
PAUL:
What the fuck is going on?
[ALL WHIMPERING]
MICHAEL: Tie it tight.
NATALIE: Can somebody please hold the light?
MICHAEL:
Good, good.
[CHRIS YELLS]
MICHAEL:
Fuck. Sorry, mate.
NATALIE: Breathe, baby, just breathe.
MICHAEL: Breathe. Just breathe, mate.
Here, hold it up. Fuck. Here, mate.
Just breathe.
NATALIE:
I'm so sorry.
MICHAEL:
Try not to look at it, mate.
PAUL:
Breathe, breathe.
MICHAEL:
I know, I know, I know!
It's gotta be tight, I'm sorry, brother.
NATALIE:
I'm so sorry, baby.
[BANGING & NATALIE SCREAMS]
PAUL: What the fuck?!
- Turn off the light, turn off the light!
MICHAEL:
Ah, fuck. Sorry, Chris.
[GROUP CHATTERING INCOHERENTLY]
MICHAEL:
Here, Zoe. It'll be all right, baby.
Just breathe, mate. You're doing good.
PAUL: I'm gonna get you out of this place.
CHRIS: I'm freezing.
MICHAEL:
Shh. Shh. Shh.
[CHRIS SCREAMS]
- I know.
- Fuck!
You're gonna be okay. Okay.
It's okay, baby.
PAUL: How are you feeling?
- He needs a doctor.
I know he needs a doctor.
How are you doing?
I just want to get the fuck out of here.
I can't fix it. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, the leads have rotted.
I mean, if we could get some new leads,
we could roll-start it, but...
I ain't fucking seen this before. Try it.
Uri, this is Paul. Can you hear me?
- That the other walkie?
- Yeah.
Uri, are you there? Can you hear me?
MICHAEL:
Come on.
- All right, I'm gonna go look for him.
- You don't know your way around.
PAUL: But he does. He can help us
get out of here.
And what if the dogs come back?
Uri said the dogs come out at night.
- Stay in the van and keep the door shut.
MICHAEL: I'll go with you.
No, you will not.
Uri is a big fellow and it might take
two of us to carry him back.
ZOE:
Yeah, what if he's dead?
MICHAEL: Don't say that. Uri knows how
to get the fuck out of here.
We might find new leads--
You saw what attacked the car.
He says that there's other things out here.
- Come on. Just stay here.
ZOE: Please!
- Please!
- Stay.
Yeah, I'm gonna come too.
I'm gonna help these guys, okay?
PAUL:
All right, let's go.
You stay in the car, you keep the door shut.
We'll be back for you.
MICHAEL: You'll be all right, mate.
We'll be back. We'll be back.
- Stay with them. Help them.
- Michael, this is stupid.
- Why would you do that?
- I'll be back.
How well you know Uri?
Not well. You?
Same, same.
You think he's still here?
It's been overnight. He could be gone.
Yeah, I know.
What are you thinking?
I think Chris got attacked by dogs.
Dogs didn't do that.
Maybe a bear? I mean, we saw a bear
run by us at the apartment yesterday.
- He said there was something else.
- Yeah, and it could be a bear.
He said there was a lot of dogs.
It was dark, he was in shock.
Try the walkie-talkie, will you?
Hey, Uri, are you there? It's Paul.
- Let's go around here.
- Uri, can you hear me?
Just stay close
and keep your eyes open, all right?
I don't believe him when he said that
animals don't come out during the day.
Yeah. I don't know what to believe.
Fuck.
This is where he went off last night, right?
Let's just try and figure out how
we get back to the van.
Good idea, mate.
Check your walkie-talkie again.
[ECHOES] Hey, Uri, this is Paul.
Can you hear me, buddy?
Whoa.
- What?
- Do it again, do it again, do it again.
[ECHOES]
Uri, do you come in--?
- Did you hear that?
- Yeah.
[FEEDBACK OVER WALKIE TALKIE]
- Holy shit.
- You guys.
Something fucking got him.
AMANDA:
Okay, let's go. We need to go.
No, we can't, mate.
We have to see if he's alive.
PAUL: Uri?
MICHAEL: Shh.
PAUL [WHISPERS]:
Uri?
[ALL GASP]
[WHISPERS]
It's okay.
AMANDA [WHISPERING]:
There's too much blood.
- There's no way that he's still alive.
- I know, I know.
We need to be smart about this.
We're not going back there.
We are. I'm gonna go.
Besides, he's got the gun.
PAUL:
He's right.
Let's do it.
MICHAEL:
Uri?
Uri!
PAUL
MICHAEL:
Oh, fuck!
Holy shit!
MICHAEL:
Look!
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACH]
Gotta check his pockets.
- Shit! Where's the gun?
PAUL: Oh, shit.
MICHAEL:
Wait. I've got the clip.
[CLAMORING]
[PANTING]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[CLATTERING]
[BANGING & CREATURE GROWLING]
PAUL:
Lock the fucking door!
Oh, what the fuck is that?
[BANGING ON DOOR]
- Holy shit!
PAUL: Gun, gun, gun!
- Fuck, there's no bullets!
- Right here!
All right, I got it! I'll do it!
Go!
MICHAEL:
Oh, shit!
Forget it!
Motherfucker.
We're getting the fuck out of here.
NATALIE: What? Where are we going?
- What's going on?
AMANDA: We gotta go.
NATALIE: Where's Uri? Did you find him?
MICHAEL: Yeah, what's left of him.
NATALIE: What?
What he said, man. Uri's dead.
- We better go, we can't stay here.
NATALIE: He cannot walk.
- We can't stay here!
- I don't have a choice. Help me.
NATALIE: What? Babe, no!
- Come on, I'll help you.
CHRIS: Ah, fuck. Ow, ow, ow.
PAUL: Real slow.
- Just do it real slow.
CHRIS: Easy, easy, easy.
All right.
CHRIS: Fuck.
PAUL: There you go. There you go.
- Ow! Fuck!
- Goddamn it, I told you, he can't walk!
MICHAEL: Put it back up, put it back up.
ZOE: Easy, easy.
- What's going on?
- We gotta carry him.
- Don't be fucking stupid.
PAUL: We're not gonna leave you here!
It'll take three of you to carry me
and twice as long!
Fine. I'm staying here with him.
- I'm not leaving him!
PAUL: I'm not leaving him either!
Would you listen to me?
You live here. You're the only one
that speaks the language.
Go get help and bring it back.
We're staying in the van.
All right.
- Take this.
MICHAEL: We'll be back. Come on, Zoe.
PAUL:
Stay on channel one.
If you guys need anything,
if anything happens, you call us, okay?
It's 13 miles. We're gonna leave now.
If we hurry...
- ...we'll be back before it's dark.
- What if you're not back?
Take it.
- You know how to use that?
- Yeah, I think so.
All right, let's go.
CHRIS: Paul, wait.
- We'll be back, mate.
Come on, let's go, Zoe.
- Look, I'm sorry--
PAUL: Stop. Stop.
I'm gonna get you home.
We'll be back before you know it.
It's okay, babe. It's okay.
Way to go, Paul.
Fucked things up this time.
Okay, don't think like that.
Come on, that's not helping anyone.
I've been doing this his whole fucking life.
I always get him into shit.
He always pays for it.
Well, despite all that, you're his big brother.
So right now he's counting on you
to get him out of this. Okay?
Oi! Oi!
PAUL:
Holy shit.
MICHAEL: Come on.
- We gotta find a way around.
ZOE: Michael.
PAUL: Stay quiet.
- We'll loop around.
AMANDA: Oh, God. Okay, go. Go, go, go.
Zoe, Zoe! Come on.
[GEIGER COUNTER BEEPING]
Ah! Shit. Guys?
The radiation's getting worse.
MICHAEL:
Let's go.
Shh! What is that? Look.
PAUL:
Holy shit.
ZOE: Will any of them start?
- No, babe. The batteries would be dead.
PAUL: We might be able to find some cables,
though. Check the cars. Let's go!
Oh, fuck.
MICHAEL:
Oi! Oi!
Jesus! What the fuck?
- Who would shoot at a bus?
- I don't know, babe.
The guards?
These are exit holes. Whatever was shooting,
was shooting from the inside out.
ZOE: Can we just find these cables, please?
AMANDA: Yeah.
Paul?
Paul? Paul?!
PAUL:
Amanda, there's shells everywhere.
Maybe there's a gun in here.
AMANDA:
Let's look.
Wait, no. No.
Let's get back to Michael and Zoe.
What if something's back there?
Goddamn it.
Nothing.
AMANDA: Ahh!
- Oh, shit!
AMANDA:
You okay?
Yeah.
Come on.
AMANDA: Any bullets?
- No.
- It's broken, it won't fire.
- Look.
It works.
PAUL:
That's a piece of a guard uniform.
Let's get out of here.
Let's go.
MICHAEL:
Oi!
AMANDA:
What?
AMANDA: Is it the same one?
MICHAEL: Oh, yeah!
- Will it work? Do you think it'll work?
- I think so.
- Are you fucking kidding me?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Call your bro.
Hey, Natalie? This is Paul.
Are you guys there?
NATALIE:
Yeah, we're here. Where are you guys?
You're not gonna believe this.
We got cables for the van.
When are you coming back?
We're heading back now.
How's my brother doing?
He's fine. Please hurry back.
Because we wanna get the fuck out of here.
[DOGS BARKING IN DISTANCE]
Come on, come on!
Hey, Chris? You hang in there, buddy.
We're coming back for you right now!
We're on our way.
MICHAEL:
Come on, Zoe!
ZOE:
I can't run!
MICHAEL: Go! Go, go, go!
ZOE: Oh, my God!
MICHAEL:
This way. Here, here, here!
PAUL:
All right, come on, come on!
Come on!
MICHAEL:
Go, babe. Ahh!
You gotta go! You gotta go.
Keep moving, come on! Come on!
MICHAEL: You gotta go!
ZOE: All right, all right.
MICHAEL:
Come on, come on.
PAUL:
Zoe, you've gotta keep moving, babe!
AMANDA: Zoe, it's okay.
PAUL: Come on, Zoe.
Yes!
MICHAEL: Come on, Zoe!
PAUL: You can do it, Zoe! Come on!
PAUL:
Keep moving!
AMANDA: Zoe!
ZOE: Oh, no!
PAUL:
Oh, shit!
AMANDA: Zoe!
PAUL: Zoe!
[GRUNTING & SPEAKING INCOHERENTLY]
[MICHAEL SCREAMS]
ZOE:
Michael!
- Get him out, get him out.
PAUL: Get him out.
MICHAEL: Oh, my leg! My leg!
- Are you okay?
MICHAEL: It's just a scratch. It's okay.
- Get him up. Let's get him up.
MICHAEL:
Pull me up!
- Come on!
PAUL: We gotta move!
- Look at me! Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
PAUL: Guys, come on.
Let's get the fuck out of here!
MICHAEL:
Damn it!
PAUL: How's the leg?
MICHAEL: I'm all right, mate.
- I just want to get us out of here.
PAUL: Chris should be in Moscow right now.
Exactly, but he's not. So tell me what you
know so we can figure out what is going on.
Just urban legend, man.
They say this place isn't really abandoned.
Obviously, the radiation
hasn't killed everything.
- I don't believe any of that shit.
- Why not can't you believe it?
There's so much that's been going on,
there's people gotta be out here doing this shit.
- Think about it!
- There has to be something. He's right.
- I mean, think about it.
- Chris.
Uri. That thing in the kitchen.
What was that?
And I swear there was something
in a photo I took the other day.
I didn't think anything of it at the time, but--
- See? The photo.
- It was a shadow--
It didn't make sense at the time,
nothing had happened then.
Listen. Listen, okay? Listen.
[CREATURE SCREAMS]
MICHAEL: Zoe, come on.
PAUL: Come on, let's go!
MICHAEL:
What? This is where we were.
AMANDA: Maybe they got it started?
PAUL: And they wouldn't call us?
- Natalie?
MICHAEL: Wait, look! Over here.
ZOE:
What? Is that from the van?
AMANDA:
Oh, my God.
MICHAEL:
What the fuck?
- Oh, fuck. Oh, fuck.
PAUL: Chris!
- Chris!
MICHAEL: Shh!
PAUL:
Fuck!
- Chris!
- Keep it down, mate.
Hey, come here!
ZOE:
Hey, guys! It's recording.
MICHAEL:
What, what?
ZOE:
I don't know. It's Chris.
NATALIE: What are you talking about?
CHRIS: Just listen.
- I love you, Natalie.
NATALIE: I love you, too, baby.
- I love you so much.
- I know.
I just need you to know that.
I was gonna wait till Moscow, but--
No, babe, wait till Moscow.
We're gonna be there tomorrow and then
you can do everything as planned, okay?
I know, but I just--
[BANGING]
NATALIE:
What was that?
Babe, grab the camera. Shine it over here.
CHRIS: Is that them?
- I don't know.
- Can you see anything?
CHRIS: I don't see anybody.
- Is it Paul?
NATALIE: I don't know.
[NATALIE SCREAMS]
[CRASHING]
[CHRIS SCREAMING]
[CREATURES GROWLING]
PAUL: What the fuck is happening? No--
MICHAEL: Keep it down.
- Chris!
- Keep your shit together.
Stay the fuck away from me!
MICHAEL:
Shit! Just keep it down.
- I'm not leaving my brother!
- He's not here.
[SCREAM IN DISTANCE]
- Chris!
- What was that?
PAUL: Chris? Chris? Chris!
ZOE: Please, be quiet.
Shit!
PAUL:
Chris!
We can't leave them.
We can't leave them. We need to find them.
We need to find them! Please! Let's go!
Please, Michael, we need to find them.
- Fucking hell!
AMANDA: Please!
MICHAEL:
There, through there.
Careful.
PAUL:
Oh, Chris!
Wait!
Chris?
AMANDA:
Natalie?
MICHAEL [WHISPERS]:
Is that Chris?
PAUL:
Chris?
Chris?!
MICHAEL:
Come on, he's not here.
Baby, we have to, he's got the gun.
Come on.
PAUL:
Chris?
AMANDA:
Nat?
PAUL:
Chris?
- He's not here.
- I heard him. I heard him.
- Paul! We have to go!
- We can't stay here. Let's go.
Come on, please?
Please, mate, we'll find him.
I'm sorry. Come on.
[CREATURE SHRIEKS
& GROUP SCREAMS]
AMANDA:
Run!
[NATALIE SCREAMS]
AMANDA:
Natalie! Natalie.
Come on. Come on, Nat, come on!
ZOE: Oh, Jesus!
MICHAEL: Come on! This way, this way!
AMANDA: I got her! I got her!
Okay, you're okay, baby. You're okay.
ZOE:
Michael!
AMANDA:
I got you. It's okay.
MICHAEL:
It's a fucking map. Look!
PAUL:
Natalie, where's Chris?
- Natalie, where's Chris?!
AMANDA: Shh. Shh. Paul!
What happened to my brother?
While we're going this way, he's in there!
Hey, leave her alone!
Shit.
PAUL:
Natalie, where's Chris?
All right, hold this, hold this.
That's the road we came in on.
So then we came on to the checkpoint,
and that's another checkpoint.
And we're here.
Hey, there's another checkpoint!
It's close. We can get there.
We'll find help and come back. I promise.
- I can't leave yet.
MICHAEL: I understand, but we gotta go.
I'm not leaving without my brother!
We need to! We don't even know
if Chris is still--
Don't you fucking say that!
Give me the gun! Back off! Back off!
I'm sorry, mate. We want to help you.
We'll find your brother, I promise,
but we gotta go. We need help.
Please? Please?
Paul, Paul?
No, Paul! We're gonna find Chris but we
are no good to him if we're dead, okay?
Listen to me! Listen to me, Paul, okay?
We're gonna go find help
and we're gonna come back...
...and we're gonna get your brother, okay?
MICHAEL: We need to get out of here.
Show me the map again.
Right now, I need you to get it together.
For everyone else's sake and mine.
All right?
Come on!
[GEIGER COUNTER BEEPING]
ZOE:
That doesn't make sense.
The radiation's getting worse.
We've got to keep going. Come on.
We've got to keep going, come on!
Zoe, come on.
ZOE: Here, Michael, it doesn't make sense.
- What do you mean?
ZOE: Because the map says
that we're supposed to be here?
MICHAEL: We gotta go that way.
ZOE: No, but look.
It says that this way is supposed to--
Michael, look at it, it stops!
- Then we have to go back.
PAUL: Which way do we have to go?
- If we go back here--
- I know it's not. Zoe, Zoe, please?
- Michael, no, we have to go!
AMANDA: Guys, guys!
MICHAEL:
What the fuck?
Wait!
PAUL:
Hello?
[SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
ZOE:
What are you saying?
[NATALIE SCREAMS]
AMANDA:
Natalie!
ZOE:
Oh, my God!
AMANDA:
No!
MICHAEL: Where is she?
AMANDA: She's gone!
Natalie!
[NATALIE SCREAMS IN DISTANCE]
Listen, listen!
This way, this way!
MICHAEL:
Zoe, stay in front of me.
PAUL:
Holy shit! That's a guard!
- Oh, my God.
PAUL: Go, go, go!
Natalie?
Natalie?!
[GROUP CHATTERS INDISTINCTLY]
Nat!
MICHAEL: Where is she?
AMANDA: I don't know.
[CREATURES GROWLING]
MICHAEL:
Oh, fuck. Oh, fuck.
Move, move, move! Come on!
ZOE:
Michael! Michael!
MICHAEL: Fuck, there's too many!
AMANDA: Come on!
MICHAEL: Where the fuck are they?
Keep going, keep going.
Come on!
PAUL:
Hurry the fuck up!
MICHAEL:
Boxes! Shut the fucking door!
PAUL:
Push! Push!
ZOE:
They're coming!
[BANGING ON DOOR]
MICHAEL:
Grab another one!
[ZOE SCREAMS]
AMANDA: Kick it!
MICHAEL: There's another room back here!
ZOE:
Michael, come on!
MICHAEL:
Zoe, just get going! Go, go, go!
ZOE: Michael!
MICHAEL: I'm coming!
PAUL: Go, get in, get in.
ZOE: Michael!
MICHAEL:
Zoe, will you go on!
PAUL:
Zoe, get inside!
Close the door.
PAUL: Push it! Push it!
MICHAEL: It's stuck!
PAUL:
Michael, get in! Get in!
[MICHAEL SCREAMS]
ZOE:
Michael!
[ZOE SHRIEKS]
[SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[SOBBING]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
No, we have to go.
PAUL:
Go!
[ZOE GAGS]
PAUL:
Zoe, Zoe, Zoe.
AMANDA:
It's okay.
No, no, no, no, Zoe!
PAUL:
Get up, Zoe, come on.
I got you, I got you. Come on.
AMANDA:
What is this place?
PAUL:
Shit.
ZOE:
Not down. Not down.
[CREATURES SCREAM IN DISTANCE]
PAUL:
Fuck!
Go! Go!
Oh, fuck. Put the light on!
Put the fucking light on!
[CREATURES GROWLING IN DISTANCE]
[ZOE COUGHS]
PAUL:
Oh, fuck.
This must be where they were living.
Keep moving. Come on, keep moving.
- Chris? Chris?!
AMANDA: Shh!
Chris?
[GROWLS]
Go, go, go!
AMANDA:
Which way?
PAUL:
Come on, I'll help you.
AMANDA: Paul, go!
PAUL: Give me your hand.
ZOE: Oh, my God! They're coming!
PAUL: Give me your hand!
Come on! Give me your hand!
Give me your hand! Pull!
[SCREAMS]
PAUL:
Don't let go, Zoe!
No!
No! No!
AMANDA:
Up here, up here.
Come on, come on!
Paul?
PAUL:
I let them all go.
It's my fault.
[PAUL SOBS]
Come on, come on. We can still find them.
We can still find them.
Come on, let's just go.
We can still find them. Come on.
Please? Just take my hand. Come on.
We gotta get out of here.
[GEIGER COUNTER
BEEPING RAPIDLY]
PAUL:
There's something wrong with my eyes.
Oh, fuck.
My face is burning.
Fuck, you look all blurry.
What is that?
[CREATURES GROWLING IN DISTANCE]
Oh, shit! Oh, shit!
Come on! Come on! Please, hurry!
PAUL: Everything's blurry.
- I know. I got you. Come on.
PAUL: We gotta find a way out of here
before the radiation kills us.
AMANDA: Are you okay?
- Yeah, go. I'm fine.
AMANDA:
Careful. Okay.
PAUL:
Oh, no.
[MOANS]
I'm so sorry, Amanda.
No.
[CRASHING IN DISTANCE]
Amanda, we can't stay here.
We can't stay here. We have to go.
And I can't leave without you,
so please, let's just go.
[PAUL WHEEZING]
PAUL: Wait.
- A way out.
PAUL:
Oh, fuck.
Holy shit.
[SCREAMING & GRUNTING]
AMANDA:
Run! Run!
[BOTH WHEEZING & GAGGING]
PAUL:
I can't see anything.
- I can't see...
AMANDA: Help!
- Help!
PAUL:
Help!
Help! Ugh...
- We need help!
AMANDA: Help!
PAUL:
Please!
SOLDIER [IN RUSSIAN]:
PAUL:
Help us, please!
- Please, help us!
AMANDA: Please, stop!
PAUL:
Please!
AMANDA:
No!
[MAN SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
GROTZKY: Hello? Hello? Can you hear me?
What is your name?
Where are you taking me?
My face!
GROTZKY:
It's okay. How did you get into Pripyat?
There were people. They were chasing us.
GROTZKY: Yes, patients, victim of radiation.
They escaped.
You saw them, yes?
They killed my friends.
GROTZKY: Anyone else know you're here?
- No.
Where are you taking me?
AMANDA:
What is this place?
GROTZKY: We're in the hospital.
We're taking you to doctor.
DOCTOR [IN RUSSIAN]:
GROTZKY [IN RUSSIAN]:
DOCTOR:
GROTZKY:
My skin is burning.
[IN ENGLISH] You were inside reactor.
It's extremely dangerous.
Okay.
We will help.
- Oh, oh, oh.
AMANDA: Ow.
[DOCTOR & GROTZKY
SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
- No, no, no!
DOCTOR: Go, go!
Who's there?
[SCREAMS]