3438.
This is it.
Pull into the driveway.
Use the remote to open the garage.
Do not exit the vehicle.
Close the garage door behind you.
Wait for further instructions.
Follow me.
Be thorough with the soap.
Eleven workers lost their lives.
Seventeen others were injured.
And soon,
nearly a mile beneath the surface...
Stand.
... of the ocean, oil began...
... spewing into the water.
Your records?
Because there's never been a leak...
Hold on to that.
... this size at this depth...
...stopping it has tested the limits
of human technology.
That's why just after the rig sank,
I assembled a team...
...of our nation's best scientists
and engineers to tackle this challenge....
Step up. watch your head.
Let me see your hand.
Finally, Peter.
Welcome.
Let's gather round. Take a seat.
First I'd like to say
welcome to our new members.
As is our custom, they have been
preparing on the outside for some time...
...but now we feel
they are ready to graduate...
...and to join us.
So let me introduce Peter
and his girlfriend, Lorna.
And this is Christine and her husband, Lam.
Now, let me say a word to you new folk.
No sudden movements.
And no questions for tonight.
The first night is always the most difficult.
But as our other members here can attest...
...an unforgettable experience.
Okay.
Maggie.
Hi.
It's nice to see new faces.
Thank you all for taking the precautions
to come here.
It shows you have a great deal of faith.
Now let me return that trust...
...in telling you my story.
Like anything new...
...it will be impossible
for your mind to digest.
Maybe close your eyes.
Try opening up. Here.
Try listening from your heart.
Two years ago, I woke up underwater.
It was a bathtub,
filled about three-quarters high.
I was gasping for breath.
Coughing up...
...snorting out this water.
I felt this...
...terrible sense of loss.
Like when you wake up from dreaming
about someone you love so much.
And you turn around in bed and remember...
...that they've been dead for years.
What was I doing in that motel room?
I remembered my name, my birthday.
October 31st.
Nothing else.
I ended up out on the streets.
As people with no ID...
...no money...
...no memories do.
I felt really lonely.
And exhausted all the time.
My immune system was gone.
At that time, my legs and my right arm
would fall asleep.
Like in meditation, you know, but for hours.
And I couldn't wake them up.
They were strangers to me.
And I couldn't remember anything.
But I still had to wake up every day,
still had to keep going.
I had no idea who I was
or what I was doing here.
And that's when Klaus found me.
He had heard about me from others.
Had heard of my tattoos.
And he took me in.
And he fed me.
And he gave me vitamins.
In about three or four weeks...
...I started to remember things.
Many terrible things.
Violent images.
I was so angry.
I thought I'd lost my mind.
And then Klaus explained it to me.
My tattoos. This failing body.
The things I'd remembered.
What it all meant.
Open your eyes.
I wanna show you something.
You see, the anchor is the sign of a traveler.
And the number 54
refers to where I come from.
You see, I come from 54.
2054.
Your future.
Did we get anything?
Nothing. Static.
We didn't get a single frame?
We went out of range.
Damn it.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
You're, like, shaking.
I'm not shaking, Peter. I'm a little racy.
It's just a bunch of crap, Lorna.
Yeah, I know.
They're weak
and they're looking for meaning.
Yeah.
You know, those people are suckers.
That's it.
But what if she is?
What? From the future?
Uh, no one is from the future, Lorna.
Well, then who is she?
She's a con artist. She's dangerous.
That's why we gotta make this film.
We have to expose her before
she has all those people kill themselves.
I've gotta take a leak.
Are you okay?
You don't wanna come with me?
Peter Aitken likes math, reason, himself.
Things he can count on.
When Peter was 12,
his mother was diagnosed with cancer.
A longtime member of a New Age cult...
...she believed that modern medicine
shouldn't intervene in her fate.
She died on the eve of Peter's birthday,
while they were both asleep.
Peter awoke 13 and motherless.
We began by preparing on the outside...
...meeting at weekly intervals...
...at the West Court shopping strip mall...
...with 20 other new recruits
that were eventually weeded down.
Couldn't tell the exact location
of the house.
By my count, we were in the van
for approximately 20 minutes...
...but it's possible that they were giving us
the runaround, so....
Hey.
To see her is to believe her.
But of course, that's how these cons work.
Even if the new recruits doubt her story,
they'll be back for more.
I'm trying to work. Please?
Maggie says
that the future is already written...
...and that her members
are the chosen ones.
Peter Aitken signing off.
Good morning, everybody.
Uh, Miss Parker had her baby,
so she will be out for a couple months.
And that means
you guys are stuck with me, Mr. Aitken.
So, what will it be, ladies?
We have the American Civil War
or the anatomy of a cell?
Lorna?
Lorna.
What?
Lorna Michaelson.
Daughter of Hollywood producer
Isaac Michaelson...
...and Allie Bernard,
the British model turned actress.
Lorna was left to an unchaperoned
adolescence of movie premieres...
...and club openings.
Lorna had her first hangover at 12,
her first intervention at 16.
By 23 she was burnt out,
tired of playing entourage.
So Lorna cleaned up her act.
Tequila shots replaced with
wheatgrass shots.
But in the end, it was one addiction
traded for another.
Lorna.
Watch your head.
Shake it out. Shake it out now.
You are fools.
Your muscles are tight
with repressed feelings.
Who you were before is irrelevant.
Let go of you, become the group.
I have to exhaust you people...
...to get you to stop thinking
and start breathing.
Don't be worried.
Maggie's tests will get harder.
But if you pass,
then you're meant to be with us.
Then you will be ready when it begins.
This is where we grow Maggie's food.
Go on, pick one.
Okay.
Are you good?
Yeah, fine. Do it.
Just think about Maggie.
She's allergic to absolutely everything
in this time period.
You can eat these?
Of course you can, kiddo. Heh.
It's the grocery store
you've gotta be wary of.
Produce grown by
someone you've never met...
...sitting in trucks for weeks...
...sprayed with, I don't know,
who knows what.
Yeah, but these aren't
exactly natural either.
Well, true. But Maggie says
when prices go up...
...people will start growing gardens
in their garages.
We'll be all right though.
Maggie's taking us to a safe place.
Maggie? Are you dying?
Yeah.
So are you. So is PJ.
Joanne's dying. Peter's dying.
Lorna's dying.
Every life is a death.
And most deaths are suicides.
Some are more gradual than others,
like cancer after years of smoking.
Or in my case...
...traveling back in time
to save the people you love.
Even if you kiss him as you leave the room
And even if we don't say a word
In front of them
And even if we never get to show our friends
Is that Abigail Pritchett?
At least three episodes a week.
Maybe she has narcolepsy.
She's always in that hat.
Okay, I bring you some hot milk. Okay?
Can you look at me
for a second there, Lorna?
Hello, Peter.
Hmm.
Okay. well, this transmitter records
everything from the camera...
...but would go out of range
outside of 50 feet.
So how in the world
do we bring this with us?
Peter. No way.
Well, people need to see this.
People need to see a video of Maggie.
Peter, that's too big to swallow.
Don't swallow that.
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
Eat this.
Give it some padding
so it won't tear you up on the way out.
Are you okay?
Not sure.
Yeah. Ahem.
Close your eyes.
Go backwards to childhood.
Travel back to a time before words.
Are you there?
What does it smell like?
What does it taste like?
How do you feel?
Now live there.
Okay, come back to me.
Come back to the present.
Now you can eat your apple.
Do you know what's in that apple?
Logic.
Bitterness.
It's intellectual bullshit.
You've already eaten the apple.
That's what it means to grow up.
The question is...
...how much of it can you get rid of?
The apple is in you.
Like the fear is in you.
It's spreading throughout your body
like a virus.
How can we purge ourselves of shame...
...of self-hatred...
...and rise to our callings as chosen ones?
You all have the privilege
of knowing the future.
But are you gonna be ready for it?
Pathetic.
See how committed Christine is.
You're purifying yourself.
Preparing to receive your destiny.
Feels good to be rid of the apple, doesn't it?
Peter, there's no rush. We'll wait for you.
Thanks, but I can't throw up. Uh....
Never have, not even as a kid. So....
All the more reason to let go now.
Just let it go, Peter.
Just relax.
And let it come up and out.
Lorna.
Sit down.
Lorna's fine.
She's just protecting you.
Do you wanna be a cripple
for life, Peter?
You're letting her be your crutch.
Do you like being lame?
Ask yourself...
...why do I like being lame?
Ask yourself.
Ask yourself now. Say it.
Say, "Why do I like being lame?"
Um....
Why do I like being lame?
That's a good question.
Why do you like being lame?
I don't know.
Liar.
You do know.
We don't have anywhere to go.
Do we?
No.
We'll all just sit here breathing in the
smell of everyone's puke until you can talk.
Because I don't wanna face myself.
Okay. why?
Because I might not....
I might not like what I see.
What do you see?
Weakness.
Tell me something I don't already know.
You wanna know what I see?
An anal-retentive prick.
Who can't dance, who can't breathe.
Stop it.
Can't make his girlfriend come...
...because he's so self-involved.
Who took your power away from you?
Who made you feel so powerless
you've become obsessed with control?
With thinking everything through
instead of feeling anything.
Who?
Who hurt you so much
you never wanna feel that way again?
Was it your father?
Was it your mother?
Shut up.
Shut the fuck up, you fucking cunt.
What are you hiding from me, Peter?
She abandon you?
She leave you to start another family?
Was she a whore?
I'll hit you.
I'll hit you in the face.
What'd she do to make you so angry?
Shut up. This is so stupid.
What'd she do to you?
She gave up.
She died.
I was a kid. And she died.
She's dead. Everybody happy?
What happened next?
You live with your dad?
Did you live in a foster home?
No.
Who took care of you?
My grandparents.
I see.
You were a good-looking kid,
weren't you?
You're handsome now.
But you must have been beautiful then.
You were in a new house.
A new bedroom.
You felt abandoned.
Angry. Unloved.
Did he come to you at night?
No, of course not.
She watched him like a hawk,
didn't she?
He wait for you after school?
You were all alone.
Fresh as the fallen snow.
And he knew.
Did he make you swallow his poison?
You were powerless then.
But you're not anymore.
You can let go of it, here, with us.
Peter.
It's not my choice, it's yours.
Let it go.
You're brave.
Thank you.
Are you okay?
Mm-hm. Yeah, I'm fine.
Okay. I know that
we just wanna start our day...
... but if we don't talk about it...
Talk about what?
What do you wanna talk about?
I don't know. I mean....
I guess I've never seen you cry.
Those weren't real tears.
But they weren't fake.
Yes, they were. They were fake tears.
She's a megalomaniac, Lorna.
She knew things about you.
No. She didn't know anything about me.
She asked questions about me.
She wanted to be right
and I let her think she was.
So all that stuff was...?
It was not true.
Come on. Of course it wasn't true.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry If I scared you...
...but I had to do what I had to do
to get us out of there.
Peter, I just feel like we're in over our heads
with this whole thing, you know?
It's like we started out wanting to make
a documentary on cults.
And now we're in one?
Yeah. That's investigative journalism.
She's dangerous, Peter.
You said that yourself.
What do you wanna do?
You wanna go back to our normal lives.
That's fine. We can do that.
I can teach all day.
You can stay home
and write and surf the web.
And on the weekends we can get wasted
at various art installations...
...or sneak forties into random foreign films.
And then it's suddenly, like, we wake up
and, whoops, where did our 20s go?
But somewhere in the Valley...
...there is a woman living in a basement
who claims to be from the future.
She's actually amassing followers.
These people who believe that
she'll lead them to salvation or whatever.
And, yes, she's dangerous...
...but we have to see this thing through
all the way or we're chumps.
Don't you wanna do something
that matters?
Yes.
Let's do it.
We're a team.
We're a team?
Oh, we are totally a team.
I'm doing this with you.
Yeah.
So after my husband up
and left me...
...I wore the same pair
of sweatpants for two years.
It was Maggie who got me to see
that humans belong in the woods...
... and not in condos.
Yeah. I'm glad that you called.
This is good.
Yeah, it feels good, don't it?
Hey, come here.
I wanna show you something.
After you.
Well, maybe we shouldn't go in
all the way because I have to be back.
Oh, come on, you'll like this.
Come on.
I do the La Brea Tar Pits field trip.
I said, you wanna run a trip, you do
the paperwork yourself, like everyone else.
Trying to steal my trip.
Give me that!
Heidi, Stop it. What in the world?
Heidi, I said stop it. Get off.
She ruined my backpack. It's new.
Get back to work. Get back to work.
The show is over.
What's happened here?
My backpack. She wrote.
You okay?
Here. I'll help you up.
Joanne?
I need to get back.
We're here.
Can't turn around now.
Here.
Why do you have a gun?
Joanne. This is weird, okay?
Hey.
I would just like to go.
Okay. Calm down.
Trust, Lorna. It is very important
that we trust each other.
We're family now.
First rule.
Always treat a gun as if it's loaded,
even if it's not.
Always keep it pointed down.
That's how you keep from
killing somebody or yourself.
Okay, you try it.
I'd rather just watch you.
Come on.
Don't be silly. I loaded it for you.
Yeah, but I just don't feel comfortable.
Nonsense. It's important.
Okay. Legs apart.
Come on.
Okay, now remember...
...push with the right hand,
pull with the left.
Okay? Keeps you steady.
Hi.
I texted you.
My phone died.
You wanna make huevos rancheros?
So, what happened with Joanne?
Oh, my God. She took me on a hike
through the woods...
...to this shooting range.
But it turns out I'm actually pretty good at it.
Uh, why is Joanne teaching
you how to shoot a gun?
I don't know, fun?
That's fun?
What do you think?
I don't know what to think.
That's the problem.
We don't know who these people are,
what they're capable of.
What's this "safe place" that Maggie
keeps talking about bringing us to?
Um, I was just wondering.
What's it gonna be like
when the civil war starts?
Things come together.
And they fall apart.
It's a really dark time.
My generation is really comfortable
with death.
And people die around you all the time.
But there's still beauty.
Especially when people start moving
to the countryside.
There's dancing and theater.
Lovemaking.
Are there still, like, CDs or MP3s
or something?
Um....
Not everybody has access
to that kind of technology...
...so there's not as many recorded albums...
...but there's a lot of live music.
But every once in a while...
...a song will come along
that moves everyone.
And that finds a way of getting around.
Even without MP3s.
Will you sing us something from your time?
No.
Come on.
I don't sing.
Come on, please?
Yeah, yeah.
Just one song.
We wanna hear the future.
You wanna what the future...?
Yeah.
what the future sounds like?
Uh....
Okay.
This song was really popular
right before I left.
I'm so sorry. I can't. Sorry.
We'll close our eyes.
Yeah.
Mm-hm.
Okay.
Oh, my life
Is changing every day
In every possible way
Oh, my dreams
It's never quite as it seems
Now I tell you openly
You have my heart so don't hurt me
For what I couldn't find
Totally amazing mind
So understanding and so kind
You're everything to me
Do you wanna try singing
the last with me?
It goes:
Oh, my life
Is changing every day
In every possible way
In all my dreams
It's never quite as it seems
'Cause you're a dream to me
Dream to me
Thanks.
Yeah. That was good.
Maggie?
I, uh.... I mean no disrespect.
But that song, you know...
I'm sure you know, is by The Cranberries.
It was from, like, the '90s.
The 1990s.
Oh, that could be.
I wouldn't know
because I wasn't alive in the '90s.
In the future, it's made famous
by a singer named Benetton.
Can you tell us something
from the future that we could prove?
Something soon.
Huh.
When were you born?
Seventy-nine.
Okay.
Prove to me that you were alive in the '80s.
Tell me something that happened
in the spring of 1959.
What?
I was born in 2030.
You're asking me to tell you something
that happens in 2010.
That's twenty years before I'm born.
So I'm asking you to do the same.
Tell me something that happens
in the spring of 1959.
Uh....
Kennedy was assassinated.
In 1963.
That's four years from 1959.
You want me to tell you something
you can prove in 2014?
Would that make you happy?
What will you do with yourself until then?
I could tell you a major event a few years off.
And after that it's gonna be
event after event after event.
But a mind as narrow as yours...
...would have no idea
what to do with that information.
You may go now, Lam.
I was just.... I didn't...
Let's go.
Wait.
Christine, you're gonna have to decide
what you wanna do here.
Christie.
Christie, she's lying. It's obvious.
You're all crazy!
I can't get that song out of my head.
Ah, neither can I.
If you were gonna pick
a song to be from the future...
...why would it be "Dreams"
by The Cranberries?
Remove Peter's restraints, please.
If you'll come with me, please, Peter,
Maggie will see you.
Just Peter, Lorna.
Okay.
I'll wait here.
No need. we'll drive you home.
Enter.
You can sit down.
Ah.
I'm from the future. I'm not a saint.
Are you and Lorna happy here with us?
Yes.
Yes. Of course we are.
People leave.
Other people I kick out...
...because they're sick or lazy.
You're neither one of those, are you?
No. No, I'm not.
Do you know why
I kicked Lam out?
Because he questioned you?
No.
I'm not petty.
I don't really care if people believe me.
I don't know that I would
if I was in their shoes.
Well, why'd you kick him out?
Because I knew Christine growing up.
But I never saw Lam.
I don't think he belonged with us.
Are Lorna and I there?
That's for you to decide.
We wanna be there.
Will you do me a favor?
Anything.
Yeah?
This is Abigail Pritchett.
I don't understand.
I need you to bring her to me.
Uh.... Are you joking?
What would you want
with an 8-year-old girl?
Don't worry about that.
Well, there's no way that I'm bringing
a little girl into this basement. That's....
Then perhaps you and Lorna should
stay away from this basement as well.
You don't mean that.
I need to see Abigail Pritchett.
Why?
Bring her to me and stay, or don't and go.
There has to be something else
I can do to prove my loyalty.
There isn't.
It has to cost something
to be worth something.
You are asking me to kidnap
an 8-year-old child.
Not kidnap.
I could get fired or arrested.
I need to know why.
She's important.
How?
She's a very bright little girl.
What do you want with her?
Just to see her.
For what?
Because I need to.
Need to?
Who is she?
Abigail Pritchett is my mother.
Okay.
Time for bed.
Come on.
That's okay. Come on.
Okay.
So?
So....
She wants me to bring her
one of my students.
Wait. what?
Yeah.
Abigail Pritchett.
Did she say why?
Yeah.
Maggie claims that the girl is her mom.
Well, how did they even know
that you worked at the school?
I don't know. I must have mentioned it.
I think we should go to the police.
Police?
Yeah.
Yeah. Um, hello, Officer Randal.
Yes? Hello.
I'd like to report a time-traveler...
...living in a basement somewhere.
I don't know where exactly.
They want you to bring them
an 8-year-old.
That's kidnapping.
I know that and I'd be the one doing it.
So, what are they gonna arrest her for?
Soliciting blood?
Okay. So you're...?
All right, let me get this straight.
So you're actually considering
bringing them the girl?
No. No.
Are you?
No, no, no.
It's a test. If we don't do this,
they're gonna kick us out.
Are you listening to yourself?
You always do this.
What do I always do?
What are you talking about?
You sign up for things and then you bail
when the going gets rough.
What are you talking about?
You. About finishing what we started.
You start novels you never finish.
Take pictures you never develop.
Finish what you fucking start.
You fucking started this.
I'm willing to go all the way.
How far are you gonna go?
And how are you any different
from your mother?
That's a cheap shot.
Yeah?
Not if it had been delivered by Maggie.
Oh, come on.
What?
I see the way that you look at her, Peter.
Pssh. You're kidding, right?
No, I'm not.
Are you jealous of that fraud?
Why not?
She's beautiful.
Mesmerizing.
In 15 minutes she brought you
to an emotional orgasm...
...that I've never seen in three years, Peter.
"Emotional orgasm"? what the fuck is that?
You tell me.
You people. You people make me laugh.
Who is "you people"?
You people...
... Who spend a fucking fortune on therapy.
You could use some.
Rehab. You think because
you put in these man-hours...
...you're somehow entitled
to a degree in psychology?
You're now this expert?
When the truth is, after all those hours,
you fuckups are just arriving at the place...
...the rest of us have been at all our lives.
You know what I think, Peter?
I think it's you who's the fuckup.
You haven't logged tapes
or captured any fucking footage in weeks.
Yeah. You don't give a shit
about making this documentary.
This is about Maggie.
You're willing to do anything for her.
You just said that yourself.
So you know what?
I'm not gonna stand in your way.
I'm gonna help you pack.
What are you doing?
What am I doing?
Get out!
I'm sorry.
We make a horrible team.
Either you stay or you go
But you can't stand there no more
My heart is burning but I
I know I started to cry
And even when I get home
I can still smell you in my clothes
And I won't pack them away
I stutter, I stutter
But just not today
Klaus, it's Peter.
Tell Maggie I'll do it.
It can't be as bad as all that.
You wanna talk about it?
No.
Thank you.
He'll come around.
You're the type of girl
you try to get to marry if you can.
Yeah.
Yeah, I don't know about all that.
Lorna?
How do you know my name?
I think I can help you
restore him to his senses.
You know her as Maggie.
Her real name is Shelly Whipple.
And who are you?
Carol Briggs, with the Justice Department.
Maggie's wanted in Sacramento
for armed robbery...
...and in Fresno for arson.
That's why she never leaves the basement.
Lorna, you are in a unique position here.
You can wash your hands of all of this,
which is what most people would do.
But I don't think you're like most people.
Why are you coming to me?
I mean, why not Peter?
We need a level head.
Someone to be our eyes and ears.
Look, I'll tell you what I know, okay,
but it's not much.
Lorna, we believe Maggie is arming.
Unwitting or not, her subjects
are being fashioned into a militia.
I'm not walking back into a snake pit.
All you have to do
is help us lure the snake out.
I'm sorry. I am done.
Have they asked for a kid?
Yeah, a little girl.
That's part of their con.
Did they say what they wanted her for?
Maggie says it's her mother.
That's a good one.
Can you keep a secret from Peter?
Then I'll tell you
what they really want her for.
I figured it out.
Hi. You scared me.
We do it in a public place.
Do what?
You bring Maggie the girl.
But you don't bring the girl
to the basement.
You arrange a meeting in a place
where we could set up cameras beforehand.
What made you change your mind?
You were right.
I think we should finish what we started.
I mean, we wanted to make a documentary...
...and what better climax
than for Maggie to meet her mother?
Come on.
We'll be late.
Are you all right, Lorna?
Yeah.
I'm just hungry.
My dad used to say that the hardest thing
for humans is transition.
We're survivors.
We can live in conditions
beyond your wildest imagination.
You guys have been fasting for a week.
Some of you have cheated.
You're only cheating yourselves.
In the future, food is scarce...
...and real hunger will be a part of life.
I have food for you.
You don't have to eat it.
But trust me that the thought of eating it...
...is much scarier than the reality.
The ones who will not only survive
but will thrive...
...are the ones who realize
that there's nothing to be afraid of.
O'Shea,
you want something to eat?
It's just new to you.
Food that moves.
Lorna?
I'm vegan.
Fair enough.
Peter?
Mel.
Very soon this group
is gonna begin its journey.
I won't be with you.
What? Where are you going?
It's just change.
And you guys are gonna be fine.
And...
...if you allow yourself...
...to get quiet now and again...
...to really be still...
...you will hear the sound of my voice.
Next Friday, there's a class field trip.
You know Maggie can't leave.
The microorganisms of our time
are too intense for her immune system.
She's lived on the outside before.
Yes, and it nearly killed her.
Well, it's the best I can do.
Bring Maggie to the La Brea Tar Pits
at 1 p. m. next Friday...
...I'll bring you Abigail Pritchett.
Mrs. Dewitt is unable to make it in today.
So Mr. Aitken will be chaperoning
your trip to the La Brea Tar Pits.
I hope to hear good things from him.
Guys.
Okay, everybody chill out. Chill out, guys.
Sandra.
When you see Peter leave with Abby, text "hi."
You'll receive a "hi" back and Andy
will come and chaperone the class.
Then you, you need to follow Peter
at a distance.
When Maggie arrives, text a smiley face.
Be sure to keep your phone with you.
That's how we know where you are.
And they know not to harm Peter, right?
No one's gonna harm anyone.
Most likely you won't even see Maggie.
We'll be sure to take her on entry.
Peter will never know
that you were involved.
Happy endings for all.
When we say "prehistoric,"
we mean "pre-writing"...
...a time before man could record
his written experience.
And in 3500 BC,
which was only about 5000 years ago...
...the written language
and thus man's recorded history began.
I wanna go back inside.
Just a second.
What am I being punished for?
Nothing.
Nothing, okay? You're not in trouble.
Okay. Listen, can you keep a secret?
My friend Maggie, she is an actress...
...and she wants to hang out with kids...
...because she is going to be
playing a mother, right?
So she just wants somebody
that she can, you know, play pretend with.
And I picked you.
I hope you don't mind.
Is she on TV?
Where's Maggie?
Go out the side entrance with Abby.
You'll receive a call with instructions.
No.
No way. This is not what we agreed to.
Tell Maggie that it has to be here or nothing.
I'll chaperone your class.
Take off your shoes.
Lorna's watching the class.
That's not the issue.
Take off your shoes.
Don't take those off, Abby.
I wanna meet Maggie.
No, you don't.
This is not what we agreed to.
You have half an hour till your bus boards.
Maggie's gonna get what she wants,
with or without you.
Come on.
Why do we take off our shoes?
Shh. We gotta keep quiet now, okay?
This is not what we agreed to.
This is not...
Yeah. Yeah, I see it. I see the....
Don't be scared.
Why would I be scared?
Don't come any closer.
Okay, I'm ready. Just the girl.
If I take off my shawl,
will you take off your hat?
How do you know my secret handshake?
You taught it to me.
Shelly Whipple, you're under arrest.
What?
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can be used...
...against you in a court of law.
You have the right to an attorney.
If you cannot afford an attorney,
one will be provided.
wait.
She's sick, you bastards!
Come on.
Let her go! Let her go!
What did you do, Peter?
Traitor.
You traitor.
Let's go call the attorney.
Who is she?
I don't know.
Peter.
It's not my choice.
It's yours.
My friend once told me
Something so right
He said to be careful
Of thieves in the night
Baby, I've lost you here in the crowd
Open your arms
I want to be found
Maybe I'm calling your name in the night
Open our eyes
We'll feel with our sight
A want is a lack but also desire
A need can be nothing
But should be held higher
A need is a want wearing disguise
It can be confused if fueled by desire
Baby, I'm calling your name in the night
No reason with need
Look into my eyes
Happiness is what we all want
May it be that we don't always want
May it be that we don't all want
My friend once told me
Something so right
He said to be careful
Of bugs that don't bite
My friend once told me
Something so right
He said to be careful
Of thieves in the night
Happiness is what we all want
May it be that we don't always want