(TRAIN RATTLING)
(MAN SIGHS) You're in my place.
I'm sorry?
You're in my place.
(RATTLING FADING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
Oh, I'm sorry.
(BUZZING)
(HYDRAULICS HISS)
(PHONES RINGING)
(BEEPS, RATTLES)
(BUZZES)
Hey, you!
Me?
Visitors have to sign in.
Oh wait, I've worked
here for seven years.
I see you every day.
I don't work weekends...
I'm sorry?
...It is therefore impossible
for you to see me every day. I.D.
Yeah, I...
Supplementary I.D.
Oh yeah, the funny thing
is I don't have any.
It's actually in my case, which
is in the door of a train.
It got stuck.
Do you think that's funny?
No. No, it's actually more
upsetting than anything else.
Don't make a jest of this, sir.
I won't.
(PHONE CONTINUES RINGING)
Oh, um... Actually my
name is Simon James.
Uh, you left off the
"J" in my last name.
(BANGS)
I need to see your pass.
Right.
(BEEPS, RATTLES)
- Uh-huh.
Sorry.
(WHIRRING)
(THUMPS)
(SOFT CHIMING)
(RAPID TAPPING)
(BUZZING)
(FAINT RATTLING)
(CLICKING)
(BEEPS, WHIRS)
(OVERLAPPING MACHINE NOISES)
MAN: Put your jacket on, son.
This isn't a brothel.
No shirking! This is the big push!
Plenty to do. The Colonel is counting
on each and every one of you, as am I.
Mr. Papadopoulos, actually...
Mr. Papadopoulos, excuse me.
Mr. Papadopoulos, I've finished up.
In fact, I completed substantially
more than my quota.
I took my jacket off only
because it's so hot,
not because I mistook the
office for a brothel.
Excellent job. That's the
type of initiative we need.
How long have you been here, son?
Just started, eh?
Yes sir, seven years ago.
You know we've been
pruning the dead wood.
The Colonel refuses to
carry any more passengers.
Er, actually, I have some
rather exciting ideas
I've been wanting to share
with the Colonel about how
we could make our
reports more efficient.
I think by using simple
regression analysis
we could really reconfigure
the entire business.
My daughter's name is Melanie.
A nice name.
(GAME BEEPING)
She's interning for the holidays.
Say hello, Melanie.
Hello, Melanie.
Stanley here is gonna
be your mentor.
Yes. What?
An hour a day,
at your discretion.
She's a good girl,
but no head for figures.
Yeah.
(GAME CONTINUES BEEPING)
Idiot.
You can go now.
Right. Yes, thank you.
Because if I were to
find out how depressing
and demeaning whatever the
fuck it is you do here,
I might be forced to
feel sorry for you.
Right. Well,
I look forward to it.
(LOUD WHIRRING)
(WHIRS)
(BEEPS)
(ELEVATOR WHIRS)
(TRAIN SQUEALS)
(COUGHS)
Hi.
Copy.
(TIMER RINGING)
- Oh.
(BELL DINGS)
Why don't you print out two copies?
That would make sense.
That would be what a
normal person would do.
Sorry.
You can't use this place for one copy.
It was the same story yesterday.
Sorry.
You're always sorry.
Sorry about that.
Hey, Hannah, can you stay late?
I've gotta get this thing lanced.
Uh-huh.
(SIGHS) One copy.
Yes, please.
(WATER RUMBLING)
(WIND BLOWING)
SIMON: I know.
I know!
Yes, mom, I'll be there.
I always work late.
I'm trying to leave now.
Because I'm talking to you. Yeah.
Okay. Yes. Bye.
You can rely on me. Okay.
(SLIDES)
(VACUUM WHIRRING)
(BUZZES)
(FLUORESCENT LIGHT HUMMING)
(HUMMING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN ON TV: People...
The ultimate resource.
Yet to some businesses
they all look the same.
But the Colonel knows
people are different.
The Colonel knows business is
people and people are business,
making your business his business.
Because the Colonel knows people.
And the Colonel knows
that you demand
the most powerful
data-processing system
on the planet to make
sense of it all.
The Colonel will show you people
in a way your business
can understand.
Because the Colonel knows
there's no such thing
as special people.
ALL: Just people.
(CLOCK TICKING)
(PERSON SNORING)
Which one was you?
Which one...
I don't know how to answer that.
The one... the one that was me.
He didn't look like you.
He had brown hair.
We both have brown hair.
I mean, I have... I...
We're the same person.
I'm not gonna die ever...
I know.
...so you can forget it.
Okay.
Will you stop talking?
I'm trying to sleep.
Your mother says
you're a strange boy.
I'm sorry?
Your mother says you're a strange boy.
Oh. Thank you.
Let me see your hand.
Oh, that's okay. I'm fine.
You're not right.
May I speak with you?
Yes.
Will you excuse me?
Yes?
There seems to be a
discrepancy in your bill.
Oh yes, well, there was a
rather large cost increase
and no explanation, so I thought...
There's a new price.
And why is that?
Improvements.
That seems a little...
Unfair.
Yeah.
Oh, sorry.
(TRAY RATTLES)
Okay.
(SIGHS)
That's all I have.
Yeah.
It's not enough.
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS)
(WATER RUNNING)
(FAN RATTLING)
(CLICKS)
(TECHNO MUSIC PLAYING)
(WIND BLOWING)
(RATTLING)
(CLATTERING)
You shouldn't be doing that.
Sorry.
(DEEP THUMPS)
(NO DISCERNIBLE DIALOG)
And then what did you do?
Sorry?
(RAIN PATTERING)
And then what did you do?
I called the police.
Right.
Anything else?
He waved at me.
Yeah?
Right before he jumped he waved.
How did he wave?
Did you wave back?
I wonder why he did it.
His note said he was lonely.
He should have got a dog.
Or exercised more.
That's important.
Should I write that down?
Maybe in parenthesis.
Does that mean brackets?
What the fuck are brackets?
Did he suffer?
BOTH: Splat.
Do you see this sort
of thing often?
Every day. That's what
we do... suicides.
Only suicides?
That's right.
For the whole city?
We can barely cover the neighborhood.
You know the funny thing is
he would have landed on that awning if
he'd just jumped a few feet to the right.
You see that? He would
have fallen, bounced off
and landed somewhere about there.
Probably would have survived.
Horribly maimed,
of course, but still.
If you get 'em to the hospital quick
enough to stop the brain swelling.
You're not thinking of
killing yourself, are you?
Sorry?
It's a simple question.
No.
Should I put him down as a "no"?
Put him down as a "maybe."
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
What are you doing here?
The man that jumped?
I saw it.
How?
I live in that building.
I didn't know him.
He waved at me.
Strange.
It's the Colonel's ball tomorrow.
Do you think you'll go?
I don't know if I'll go.
It's mandatory. Everyone has to go.
Hannah?
Yeah?
It's terrible to be alone too much.
(RUMBLING)
I think it was an orange
juice. I just...
Are they normally that rude here?
Yes.
Then why do you come?
I think I'm quite loyal.
(CHUCKLES)
WOMAN ON TV: You'll have to hand
in your holo-badge and blaster.
Come and get 'em.
Holster your blaster, Jack.
I like this show.
JACK: I don't mind dying.
(CHUCKLES)
In fact, I'm getting
quite used to it.
The way I figure it,
you only get one life.
And like they say...
...There's no such thing
as second chances.
WOMAN: Jack, this isn't you.
JACK: Then who the hell is?
He's in your heart.
He's good and right and true.
I was lying when I said
I didn't know him.
The man who jumped?
I kind of knew him.
I'd never really met him.
I'd more confronted him.
He was this person who'd been
following me around for a while,
and I'd always see him,
no matter where I went...
Like at the office, on the
subway, by my apartment.
You know, in that little underpass
thing by the apartments?
He'd just be there, watching.
And I thought, "that's strange."
But, you know, whatever.
Men look at women.
You get used to it.
But then I found out that he lived above
me and I thought, "that's really odd."
Like, did he follow me around because
he lived in the same building as me
and he got fixated? Or did he
get fixated and then move in?
So anyway, eventually I
thought, "you know what?
Enough is enough." Because it was
actually getting frightening.
Well, like a little bit frightening. It
was more annoying than frightening, so...
I went up to him and he looked
over his shoulder at me
as if to say, "who, me?"
Like he hadn't been stalking me.
And so I looked at him square in the eyes
and I said, "what do you want from me?"
(RUMBLE LOUDER)
And he starts stumbling and mumbling
and says, "I think I'm
falling for you."
And I said, "do you think
just staring at me
is some kind of meaningful gesture?
What exactly do you think
is going to happen here?
Do you think you know who I am?
You know, that if you
stare long enough,
I'll just turn around one
day and I'll kiss you?
Like we're going to
somehow be together?
Stop fucking following me!"
(RUMBLING FADING)
(EXHALING)
And he did.
My God, when was this?
Last night.
(MOUTHS)
Do you think there's a connection?
No. I mean, it sounds like he
had a lot of things going on.
I mean, maybe he just wanted
somebody to notice him.
You know, a person can get
really sick of just floating by.
But I attract so many weirdos.
(RUMBLING STARTS)
Anyway what's your story?
When did you move into the building?
A long time ago.
Yeah, I definitely
didn't move in recently.
Thanks for this.
I feel better.
Hey, I just got my ears pierced.
(CHUCKLES)
That's weird, huh, at my age?
No. I mean, you're not that old or weird.
You're just...
Hey, you got a call.
Oh, it's not for me.
Frumpy-looking guy named Simon?
That's me. Yeah.
Would you excuse me? Mom?
No, it's just a night terror.
No, that didn't ever happen.
I know I'm a disappointment.
(WHISPERING)
I have to go now. I'm with a girl.
Yes, a female girl.
I don't know if she's fertile.
(SIGHS)
"Thanks for the talk. Maybe
see you at the ball.
Here, play a song for me. Hannah."
(TINGS)
(RATTLING)
('60S POP MUSIC PLAYING)
(MAN SINGING IN JAPANESE)
(MUSIC STOPS)
(DISTANT DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
No, nothing, you're not here.
My card hasn't been working.
Why does no one else
have to swipe in?
See you in there!
Harris. Wait, Harris, he knows...
Harris, could you please
tell her who I am?
I've never seen this man before in my life.
You're not here.
I've worked here for seven years.
You're just not here.
Why would I try to break into
something that's mandatory?
Planning on breaking in?
You know what "mandatory" means?
'Cause that's not allowed.
It means that no one wants to be here.
You don't know what I want.
(DISTANT PARTY SOUNDS)
(CROWD CHATTERING)
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ I was born
♪ In east Virginia
♪ North Carolina
♪ I did love
♪ There I met
♪ A very pretty baby
♪ Her name and age
♪ I do not know
♪ Well, in my heart you are ♪
♪ My darling
♪ At my door
♪ You are welcome in
♪ At my gate
♪ I meet you, my darling
♪ If your love
♪ I could only win...
You're not meant to be here.
I have worked here for seven years.
I am an employee of this company.
You'd be well-advised
to let go of me.
Do not test my strength.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
♪ Still in the night...
(MUTTERS)
♪ I'm dreaming about you...
Sir, this is not me.
(WHISPERING)
This is not me.
No. This is not me, sir!
♪ Just the thought
♪ Of you, my darling...
(RUMBLING)
♪ Sends aching pains
♪ All through my breast.
(WHIRRING)
(WHIRRING BUILDING)
(WHIRRING STOPS)
(PHONE RINGING)
(BEEPS, RATTLES)
(BEEPS)
(PANTS, SIGHS)
(BUZZES)
(SIMON SIGHS)
(PHONE RINGING CONTINUES)
(BUZZES)
I bought you a present, but I
decided it wasn't appropriate.
Hmm?
I bought you a present, but I
decided it wasn't appropriate.
Oh.
Okay.
(FLUORESCENT LIGHT HUMMING)
(THUMPS)
(ALARM BLARING)
I really didn't kick it that hard.
The hardness of the
kick was recorded.
Super.
I don't know what I was thinking.
I've never done anything like that before.
If I could just trouble you for your card?
Yeah.
Magic.
(BEEPING)
I'm afraid this card is corrupted.
Corrupted? What does
that mean, "corrupted"?
You will receive a replacement
within six to eight weeks.
Well, how will I get in
and out of the building?
Lovely.
This one?
Er, no, that one. And
it's worth checking
after a couple of screen pages.
How do you not kill yourself?
Jesus, that was brutal last night.
So embarrassing getting chucked out.
Hannah saw the whole thing, of course.
Oh, yeah, you got it. That's it.
Do you think you're being encouraging?
Is that why you keep saying things?
Maybe you should get your printer
fixed is what I'm saying.
Are you touching my earlobe?
Yes, I am.
Aren't you like a
million years old?
Don't fight this.
Harris, that's not appropriate.
Why won't you die?
(PAPADOPOULOS LAUGHS) We could really
use a bright young man like you.
Especially right now, with the
big push and all. (CLAPS)
I'd like to introduce everyone
to our newest co-worker.
A bright young man who I'm
sure will be an asset.
He was the only one not fired in
the final cull at our sister office.
Even the cockroaches
didn't survive.
Well, I'll let you get
started, young hotshot.
Soon you'll have my job.
Everyone, please
welcome James Simon.
There's no need to be alarmed.
My cleaning lady's a diabetic.
We just need to jam a
cookie down his throat.
No, no, sir, I'm not diabetic.
It's just a shock that...
Don't worry, son.
We're not replacing you. I'm not one
of these holier-than-thou types.
Drugs can be healthy for a person.
Just leave it out of the office.
No, no, not drugs, sir. No, no.
Last night was a
mistake. And now...
Now... now this strange
man, I just...
No need for details.
It's happened to us all.
Have a drink of water
then get back to work.
(WATER RUMBLING)
(TOILET FLUSHING)
(DRYER BLOWING)
Harris.
Harris, have you spoken
to the new employee?
James? Yeah sure, I met him.
And?
He seems all right.
But did you notice anything
strange about him?
I mean, did he remind you of anyone?
No.
No one at the office?
Okay. Would...
Can I... could you...
Would... could I please just...
You can...
(SIGHS)
Thank you.
Yeah.
(CLOCKS TICKING)
(SIGHS)
Who did you have in mind?
Me, for instance.
Oh yeah, suppose so.
You suppose so?
HARRIS:
Yeah yeah, you look just like him.
Yes, I do, don't I?
Yeah, and you're not even Chinese.
It's pretty fucked up.
Yes, it is that.
Now now why didn't you notice?
Well, no offense, mate, but...
You're pretty unnoticeable.
(YAWNS)
Bit of a non-person.
(BANGS)
(MACHINE RATTLING)
(VACUUM WHIRRING)
(FLUORESCENT LIGHT HUMMING)
(KICKS)
(FOOTSTEPS CONTINUING)
(TRAIN APPROACHING)
What'll it be?
What, do you want to go...?
Okay, no, sorry then.
I'll just have a...
Coke and a bagel.
We're out of bagels.
Oh.
Right, then, um...
Right. Then I'll just...
Come on.
Right, sorry, I just...
I'll just... I can just have
the coke then, I guess.
A coke. And you?
A coffee.
JAMES: And scrambled eggs.
We don't serve breakfast
in the evening.
Why not?
Because it says so on the menu.
Well, do you still have eggs here?
Yeah.
And do you have a frying pan?
Then do me a favor and make
me some scrambled eggs.
Fine. Anything else?
Bacon.
And toast.
And a beer.
And a beer. Anything else?
No, that's it.
Are you sure?
(BANGS) Just get me the damn food.
(LOUD RUMBLING)
What? I'm hungry.
No, it's just...
I don't know, I would
have never done that.
You don't like eggs?
No, I mean, I just...
Don't think I would feel comfortable
talking to someone like that.
She's a waitress. She's
here to serve us.
If you don't tell her what you
actually want, how can she do her job?
No, I can see that... (WHISPERS)
She can be a little short sometimes,
and I do think being forthright
certainly has its place.
And I'm not, like, criticizing
your behavior or anything.
Here is your coffee,
your beer and your breakfast.
We're out of coke.
(LOUNGE MUSIC PLAYING)
You both have very beautiful hands.
To be continued.
Don't go anywhere.
The dark-haired one is a dirty dirty
thing. Which one do you want?
I'm sorry?
I prefer the brunette, but either way.
That's all right,
you can have both.
Never again.
I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
Hey, watch it, will you?
Sorry, sorry.
What the fuck are you
gonna do about it?
Hi, I don't think we've talked.
Would you mind holding
this for me? Thank you.
We should leave.
(MUSIC CONTINUES,
SINGING IN JAPANESE)
(SHOUTS)
(HOOTS)
(SPITS)
(MUSIC ENDS)
How come you don't
have a girlfriend?
I don't know.
You a flamer?
No, there's someone I've
been thinking about.
A lot.
Like some fantasy shit?
No, she's real.
A person.
So what's the problem?
I don't know.
I have all these things that I
want to say to her, like...
Like how I can tell that she's a lonely
person, even if other people can't.
'Cause... 'Cause I know
what it feels like
to be lost and lonely
and invisible.
Simon, you have to go
after what you want.
I would tear the asshole off an elephant
for a piece of trim I wanted that bad.
I've tried talking to her, but
I don't know how to be myself.
It's like I'm permanently
outside myself.
Like... like you could push your hand
straight through me if you wanted to.
And I couldn't see the type
of man that I wanna be
versus the type of
man I actually am.
And I know that I'm doing it, but I'm
incapable of doing what needs to be done.
I'm like Pinocchio.
I'm a wooden boy,
not a real boy.
And it kills me.
(DISTANT SHOUTING)
(PHONE RINGING)
JAMES:
Hey, it's okay. He's with me.
Oh. Please.
Any friend of James's
is a friend of mine.
(BEEPS, RATTLES)
I'm not even making
that up, really.
Oh, Harris, did you get a chance
to take a look at that report yet?
Ah, good, thank you. No, not now.
And, uh, Rudolph,
no rush on the coffee.
I'll take a nap or something.
(TAPPING)
What switch?
The switch. You're taking
the aptitude test for me.
We-we went through all this
last night, the switch.
Please stop saying "the switch."
You said you would help me
with all this boring office-work
crap like this test.
I've got reports to finish. I am out
of my booth. I have to teach Melanie.
Just take the test.
I'll babysit for an hour.
Do you even know what we do here?
What's to know?
(HYPERVENTILATES)
What if we get caught?
Well, how will we get caught?
We have the same face.
You may now turn over your paper.
MAN ON RECORDING:
Look at the two screens
and identify the next
figure in the sequence.
All the boys in my school are
so childish, so immature.
No, nothing but a batch
of raging hormones.
It's like daddy wanted me to go
on a date with his friend's son.
Like just 'cause we're the
same age doesn't mean
we have anything in common.
Mm-hmm, no.
It's no substitute for a real spiritual
connection or... or finding your soul mate.
I don't know, I've always
felt that emotional maturity
is totally unrelated to material age.
I'm just interested in the real person.
Do you drink coffee?
No.
Would you like to try one?
Finished already?
Yes, sorry.
When do you think you'll
have the results?
For you, right away.
But you need to realize
that data entry
and collection and
computers and stuff,
it can be sensual. It
does have a romance.
It can be sexy. All these
lives that we're recording,
their hopes, their
dreams, their loves...
Each person out there,
apart yet connected.
We're giving these faceless
people immortality.
Wow.
That's an amazing way
of looking at it.
(MACHINES WHIRRING)
These results are off
the charts, James.
I knew we hired the right
man, I just knew it.
Thank you, sir.
Where is the kid from that desk?
He's been here a while;
Just between you and me,
he hasn't impressed.
I'm sure there must be some explanation.
Sticking up for a co-worker even
though he has limited ability...
I like that. Very admirable.
So?
Where were you?
- How did I do?
You aced it.
Oh! I knew it.
I told you to be back an hour ago.
Oh, don't worry about it,
the old man's an idiot.
We are gonna be running this place.
All right, so I will leave you to
finish up and get out of your hair.
Where is she? There she is!
Oh, you got me. You got me.
And it's a good thing I fixed my printer.
Just used a little elbow grease,
so I won't be needing
to come down as much.
When you rub them together
they usually sound like crickets,
but... I've lost it.
And I'm sorry
I missed you at the Colonel's
ball the other night.
I think they've changed the cups.
Well, back to work.
Hmm. Strange.
Hey, that went great!
I don't know.
Leave her wanting more. Did you use the
line about the elbow grease? That's erotic.
Okay, within a week you're
going to get hand on boob.
That is a promise. Now we stick
to the plan, okay? No contact.
Cold Turkey for a
few days. All right?
Yeah yeah, she's
definitely looking at you.
You had a little setback at
the ball, but now she's going
"how come Simon hasn't been down to
see me? Why is he being all mysterious?
What's going on in that
magnificent mind of his?"
Do you really think she's looking at me?
Yeah.
All right, now lick your lips.
Yeah. What?
It sends out a subliminal
sexual signal.
Show the tongue, but be careful
not to look like a lizard. Go.
Yeah, now.
I feel so stupid.
Here we go.
Oh... oh.
Is that okay if I stand here?
Yes, it is.
Hmm.
So I was thinking maybe we
should meet up sometime.
Just you and me.
(CHUCKLES)
(LOUD RUMBLING)
HANNAH: This is obviously
making you uncomfortable.
I was wondering if he mentioned me.
No, it isn't.
When you say you've never
met anyone like James...
Yes.
I've never met anyone like James.
I find that hard to process.
What's hard to process about it?
What is so unique about him?
I don't know.
Try to think.
He has something.
Yes, okay, but you've
never even spoken to him, so how
can you know if he has something?
I think you can tell
by looking at someone.
By looking at someone? I don't under...
Yes, fuck!
I'll tell him myself.
Let's not do that. That won't work.
I'm putting myself on
the line, I'm vulnerable...
I understand that.
I thought you might wanna help.
I didn't mean to impose.
No knife to your throat
so don't worry about it.
No, no, I wanna tell him. Please let me.
Really?
Yes, I will tell him.
Are you sure?
- Yes.
My God, thank you.
Thank you.
That's great, thank you.
Okay.
Um, thanks, er...
Simon.
...Simon. I'm sorry.
I'm just flustered, but
that's great, thank you.
Are your hands normally this warm?
Quite often.
Hmm. And when did you
think our food will arrive?
It normally takes awhile.
JAMES: I can't say I'm surprised,
but I think this is a good thing.
We'll make a date and
you can go as me.
I'll give you more coaching.
Do you think that's ethical?
Er, don't take this the wrong way, but
I think it's unlikely you'll be able
to get into an unethical
situation on a first date.
"Unethical," that's very sweet.
When you're walking with a
woman or standing next to one,
you wanna put your hand on their
lower back, not the ass...
They sometimes get upset
about that... but just above it.
It shows you're interested, but you can
push them down the stairs at any moment.
Why?
Because you've got leverage.
So wait, here? What?
Stop that. That's gay.
But you just did it to me.
Yes, but it was me.
Do you see the difference?
Oh.
You can't be doing anything gay.
No ice-cream cones.
I like ice cream.
Of course. It's delicious.
Ice cream is fine in a
cup, but in a cone is gay
unless you're with a woman at the time.
Anything else?
No riding on a motorcycle
with another man.
Exceptions are drive-by
shootings, bomb throwings
and purse snatchings.
Anything else is gay.
You seem to know a lot about this.
Defense wins championships.
You need to tell them how
great you are all the time,
which means make things up.
What if they find out?
Make it hard to research, like you
were the captain of a Jai-Alai team
or a brigadier general in the
Navy. Something like that.
I don't think anybody
would believe that.
Then change the subject
and deny everything.
I just don't know if that's me.
That's why it's so good.
(WIND BLOWING)
JAMES THROUGH EARPIECE:
Just say something.
I used to be an olympic swimmer.
JAMES: Go to the bathroom now.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
What the fuck?
I can't do this
with you shouting in
my ear like that.
This would be fine if
you'd do what I tell you.
Like jam my knee between her thighs?
I can't do things like that.
I know, that's why
you're gonna die alone.
Sorry, that was cruel. I'm just...
I'm just so frustrated for you.
Look, just give me your jacket.
I'll patch things up, okay?
I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry.
No, I am. I've screwed this up.
You can't help it. You're
just not good at this.
I know.
I know you know. Give me your jacket.
Wait, did you move tables?
No.
(LOUNGE MUSIC, SINGING IN JAPANESE)
JAMES: Hey, what are you doing?
I'm leaving, is that okay?
No, why?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ ...blue blue, blue chateau... ♪
just put it back on the
hanger, thank you.
(MUSIC PLAYING OVER DIALOGUE)
♪ ...blue blue, blue chateau... ♪
(LOUD WHIRRING)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
(WHIRRING)
♪ ...blue blue, blue chateau ♪
♪ Blue, blue, blue,
blue, blue, blue ♪
♪ Chateau...
(MUSIC CONTINUES SOFTLY)
(RATTLING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Excuse me.
Did you see a man
who looks exactly like me
walk in here with a woman?
This boy's not serious.
Visitors have to sign in.
I'm not a visitor.
(TAPS)
(HANNAH LAUGHING)
No, I have to go.
No, I really have to go.
Okay, but I have to go.
Yeah, I have to go.
No, it isn't, I need
to go. It's fine.
I'm at work.
(LAUGHS) Okay.
Hi. Uh, I know the policy, but my
printer is actually broken again, so.
How's your growth?
Hannah, the creepy guy's here again.
Yeah.
Hi, creepy guy.
Hey, Hannah.
I was just telling your colleague
that I know the policy,
but my printer is
actually broken again.
Oh, I thought you fixed it with elbow grease.
Yes.
Want me to call someone up to
fix it? What's your desk number?
Hi, I'm with somebody whose printer is broken.
Oh no, no. No, no.
No, no, no, no, I actually need
the copy pretty urgently, yeah.
Uh... it's a report of special
importance to the Colonel.
He's taken a particular
interest in my findings lately.
I haven't actually
met him in person,
but I think he knows a lot about
my work, so maybe I'll just...
Oh, that reminds me, you had
your date with James, did you?
Was that last night?
Did you want me to photocopy that?
Yes, please. That is why I'm here.
(SWITCHES CLICKING)
(LOUD RUMBLING)
(BUZZES)
One copy.
So how'd it go?
How did what go?
With James. I just wanted to ask 'cause I
didn't see you on the train this morning.
Not that I'm in the habit
of seeing you on the train,
but I wanted to ask 'cause
I made the introduction.
Thanks for the introduction.
I wanted to make sure...
That he didn't take
advantage of me?
Did he?
Do that? 'Cause then
I'd feel responsible
'cause I made the introduction.
That's very kind of you.
So you're okay?
I'm okay.
Okay, good. Then
that's fine. Thank you.
That's a relief, actually,
to me. That's relieved me,
because I made the introduction
is all. Thank you, good.
Guess who.
Oh God. This is Melanie.
Hi, Melanie.
We've met.
Have we?
Yeah. Papadopoulos
asked me to tutor her.
He's the best teacher I've ever had.
Thank you.
I'm learning a lot.
Well, she's a good student.
Pupil, so. So we'll get back to work.
A lot.
Okay.
I'm not actually meant to be
here, but I have a report
that I think would be of
interest to Mr. Papadopoulos.
Sorry, my name is Simon James,
but I don't have my I.D.
Or my supplementary I.D.
The only thing it hasn't been is
consistent. I'll be one moment.
This is the report I
was telling you about.
Great work, James!
That's the type of
initiative I like.
Oh, thank you, sir. I just
think a man should do
the best he can possibly
do at the work he's doing.
But, sir, I...
I don't know what I'm paying you for.
This guy just started.
Why can't you work like that?
I just started.
Sir, I think I have to make
something clear here. I...
Use words.
(LAUGHS)
Look, I'm not angry with you, son,
I just hope you can raise the
level of your performance.
Hell! Why don't you
work with James here?
See if you can help him
put something together.
I would really like that.
Yeah, Mr. P, that's
a fantastic idea.
I'm a good worker. I...
So this is the great James Simon.
This used to be my favorite song.
SIMON: There's no song playing.
And you hate music.
I think the nurse
stole my undershirt.
You're right, I do hate music.
GYPSY: You're still not right.
Make the cut deep.
Oh, excuse me, sir?
Yeah?
Did you know that people in
here are carrying weapons?
Yeah.
How long has this been going on?
A while.
(DISTANT TV PLAYING)
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS)
(DISTANT YELLING)
(LINE RINGING)
Hello.
Hannah, this is James.
Come up. I want you.
(RUMBLING)
I want you to stop seeing Hannah.
I see.
And I want you to stop
messing around with Melanie.
What else?
And I want you to tell
Papadopoulos that I've been
doing all your work for
you since you got here.
Mm-hmm, okay. Well, I
wanna show Papadopoulos
this photo of you and his daughter.
Oh, well...
How do you sleep?
Yeah, I just...
Now who do you think
Papadopoulos is gonna believe?
Some dink he still calls Stanley?
Or this guy?
So I need the key...
To your apartment.
You see, Melanie is
a bit of a screamer
and I don't want Hannah coming
up and making another scene.
It'll just be easier
if we use your place.
Now do you need to see the
photo again or are you okay?
(LOUD RUMBLING)
(KEY JINGLES)
I'll also be taking other women up there
in case you notice different smells.
(LOUD RUMBLING)
Hey.
I'm James.
(YELLS)
Get up.
Or do you wanna die on the
ground, like a snake?
(CLASSICAL SCORE PLAYING)
JAMES: There he is.
(GIRL LAUGHS)
Hey, what are you working on?
It's private.
Can you please not lean
on my work station?
So I need that key again.
No.
That was it. No more.
All right, I understand.
Hey, Mr. Papadopoulos.
Simon has something he
wanted to show you.
Oh. Key.
No, I can't.
Key.
No.
Key. I have more.
Fine.
I'll get a copy cut.
Save future confusion.
Well, this better be good.
Oh no, no, no, I'm sorry.
You need to step up, Stanley. I
wanna see some real work from you.
Actually, I'm working on
something at the moment, sir.
Something that I...
Don't mistake my kindness for weakness.
Simon, I think that James
is seeing someone else.
And he told me that you sometimes watch my
apartment from a telescope in your room,
which I'm fine with actually,
I don't really mind.
It's kind of reassuring
in a strange way, but...
Wanna go to the coffee
room? It's a little public.
It could be interesting to find out who
else he's seeing. Are you hearing this?
Does that mean he's not seeing you?
Not that he's even trying to hide it.
He's not a very good guy.
Which I know and I always have known,
but to be made a fool of by him?
One second. By a villain.
I knew what he was...
Oh no. It's not your fault.
Then he'd say something
about how he knew me,
that he could tell I was a lonely person,
because he knew what it was like
to be lonely and
lost and invisible.
Like...
Like someone could just push
their hand straight through you.
I think you should
definitely not see him.
He told me he felt like Pinocchio.
Do you know who Pinocchio is?
No.
He's this wooden boy.
He's held up by strings.
He wants to feel like a real boy.
Do you understand?
No.
I feel like Pinocchio.
Okay.
So is that okay if I come
to your apartment tonight?
I know it's kinda strange to ask
but I wanted to see for myself,
you know, if he's taking
girls back there.
No, I'm sorry, that's not
possible because I have to work.
I'm not gonna be home
tonight, I'll be here.
But that's okay, you can
just give me your key.
I don't have a key.
You don't have a key?
No.
You don't have a key
to your own apartment?
No.
How do you get in?
I can't get in.
Why are you lying?
I'm not. I just don't know...
If it's a good idea
to spy on people.
And...
I think you might be
becoming a little obsessive.
Why are you touching me?
I'm not.
I just...
Also...
Feel like Pinocchio.
You're a snake.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(WIRE RATTLING)
I haven't done anything wrong.
(DOOR CLATTERS)
(MUMBLES, LAUGHS)
(PHONE RINGING)
GUARD: What is your name?
I'm a visitor. I would
like to sign in.
(ENUNCIATES) What is your name?
My name is Simon James.
You're wanted in worker
services, Simon James.
(BEEPS)
Mmm.
(BEEPING)
Mmm. Poor chap.
Oh.
(MUTTERS)
You don't exist any more.
Excuse me?
You're no longer on the system.
Well, just put me back in the system.
I can't put you back in the system.
Why?
Because you don't exist. I can't put
someone who doesn't exist in the system.
But I used to be in the system.
Not according to the system. In fact,
according to the system,
you've never existed.
How reliable is the system?
Hey, it's completely reliable.
Yes, but I used to
exist... I do exist!
I'm standing in this room, aren't I?
And?
So how do I get back in the system?
You need a card.
Right. So can I please get a new card?
No.
Why?
Because you're not in the system.
So, it's... Well...
So that's it?
(SOFTLY) That's it.
I'll leave you to make
your own arrangements.
(FOOTSTEPS DEPARTING)
HARRIS: You okay, buddy?
- Yeah.
Thanks, Harris.
Yeah, it's gotta be pretty rough on you.
Yeah, I guess it is.
I, uh, got you this book.
James told us about your problems.
You need to read it pronto though;
it's only returnable through Friday.
Thanks.
No worries.
Hey, ah, I was just wondering...
Yeah, I'll help you
with your report.
If you could have it ready by tomorrow.
Fine.
And tomorrow's Friday.
I know.
So both the book and
the report need
to be finished by tomorrow.
Okay.
Friday. Yeah, oh, by the way,
if you're looking for James, he's
in the office with Papadopoulos.
Apparently he's written this incredible
report on how to increase efficiency.
Yeah, pap's pretty impressed.
Hey, you're fucking boring;
What's regression analysis?
JAMES: Oh, this one is so silly.
These two Chinese
virgins get married.
It's the night of the wedding,
they've just finished boning.
And the husband says, "that was
great, that was really great.
Is there anything else
you'd like to try?"
And then the woman says...
Mr. Papadopoulos?
Hold on a sec.
No, it's okay.
So the woman says, "I think
I would like to try # 69."
And the guy, he
thinks for a second.
And... pay attention,
Rudolph, you'll like this.
He says, "you want
breef with broccori?"
(LAUGHING)
It is silly. What did I tell you?
Sir. Sir, I think we need to talk.
You! I can't believe you'd dare.
Sir, I work here and I...
You pervert.
James told me everything
about you and Melanie.
Hell knows she's handsome,
she's a Papadopoulos,
but to abuse a young
woman's trust like that?
Sir, this man is a fraud.
You should talk!
He's the finest employee
we've ever had.
Oh, sir, thank you.
He doesn't even know
what we do here.
Er, this and that.
Okay, what is regression analysis?
Who took your test for you?
Sir, I have been through
all of this in the report.
I think maybe he needs some help.
He's gone a little crazy.
No, no, no, no, no.
No sir, this cannot stand.
No, no, no, no.
Stay away from me. Stay
away from me. No, no, no, no.
No. No sir, he stole my face.
Look at me! Look at me!
Look at him! He stole my face!
PAPADOPOULOS: You need to leave.
No!
You do! Get off of me!
(SIMON GROWLS)
PAPADOPOULOS: Stanley!
Give Rudolph his arm back!
No, no, no, no, no!
Stay back! Stay back!
No, no, no. No, no, no, no.
Stay away from me! No,
I need to see the Colonel.
Stanley, we all love you.
The Colonel will understand.
Please, where is the Colonel?
You need help.
No, I don't need help.
What's the problem, Stanley?
Hey! You fuckers!
You don't know who
you're dealing with.
You don't know who you're
dealing with, you fuckers.
You fucking fucks.
I am a person.
Stay back! Stay back, you fucks!
You fucking fuckers!
I am a person!
I exist!
(VIOLINS PLAYING)
(KEY JINGLES)
(LOCK CLICKS)
(PENCIL SCRATCHING)
MAN: Here we are.
Has she ever tried
anything like this before?
No.
No? First timer!
Good stuff. Well,
these things happen.
You mustn't blame yourself.
Was it pills that she took?
I heard it was pills.
Yes.
Fantastiche. How many pills
do you think she swallowed?
I have nought to 10, 10 to
20, 20 to 30, or 30-plus.
I don't know. I wasn't there.
If you were to guess.
I'm not going to guess.
But if you had to guess.
I don't have to.
Is she going to be okay?
I'll just stick a little
question mark on it for the moment.
What? What is it?
All bloody morning, you know.
How long have you two been married?
MAN: Would you excuse
us, please, Martin?
Mr. James, can I have a word?
Yeah, that's fine.
I'll just keep going with this...
(SHOUTS)
And take care of this bloody guy!
Has she tried anything
like this before?
No, I don't think so.
- Do you fight a lot?
Sometimes.
I'm afraid to say she's had
a miscarriage. I'm sorry.
Was it your first pregnancy?
Yes.
The good thing is she's healthy
and it was very early, so she
won't feel too much pain.
These things happen.
You mustn't blame yourself.
You probably think I
should be thankful
that you took me to the
hospital, but I'm not.
I wanted to die and now I'm afraid I
won't have the courage to try again.
Do you wanna know what I think?
I think that you
should kill yourself.
I promise I won't try to
stop you halfway through.
(DOOR BANGS)
(RAGGED BREATHING)
(SOFT SOBS)
(ANSWERING MACHINE CLICKS, REWINDS)
(BEEPS)
(MAN CLEARS THROAT)
Hi, uh, this is a message for...
Simon James.
Uh, your mother passed
away this morning
following a major ce-ree-bral
s... ceree-bral?
Cere-bral... Cerebral occurrence.
Um, in accordance with her wishes,
she's to be buried at night.
If you wish to attend the funeral,
it starts at midnight
at the cemetery
to the rear of the home.
Not the rear but, um...
To the... down the side and then
towards the rear of the home.
- All right. Bye.
(BEEPS)
PRIEST: Yea, though I
walk through the valley
of the shadow of death I will fear
no evil for thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff...
(MUTTERS) Don't look now.
They will comfort me.
Thou preparest a table before me
in the presence of mine enemies.
Look look, we can get you help,
but now is a time for family.
Just don't engage.
WOMAN:
Who are you? Who is this fuck?
Why have you got his face?
Just don't engage. Don't engage.
Is he mental? Are you mental?
Just don't engage.
What are you doing?
Okay.
Don't touch me!
Don't engage.
WOMAN: Oi!
(PRIEST GRUNTING)
Don't engage.
Don't touch me!
(YELPS)
What is it?
Get up.
Get off your knees.
(SHOVEL SCRAPES)
(DISTORTED ROARING)
(BELL TOLLING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLARING)
Oh.
Where are you going?
Fuck off!
Oh hey, James.
(PANTING)
(DOOR OPENS)
Oh my God, look at you.
You know who I am, don't you?
Are you okay?
You recognize me.
Of course. Simon,
what happened to you?
I don't want to be a
boy held up by string.
Okay.
Okay?
Bye.
(WIND BLOWING)
(PHONE RINGS)
Yes.
I'm okay.
(SLICES)
(RUMBLING, WIND BLOWS)
(PHONE CLANGS)
SIMON: That is where I am.
Yes, I am looking at him now.
He is about to jump.
Please hurry.
(DEEP THUMPS)
COLONEL:
There aren't too many like you.
Are there, Simon?
I'd like to think
I'm pretty unique.
(WAVES LAPPING)
(DISTANT TRAIN SQUEALS)
(GUITAR MUSIC PLAYING)
(WOMAN SINGING IN KOREAN)