Lord, blind my eyes
to these visions...
and deafen my ears
to the screams.
For I have seen legions
of God's army fall...
and heard the dying cries
of 10,000 angels.
Guide my hand, Lord,
for what I see is the coming end
of the Kingdom of Heaven.
Protect and keep these pages
in Heaven's darkest hour.
And watch over us, Lord.
For Heaven's war
has come to Earth.
Thomas Dagget.
It's five past the hour,
and that means a quick look
at today's weather.
This morning, San Fernando valley
residents got a surprise...
when they found frost
on their windshields.
But things will be
warming up this afternoon.
The gusty winds will be dying down.
We'll have clear skies,
good to moderate air quality.
Temperatures... seventies in
the valleys, sixties at the beaches.
As far as traffic is concerned,
the SIG alert we had this morning,
reported northbound on the 405
at Sunset, is still backing things up.
We'll have to wait
while authorities...
What time is it?
I'm coming. I'm coming.
investigate that situation.
Southbound on the 405 has normal
slowing. However, it has snagged up...
quite a ways past...
Aah!
What do you got?
Hit by a pedestrian.
Car accident. EP: 90 over 60.
Contusions to the head
and neck. Clear this hallway!
People, get out of the way.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I will be if... Jesus!
I don't know what happened.
He was just there.
How fast were you going?
Twenty, thirty.
All right, prep four.
I'll be in in a minute.
You got it.
Get the door!
Don't be afraid.
What?
We'll take it from here, Val.
Thanks.
He's coming!
Gabriel's coming!
He's coming for me!
What's going on?
I don't know, Father.
He just started screaming.
I tried to open the door,
but he locked it.
Yes.
Thomas?
Thomas? Step back!
He's coming for you.
It's time for you
to go, Gabriel.
This is not my war,
and Hell isn't big enough
for both of us.
Hey.
How are you feeling?
Look, I, um...
Danyael.
Danyael?
I don't know if you remember me.
I just wanted
to apologize.
I could've killed you.
Take a lot more than that to kill me.
Valerie...
talk to me.
The monkeys
never did get that one right.
It's not willing servants of Heaven.
It's winged.
So, you found me.
This place looks lived in.
What about these visions,
Thomas?
What do you do?
You write them down
on a-a scroll...
and stone tablet.
I know you prophets
enjoy doing that.
Or... maybe a picture?
A certain someone?
I know you've
seen her, Thomas.
So?
Who is she?
Ironic, isn't it?
An archangel needs a monkey
to get a vision from God.
That's a small step
from prophet to mortar.
Can you take it?
Dr. Parson said you'd sign these.
Can we do it later?
Yeah, sure.
Thanks.
Ready?
One, two, three.
Wow!
See that?
Whoa!
Do it again.
Be well, guys.
Bye.
That was
a pretty great exit.
I got waylaid.
Well, I hope you don't mind.
I had this dry-cleaned.
I figured it was
the least I could do.
You don't have to keep
apologizing, Valerie.
Yeah, well, you don't have
to keep forgiving me either.
It's in my upbringing.
Well, guilt's
in mine, so...
How would you feel
about seeing me again?
Most of the kids
in the ward are terminal.
I mean, I used to spend
a lot of time hoping and hoping.
And then I just stopped.
It makes you wonder
what the point is.
And what do you think
the point is, Valerie?
Right now?
Four hundred and seventy-two
dollars a week, plus benefits.
Makes me sad.
Hmm.
Wonder if it should
make me sad too.
Maybe it should.
What, you just don't like
talking about yourself?
Not much to tell. I think you're
the more interesting one in this pair.
You think?
Mm-hmm.
I don't know.
That looks pretty interesting to me.
Just something I got
when I was young.
Yeah?
You were married?
Uh, yeah.
What happened?
Um... Well, we lived together
for three years,
and then we were married
for three months.
And when he wasn't running up my
Visa card, he was home watching that...
You know that
real-life cop show?
He wasn't exactly the most
employable soul on the planet.
Where is he now?
He left.
I'm sorry.
It's okay. I mean,
it's probably for the best.
I was miserable.
I just didn't know it.
He was a fool.
I thought you were
just walking me home.
Would you rather
I leave?
I'm not sure.
It's not a good time.
Yeah.
I know.
You all right?
I'm fine.
Do you accept me?
What? What?
Yes.
Valerie?
Be well, Valerie.
Is it done?
It's done.
It took you
long enough.
Michael said
not to force her.
Michael didn't say
take your time.
Long time, Danyael.
Nice to see you again.
Good-bye, brother.
Aah!
Take a deep breath,
Danyael.
It's not too late
to fix this.
Come back. Now.
As far as I'm concerned,
nothing happened.
She was a momentary lapse
of self-control, Danyael.
But I'll find her.
Don't walk away!
Kids.
They don't listen
these days.
You're no kid, Rafayel.
The monkey. Hmm?
Who is she?
Where is she?
Why couldn't you have just stayed
in the basement, Gabriel?
Why couldn't you stay out of it
and mind your business?
This was my fight.
You made it yours.
My enemy's friend
is my enemy.
How many more worlds have to burn
before you're satisfied, Gabriel?
Just the one.
This one.
Aah!
I'm not greedy.
Hi.
I'm wondering if you could help me.
I have a friend...
and she got herself
in a bit of a situation.
And I was wondering if maybe
she might've been in to see you?
We have a very
broad-based clientele, sir.
If this was her, um...
Claim check.
Exactly. Claim check.
If this was her
claim check,
could you find her name
and where she lives...
in that, uh,
whatever it is?
Of course.
Thank you.
This laundry's already been picked up.
So I can't give
that information out.
Oh, she wouldn't mind.
We're family.
You just said you were friends.
Caught me. Very good.
Martin, don't ask me
how I know. Shh.
Uuh!
Your head.
It hurts here, or it hurts here?
Here.
Mm-hmm.
And your belly... la panza...
it hurts up here...
or down here?
Kind of... here.
Well, I'm making
you some eggs.
No, the cereal was
just fine. Thanks.
But you love eggs.
I'm making you eggs.
Nana, gross.
No eggs.
No eggs, please
Every morning, you ask me for eggs.
Na...
I am making some eggs.
Nana, I don't want eggs.
I don't wanna be skinny.
That's not what this is about.
Pr... I'm pregnant. I'm pregnant.
I have a cold. I have a cold.
Every time I skin my knee,
you're telling me that I'm pregnant.
Jesus, that's why I wanted
to become a nurse:
to prove to you that people
don't get pregnant just because
they've scraped their knee.
So?
I'd like to know where your
grandmother went to medical school.
There must be
a mistake.
There's no mistake, Vally.
You're pregnant.
That's not possible.
Kath, I've been
with one man.
And that was just
a couple days ago.
Um... You know,
you're not just pregnant.
According to the test,
you're in your second trimester.
Hey.
It's done.
Oh, it's incredible.
It is.
I can't think of a better night
to do it,Julian.
If it's the only way
I can have you,
then I won't have it
any other way.
I put that in the note.
That's just beautiful.
Are you ready?
I'm ready.
Oh!
I'll see you
in Heaven, baby.
Meet you there.
Aah!
Show time.
Anybody home?
Huh?
Hmph.
That's too bad.
Intensive care.
My favorite.
Izzy. Izzy.
Isabelle.
Come back.
I know you're in there.
Come on back now.
Back it up.
Hi.
Nice hair.
Julian?
He's gone. He's dead.
He's taking
a dirt nap.
Julian.
Look, I need your help.
I'm short-staffed at the moment.
Don't start.
Don't start. I hate that. Please.
He's the cold eye. He's spilled milk.
Ju...Julian.
Julian.
Come on. Come on, kiddo.
Oh.
Come on, kiddo.
We got work to do.
Julian.
Julian!
Didn't I kill myself?
Yes and no.
The answer to that
is up to me.
Oh, my God.
How do you know
he did it?
A witness saw your friend rip the guy's
heart out with his bare hands.
Plus, he left this
at the crime scene.
Somehow, he managed to check in and out
without leaving his name.
But we traced him to you
through that patient I.D. number.
So what can you tell us
about the man?
Nothing. I...
I barely knew him.
It's not surprising.
Does that ring a bell?
Well, he had a,
um, like...
You Val?
Yes.
You the nurse?
You done with her?
Yeah. Take her.
Come here.
I don't know what to tell you.
Yeah. Shut up.
Listen.
No. Really listen.
Both ears.
Nod to tell me both ears
are listening. All right.
I've dealt with a thousand bodies in
this office. Floaters, crispy critters,
bunk bait; bodies you wouldn't
even know were bodies if it
wasn't for a driver's license.
Yes, well, I don't see
what that has to do...
Don't talk, Val.
Bodies chopped and minced and skinned
and used as table decorations.
That's your job.
You're talking again.
Yeah. No. Listen.
Four years ago, a body came in here
tattooed like those;
crushed like those;
eyeless.
But hey, I'm a sport.
I play along.
I tried to determine
what had rolled into my office.
But the questions just got deeper.
No sign of growth,
no white cells,
no optic nerves.
I realized what was there before me
had never been born.
That's not possible.
That's what I thought.
And then it was gone. Burned up in
a flash one night. All the records...
Everything to indicate that
it had been there disappeared.
Everybody that had anything
to do with that body...
has either died...
or gone mad,
including my friend Thomas.
Who's he?
A detective.
Became a monk.
He used to send me cheese wheels
every Christmas.
Where can I find him?
You can't. He's dead.
Burnt to ash up at
St. Gregory's Monastery.
What do you mean,
burnt to ash?
You look like
a nice person, Val.
Take my advice:
walk away.
Don't get involved
whatever you do.
Get the lights.
Hey,Joe.
Thank you.
Miss Rosales, I really don't know
what else I can tell you.
His death shocked everybody.
Thomas was a fine member
of our order.
I understand he used to be a detective.
Mm-hmm.
Well, did he ever talk to you about
any odd cases that he had?
Anything dealing with cults
or gangs or anything?
Miss Rosales, I really can't
disclose anything more.
I know, Father.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
It's just that...
he was involved with
something a while ago...
and it's something that I
may have stepped into as well.
It's, um, angelic script.
According to the old Hebrews, God marked
all his angels with such a sign.
Or so Thomas told me. He was
a bit of an expert on such matters.
How so?
All right.
Uh, listen.
This is not something
I would normally discuss, but, uh,
since it seems
so important to you.
Please.
Thomas was obsessed
on the subject of angels.
So much so that he claimed
to have had visions about them.
According to him,
some angels became jealous that God was
giving too much attention to mankind.
So they tried
to wipe humans out...
under the archangel Gabriel.
Please, have a seat.
Thank you.
The problem was,
to do that...
they had to contend with other angels
that were still loyal to God's will.
It caused a kind
of civil war up there.
It tore Heaven apart.
Thomas believed...
there was to be
a final confrontation.
And if the good side wins,
great.
And if not?
If not...
What does that mean?
Then ash from
a burning Heaven...
will cover the Earth.
Well, if this guy was
so good at prophesizing,
did he bother to say
how it ends?
It gets metaphorical. It talks about
the union of Heaven and Earth.
The coming of a Nephilim.
A what?
A Nephilim.
A child born...
of an angel
and a human woman.
It's talked about
in Genesis six.
I, honestly, don't know
what to make of it.
When humans began
to multiply on the face of the Earth...
and daughters were born to them,
the sons of God saw they were beautiful,
and took wives for themselves.
All that they desired.
The Nephilim were on the Earth
in those days.
When the sons of God went
into the daughters of humans...
and bore children to them,
they were giants,
men of great and terrible renown.
So, you're keeping me alive
because you don't know DOS?
What was the number?
Three-three,
six-six.
Wait. What's that?
Something's happening.
Is that her?
Bingo.
Rosales.
Valerie.
And folks,
up next, a very special item to
make a bright day even brighter.
This beautiful, soft
white and lavender gown...
Nana?
will compliment a new bride
as she walks down the aisle...
on that most special of days.
This fine quality linen,
cotton and silk dress...
will surely become
a family heirloom...
that will last for ages.
Nana?
That's right, Jim.
And notice the fine...
satin applique
around the neckline.
Isn't it beautiful?
Karen, it's really...
craftsman work throughout.
They don't make them like this anymore.
Nana?
Nana's gone, you know.
Nana didn't have much time left,
in any case.
In the end, it wasn't gonna be
something you'd wanna witness.
Look at it this way.
You two can
hook up later.
You have no idea
the trouble you got there.
No!
What's going on here is not personal.
It's business.
It's what I do best.
Get out!
Monkey wannabe. Wanna dance?
You'll have to learn
a modicum of respect.
Remember who
did this to you.
Go!
This is good.
Step on it.
Stop!
Back it up.
Back it up!
Drive much?
Try not to hit the dog.
You didn't say anything
about me killing anybody.
Do it... for Julian.
Or forever wish you'd had.
Just do it.
Atta girl.
I'd get the fuck out of here
if I were you.
Valerie. Shh.
Hello?
Help!
Hello!
Who are you?
I think you know.
You didn't answer me.
I'm sorry.
That's the best I can do.
The best you can do.
Well, guess what?
Your best is not good enough!
I don't know...
what they taught you
in kindergarten, but your best
does not cut it here, okay?
You seduce me! You knock me up!
My grandma's dead!
And some freak comes to my house
and he tries to kill...
I mean, who... who was that
trying to kill me?
Gabriel.
I must've missed
the trumpet.
Valerie, please.
You don't understand.
I understand fine.
You are psychotic.
You don't know how
important you are.
Let me tell you
a secret.
It was revealed to us that
there would be a child.
A child born of
my kind and yours.
The child that would unite my brothers
again and bring an end to this war.
That child has been
given to you.
Certifiable.
You're certifiable.
You... You...
You're probably one of those guys
who, like, goes around...
door-to-door selling bibles,
and you and your brothers... You have to believe me.
probably all wear white and
you probably have a Web site somewhere.
And you probably bake brownies
on the weekend...
and you sell them to raise money
for your cause or your cult...
Don't be afraid.
Sir, did you notice any unusual
activity in the neighborhood tonight?
I got a wrecked car
in the alley back there.
No, sir.
So you didn't see anything,
hear anything. Is that about right?
The fact is, officer,
I wasn't paying much attention.
See, I was with
my woman.
7-Charlie-63. Come in.
Dorfman, come in.
Yeah, this is Dorfman.
63, report to
Rosales residence.
May I ask, you fellas use that
to what, talk to each other?
Yeah?
What, are you high?
It's a radio. Yeah.
It's a miracle.
Shh.
Do you read me, 63? 63, come in.
Dorfman, where are you?
Come in. 63.
Checking on the DMV report on the, uh...
Okay. Pop quiz.
How do you make that work?
How do you use that?
Hmm?
We have nothing showing yet.
Uh, Roger, dispatch.
Are we having
a communication problem?
What? Take it easy.
Come here.
It's all right.
Come here. Come here.
Don't be scared.
Here.
Sit.
I want to be with Julian.
Please. Why can't you
just let me die?
Let's understand
each other.
I sang the first hymn
when stars were born.
Not that long ago,
I announced to a young woman...
Mary... who it was
she was expecting.
On the other hand,
I've turned rivers into blood.
Kings into cripples.
Cities to salt.
So I don't think that I have
to explain myself to you.
You have the child. You'd raise it.
Maybe on his first
morning of school,
you'd put him on a bus
and he wouldn't come back.
Or maybe as a teen, he'd dive into
a pond and he wouldn't come up.
And I was just supposed
to accept that?
It's how you live here,
isn't it?
Doesn't give you
the right to use me.
It wasn't my decision.
But it was your choice.
I never had a choice,
Valerie.
Listen, I have to
get you to Michael.
Michael?
He can protect you.
He's gone somewhere
with the others.
I don't know where,
but we have to try to find him.
There's a book that
a priest gave me.
It had... It had prophecies
about your war.
It might help you.
Where is it?
It's in my car.
At my house.
Can I ask you something?
Yes.
What are my chances?
Be honest.
I don't know.
But stay here.
He won't kill you in a church.
Respond to Trinity Church,
2222 West in. Silent alarm tripped.
All available units.
Please respond.
Wow. That's where I'd take her.
I love this thing.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
2222 West in. Trinity Church.
Dispatch, this is 1 -Adam-19.
Responding to the call
at Trinity Church.
Roger that, 1-Adam-19.
As soon as the coroner's through.
Can I get an I.D. on her?
Yeah. It's Rosales.
Nina Rosales.
Sir, please go
to the other side of the...
Shh.
It's okay.
You wanna help me
out here? Thanks.
Be careful.
I know you're here, Val.
I smell you.
I see you. Yeah.
Why hide?
I'm doing you a favor.
What did Danyael
tell you...
about your rug rat?
1 -Adam-9.
Units 20 and 30 are responding.
35-Adam-9.
5-Lincoln-22.
Report to Vermont and Sunset, code 9.
We've been through this before.
My kind, your kind.
It's not a good mix.
The power of an angel.
The free will
of a human.
The mothers love it
at first...
until the birth.
I've seen women rip themselves open
trying to get these things out...
'cause they knew they were
carrying bad kids, Val.
Nobody liked them,
not even you-know-who.
It took a big flood.
I think we have to...
So, since you're here...
Confess. Say you're sorry.
Drop it!
Drop the weapon!
Freeze!
Help me! Help me!
Drop it right there!
Gabriel!
Hold it right there, sir!
Freeze! Right there!
He's got a weapon!
No, wait.
Isabelle.
Izzy.
You can be straight with us.
Come on.Just tell us who he is.
The angel of death.
I'll get some coffee.
Nice coat.
So what was he up to
in the church?
Trying to kill
the savior of humanity.
Just ask him.
What the...
Shh!
Loose lips sink ships.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
What is that?
That's tomorrow's newspaper.
Huh? Come on.
Bad monkey. Come on, come on.
I don't know...
Hah?
How?
You don't even know where they are.
Yeah.
But, I know where they're going.
Where?
Eden.
I'll go get another car.
Here.
Just take my hand.
This is it?
This is Eden?
What man
has made of it.
Just her.
Michael wants to see her alone.
It's all right.
Don't be afraid.
It's your tradition too, isn't it?
Lighting candles
for the dead?
Michael?
What a dump!
Gemayel.
Long time no see.
Would you get
the big guy for me?
Don't eat that!
Trust me.
I've lit far too many
in this war.
Is that one for me?
It could be...
for all of us.
Danyael said you
could protect me.
If that were the case, this war
would have been over a long time ago.
Are you telling me that I've come
all this way for nothing?
If that's what you
want to believe, then yes.
I can't believe that.
Then don't.
Ah... ah.
You've done wonders with the place,
I have to say. I hardly recognize it.
Talk to me! Why fight?
I'm not here to argue.
We're family.
You know what I want.
What you want has made you
a walking tragedy, brother.
Even Lucifer
wouldn't have you.
Surprising, since the two of you
have so much in common.
What have I done? You speak to me that
way... How do you compare me to him?
Everything I've done
has been for us.
I don't want this.
I don't want this!
I want it back the way it was,
when... when He loved us best.
Then submit.
To what? A talking monkey?
Obey, Gabriel. Or you'll be
called to a stricter punishment
than any of us ever known.
I don't think so.
And, uh, it seems to me,
the numbers here speak differently.
One way or the other,
this war ends tonight.
You think you can take her,
Gabriel? Then come.
But your brothers
stay behind.
No one will lift a hand
against you. I promise.
Michael. Please,
you can't let him have her.
Whether she lives or dies
is her choice, not ours.
I'm not going to let her
die like this.
Even if it means
disobeying me?
Yes.
This way.
Valerie!
Danyael, Michael let him in.
This way.
Go ahead.
What about you?
It's all come down
to you. Just go.
Ah. The honeymooner.
The price of freedom.
You know what to do.
Come on!
It's not that you slept with
that monkey-skin suit that gets me.
It's that you liked it.
What are you, in love?
What do you know about love, Gabriel?
It's wrong to go
against your family.
You chose them. I want it back
the way it was. You want them?
I'd rather be
one of them.
Aaghh!
It's too bad.
Hmm. Oh!
Thanks.
It's about time.
Nice move.
I'll say hello
to Julian for you.
You have no idea
what you're in for. Shh.
Val, we don't have
to do this.
Fuck you.
Uuh!
Now you're gonna get hurt.
Val, it's time to go.
If He wanted me to die,
He would've let you
kill me a long time ago.
This isn't about you.
This is about
what you got there.
The power of an angel,
the free will of a human being.
All I want is what's mine.
Heaven. Have you been?
It's paradise.
One thing.
I'll let you go easy. Say it.
You know He's not with you.
Say it.
When was the last time
that you and He spoke?
Not lately.
It's not that He doesn't talk
to you, you know.
It's just that
you don't listen.
How do you know?
I can hear Him.
What's He say?
Jump.
There is your answer,
brother.
So you'll become
what you loathe the most.
Good-bye, Gabriel.
So, what happens now?
I can't see into the future,
Valerie.
You're gonna take my child
when it comes, aren't you?
He was the only one
of you worth anything.
who cared.
His child deserves
better than you.
I'm keeping him.
I'm raising him.
And maybe one day,
he'll get on the school bus,
and he
won't come back.
And maybe one day,
he'll dive into a lake,
and he won't come up.
I'll take my chances.
It's not yours to decide,
Michael.
Mom, when's vacation?
Well, you have one month,
and then you have the whole summer off.
Can we start now?
No, you can't start now.
Oh, I never like leaving her.
They'll be fine.
You just
gotta have faith.
Oh, honey, just let me give this.
There you go.
How are ya?
I'm fine.
You stay warm now.
Thanks a lot.
Take care.
Why you always so nice to that guy?
I think he's sweet.
He says he used to be an angel.
Phone's gonna ring.
It's gonna be
you-know-who.
Everything's gonna
be made right.
Phone's gonna ring.