Is it finished?
The engine still knocks
when it's cold, but that's normal.
Foucher!
Can you stay an extra hour?
Tonight, it's a problem.
But I think Pierre is free.
Pierre, can you stay tonight?
Check the ignition
on the gentleman's Mercedes.
Are you coming to the game?
No, I can't.
Are you going?
Sure.
Aubin asked me
to stay overtime... No way!
Tonight is special!
I'm going to the theater.
What are they playing?
Carmen!
I don't like operas.
Movies are better.
I'm going dancing tonight.
Give me a smoke.
All that singing
gives me a pain.
I like movies better.
You said that already.
See you tomorrow.
My love... oh, my love.
Geneviève,
my little Geneviève.
Guy, I love you.
You smell like gasoline.
It's just another perfume.
Guy, I love you.
Oh, Guy, I love you.
A customer. I have to run.
See you at 8:00
in front of the theater.
I've thought of you all day!
Would you like
to go dancing later?
If you wish.
Can I help you?
An umbrella.
Where were you?
Just across the street.
Have you decided
which kind you would like?
An umbrella.
A black umbrella.
Geneviève, show the gentleman
the umbrellas.
Is that you, Guy?
Good evening, Aunt Elise.
Good evening, my boy.
How are your legs?
Fine, my boy.
What are you up to?
I'm hungry.
You'll spoil your appetite.
I do what I please.
Calm down and talk to me.
I haven't much time.
You seem very nervous.
I'm going out.
Alone?
None of your business.
I think it is.
With a girl.
Do you love her?
It could be.
Tell me the truth.
Yes, I love her.
What's the matter?
You're crying!
No, I'm not.
I can see that you are.
Is it because you're lonely?
I'm not lonely.
I have my books.
Madeleine will give me my shot.
She will keep me company.
What, then?
Maybe happiness makes me sad.
That's silly.
You big brute,
you're messing up my hair.
Good evening, Guy.
Good evening, Madeleine.
You are sad.
You seem happy.
Does it show?
I had a terrible time...
Why?
Persuading Mother.
It was getting late,
and the seamstress was late.
Look.
Careful, it's still full of pins.
You know,
I think she suspects something.
Who?
Mother.
When I said I was going
to the theater with Cécile,
she gave me a funny look.
What kind of a look?
Like that.
She knows quite well
that Cécile hates shows,
and since I'm a very bad liar...
That's what you say!
I assure you, I'm very awkward.
I stammered and blushed
and immediately
changed the subject.
Something squeezed.
Something?
Lemon.
The same.
Do you love me?
A mambo. Let's go!
I should have changed shoes.
We'll have children.
I'll call my daughter Françoise.
And if it's a boy?
It will be a girl.
We've always had girls
in the family.
One o'clock.
If Mother's not asleep,
what a scene there will be.
I should wear makeup,
don't you think?
You're lovely as you are.
A little bit here.
Where?
There.
We'll sell umbrellas.
No, not umbrellas.
We'll sell the shop.
We'll buy a gas station.
Why? What an idea!
All white, with an office.
You'll see.
You'll smell like gasoline all day.
What happiness...
We'll be very happy...
And we'll stay in love...
You haven't told your mother?
Not yet.
Why? You're a coward.
You mustn't be angry.
I know what she'll say.
What?
"My little girl, you're crazy.
Thinking of marriage at your age!"
My little girl, you're crazy.
Thinking of marriage at 16!
Seventeen.
In love!
Am I too ugly or too stupid?
No, you're not ugly.
You're not the fairest of them all,
but you're neither ugly nor dumb.
The thing is,
you have plenty of time.
You think you're in love.
But love is something different.
You don't just fall
in love with a face
that you've seen in the street.
He's a young man
I've met several times,
and he loves me.
We want to get married.
You don't answer?
I'm flabbergasted.
I went with him
to the theater last night.
Great!
First you lie to me,
then you admit it
without the slightest shame.
There's no shame
in wanting to get married.
At your age, there is.
Well, no...
You're just a little girl.
You know nothing.
Well, what you've taught me
sure won't take me very far.
When I married your father,
I knew nothing.
That's nothing to brag about.
The paint shop, please?
Next door.
How old is he?
Twenty.
Of course, he hasn't done
his military service yet.
He lives with his godmother,
the lady who raised him.
I'm all he has,
and you'll see,
he's very handsome.
I'll see nothing of the kind.
But Mother...
Go upstairs to the apartment.
It's time to fix lunch.
Geneviève!
We're ruined!
You always exaggerate.
I owe 80,000 francs by the 15th.
Is that funny?
And if you don't pay?
They'll seize our property.
I'll get a job.
What sort of a job?
Anything.
Post office or city hall?
Why not?
You understand, if I get married,
Guy and I will work,
and we'll help you.
But, my little girl,
it's out of the question
for you to marry.
Take that away.
You're in my way.
Anyway, what can he do?
Can he support you?
Raise children?
He's not rich.
We'll live modestly,
and we won't have
children right away.
No, but one at least.
He's not the one
who will pay my taxes.
There isn't a penny left in the till.
Sell your jewels.
My jewels? Never!
What good are they?
You don't even look at them.
What if there's an emergency?
Isn't what's happening
an emergency?
Impossible!
If I sold my jewels, I'd feel...
stripped and naked.
Find something else.
Something else?
We have nothing.
Then sell the shop.
Stupid!
What will we live on?
Then again, a jewel is just a jewel.
Should I change my hairstyle?
My engagement ring...
It's atrocious.
This bracelet...
I could never wear it.
Nobody will want that.
What about your necklace?
My necklace? You think?
That'd be a crime.
No, I'll never part with it.
Anyway, it's probably fake.
Come on!
Then again, it's not that pretty.
This afternoon
we'll go see Mr. Dubourg.
Then I'll have my hair done.
How beautiful!
Truly marvelous.
Isn't it?
This is an impressive stone...
if I may say so.
Here are
rubies, sapphires, emeralds.
Ali Baba's cave.
The jewels...
of Sleeping Beauty.
Of Sleeping Beauty.
Hello, Mrs. Emery.
Hello, Miss Geneviève.
Hello, Mr. Dubourg.
Will you excuse me?
Please.
The young lady
has become very pretty.
It's been such a long time
since I've had the pleasure.
But what can I do for you?
You may speak frankly.
We are in an embarrassing situation.
Geneviève helps me
as much as she can.
It has nothing to do with her.
But I have heavy expenses
and I thought...
Well, I have a payment to meet
and if I don't,
consequences will be dire.
So I come to you as to my savior.
I hesitated a long time,
and Geneviève,
who is the voice
of wisdom and reason,
persuaded me.
It breaks my heart
to be forced to give up
this jewel, which to me
represents...
I understand, dear madame,
but my business involves risks
and I've already taken too many.
At best, I can put
your necklace up for sale,
but for much less
than its real worth.
I cannot buy it myself.
Couldn't you at least
give me an advance?
Nothing, I told you.
We can do nothing.
Don't insist, Mother.
This is a disaster.
Excuse me, but I'm interested.
I'll buy your jewel.
I can save you
from your predicament.
Allow me to introduce myself.
Roland Cassard, diamond dealer.
But, sir...
Don't worry, madame,
I'm no philanthropist.
I'll easily sell this necklace
in Paris or London,
where I often go on business.
I don't know if I should.
Please, I'm serious.
I'm ashamed,
and at the same time, delighted.
I don't have enough cash with me.
I can give you a check.
There's no hurry.
Could you come tomorrow
to my shop?
"The Umbrellas of Cherbourg."
I'm always there.
See you tomorrow.
What time is it?
6:15.
How come he isn't here yet?
He might be a crook.
He could have been leading you on.
Don't imagine things.
What's the matter with you?
Nothing, Mother.
Then be quiet.
I'm going to see Guy.
I forbid you to see that boy.
Stay here.
I wouldn't want to be disrespectful...
Well, that's good!
But I'm going.
You'll stay here.
Anyway, Mr. Cassard
will be here soon,
and I want you to be present.
Why?
Because!
If he's a crook, as you said,
we'd better face him together.
You think we'll be smart enough?
I don't know, but stay here.
I can't.
Don't leave. I don't want you
to leave. Geneviève!
I had given up waiting for you.
Are you crying?
It's nothing. Sometimes
I don't have the courage
to deal with my troubles
and my debts.
Am I not here to help you?
It's most kind of you.
I just saw Miss Geneviève.
I would have liked...
She's gone out.
The life we lead
is so sad for a young girl.
This dreary shop...
I no longer amuse her,
and I fear she'll become depressed.
You see, she's bored.
Would you like some tea?
With pleasure.
We've just had
a terrible fight about you.
About me?
She wanted to go out.
I didn't want her to.
We quarreled. We're so lonely
since my husband died.
Maybe you should...
I don't know...
take her to a show.
Maybe.
Will you come to dinner tomorrow?
Geneviève would be happy
to see you.
Impossible. I must leave tonight.
I'm going back to Paris,
and tomorrow I'm off to London.
Here's the money I promised you.
Give Geneviève my best regards,
and I shall not fail
to visit you
on my next trip.
I was so afraid
I wouldn't find you.
I'm so happy to be with you!
Now I'm laughing
because I realize
how foolish I am
when I'm alone.
I talked to Mother
about our marriage.
Of course, she said I'm crazy.
And tonight
she forbade me to see you.
You see, I was so afraid.
I'd go anywhere,
I'd never see Mother again,
rather than lose you.
We'll marry in secret.
It doesn't matter anymore now.
We have plenty of time.
I just received my draft notice
this morning.
I'll be gone for two years.
So we'll have to talk
about marriage later.
With the war in Algeria,
it will be a long time
before I can come back.
But I'll never be able
to live without you.
I won't be able to.
Don't go. I'll die.
I'll hide you...
and keep you...
but, my love, don't leave me.
You know it's not possible.
I won't leave you.
My love, I have to go.
I want you to know
that I'll think only of you.
And I know
that you'll wait for me.
Two years...
Two years of our life!
Don't cry, I beg you.
Two years...
No, I can't face it.
Calm down.
We have so little time left.
So little time, my love,
and we mustn't waste it.
We must try to be happy.
Of our last moments
we must keep a memory
more beautiful than anything.
A memory to help us live.
I'm so afraid when I'm alone.
We'll be together again,
and we'll be stronger.
You'll meet other women...
you'll forget me.
I will love you
until the end of my life.
Guy, I love you.
Don't leave me.
My love, don't leave me.
Come, my love.
Is that you, Guy?
Good evening, Aunt Elise.
Are you in bed?
I don't feel too well.
Is there anything you want?
Nothing.
I just need to rest.
Good night, my little one.
I'm afraid...
I love you.
Where were you?
With Guy.
What did you do?
He's leaving.
He'll be away for two years.
I can't live without him.
I'll die.
Stop crying. Look at me.
People only die of love in movies.
It's too cruel...
Separation is cruel, that's true.
But time fixes a lot of things.
You speak of love.
What do you know of love?
Are you sure of your feelings?
Mother, can't you see
how unhappy I am?
I know, darling, I know.
I have also loved, and fought...
and suffered.
You should listen to me.
I do listen to you.
Isn't it better to wait?
Two years from now,
perhaps you will have forgotten Guy.
No... I'll never forget him.
If you still love him
when he returns, you'll see.
You must believe me.
You must calm down
and get this affair
out of your mind.
Have you had dinner?
Yes, Mother.
Have some fruit.
You need distraction.
Go out and live a little.
It's not difficult.
You're young, pretty and witty.
You'll make friends
your age... or older.
Mr. Cassard came by this evening.
He was sorry he missed you.
I'm certain
he could give you good advice.
I can do without his advice.
You're wrong!
For me, he's the kind of man...
Don't bore me with his kind!
You look terrible.
Leave me alone, Mother.
Give me a kiss at least.
Have faith. You'll see.
Look at me, my boy.
When you return, I don't know
if I shall still be alive.
But Elise!
Don't say "but."
I've had a good life,
and I can leave it without regrets.
Nonsense! Right, Madeleine?
Of course.
She's better already.
I'll meet death before you do.
It's the army, not the war.
Before you go,
I want you to know
that everything I have will be yours.
Don't ever forget me.
Write me from time to time.
Madeleine will keep you informed.
Farewell, my little one.
My love, I'll wait for you
all my life.
I'll think only of you.
Stay. Don't go,
I beg you.
Stay, my love.
It's not time yet.
I'm leaving now.
Don't look at me.
I can't.
My love...
I love you...
I love you... I love you...
My love...
I love you... I love you... I love you...
Well?
Well what?
You're so pale.
What did the doctor say?
Practically nothing.
That I need rest.
You didn't need
to see a doctor for that.
I could have told you myself.
What else?
He gave me a prescription.
Sedatives, tonics and stuff.
Stuff!
Then it can't be very serious.
You see, Geneviève,
if the shop were doing better,
I'd be the happiest of women.
It's freezing.
Do you know whom I met in town?
You'll never guess.
Roland Cassard!
What do you say to that?
What do you want me to say?
He's incredibly nice.
We talked for over an hour
this morning.
He's back from the US.
What a man!
He told me a thousand stories.
I invited him to dinner.
What's the matter, Geneviève?
Nothing, I'm just tired.
That's no reason
for sulking like that.
You may be tired,
but you're not dying.
It's not the fatigue
that saddens me. It's his silence.
Guy left two months ago.
He's only written me once.
Don't start that again!
If I knew where he was,
I could write him.
I'm sure they've sent him
to some dangerous place
where he's risking his life.
It's simpler than that.
Simpler than what?
He's forgotten you.
You don't know what you're saying!
He doesn't think about you.
If he did, he would write.
One can write,
no matter how far away one is.
It's nothing.
I got so frightened.
I suddenly saw Guy laughing
with another woman.
Sit down.
I'll close the shop.
You're hiding something.
I'm not.
It's serious, isn't it?
I'm pregnant, Mother.
This is horrible.
Pregnant by Guy?
How could this happen?
Same as with everyone else.
Don't joke about it.
This is serious.
What are we going to do?
What do you mean?
With the child?
Bring it up.
What will we say?
To whom?
I don't know...
our neighbors, our friends!
We have no friends.
And you never speak
to the neighbors.
And Roland Cassard
is coming to dinner tonight!
We'll have to make him feel welcome
and put up a good front.
The way you look...
pregnant...
You don't need to tell him.
Be quiet.
It makes me shiver...
just to think of it.
Go upstairs and lie down.
I feel just fine.
Don't argue. Obey me.
I'll cook dinner myself.
Don't worry.
Maybe you need some rest.
Yes, Geneviève has been
overdoing it somewhat
lately.
She's a bit pale.
Why don't you go live
in the country?
The situation
in which we find ourselves
is such that we cannot,
for the time being,
take any rest.
Geneviève wouldn't go alone,
and I can't leave the shop.
There's no way out of it.
So you can't be separated?
We've practically never
been parted.
I haven't found the bean.
I have it.
You must pick a king
and make a wish.
I have no choice.
You are my king.
Thank you, Geneviève.
Put this crown on.
Put it on, Geneviève,
like he asked you to.
You look like
the Virgin with Child
I saw in Antwerp.
My cheeks are burning.
How amusing!
I think I drank too much.
I'll leave you now.
I'm not feeling very well.
Then I'll be going.
Please.
Let's chat a bit more.
Good night, my darling.
I'm really worried.
Geneviève is sad,
secretive, independent.
And I admit I'm probably not
tactful or understanding enough.
I'm always afraid of hurting her.
I wouldn't want to sound ridiculous,
and my feelings
could seem insincere,
however...
although I am taking this step,
I wouldn't want
to give the wrong impression.
My only desire
is to bring happiness.
Am I making myself clear?
Actually, not really.
Ever since dinner began,
I've been trying to broach a subject
that preoccupies me,
but my feelings are equaled
only by my shyness.
I came to ask you
for Geneviève's hand.
I'm very clumsy, I know.
Not at all,
but this is so unexpected.
Geneviève for me is still a child,
and your abrupt request
is somewhat unsettling.
You see, I don't know
Geneviève's feelings for you.
She's only spoken of you as a friend.
I wouldn't want
to pressure her in any way.
We know nothing about you.
Long ago, I loved a woman.
She didn't love me.
Her name was Lola.
It was long ago.
Disappointed, I tried to forget her.
I left France.
I traveled to the ends of the earth.
But I had no more taste for life.
Then, by chance,
our paths crossed.
As soon as I saw Geneviève,
I knew she was the one
I'd been waiting for.
Since I met her,
life has new meaning.
She's always before my eyes.
I live only for her.
I think only of her.
I had to
speak to you frankly.
Don't be offended.
Of course, I wouldn't think
of influencing Geneviève.
Geneviève is free.
Tomorrow I go back
to Amsterdam for three months.
When I return,
Geneviève can give me her answer.
I don't know what to say.
Don't say anything.
Geneviève will decide for herself.
You're not asleep?
You can see that.
Roland Cassard asked for your hand.
I heard.
You didn't tell him I'm pregnant?
I didn't dare.
I'm very proud of you.
François is a pretty name
for a boy.
Time passes slowly here.
Furloughs have been suspended,
and I don't know
if I'll be returning
to France very soon.
My love,
I know you're waiting for me.
Last night, one of our patrols
fell into an ambush.
Three soldiers were killed.
All the same, I don't think
that there's great danger here.
But it is strange how sun and death
travel together.
Geneviève, come to dinner, darling.
Dear Mr. Cassard,
we greatly appreciated
your postcard,
Mother and I.
I find these people ridiculous.
I hate the carnival.
Don't be bitter, darling.
It's incredible how big you are!
You're carrying in front.
It will be a boy, or twins.
No, everything is normal.
I feel wonderful.
You're like me.
I was delighted, never sick.
The day before you were born,
I was up on a ladder,
changing the wallpaper in the shop.
Has the postman come?
There were only bills
and some advertising.
Why? Are you still waiting?
In his last letter, he wrote
he was sad because
he wouldn't see me pregnant.
And perhaps it's just as well.
I look awful.
A pregnant woman
is always beautiful, my darling.
That's true.
Look at this.
A vest. And I saw pretty rompers
at the department store.
Admit that you're pleased.
I'd be more pleased
if that child had a father,
and if you had a husband.
Guy will return.
Guy or someone else.
Absence is a funny thing.
It feels as if Guy left years ago.
I look at this picture,
and I forget
what he really looks like.
And when I think of him,
it's this picture that I see.
It's all I have left of him.
Don't smoke. Be reasonable.
What's that?
A postcard from Hamburg.
From Roland Cassard.
For me?
For us. You may read it.
He says he'll be back soon.
He asks if you've thought it over.
It doesn't seem to me
there's any hurry.
No, but you must think it over.
I am thinking it over, Mother.
Here's a man, rich, refined,
and enamored of you,
and I think...
What are you doing?
Aren't you feeling well?
I'm all right, Mother.
You're eating.
I can't help it.
I'm always hungry.
He's not a womanizer,
a smooth talker on the prowl,
but a man who has lived
and suffered.
I know, Mother,
but don't give me a sales talk.
You praise him
like you praise your umbrellas.
Because he'll protect you, Geneviève.
Very funny.
If you can't take a little humor,
you're lost!
Guy might have been your ideal,
but what future did he offer you?
You know,
I too was once wooed
by a young man
who was not your father.
You'd have done better to marry him.
You're right.
But understand
that I want you to be happy
and not ruin your life
the way I ruined mine.
Don't worry about my life, Mother.
I have no intention whatsoever
of ruining it.
Do you think Cassard
will want to marry me
when he sees I'm knocked up?
Watch your language!
Deformed! Bloated!
Since neither you nor I
had the courage
to confess the truth to him,
now, at least, it will show!
Do you believe
he'll take me like this?
If he refuses me as I am,
it means he doesn't have
deep feelings for me.
But if, by some unlikely chance,
he accepts me,
I'll have no reason to doubt him,
and I'd be a fool to reject him.
So, you see, I'm thinking it over.
But all this is so difficult.
Why is absence
so heavy to bear?
Why is Guy
fading away from me?
I would have died
for him.
Why aren't I dead?
Look.
What is it?
It's for you.
Roland sent it for you.
I can't accept it.
Do as you like.
We'll bring this child up together.
He'll be our child.
Please say yes,
Geneviève.
I don't want all this
to upset you in the least.
I love you,
Geneviève.
She accepts,
since her present condition
doesn't frighten you.
But don't rush her.
She's so fragile
that the slightest mistake
could compromise everything.
Madeleine told me everything.
Why didn't you say anything?
I didn't want to.
I thought you knew.
Didn't you suspect anything?
Of course. Over the last few months,
her letters weren't the same.
She didn't answer my questions.
She wrote without conviction.
But from there
to marrying another man!
No, I thought she was mad at me,
but I didn't know why.
Then there was the hospital
and my letters
that went unanswered.
Here nothing has changed.
I have.
I can let go
now that you're here.
I would have been so unhappy
not to see you again.
Don't talk nonsense.
Come on, make yourself useful,
my boy.
Give me some herb tea.
Everything's ready
in the kitchen.
There's water in the kettle.
Something wrong with your leg?
You see, I limp a little.
It's like having
a barometer in my knee.
Especially when it rains.
It was in the hospital
that I suffered the most.
But how did it happen?
Returning one night from maneuvers.
We were attacked.
Hand grenades.
It happened often.
What about Madeleine?
She's coming.
She's been very good to me.
Isn't she married yet?
You know how well-behaved she is.
Put it over there
on the table.
What will you do now?
Work. Or maybe live
off my pension.
Aubin promised to take you back.
You liked his gas station.
Oh, his or someone else's.
We'll see. I have time.
There's no hurry.
The child she was expecting...
do you know anything about it?
No. Geneviève left
just after the wedding.
Mrs. Emery stayed
in Cherbourg a month or two.
Then she sold the shop.
I think they're in Paris.
You haven't changed.
I'm happy
that you've returned.
Foucher!
The boss wants you.
Shit!
Did you service this gentleman's car?
Complete checkup on the 26th,
right, sir?
Two thrown rods this morning.
The engine is dead.
A brand-new engine.
Not a drop of oil!
I'm not blaming anyone,
but that's it. I'm real sorry.
Did you check the oil gauge?
Of course.
You forgot to screw the cap on.
I know my job.
Don't talk to me like that!
And apologize to the gentleman.
I don't have to.
It wasn't my fault.
You don't give a damn
about your work.
Why don't you buy some new overalls?
And shave before you come to work!
I've had enough.
I'll find another job.
That stupid ass.
Since he got out of the army,
he acts like a hoodlum.
What's going on?
I'm quitting.
I had a fight with Aubin
and quit before he could fire me.
What will you do?
Live off my pension.
A dry white wine.
Another.
Take it out of this.
Don't you have anything smaller?
You're all the same,
with your big bills.
What of it, you bum?
Just do your job and lay off!
Just forget it.
What are you looking for?
Nothing.
Then move your ass.
You're in the way.
Cognac.
Want to dance?
Leave me alone.
Something wrong, baby?
Come with me if you want.
You're really
a sweet girl.
Evening, Madame Germaine.
Evening, Jenny.
You can call me Geneviève
if you'd like.
You're going to say
I remind you of someone.
Good-bye, Jenny.
Come again sometime.
Sorry, Madeleine.
I didn't have my key.
What's the matter?
Elise died
last night.
I can't stay any longer
in this apartment.
I'm too unhappy.
I want to leave soon.
But where will you go?
I don't know.
You have no family.
Don't you want to stay here?
What would I do?
You'd help me.
I'll be lonely.
You don't need anyone.
I need you, Madeleine.
Why don't you just say
you don't like
being alone?
I don't see
what I could do for you.
I have no influence over you.
That's not true.
I don't like what you've become.
You hang about
with nothing to do.
You're sad and bitter.
You've changed a lot.
It's not my fault.
Since I came back,
things don't make sense anymore.
I don't think I can help you.
You're too far away.
What if I asked you to try
despite everything?
I wouldn't hesitate to stay.
I'm asking you.
Then I'll try.
I'm a bit late.
The lawyer took forever,
and I stopped by the garage.
Now everything is settled.
Poor Elise.
Nothing will be left of her.
On the contrary.
She'll be part of everything we do.
Are you happy?
Very.
And it's all thanks to you.
Madeleine, you know it's true.
And you? Are you happy?
I'm not unhappy.
I wanted to tell you...
That is, I've been thinking
that if you wanted
to share my life...
if I weren't
too much of a burden...
and that...
Are you crying?
No.
Did I say something wrong?
Not at all...
but it makes me so happy,
and at the same time,
it scares me.
You're scared of me?
No... a little... well...
you understand...
Have you given up
thinking about Geneviève?
Are you sure you really love me?
I'm not scared, but I wonder
if you're not acting
out of despair.
You're quite wrong.
I don't want to think
about Geneviève anymore.
I assure you,
I've forgotten everything.
I want to be happy with you.
Madeleine, don't cry.
I don't have much ambition...
but if I could
make this dream come true:
To be happy with a woman...
in a life we've chosen
together...
I'm done.
It's very beautiful.
You think so?
Your hands are cold.
I'm going out now.
If you want.
Our son would like to see
the toys in the store windows.
He's been talking about it all week.
I'll take him for a look
before dinner.
Stop that, will you?
François, you'll make us deaf!
I got you a lovely
Christmas present.
What is it?
It's a surprise. You'll see.
Bundle up.
I love you, Guy.
François,
come and put your coat on.
Say hello to Santa Claus for me.
Françoise, stop that.
The horn isn't a toy.
It's cold.
Come into the office.
It's warmer here.
This is my first time
back in Cherbourg
since I got married.
I went to pick up my daughter
at my mother-in-law's in Anjou.
On the way back to Paris,
I decided to make a detour.
I never thought I'd run into you.
It's pure chance.
Does madame want me to fill it up?
Geneviève...
Yes, fill it up.
Super or regular?
It doesn't matter.
Which do you want?
Super?
This is a pretty tree.
Did you decorate it?
No, my wife did.
It's mostly for the kid.
Of course.
Are you in mourning?
Mother died last autumn.
What did you name her?
Françoise.
She's a lot like you.
Do you want to see her?
I think you're all set.
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine.