And now on BBC2, a look at
the world of science and technology
with a new series
of Look Around You.
(Cheering)
(DJ) And now let's take a look
at this week's Top 10.
At No.10, it's Jonathan Silverstein
with Punky Bar Mitzvah.
The Emerald Sisters are at 9
with Botched Operation.
At 8, it's The Nuts
with Black Thatcher.
The outrageous Marigold's at No.7
this week with Romeo And Julian.
At No.6, everyone's favourite
pensioner, Grandad,
with The Good Old Days. Aw.
At No.5, it's Imhotep
with Hurts Like Crazy.
And Corville Bedford
spends his 60th week at No.4
with Nuclear Winter.
No.3 this week is cancelled.
And his second entry
in the Top 10 at No.2,
Grandad with Freudian Slip.
Which means that this week's No.1
is, yes, you've guessed it,
Jack Morgan with Little Mouse.
No, you haven't gone mad.
This is Look Around You and that was
Top Of The Pops from two years ago,
when our very own Jack Morgan
had a No.1 single with Little Mouse.
♪ Hey, now, little mouse
♪ I hope we understand one another
♪ Hey, now, little mouse,
show me what to do
♪ Little mouse... ♪
Jack took a year off from presenting
to concentrate on his music
and scored a worldwide hit
with this song,
which was inspired
by a vermin infestation.
♪ Show them what to do... ♪
- Nice hair, by the way.
- Thanks, Pete.
We've got a very special show
for you tonight,
because Jack will be performing his
follow-up single here in the studio.
That's because tonight's programme
is about the world
and the future of music.
So stay tuned.
(Pseudo-futuristic synth music)
♪ Look Around You ♪
(Muffled synth music)
(Music stops)
What music will be listening to
in the year 2000?
Will we still be enjoying
pop music like Jack Morgan,
or classical, like the operas
of Bach or Mozhoven?
Well, that's the question we asked
you in the Radio Times recently.
And we set you a challenge,
to come up with what you think
music will sound like
in the year 2000,
in an event we call music 2000.
(Funky music)
(Electronic voice) Music 2000.
We had thousands of entries
from all over the British Isles
but unfortunately we only
had time to listen to a few of them
and we've chosen the three acts
that we feel come closest
to predicting the musical styles
of the year 2000.
And they're here with us tonight.
And they are...
And they each stand the chance
of winning the music 2000 prize
of a professional
recording contract.
Judging their performances tonight
is somebody who knows
a lot about music.
In fact, he's even been
described as a musical genius.
Please welcome the ghost of
world-famous Russian composer,
Tchaikovsky.
Well, we're just waiting
for the materialiser to start up.
(Bleeping)
And there he is.
- Hello, Tchaikovsky.
- (Translates to Russian)
- And welcome to Look Around You.
Spasibo, Peter.
(Speaks Russian)
Thank you, Peter. It is great
pleasure to be on the BBC tonight
and great privilege
to be judging music 2000 contest.
Well, it is a great privilege
for us, sir,
to have you on the programme.
You truly are a fantastic composer.
(Translates to Russian)
- Tchaikovsky...
..what qualities will you be
looking for tonight?
(Translates to Russian)
(Speaks Russian)
A futuristic vision
but also a timelessness.
Drama, of course, strong melody
but perhaps most important of all,
star quality.
Well, Tchaikovsky,
you've certainly got star quality.
And we hope you enjoy
our three musical guests,
starting with Tony Rudd,
who is a music teacher from Bristol.
Hello, Tony.
Welcome to Look Around You.
Tony, tell us a little bit about
the piece you're going to perform.
I got quite a lot of help
from some of my pupils
and incidentally, I'd like to give
a big wave to everybody in class 4/4
at St Cerberus Comprehensive.
Erm...we thought long and hard
and we decided to look
at current trends in music
and extrapolate from that
what we imagined would be
the most futuristic music possible.
Erm...so hopefully
that's what we've come up with.
So...Tony Rudd,
you now have 30 seconds
to give us your music 2000.
Good luck.
♪ Machadaynu, Aberdeenu
♪ Machadaynu-daynu-daynu
♪ Machadomis, abatetron
♪ Abatetro-tetro-tetro
♪ Ooh
(Falsetto) ♪ Ooh
♪ Machadaynu, Aberdeenu... ♪
(Cymbal crashes)
(Muted applause)
Oh, well done, Tony, that was
great. Wasn't that fantastic?
- Oh, brilliant.
- Superb.
Bravo.
And we'll be returning to music 2000
and the ghost of Tchaikovsky
throughout the rest
of the programme.
(♪ Electronic opera)
(Cheering)
Ooh, thank you.
You might be forgiven for thinking
we have a real-live orchestra here
but in actual fact
the symphony you just heard
was performed not by an orchestra
but by a simple synthesizer.
And the man who programmed it
is someone who loves
synthesisers so much he even changed
his name to Synthesizer Patel.
(Mumbles)
(♪ Look Around You theme)
- Hello, Synthesizer Patel.
- Hi, Pealy.
Synthesizer Patel, synthesizers
are really taking off, aren't they?
Oh, yes, Pealy. Every pop group
wants a synthesizer these days
because a synthesizer can reproduce
the sound of any instrument,
except perhaps for the bassoon
but they're working on that one.
But they can do more
than that, can't they?
Oh, certainly. This is something
that might interest you.
OK, so what I did earlier was
I made recording of my own voice
- using this microphone.
- Mm-hm.
And I stored that data into
the synthesizer's memory banks.
And now here is the fun bit.
I can play back to you.
(A capella style)
♪ Synthesizer Patel...
(Very deep bass)
♪ Synthesizer Patel ♪
- That's amazing.
- Mm.
It comes fitted with
a burglar alarm.
A burglar alarm?
(Piercing alarm)
In fact, they all come
with burglar alarms these days,
because crime's so bloody bad
and these bastards, they steal
your synthesizers and er...
- Yes, it's a shame.
- Yes, it is a shame.
Now, Synthesizer Patel,
synthesizers come in all sorts
of shapes and sizes.
This one here, for instance,
looks like a calculator.
Ah. That is quite right, Pealy.
That is because it is
a calculating synthesizer.
It is similar to the one used by
the Chancellor of the Exchequer
in his recent musical budget.
So it's ideal for anyone
who loves music and maths?
Exactly and there is security lock
here for extra security,
because synthesizers
are so expensive and...
Now, Synthesizer Patel, I've never
seen an instrument like this before.
- That looks like water.
- It is indeed water, Pealy.
The water makes it easier for the
hands to move around over the keys.
It also makes the music sound
smoother.
Listen.
(♪ Bland electronic tune)
Gosh, that's lovely.
If anyone tries to steal it,
the water becomes electrified
and they receive a nasty surprise.
Well, Synthesizer Patel,
thank you very much
for enlightening us on
the wonderful world of synthesizers.
They really are amazing devices,
aren't they?
Synthesizer Patel, you mentioned
earlier the bassoon.
When do you think a synthesizer
will be able to imitate one?
Realistically? Never.
The bassoon is such a particular
instrument with such a unique sound,
I don't think they'll ever
approximate it.
Certainly not in my lifetime.
I suppose that's good news
for all you bassoonists out there.
Don't go throwing away
your bassoons just yet.
Peter. (Chuckles)
Synthesizer Patel, you're going to
play something we should recognise.
That's right.
(♪ Out-of-tune
Look Around You theme tune)
♪ Music 2000 ♪
We're back with the second round
of music 2000,
our quest to discover the music
we'll be listening to in the future.
Our judge, the ghost of Tchaikovsky,
has already seen our first act,
Tony Rudd.
And now it's time to meet
our second act.
She's Toni Baxter
who is a theoretical physicist
from the MacBritish Institute.
- Toni, welcome to Look Around You.
- Hello.
Toni, as a physicist,
what do you think life will be like
in the year 2000?
I really don't know.
I don't know.
Do you think technology will play
a much more integral role
in music production, for instance?
We don't know.
We just don't know.
Well, perhaps we'll all be listening
to your composition.
So, Toni Baxter,
you now have 30 seconds
to give us your music 2000.
Good luck.
♪ Yes
♪ No
♪ No ♪
(Cymbal crashes)
(Applause)
Well done, Toni Baxter.
That was spectacular.
How do you think you did?
I don't know.
I just don't know.
You've certainly given
the ghost of Tchaikovsky
something to think about.
Later on we'll be meeting our third
and final contestant in music 2000,
so do stick around
and thank you once again
for your performance, Toni Baxter.
Have you ever wondered
how the pop charts are compiled?
Well, every time you buy a record,
the record shop owner
immediately notifies
the people who put
the charts together,
the Royal Pop and Rock Association,
using a system of pneumatic tubes.
Once it arrives at ROPRA,
the sale is logged
and that information
is used to calculate the positions
of the songs in the charts.
However, the pneumatic tubes
themselves are pretty old
and often get clogged up.
Worse still, because so many other
businesses use this tube system,
the information
sometimes gets mixed up,
which can lead to
discrepancies in the charts.
We all remember last year's fiasco
when the Post Office tower spent
six consecutive weeks at No.1.
So in the words of Elvis Presley,
"Something had to be done."
And here at ROPRA's headquarters,
in London's West End,
something is being done.
Sir Alan Rees
is the chairman of ROPRA.
- (Knocking)
- Go out.
Sir Alan, what is being done?
Well, we're phasing out
the whole pneumatic tube system
because it's clearly not working.
As well as
the Post Office tower business,
we've had everything from a coat
hangar in the Top 10
to a motor insurance policy
popping in and out of the charts
and driving everybody mad.
Erm, so now,
when you buy a single, um...
- it will look like that.
- What's that little box?
That is actually a transmitting
device that's built into the record.
So as soon as you place the needle
on to the groove of the record,
it sends out an electronic signal
to our central computer,
which registers the details of the
record, the name of the pop act,
the song, umcetera, umcetera
and from that we can completely
accurately produce the um...charts.
So, Sir Alan,
what's to stop an artist
from playing their record
again and again,
sending out multiple signals
to your computer
in a bid to drive
their record up the charts?
Well, we've um,
thought of that, Pam.
From now on, when you buy a record,
you will only be able
to listen to it once.
I see.
After that,
if you do try to play it again...
um...it will sound like this.
This record has been erased.
(Bleep) This record has been erased.
(Bleep)
This record has been erased. (Bleep)
And um...
Now the record is totally useless.
That's amazing.
Well, Sir Alan is not only
an expert on records,
he's also a record holder.
Um...that's right, Pam. I currently
hold the record for French kissing.
- So, could I have a demonstration?
- Certainly.
Um...
Well, that certainly
topped my charts.
Um...
♪ Music 2000 ♪
And now it's time to meet our third
and final contestant on music 2000.
He's Antony Carmichael, who
is a profiterole chef from London.
- Hello, welcome to Look Around You.
- Thank you.
Antony, before we go on, what is
the secret to a good profiterole?
I suppose the secret to
a good profiterole is fresh cream
and good ingredients.
Well, let's hope you have
the right ingredients tonight.
Now, Antony, tell us,
what is your prediction
for the music of the future?
Well, there's a new type of music
that's emerged
from the streets of America,
where people talk over the music.
- They talk over the music?
- Yes and the rhythm.
- And it's known as rap music.
- Rap music?
Yes and I definitely think
we'll be listening to rap music
in the year 2000.
Well, this is a first for me
because I've certainly never heard
rap music before.
So, Antony Carmichael,
you now have 30 seconds
to give us your music 2000.
Good luck.
(Slow electronic drum beat)
♪ I'm rapping all day
and I'm rapping all night
♪ Rapping to the beat
and I rap it up tight
♪ I rap in the morning
and I rap till I'm done
♪ And everybody knows that I'm No.1
♪ Cos I'm rapping, I'm rapping,
I'm rap-rap-rapping
♪ I'm rapping, I'm rapping,
I'm rappity rapping
I'm rap-rap-rapping
♪ I'm rap-rap-rap-rap-
rap-rap-rapping
♪ I'm rapping all day
and I'm rapping all night
- (Cymbal crashes)
- ♪ I'm rapping to the beat... ♪
Well done. That was fantastic.
And thank you for introducing
us all to the world of rap music.
Well, we've seen
all three contestants tonight
but which one will be walking away
with a recording contract?
Find out after this.
(Upbeat disco music)
We've all heard of disco damage,
the harm caused to our ears
through excessively loud music.
That's enough now, thank you.
I said that's enough now, thank you.
- (Music stops)
- Phew, that's better.
If we think of our ears
as this crystal glass...
(High-pitched note)
..we can being to understand
the immense power of sound
and realise just how fragile
our ears actually are.
Thanks, Pam.
(Deep bass note)
You're good at that.
So what can be done about it?
Short of writing to
your MP about noise levels
or picketing your local discotheque,
there's nothing much
we really can do.
But now there may be an answer
and it comes, surprisingly,
in a can.
Psilence, so its maker claims,
can reduce all external sounds
by up to 100 per cent.
So let's meet its maker,
inventor Leonard Hatred.
(Shoes squeak)
Hello, Leonard,
and welcome to Look Around You.
Leonard, you've been rather followed
around by noise all your life.
That's right.
When I lived with my parents,
erm...they were both great snorers
and er...I've always been
a light sleeper.
Erm...so they caused me
a lot of annoyments.
I see.
And also we lived in Heathrow,
erm...which wasn't marvellous.
We moved to another house
and that was unfortunately
Gatwick... (Laughs nervously)
..which wasn't an improvement.
No, I suppose not, no.
When I got married, we moved
to the countryside and er...
they proceeded to build an abattoir
directly opposite the house.
So it was the constant noise
of dying cows,
which was the er...the final straw.
And I understand that your wife
suffers from a condition
that causes her
to scream incessantly.
That's right and her sister
has moved in with us also.
- And she...
- She has the same condition. Yes.
So I suppose
that's a noisy household.
So I suppose it was the culmination
of all these things
that led you to create your noise
reduction spray Psilence.
And you're going
to demonstrate it for us now.
Now, Leonard, can you tell me
what does your spray contain?
It's obviously a secret formula
but I can reveal
that it contains liquid skin.
- Mm-hm.
- Hold still.
OK.
Oh. Ah. That's very cold.
It'Il dry off in a minute.
Now, er, I can't hear
anything out of this ear.
No. Can you see that?
Nothing at all.
Let's do the other ear.
It's cold.
Now, ah... Ah... Ah...
(Loudly) Well, erm, both of my ears
are now completely sealed.
And erm...
Er, this is odd. I can't even...
I can't hear anything.
I can't even hear
the sound of my own voice.
Psilence will be going
through to the final
of our Look Around You Invention
of the Year Competition
and Leonard Hatred could be walking
away with this magnificent trophy,
presented at the end of the series
by His Royal Highness,
Sir Prince Charles.
And here's your rosette.
(Electronic voice) Music 2000.
Well, it's decision time
for music 2000.
I've just picked the last bit
of Psilence out of my ears.
So before our judge, the ghost of
Tchaikovsky, gives us the result,
let's first remind ourselves
of our three acts.
First of all we had Tony Rudd
with Machadaynu.
Then we saw Toni Baxter
with her entry, Sexual Interface.
And finally, Antony Carmichael
with The Rapping Song.
I think you'll agree
we could be listening
to any one of those songs
in the year 2000.
- Absolutely.
- Terrific. Very impressive, chaps.
However, there can be
only one winner.
- So, Tchaikovsky...
- Tchaikovsky.
..could you now please
tell us who that is?
(Speak Russian)
I talk. I talk.
Here... (Clears throat)
(Strong Russian accent)
Thank you very much.
Ten years ago...
I judge similar contestizion...
called music 1990.
Same standard was good.
But today standard much bigger.
And so...
It give me great...
- (Speaks Russian)
- (Whispers)
..bosoms to present music 2000 prize
to...
Toni...
Baxter.
(Cymbal crashes)
Well done.
Congratulations, Toni.
Congratulations. So, Toni, how does
it feel to have won music 2000?
I don't know.
I really don't know.
Well, here's your prize,
a professional recording contract,
which comes into effect on
January the 1st, 2000. Well done.
Yes, congratulations, indeed, Toni,
and we look forward to hearing
your music in the future.
And, of course, commiserations
to our other contestants.
(Muted applause)
And thank you once again to our
judge, the ghost of Tchaikovsky.
Thanks, Tchaikovsky.
Thankovsky.
Well, next week one of us
will be having plastic surgery
here on the programme,
as we take a look at the world
and the future of health.
But now it's the moment
we've all been waiting for.
Look Around You's Jack Morgan
performing his latest single.
So, from all of us here at
Shepherd's Bush, good night
and take it away, Jack!
(♪ Reggae)
(High-pitched) ♪ Hello, everybody,
listen to my song
♪ About a young man
who was always doing wrong
♪ And never seemed
to do or say quite the right thing
♪ But when you play my record,
you'll hear him sing
♪ Reggae man, what you doin'?
♪ Reggae man, hear me now
♪ Reggae man, do it
♪ Walk round town
with a very sad face
♪ All London all bopping the place
♪ I'm walking down the road
with a skanking style
♪ I'm rocking and I'm walking
in a boom-town style
♪ Hear me ragamuffin
in the rub-a-dub style
♪ Skanking and a-skanking
in the boom-city style
♪ I'm walking round the place
with a smile on my face
♪ Cos they're playing my record,
gonna mash up the place
♪ Reggae man, what you doin?
♪ Reggae man
♪ Come on, Reggae man
♪ Reggae man, what you doin'?
♪ Reggae man
♪ Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah
♪ People ♪