Dude, do you know they
make silent window shades?
Some woman in Washington
invented them
back in the early '90s.
Since when is the sound of
opening and closing shades
so disruptive that it
has to be alleviated?
Why do you have to hate on other
peoples triumphs of innovation?
Weird.
It's not weird, it's selfish
and more than a little petty.
No, not that,
come take a look at this.
Man, this better not
be another auction
for one of Stoney
Jackson's neckerchiefs.
It's not, Shawn.
This came in
on the Psych account.
The sender is
"me-at-under-the-nail- dot-com."
I'm pretty sure
it's not spam.
Well, what's the attachment?
Cinnamon festival.
The Great Northern.
I'm not familiar
with that publication.
What, you know every small
town newspaper in California?
Actually, I do, Shawn.
Ridgecrest?
The Daily Independent.
Shawnopolis.
That doesn't exist.
Yet.
I just need 50,000 signatures
and a large plot of land.
Well, look up this town,
Dual Spires.
I mean, how can there be a cinnamon
festival that we've never heard of?
Zoom in.
Zoom in again.
Keep zooming.
I am, Shawn.
Dude, this town is so small
that it's in parenthesis.
How the heck
did we get this email?
It's a delicious mystery.
Think about it,
a tiny little town
we've never even heard of?
What's your schedule
look like?
I'm open till
my route tomorrow.
Let's see here.
You think they'll
have monkey bread?
Yes, I do.
What?
I'm good till
next WrestleMania.
Half a mile
from the nearest road.
No wonder it's
in parenthesis.
This is one
secluded town.
Let's get
some cinnamon.
Wow. Everyone
looks so happy,
and yet, so perplexed.
Something's off
about this place, Shawn.
People keep looking,
like I'm the first
black man they've seen.
Come on, Gus.
Don't be absurd.
Hey mister, are you
Frederick Douglass?
Shawn, we need
to get out of here.
Nah, let's get
something to eat.
Hey, top of the morning
to you, boys.
Robert Barker.
You can call me Bob.
Just passing through?
We're here
for the festival.
We take our cinnamon
very seriously.
Well, then you're in luck,
because so do we.
Ninety years running.
Why do you call
your diner The Sawmill?
'Cause that's
what it used to be.
Most of it burned down
back in '58.
Granddad turned it
into this place,
and now it's just a bit
of a local landmark.
We just need
a little something
to hold us over
until show time,
so, uh, what's good?
How about a cup
of the best
pipin' hot apple cider
this side of
the Mississippi
and a slice of cinnamon pie
that may just bring tears?
Two slices
of cinnamon pie, hon.
That's the wife.
Isn't she a peach?
Ah, I'll get that cider.
Bob's a real Chatty Cathy.
You think?
You should check your email.
See if our secret pal
sent us any cinnamon comps.
I'm afraid you won't have much
luck with those here.
Sheriff Andrew Jackson.
You know,
we had the opportunity
to put up some of
those fancy towers,
but folks decided a basic
landline was fine with them.
I couldn't help
but overhear
that you're in town
for the festival.
It's rare to get visitors.
Well, we heard all about
it on underthenail. com.
We don't have the
Internet in Dual Spires.
It's simpler that way.
Dude, we're doing Witness.
They were Amish.
Not Danny Glover,
he was black.
What are you
talking about?
Well, we are happy
you're here, nevertheless.
It should be a heck
of a celebration.
Two slices of cinnamon pie.
Oh, thank you.
Well, we'll see you
at the festival.
Sheriff.
What's the verdict?
Really?
Mmm.
Oh, mother of God.
Mmm-hmm.
Mmm.
Dude, that owl is made
entirely of cinnamon.
Which means that it is
both wise and delicious.
Let's have a nice,
warm round of applause
for Mayor Douglas Fir.
And, this year's
festival mascot,
Leo, the cinnamon owl.
You found the monkey bread.
You know that's right.
And now, the moment I know
you've all been waiting for.
It's time to announce this
year's Cinnamon King.
Who-oo will it be?
Who, who, who?
Oh, who are we kidding?
Put your hands together
for the future leader
of Dual Spires.
A young man that
needs no introduction,
come up and
claim your crown, Randy.
That's my boy.
What's 24 times 12?
Two-eighty-eight.
Why?
There's a chair here
for every person in town.
Three are empty.
Sheriff's talking, so that's one.
Check it out.
There's one
right next to the Barkers.
Hey. Hey, you found
the monkey bread.
Yeah.
Mrs. Barker,
is everything okay?
No.
Everything is not okay.
Shelley.
What?
I can't just sit here
and pretend to be excited
about churros and
Leo the cinnamon owl.
I sense someone is missing.
Yeah.
Our niece, Paula.
She's been gone
about a day and a half.
Everyone keeps
telling us not to panic.
She's a teenager.
Wait, what did you mean,
you sensed it?
Mr. and Mrs. Barker,
I have a confession to make.
I'm not just
a cinnamon enthusiast.
I'm also a
psychic detective.
And this is my partner,
Lodge Blackmunn.
Can you find Paula?
Perhaps.
Oh!
I got a little something
under the nail.
Right here, under...
Under the nail.
We are available for hire.
We don't have
much money.
None of us do, here.
We believe
it complicates things.
Well, we have been known to work
for cider or pie in the past.
Oh, of course.
As much as you'd like.
We will find your niece.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Who is supposed to be
sitting over there?
Oh, that's Paula's
best friend, Jack.
I'm not sure where he is.
Would this be...
Something happened
at the lake.
at the lake!
It's Paula.
I know it is.
Jack just discovered
her, about an hour ago, Doc.
So young.
My God, Andrew.
Jack, is this
how you found her?
No, sir.
She was half naked.
It wasn't right.
I didn't want people to see her like that.
I'm sorry.
Oh, now I've got to let
the Barkers through.
No!
No, my baby.
Paula.
Paula!
Come on, dude.
You know I'm a sympathetic
crier, Shawn.
Just leave me be.
Dude, I have a bar.
And an email.
Gus, we weren't called here
for a cinnamon festival.
In between the lines
there's a lot of obscurity
I'm not inclined
to resign to maturity
If it's all right
then you're all wrong
But why bounce around
to the same damn song?
You'd rather run
when you can't crawl
I know, you know
I'm guessing
the time of death was
sometime night
before last.
Doc Gooden will do
a full autopsy.
You know she won't
miss a thing, Bob.
But I suspect
what we will find
is that Paula went
swimming after curfew,
like she always did,
and got pulled under
by the current
and hit her head.
I'm gonna rule it
an accident for now.
She must have snuck out.
Bob, we both know
she's been sneaking out
just about every night
since she got here.
Listen, why don't you
take Michelle on home.
She's gonna need you
to be strong now.
I'll get Deputy Frost to
take you back in the rickshaw.
I'm so, so sorry, Bob.
Looks like we won't be needing
your services after all, boys.
Mr. Barker, I am sensing
there is more to Paula's
death than meets the eye.
What are you saying?
That she...
Oh, my God.
We'd like to stick around.
See what we see.
Feel what we feel.
Okay.
If someone hurt Paula,
we sure as hell
want to know about it.
I'm also sensing that Paula didn't
grow up here in Dual Spires.
May I ask where
she was before?
Paula lived in Santa
Barbara till she was 11.
Well, you have
our condolences,
and we will be in touch.
I think your ride
is here.
The earth is soft and moist.
That is so bizarre.
It's like I only have
reception in this spot.
In all my years
of police work,
I've never seen
anything like it.
I know.
Our new station manager
is an angel sent from heaven.
O'Hara.
Yes, Detective O'Hara.
Shawn Spencer calling.
Did you just use both of our last names?
Don't be weird.
Okay, Miss O'Hara.
Detective.
Shawn.
Look, I'm really struggling with
the whole work formal thing.
What are you wearing?
Okay, you just took it from one
awkward extreme to another.
I need you to run
a name for a girl.
Used to live
in Santa Barbara.
Paula Merral.
Two "r"s.
Sure, is everything okay?
Yeah, absolutely.
I'm gonna have to
call you back, though,
'cause there's not really
reception up here.
Up where?
Hello?
Jules.
Shawn?
Wow, it really is
just the one spot.
Your conversations with Juliet
are too uncomfortable
to listen to now.
I'm calling next time.
Fine.
Look, if we're going to
accomplish anything in this town,
we are gonna
need wheels.
Shawn, we have reached
a new low point in our life.
Are you kidding me?
It's like Driving Miss Daisy.
Except you
get to be Miss Daisy.
I don't wanna be
in the movie, Shawn.
Looks like the doctor
stays pretty busy.
Guess you're out of luck
if you need a massage.
Good job saving
your receipts, Patrick.
May I help you, gentlemen?
Hello, Doc Gooden.
My partner,
plus too much
cinnamon monkey bread
equals tummy shame.
Can you help us?
I'll see him
after my next patient.
Doc, this could
get ugly fast.
All right.
Sheriff Jackson
mentioned we had
a couple of visitors
in town today.
You are aware the cinnamon
festival has been cancelled.
Oh, yes.
We heard there was
some sort of tragedy.
Must be so difficult
in a small, happy town
like Dual Spires.
Put this on and then lay
face down on my table.
Uh, well you know...
Ah, ahh!
Actually, I think...
Snap to it.
I'm not putting this on.
Fine.
So how well did you
know the girl?
I'm sorry, I don't
know why I do that.
I can just sense that
you have a heavy heart.
I'm a woman of science.
And law.
And accounting.
But that doesn't mean
that I don't feel.
Paula was
a troubled young girl.
I wish I could have
done more to help her.
You were her
psychiatrist?
You ask a lot of questions.
It's just... I recently
lost someone myself.
He was murdered too,
so I know how difficult...
Paula wasn't murdered.
Who told you that?
Oh, no one.
I just assumed, because...
I haven't done
an autopsy yet.
There are no obvious signs
of foul play.
I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to...
No, it's not you.
Like I said, she was
a troubled young girl.
She had a dangerous side.
Nothing scared her.
Not even dying.
You think she
may have taken her own...
No, I can't bear
that thought.
I've said too
much to a stranger.
I should be ashamed.
For caring?
No, you shouldn't.
You know, I actually
feel better.
The myna bird
can come in now.
What's up next?
We need to find
our cinnamon king.
That kid
has a secret.
What did
grandma tell you
about wandering off
in the store?
Oh, come on.
I was getting
ready to say...
That would have
been too much.
Dude. That's him.
Dude, that's our guy.
Oh, Sheriff.
Didn't expect
to see you here.
I live here.
What do you mean?
Of course you do.
Oh...
You're Randy's father.
Yes, wow.
You guys have Bob Barker, Doc
Gooden, and Randy Jackson.
All living in
the same inlet town
with no cars, cell
phones, or internet.
Shawn, we need to pitch
this to Mark Burnett.
You fellas realize
the festival is canceled.
As you know, we lost someone
very dear to us today.
That's actually why
we dropped by, Sheriff.
You see, Gus and I are grief
counselors back in the big city.
And you all have been
so kind and welcoming to us
that we figured
the least we could do
would be to offer our
services before we left town.
Well, come on in, fellas.
Yeah.
I'll confess, Randy and I
haven't been communicating
too well as of late.
I know he's hurting,
but he won't talk to me.
You know,
it wasn't too long ago
that Gus and I
were Randy's age.
It was a pretty
long time ago.
Ah, it wasn't
that long ago.
You like to think so.
I can't do this with you right now.
Fine.
He's upstairs
in his room.
We'll give it a shot.
So my dad hired you
to shake me down, right?
I'm fine.
I barely knew Paula.
Then why did the two of you share
secret, special lover earrings?
Come on, Randy.
How long had you been seeing her?
Who are you?
A couple of guys with a
passion for the truth.
And cinnamon.
We'd been together
six months.
Why was it a secret?
It's complicated.
I get it. It's Pretty in Pink.
You're Andrew McCarthy.
Who's Andrew McCarthy?
That's fair.
Where were you
the night Paula died?
I was at the library,
studying.
The librarian
can confirm it.
Do you always study
so late on a Friday?
I'm at the library
almost every night.
I've been taking
correspondence courses.
I need a business degree
to be a good leader.
That's true.
I never could
have hurt her.
I loved Paula.
We were gonna see
the world together.
I'm gonna be so
lost without her.
Oh, Paula.
Paula.
That's a little
dramatic, don't you...
You have a problem.
Excuse us.
Keep your
voice down, please.
It's just us
and you.
Just a bunch of words on
paper to you guys, right?
Wrong.
Each is alive
with a story to tell.
Listen.
I'm just
messing with you guys.
Thanks for playing along.
That's really sweet.
I'm Maudette Hornsby.
Isn't cherry the best?
The best what?
Everything, silly.
I thought you were psychic.
I am.
I'm the psychic.
But how did
you know that?
Mmm, word travels.
You know, we don't get a
lot of gossip around here.
So untimely death,
a psychic,
and a black man,
all in one day.
Epic.
I really thought we
were being discreet.
Do you even know
what discreet is?
That's a
serious question.
I know what...
Shh!
Was Randy Jackson with you
the night Paula died?
Why?
Do you think she was
M- U-R-D-E-R-E-D or something?
M- A-Y-B-E.
Yes, Randy was here.
We have a very
special bond, you see.
His mom passed away
when he was very young.
Sheriff Jackson
never remarried.
So I sort of stepped
in and filled a role.
For both of them.
Is there anything else
you need to know?
Uh...
Feels pretty good
for now.
Do you mind
if we poke around?
Poke?
Peek.
Peek around.
Yes.
Knock yourselves out.
Okay, remember
the last email,
the one with all
the weird hieroglyphics?
They were letters
and numbers, Shawn.
Okay, it was one
of these things.
The Dewey
Decimal System?
I didn't even know
they still used this.
That's 'cause people don't
want to crack war codes
when the payoff
is Jane Eyre.
What was the
number, Shawn?
F-7-9-6-dot-3-5-2.
Seven hundred's that's
sports and recreation.
These books
are archaic.
And really old.
Except this one.
By Earl Wyndam.
My short game
could use some work.
There's no pictures?
This is the weirdest
golf book I've ever seen.
Let me see that.
Our emailer wants us to think
that Paula was reincarnated?
We should get
back to the lake.
Juliet should have
something by now.
You're gonna need
a library card
if you want to check
something out.
I think we're good,
Maudette.
Juliet, it's Gus.
Gus, what's going on?
Is Shawn okay?
Oh, he's fine.
Tell her I said "Hi."
Ask her what
she's wearing.
Do you have anything
on Paula Merral?
Do I?
Look, I don't know
what you guys
have gotten yourselves
into up there,
but Paula Merral drowned
here seven years ago.
What?
Did she say "Hi" back?
Is he looking at us?
I think he is.
Dude, take it easy.
That's your seventh piece.
You know I get hungry
when I get freaked out.
Besides, you've had five.
Exactly, I believe
in portion control.
A girl drowns,
gets reincarnated,
and drowns again
seven years later?
Worst cinnamon festival ever.
We definitely
stick out around here.
True, but not
as bad as them.
What are you
staring at, Jesup?
Scoot.
Wow, did you guys just
hoof it from the highway?
What? Oh, hell no.
No, we took the seven-mile
dirt road that connects
this crap hole
to the next town over.
We came up here because
the chief wanted us
to get a positive ID
on Paula Merral's body.
To see if it matched the one
found in Santa Barbara?
No, see
that's the thing.
We never
recovered her body.
Which didn't
sit well with me.
The inlet where she supposedly
drowned has no current,
which means her body
should have floated up
between 2.3 to 3.1 days.
Oh, I know this because
waiting for corpses
to resurface is
a passion in my life.
The sweater she was wearing
was found on the shoreline.
And her bike was discovered
at the end of a nearby dock.
It was lying next to a
pile of sunflower seeds,
which was also weird.
What 11-year-old girl
chews sunflower seeds?
Excuse me, Flo.
Where might we find the proprietors
of this fine establishment?
Robert and Michelle?
They've been home ever since
they got the news about Paula.
Do you have something you
want to tell us, Mr. Barker?
Twelve years ago,
Michelle's sister, Lucy
ran away from Dual Spires,
taking seven-year-old
Paula with her.
We were worried
sick about Paula.
See, Lucy was an incredibly
unstable person.
Michelle and I practically
raised her daughter for her.
Then one day, we got
a letter from Paula
confirming
our worst fears.
It described how
magic white rocks
were making
her mom crazy.
Methamphetamines?
Along with other stuff.
A couple of letters
after that
was the first mention
of the abuse.
And that's when
we knew we had to act.
You helped her
fake her death?
We had no other choice.
Lucy wouldn't let her go.
And Paula
was all for it.
In fact,
it was her idea.
It doesn't matter.
What you did
was against the law.
If I had jurisdiction here,
you'd be under arrest
for obstruction
of justice.
She was happy here.
And safe.
Until two days ago.
Right.
I'm heading
back to Santa Barbara
to reopen this
case, Mr. Barker.
Once I do,
a warrant will be
issued for your arrest.
Come on, O'Hara.
Call when you can.
You two
understand, right?
We're not here to judge you, Mr.
Barker.
We came to investigate, catch
bad guys, and eat pie.
Not necessarily
in that order.
And it hasn't been.
No.
We started with the pie.
Always.
Do you think we could take
a look in Paula's room?
By all means.
We haven't touched a thing.
It's at the top of the
stairs on the right.
Dude, the Dr.
Ombudsman wasn't kidding.
Sister definitely
had a dark side.
Hmm.
What are you doing?
Looking for places
she may have hid stuff.
Every teenager has
a secret spot, Gus.
Remember when
I found those
weird photos of John
Cusack in your nightstand?
That was Joan.
Really?
Oh, that's
much less weird.
Wait. No, it's not.
Not really. Incoming.
Dude.
Diary. Jackpot.
What does it say?
"Math was really
hard today."
Blah, blah, blah.
Seems like normal
high school stuff to me.
Whoa.
What is this language?
Is this Chinese?
No.
It's Latin, Shawn.
Latin?
Gus, Paula must have thought
someone was reading her diary.
We gotta find out
what that says.
Yeah, but who do we
know that speaks Latin.
"Absens... Haeres."
Hairy ass?
"Non erit."
Did you get all that?
Uh-huh.
I believe so.
Haven't you ever heard
of faxing, Shawn?
I'm sorry, Father.
We don't have that
capability right now.
Besides, I thought
that priests thought
all technology was evil.
It's only now that it
begins to dawn on me
how little you learned
in my CCD class.
Look, Father, it's very
important that we understand
what these passages mean.
All right, all right.
Well, this first part talks about
a young boy she was seeing.
Someone popular.
Randy.
Yeah, that makes sense.
She refers to him as "R."
Ah, she may have also
been seeing someone else.
Excellent,
is there a name?
No, just the letter "J."
Letter "J."
All right, thank you Father.
You've been so much help.
Gus will see you
at church on Sunday.
Uh-huh, what about you?
What? Oh,
you're breaking up.
What? What...
Can't hear anything.
Hello? Father?
Whoa, whoa, wait, wait.
There's more.
It really is one square
foot of coverage.
Jules, what are
you doing here?
Well, Lassiter's handling the reopening
of the case back at the department,
so I thought I would come
back and lend a hand.
Fantastic. We have
to hit the library,
follow up on
a vision I just had.
All right, well,
you two go ahead.
I'm gonna notify
Sheriff Jackson
that I'm gonna be
looking into the case.
What do you say we all
meet up at the diner at,
uh... 4:30?
Labradoodle!
Where?
We should go.
I didn't see any
labradoodle, Shawn.
Well, you weren't
looking very hard.
Nice shoes.
I know.
Gus was wondering if you
would like to be his date
to Betty Boop Night
at the Road House.
They don't have a Betty Boop
Night at the Road House.
Oh, then they don't have my
business anymore, either.
Sure you can
keep up with me?
I like to dance
all night long.
Well... Shawn.
What?
Relax.
Okay, here we go.
This is the most recent
Dual Spires's yearbook.
Thank you, Maudette.
Feels a little thin.
Small book
for a small school.
There were only six people
in the graduating class?
Yeah, and even
that was large.
Mine only had three.
You, Robert, and Michelle?
You're very impressive,
Mr. Spencer.
None of the guys
in Paula's class
have names that
begin with "J."
Let's see here.
Paula sure is
in a lot of photos.
Oh, that's not surprising.
She loved the attention.
Huh.
Thank you, Maudette.
Bye, Gus.
Whoa, Jack.
You didn't even
give me a chance
to see if I had
food in my teeth.
They're good.
I'm Shawn.
He's Blackmunn.
Yeah, yeah.
I know who you are.
Oh, good, so you know we're here to
ask you some questions about Paula.
You, uh, you ever
think about hanging
any of your photos
on the wall?
Well, to me, each photo
is like a memory,
so I like to keep them close.
Looks like you and Paula were
more than just friends, huh?
Yeah, we were.
Until about a year ago, she
left me for the Cinnamon King.
You must have been
pretty angry with her.
At first I was, yeah.
But then we became best friends.
I was her confidant.
And we would lip synch
to old records together.
Jon Cryer from
Pretty in Pink.
No one in this town has ever
seen that movie, Shawn.
Well, I refuse
to accept that.
Oops! Jack,
that's my bad.
Uh... Let me
clean this up.
No, no, no, no.
Don't, don't, don't.
The broken glass will make
for a beautiful photo.
Yeah, it will.
So what do you think?
You think this guy killed Paula?
Most definitely.
He's a freaky dude
living in a freaky place.
And have you noticed
he won't ever make
eye contact with you?
There's only
one reason for that.
Guilt.
Actually, there
may be another.
Hey, Jack.
The glass is
over here, man.
I know.
Yeah.
I gotta tell you, you are
the highest functioning
blind person
that I've ever seen.
I'm not technically blind.
I still have 30% vision
in my right eye
for now.
A couple of years ago,
I developed early onset
macular degeneration.
I'm sensing
it was around '05.
Yeah, that's right.
Where were you
the night Paula disappeared?
I was with her.
At the beginning
of the night.
We took a walk in the forest,
and she told me
she wanted
to leave Dual Spires.
I said that
was a mistake.
And then, jet blackness.
What does that mean?
It would be a great
porn name for you.
I woke up about
an hour later.
With this,
a bump on my head.
And there was no Paula.
She knocked you out?
Come on, Jack.
A big guy like you?
No, no, no.
Somebody else snuck up on me,
and I wasn't looking.
Well, you could
have been looking.
Probably wouldn't have
made much of a difference.
He's practically blind.
Why didn't you take any of
this to the sheriff, Jack?
Because I may have been
the last person
to ever see her alive,
and my story
sounds fishy at best.
I mean, do you believe me?
Were you taking photos
that night on the walk?
Yeah, yeah.
Of course I was.
Well, why don't you let us
take a look at that film?
Okay.
Ooh.
Why?
Oh, this is good.
This will go well with
the five shots of her boots.
Take a blindfolded
photo sometime.
Let me know
how it turns out.
Wait a second.
Here's something.
Dude, we gotta
get to Jules.
Hi, I'm looking
for Sheriff Jackson.
The deputy said
I could find him here.
Yeah, uh, he just
stepped out for a sec.
Do you know
when he'll be back?
Oh, any minute now.
You can wait
in the back with me.
I'm just doing a little
work for shop class.
Okay.
I'm Juliet O'Hara.
Randy.
Randy Jackson.
How much do you weigh?
Excuse me?
I'm sorry, I'm not supposed to
ask a woman that question, am I?
Not unless you're
piloting a very small plane.
About 105?
Will your dad
be here soon?
I imagine so.
Paula weighed about 105.
You kind of
remind me of her.
I understand you two
were quite close.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Yeah, it's a
real tragedy.
You know what?
Why don't I just come back
in, like, an hour or so.
No.
Stay.
Hey!
Get your wood
out of her face, Randy.
What's going on?
We know you knocked out Jack Smith,
when he was with Paula
the night she died.
Yeah, I thought he was trying
to steal my girlfriend.
Really?
You're jealous of the goofy kid
who snaps photos
like Jose Feliciano?
Hey, Paula always
had a thing for him.
For Jose Feliciano?
No, Jack.
I just gave him a super elbow
and he crumbled like feta.
What did Paula do?
She freaked out
and went on this rant
about how I'm a hypocrite
'cause I spend a lot of time
with my ex-girlfriend.
And who's that?
That's none of your business.
What is it with all the secret
relationships in this town?
It's like
General Hospital.
You're kidding me.
All right, that's it.
Is there a film,
or a television series,
that you people actually saw?
The town gets together
every Thursday night
to watch
reruns of Everwood.
Okay, I can work with that.
What happened next?
She got mad at me
for hurting a blind person.
She then went
to find help for Jack.
I offered to go with her,
but she wanted
nothing to do with me.
So I tied his
shoelaces together,
and went to the library
and waited to hear from her.
Of course,
I never did.
Just like Treat Williams'
character on Everwood.
Never got to say
good-bye to his wife.
Shawn.
Look, I'm telling
you guys the truth.
Plus, I have an alibi,
remember?
All right.
But we're on
to you, Randy.
Just like the townspeople of
Everwood were on to the fact
that Nina was
a surrogate mother.
Will you stop it?
Enough.
She was.
Thank you.
So, who do we think
Randy's ex is?
Mmm, Jules, you gotta
order a piece of this pie.
I did. You guys
immediately ate it.
Well, it's gotta be someone
who's into the creepsters,
but I'm guessing she's older,
'cause I'm yet to see
a woman under the
age of 35 in this town.
It's also someone that Randy
spends consistent time with.
Mmm-hmm, mmm-hmm.
I'm getting something.
I'm at the library
almost every night.
Randy and I have a very
special bond, you see.
Four slices to go, please.
If Maudette was sleeping
with Randy, that's gross.
She practically raised him.
The only thing that
would make it grosser
is if she wasn't attractive.
What's wrong with you?
This goes beyond Maudette
getting her Pamela Smart on.
I think she killed Paula.
What?
How do you figure?
I'm sensing that Randy went
to the library that night
to finally tell Maudette
that he and Paula
were leaving Dual Spires.
Sent her into
a jealous rage.
She snuck out,
killed Paula,
because if she
couldn't have Randy,
no woman would.
That changes everything.
Remind me to never have
an affair with an older woman
or a librarian.
Maudette.
That's not good.
Oh.
I am so sick
of this town.
Go ahead and wheel her around
the corner to my office.
I can't believe
Maudette Hornsby
was taking
advantage of my son.
Taking advantage
is a little strong.
The dude was 17
and she was fine.
What exactly constitutes
the difference between
altar boy Gus
and degenerate Gus?
Reputation
was everything to Maudette.
The prospect of the town
knowing about that scandal
was probably more
than she could live with.
I better speak to my boy.
And I'll get on
that autopsy.
The fact that
she murdered someone
may have also
hurt her reputation.
All right, I'm gonna get back
and brief the department.
Do you want me to drive
you to your car?
No.
Yes.
We'll meet you
back there in a bit.
Okay.
Why are we not getting
the hell out of here?
Because my theory
is half-baked, Gus.
Something isn't
sitting right with me.
You know what's not sitting
right with me, Shawn?
Being stuck in a tiny town
with no phone access
and all white people.
Let's go.
Now where are you going?
If we leave now, I'll
let you play the theme
to Weird Science over and
over in the car. What do you say?
That's happening regardless.
This way.
Here is the most recent
Dual Spires yearbook.
Maudette was
the one emailing us.
That makes no sense.
Why would the killer lure
detectives to the scene
and then start
feeding them clues?
Because she
didn't kill Paula, Gus.
I'm never gonna
leave this town.
She suspected foul play
and knew she'd be
the prime suspect
if anyone found out about her
relationship with Randy.
So she started snooping
around on her own,
discovered the drowning seven
years ago in Santa Barbara.
Found us on the Internet.
So who killed Paula Merral?
I don't know,
but we're gonna find out.
Gus,
stop messing around.
I'm not, Shawn.
Shawn?
Yes, Gus.
Something's burning.
I see that.
Help us!
Somebody help us.
We're stuck
in this tiny room!
Help us!
Let us out!
Shawn, we're gonna die in
this tiny, stupid room.
Gus, don't be the scream
from Holding Back the Years.
You're right, though.
This could be it for us.
Man, we are gonna burn!
I know.
No, wait, wait!
Who are you?
Gus!
Father Westley.
Thank God you were here, literally.
We were about to be Wicker
Men, How did you find us?
I just had faith.
Really?
No, boys.
I just got to town,
I saw the fire,
I saw the tandem bicycle outside.
It all added up.
But how did you know we were
in trouble in the first place?
You hung up on me when I was
transcribing the Latin, Shawn.
I just
I got excited.
I took one little
step to the left.
And that girl, Paula.
She felt she was in danger. She was afraid.
Which led me to be afraid
for the two of you.
And, honestly,
I owed you one anyway
because of that
whole exorcism thing.
What happened to your hair?
Oh. Yeah, it was
an ill-advised attempt
to cover up some gray
that went terribly awry.
But technically,
Sister Rita's to blame.
She's the one
that did my hair.
Guys, get in.
We don't have much time.
You have a car?
What gives?
Why should we trust you?
You probably shouldn't,
but if you stay here
you're gonna be sitting
ducks for whoever it was
that tried to burn
you guys alive.
I'll explain everything
at the cabin. Get in.
Have a seat,
I'll make a fire.
All right, we're listening.
My great grandfather founded Dual Spires.
That's him there.
I might have
guessed that one.
After World War I ended,
he'd seen the
absolute worst in man.
He decided to settle here
with two other soldiers from his
squadron and their families.
I was wrong, it isn't Witness.
This is The Village.
The Village
was a ridiculous film.
"Those we do not speak of."
Remember all that nonsense?
It's always been
the responsibility
of the three leaders
of the families
to watch over the town
and its best interests.
Try to understand, their
intentions were so pure.
Create a community
that wouldn't be subjected
to the horrors
that they lived through.
And it worked for 40 years.
Dual Spires was perfect,
until...
The great sawmill
fire of '58.
It was arson.
A drifter, who had been
in town doing odd jobs.
Eight people burned to death.
After that,
we became insulated.
Looked at all outsiders
as a threat.
Like Paula.
She was afraid.
She thought she was being watched.
Even followed.
She was.
Which is why Michelle and I were
supportive of her decision to leave.
I...
We loved her so much.
We just wanted her
to be happy.
Did Paula ever know
that you were her father?
Yes.
I had to tell her,
in order to get her
to come here
in the first place.
What about your wife?
Did she know you had
an affair with her sister?
No.
She never will.
I think she's
been through enough.
You know, for a town that prides
itself on honesty and do-goodedness,
you have a lot of skeletons
in your closet.
Judge not, that ye
may be judged, Gus.
Although, I must say,
in this case,
it's pretty messed up.
I know who
killed Paula Merral.
Sheriff, you can
put the gun down.
This is Father Westley.
He saved us.
My hair doesn't normally
look like this.
Bless me father,
for I have sinned.
But I'm afraid
I can't put away this gun.
No, I suppose
you can't.
You see,
the other two families
that settled this town
were the Jacksons
and the Goodens,
am I right?
And as its other two
leaders, you panicked
when you caught wind
that the evil Paula
was running away
with Randy.
I mean,
without the Cinnamon King,
who would lead
over future generations?
The good doctor
can't conceive.
The Barkers didn't have
a child of their own,
which means Randy is
the only direct descendent
to protect Dual Spires
and your way of life.
Especially now that the
sheriff is dying of cancer.
I know he's hurting,
but he won't talk to me.
The two of you wielded
all the power necessary
to kill Paula and make it
look like an accident.
And you would have
gotten away with it too,
if Maudette hadn't
sent those emails.
But even that was nothing a little
rope couldn't take care of.
Isn't that right, sheriff?
You truly are amazing.
But you shouldn't
have come here.
Our business
was not your concern.
Your business is murder.
Her death, though tragic,
saves our future.
You killed my little girl.
What about us?
Honestly, far less tragic.
We barely know you.
I'm in my own special category.
Right?
Really, father?
Freeze!
Drop it, now.
How did you find us?
Oh, miracles happen
every day, Gus.
This is a miracle?
No, I called the detectives
before I came to town.
You sly old dog.
We ran into Jack,
and he led us here.
They thought
this place was a secret.
I've photographed every
single inch of this town.
Ah, good work, son.
We're over here.
Oh, Jack.
Yo!
SHAWN Now, Jack, really...
It's brighter than the sun.
Enough. Enough.
It's nice to finally
have some alone time.
It is.
Though, you know,
we're not really alone, Shawn.
You were not lying
about the pie, Burton.
It's heavenly.
Right?
Now on to Ecclesiastes.
It's one of my favorites.
Hmm?
Couldn't blow off a priest,
I'm pretty sure that's a sin.
It's not so much Gus, and
Father Westley, and Carlton.
That is a damn fine
cup of cider.
It's the other people.
Three cinnamon pies, please.
What do you say we get out of here?
I'm in.