Dad, why do those people
get better seats than us?
Your Honor,
it's not that I...
Shawn, those people aren't just watching
the trial. Those people are the trial.
They're the jurors,
and they're the most
important people in this room.
They are?
The thing about
the jury is, Shawn,
you gotta learn how to look
at them, how to read them.
For instance, take a look
at juror number five.
He's the guy in the front row,
second one from the left.
Tell me what you see. Go.
Brown shirt,
little hole in his collar.
His coat is too tight on him.
He's got rough hands, he's looking
down mostly and nodding a lot.
Good, good.
All right, let's take
that hole in his collar.
Now, would Mom ever let you leave
the house looking like that?
Never.
You believe it.
So, that tells us that
he's probably not married.
That's called
deductive reasoning.
Your Honor, the people call
Detective Henry L. Spencer to the stand.
All right, watch closely, kid.
One day you're gonna walk up
the steps of this courthouse
and you're gonna make
your old man proud.
Gus, they impounded
my motorcycle without warning.
I'm pretty sure the warning was the $900
worth of parking tickets you racked up.
Still, man, you can't take a man's
means of transportation away.
It's, like, unconstitutional
or something.
I'm pretty sure
it's not in the Constitution.
Oh, don't be so sure.
I think it says, "Thou shalt not
something, or covet something.
"Don't mess with Texas or
the right of transportation."
You're thinking
of a commandment.
That's even better.
Can we just pay this ticket
so we can get out
of here, please?
You gotta be kidding me.
We came all the way over here,
and now you're not
gonna wait in the line?
Gus, did you see it in there?
It's a ticket payment line,
not Space Mountain.
Hardly worth it.
Plus, I don't wait in lines. What
do you mean you don't wait in lines?
Everyone waits in lines. That's what
we do as people, we wait in lines.
I don't.
It's not in my nature.
That makes no sense, Shawn.
You remember the story
of the scorpion and the frog?
Burton Guster. They're both on
the riverbank. The scorpion's like, "Hey"...
The point is I shouldn't
have gotten any tickets, Gus.
I was using
my ambassador plates.
Ambassador plates? You're
not an ambassador, Shawn.
Impersonating a government
official will land you in jail.
I am an ambassador,
of sorts.
I am a goodwill ambassador
to Paraguay.
To where?
Paraguay.
It is an honorary title
that I received
after overseeing all sand castle
construction at a South American Club Med.
You never worked at Club Med.
Ooh, turn that up.
Someone we know,
someone we love,
someone we invited into our...
I just saw that woman
at the courthouse.
That's Sandra Panitch, the fourth grade
teacher who murdered Jackson Hale.
Don't you watch the news? I
can't watch Channel 8 anymore.
Lloyd Lansing wears a toupee. It's
like every newscast starts with a lie.
I can't stand this guy. Something
about him just irks me. Listen to him.
Sandra Panitch went with weatherman
Jackson Hale to his Channel 8 news studio,
engaged in sexual relations
with him,
and then stabbed him in the
heart with a letter opener.
She fled the scene,
but not without leaving behind
a mountain
of physical evidence,
including a trail
of the victim's blood,
and her fingerprints
all over the murder weapon.
This is why the state
is going after murder one.
But she didn't do it!
What?
Gus, I'm getting
a very strong feeling here.
I think that woman
is innocent.
I do watch the news, and
I've been following this case.
They have a mountain
of evidence against this lady.
Look, they call her
the "School Marm Murderer."
Okay, first of all, there's a
question mark at the end of that.
They call her the
"School Marm Murderer?"
Even the news people
aren't convinced.
And today at the courthouse,
in the middle of a conversation,
I saw her bend over
and pick up a piece of trash!
Oh, I see. So because she picks
up somebody's KitKat wrapper
means she didn't kill anybody?
That makes sense.
Gus, she didn't
have to do that.
The woman is about to be
on trial for her life.
She takes time out
for common courtesy?
That is not the mindset of
a cold-blooded murderer. No!
This is what I know. She
looked at me right in the eyes.
Now, there are a lot of tells
that people have
when they are trying
to appear not guilty.
The way that they sit, crossing
their legs, uncrossing them,
crossing them back, eye lines to inanimate
objects, twitching, itching, rubbing.
All of these affectations,
I am an expert on all of them.
But there is one thing that you cannot
change no matter how hard you try,
and that is the tent
on the windows to the soul.
Adam Hornstock,
attorney for the defense.
Sandra Panitch
is a victim of circumstance,
of being in the wrong place
at the wrong time.
I know.
Look at this poor guy.
Look, he's hunched over,
he's not making eye contact.
Look at the handkerchief
in the left pocket, there.
It's not decorative, Gus.
That's crumpled and stained.
That's used for
dabbing sweat, a lot.
Her lawyer's a beaten man.
Whether he knows it or not,
Adam Hornstock needs us.
What are you talking about?
Dude, we're going to be
legal consultants.
It's awesome.
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
Ooh, let's get in there
and grab seats.
How? You think that court officer
is guarding the door for his health?
Just roll with me on this.
Excuse me, people.
Coming through!
Shawn Spencer here. Spencer.
That's S-P-E-N-C-E-R.
This is my partner,
Burton Guster. G-U...
Look, I know I've been
reluctant to go on record
about this trial
up to this point...
I'm sorry, who are you?
What is this,
Journalism 101?
I give my statement, you berate me
with your rudimentary Q and A later.
In fact, you two
switch places.
Come here. Excuse me.
Come on, don't be shy.
He puts his pants on
one leg at a time. I do.
As I was saying, this trial
is not about a particular case.
It is about our rights
as citizens.
No one, and I mean no one, should ever
wake up and I don't know, let's say,
find that their motorcycle
has been taken away from them.
As this trial moves forward, I'll have
more to say. That is all. Thank you.
Motorcycle? Whose motorcycle are
we talking about here? Did...
Guys, please. Please,
give them space. Please.
Are we ready yet,
Mr. Hornstock?
Oh, yes.
Just one moment, sir. Ah!
You know, I was pre-law once.
Maybe I should have stuck with it.
You were never pre-law.
Well, I was pre-pre-law.
Sixth grade, but it was
an accelerated program.
I won a mock trial of
Tortoise v. Hare, you know.
The hare did it.
Of course he did.
The court will take a short
recess, and then perhaps,
Mr. Hornstock, we can get
going with these proceedings.
Dude, we're so hired.
We are?
Watch this.
Excuse me, Mr.
Hornstock? Right?
You don't know me.
My name's Shawn Spencer.
I'm the lead psychic detective
at the SBPD.
Yeah, I'm a little busy
right now.
I can see. You're doing a
bang up job. Please don't stop.
I just... I think maybe you
should be a little careful.
Of?
Juror number four.
Juror... Oh, yeah?
Why is that?
Something about you
really bothers her.
And something about her
bothers me.
I mean, she's been frowning
at me the whole time,
and I haven't even
gone up yet.
Here's the thing.
She's a fashion maven.
She has a problem
with your appearance,
and until you change it, I don't think
she's gonna listen to a word you say.
My appearance? The manner
in which you appear.
Your look.
I don't know exactly what the
problem is, but let's check it out.
Why don't you give me the... Give
me the 360 cat dance real fast, huh?
Excuse me? Just twirl it up for
me, and then twirl it right back.
There it is. And back.
Suit, pleated. I would have
gone with a three button,
maybe something
in a wool-cotton blend,
but I don't think
that's the problem.
Sideburns? Check. Hair,
bold, Strokes, Hives.
I don't think
that's the problem.
The shoes, not a spit shine, but like
you said, you haven't gotten up yet,
so I can't make
heads or... Whoa!
What?
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
I think it's the tie.
What? My tie?
What's wrong with my tie?
Well, it's a little bit...
Well, look, it's not
like my favorite tie...
I'm so glad to
hear you say that.
Gus?
What?
Quick, give me your
tie. I'm not giving you my tie.
It's a good tie!
Give me your tie, please.
It's a Thomas Pink tie.
One second.
Why don't you give me the
tie? Just once will you...
Come on, Shawn!
Look high, reach low.
Got it.
Now, we're also
going to take this.
Primarily because
it's covered in sweat,
but also because it reads
cruise ship waiter to me.
Cruise ship?
Go get 'em!
And so, I will demonstrate
to the court
that Sandra Panitch is an upstanding
citizen with no criminal record,
and the district attorney has rushed
to the prosecution of an innocent woman.
Are you finished now,
Mr. Hornstock?
Hmm? Ah! Oh, yes.
Yes, Your Honor.
Brilliant.
Well, things are
finally moving along.
Court will recess
till after lunch.
Did you see that? That was
amazing! Did you see that?
That was a whole 180!
Well, it's a pretty
amazing tie.
Hey, strong shag, strong
tie, strong person.
You know, guys, I would hire
you in a second. It's just...
Well, I, I don't
have the authorization.
My firm doesn't really
believe in...
Winning?
No.
Mermaids?
The Minotaur?
No, me.
Yeah, at least not anymore.
No, there's no buts here.
A lot of the cases my partner
Gus and I take, we do for free.
It's called pro bono.
Gus?
What?
A little decorum,
we're in a courtroom.
Congratulations, you got yourself
a couple of legal consultants.
Wow.
Oh, boy.
Did he just grab your fist?
And then he shook it.
Well, well, well,
what do we have here?
Hi, Jules.
Please tell me you're not one
of those courtroom groupies
that bounces
from trial to trial?
Wait a second, was that you
at the Michael Jackson hearing
with the sequined glove
and the shirt that said,
"Please free the man
in the mirror"?
That's actually
really funny, Shawn.
Detective Lassiter is the one who
actually made the arrest of Sandra Panitch.
See, that makes it my case.
What a coincidence.
It's also our case.
Yeah, we just signed on as legal
consultants to the defense just now.
And you will sell your little sideshow
act to anyone who'll listen, won't you?
Just don't screw this one up.
"Don't screw this up"?
Hey, Lassy, that really
wasn't much of a put down.
In fact it was
somewhat inspiring.
Las, let's roll that back!
I don't know.
It feels a little weird.
I mean, you should really be
sitting here. This is your office.
Yeah, this isn't my office.
You didn't like mine. This is Carter
Jarecki's office, one of the partners.
Actually, he's the guy who took
the case in the first place,
but then dumped it on me when
he decided it was a lost cause.
You see, that's exactly
what I'm talking about.
Why didn't you stand up
to that guy?
For the worst reason possible. I
actually believe this woman is innocent.
Now, can we please
go before Jarecki gets back?
Carter Jarecki just left for a nooner with
his mistress. We have at least two hours.
Maybe an hour and a half.
Hornstock, I think you have the
potential to be a fantastic lawyer.
You just need confidence. After all,
that's your name on the door. Now come on!
Oh, no. No. None of those
Hornstocks are me.
The first one is my
grandfather, he founded the firm.
The other one is my father,
then my brother.
Wow. A whole
family of lawyers?
Yeah, even my sister.
Well, there you go.
She didn't make the door.
She's Biederman.
It's her married name.
Well, we're gonna need to take
a look at your witness list
and your deposition
transcripts.
Oh, yeah. Well, I prepared
all that for you.
I have... Here are all the
forensic and arrest reports.
And I deposed several of
Hale's coworkers from Channel 8,
mostly to refute timelines
and for character testimony.
Can we see those?
Oh, sure, yeah. It's...
Oh, yes.
And maybe, later on we can read
the phonebook, just for fun.
Hornstock, I've gotta do
what I do.
That's not the way I do it.
I need to see,
feel and smell people
in order to figure out
what happens.
Smell them?
So, this is where the...
The crime took place.
So, just feel free
to have a look around,
and do whatever it is
you do.
Okay.
Thank you.
Let's walk the
crime, shall we? Yeah.
He probably came in from that
same entrance we did. Right.
Found their way over here to
the Channel 8 anchor desk area.
Of course, the body
was found here.
It was a short walk.
Yeah.
Priscilla, what are these
green walls for?
Oh, well we do it all
on green screen.
Really? Can you show me
how that works, please?
Sure, I just need someone
to sit in front.
Gus, go sit over there.
I'm not going to sit there just
'cause you tell me to, Shawn.
Fine, I'll...
I'll play anchorman.
I got it. I got it.
Okay, so we've just have to go to
the control room. It's just this way.
Okay.
You know when we're watching
the weather guy,
and it looks like he's got,
like, rainfall behind him? Yeah.
Or snow or hail?
Yeah.
How does that work? Well,
the green background works
as a blank slate. Then I
just run it through the board
and presto!
A composite of the
two images is made.
Oh, oh! Can we
get sound in here?
Yeah, yeah. Sure.
In local news,
a pharmaceutical
representative again provided
the key piece of information
in a baffling police case.
But ran screaming
from the scene,
like a little girl before
he could make a statement.
That was one time, Shawn! One
time! I don't like dead bodies!
I told you that.
Now stop bringing that up!
Hello, this is
your local news.
This next office
was Jackson Hale's.
I've got to tell you guys,
everybody's been acting a little weird
since it happened.
It's just not the same.
Oh! Ruben, this is Shawn
Spencer and Burton Guster.
They're working
on Jackson Hale's case.
This is Ruben Leonard, he's a lab
meteorologist on Jackson's team.
Was.
I was just sorting and packing
some of his more important
things to send to his family.
It's the least I can do.
That's very thoughtful.
Thank you.
That reminds me of a hot,
little señorita I met there.
She was serving
fried jalapenos...
Would you excuse me?
Sure.
Thanks.
So,
if you'll notice that...
Did you work
with Jackson Hale long?
Six years. He was a great man.
I had a lot
of respect for him.
He was just so good
at what he did.
Take your umbrella
because I guarantee,
it's raining cats and dogs
out there.
A broadcasting treasure.
Anyway, take a look
at Thursday here...
Dude,
Ruben's in there
destroying Hale's awards.
What?
Yeah.
Unless he's really offended by the
shoddy engraving on the plaque,
that guy hates Jackson Hale. I'm not saying
he did it, but reasonable doubt, anyone?
Okay, Miss Panitch. Please, walk
us through the night of the crime.
Well, I never met Mr. Hale
before that night.
I just moved here
from Wisconsin.
It wasn't like
I was a fan of his.
I only vaguely knew
he was a weatherman.
So we talked,
and he was charming...
So the scratches
on Jackson Hale's back
and his skin under
your the fingernails,
this all happened
during the sex,
as well as the bruises
on your arm?
It got passionate.
I don't remember anything until
I woke up the next morning.
With his blood on you?
And then you fled
to the parking lot?
Look, I was scared.
I, I know how bad
all of this looks, I do.
But I swear
I did not murder anyone.
Do you guys believe me?
Do you?
Of course we do, Sandra.
Don't be ridiculous.
Counselor?
Yes?
Would you please retire
with me to the hallway,
where we can exchange words
in hushed tones?
Okay, what are you doing?
What?
You are supposed to be demonstrating
confidence and swagger for Hornstock.
Instead you're poking holes in our
case, and you're scaring our defendant.
Here are the facts, Shawn. All we know
about Sandra is what she's told us.
I think we need
to do some investigating.
I believe her. Hornstock believes
her. What else do we need?
We need proof, Shawn.
Look, right here in this book?
Corey v. Bulevic in 1955. The key piece
of evidence were half-melted candlesticks.
We need evidence! Where are
our candlesticks, Shawn?
Maybe you just
jumped over them?
What?
Be nimble. Be quick.
You're not going to give me
anything for that?
Now can we please...
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Check out the judge.
He's grabbing his back.
No wonder he's so grumpy.
He's not grabbing his back,
he's grabbing his kidneys.
He probably
has a kidney stone.
Dude, nice!
Thank you.
Please state to the court what
your relationship with Mr. Hale was.
It was professional. He was my
boss. I was his receptionist.
And as the Channel 8
receptionist, Miss Osterman,
if people were to call Jackson
Hale, you took those calls?
I did.
And did you receive any calls from the
defendant, Sandra Panitch, at any time?
Oh, not to my knowledge. No.
But other women would call?
Sure.
Was Jackson Hale
sleeping with these women?
Objection, Your Honor,
hearsay.
I'll allow the question.
Well, I can only say that
I fielded many calls,
and sometimes I helped
to juggle these calls.
He was a handsome man.
He certainly was.
Thank you, Miss Osterman.
You may
step down, Miss Osterman.
Thanks.
Your Honor, the state requests a
moment to prepare for our next witness.
"He certainly was"? What
happened? You were rolling!
I don't know, I don't know,
it sounded good in my head.
You have a great
support system, you know,
it gives you
that easy confidence.
But, you know, my father hasn't
been in the courtroom once.
Not one of my trials.
You've been here one day, and
your father's already here.
What are you talking about?
Oh, I met him outside.
He's a really nice guy.
Your Honor, the
defense would like to call for a recess.
Excuse me. Who are you?
I'm sorry, Your Honor.
My name is Shawn Spencer.
I'm a psychic legal consultant
on this case.
Objection, Your Honor. We were not made
aware that a psychic was hired on this case.
Approach the bench,
all of you.
Sweet.
Your Honor, the people
question his validity.
Okay, first of all,
that's hurtful.
Look, I know you're
the big bad prosecutor
with the sweet head, but is
this tone really necessary?
No. Look,
I'm a legitimate consultant.
I've been hired often by the
Santa Barbara Police Department,
and there is a high-ranking detective
in this very courtroom right now,
who will vouch
for my validity.
And who is this?
He's right there. The wispy,
yet commanding Irish fellow,
who looks like he's been
sucking on the Sour Patch Kids.
Will you stand and state
your name for the court?
Carlton Lassiter, Santa Barbara
Police Department, Your Honor.
Head detective,
11 years this May.
Perhaps you'd like to inform the
court of your favorite color as well.
The point is,
do you know this man?
I do.
And has he worked on cases
for the department?
He has.
There you have it.
And he was helpful?
Absolutely.
Did he just say absolutely
with a little half smile?
I'd like that
printed out, please.
I'm thinking of shellacking it on a nice
piece of maple, maybe a little decoupage.
Your Honor, as you can see,
I'm responsible
for breaking many cases here
in the state of California.
Well, guess what? I don't care who you
are, or what you've done for the state.
I don't believe in that psychic mumbo-jumbo
and it's not welcome in my court!
"Mumbo-jumbo"?
Oh!
You poor, poor man.
No wonder. You're...
Passing a kidney
stone can be very stressful.
Who told you that?
I never told anyone.
You tell me if I'm
overstepping my bounds here,
but I'd like to suggest an old home remedy
that did wonders for my Aunt Dolores.
She simply gargled
with some mineral water,
followed it up
with some raw greens.
Me, personally,
I'd go with asparagus tips,
that way, later on,
when you're making water,
you'll know that it's working.
Let's proceed with the trial.
Okay, you got me? I'm startled.
What are you doing here?
Well, maybe
we're both psychics.
I am serious.
Occasionally, I come down
here, I sit in on a trial.
Today, I get a phone call.
Guess who's practicing
law now?
Wait a minute. You come
down here regularly?
Thursdays, usually.
Today was just a bonus.
My God, you just
can't let go, can you?
You retired too early. Not my fault. I
didn't ask you to turn in your badge, Dad.
Shawn! Shawn! Shawn! I'm in
there trying to do something...
You seem to forget whose name you've
got at the end of your letterhead, kid.
When you use my name,
it is my business as well.
Give me my phone.
Took you long enough to
figure out the kidney stone.
Let it be noted that the witness
identified the defendant, Sandra Panitch,
as the woman he saw running through the
parking lot on the night of the murder.
Has it been authenticated?
Hey, what would Phelps need
to get authenticated?
I don't know.
His little collection
of green army men?
H-Stock, did you just
make a joke?
Hmm?
I think you did.
Your witness. Does the
defense wish to cross-examine?
Your Honor, the defense rests.
No. No, it doesn't.
Your Honor, the defense may
rest. Why am I not resting?
I have a vibe
that's very strong.
Hatred, jealousy. That guy
wanted to be a serious weatherman.
He has no sympathy
for Jackson Hale whatsoever.
Wait. What?
You think he did it?
No, I'm pretty sure he didn't.
But we can plant a seed.
Johnny Applestock.
Your Honor, the defense
does not rest.
Mr. Leonard, you are a
meteorologist, are you not?
Yes, I am indeed.
But not on the air?
No, not on the air.
Hmm. Maybe because you don't
have a meteorologist name.
I don't follow.
Well, correct me if I'm wrong,
but Leonard isn't a term
for any kind of weather?
No, it is not.
So, if I was to look up Leonard,
in say, a weather glossary,
there would be no definition?
No, there would not.
Excuse me,
where is this going?
Yes, Mr. Hornstock,
where are you going with this?
I'm sorry, Your Honor, it's just
that every successful weatherman
that I know of,
has a real weatherman's name.
Johnny Mountain, Dallas Rains?
Oh, Jackson Hale, for example.
Hey, first of all that
wasn't even his real name.
Precisely.
Have you ever considered going
by the name of Bolt Lightning?
No.
Cloudy McMillen?
Wendy Morning Dew?
That's a woman's name.
Okay, look, I have a degree
in meteorology from
the University of Virginia.
I wrote my thesis
on Bernoulli's theorem
of incompressible level flow,
and I was a junior tornado
safety captain for seven years.
Jackson Hale
has a degree in what?
Physical education
from a junior college.
He was an embarrassment.
He was worthless, all right?
He was worthless to anyone who was
a real meteorologist like myself.
He should have been stabbed
in the heart long ago!
Objection, Your Honor.
It's a little late for that,
don't you think, Counselor?
That's the kind of confidence
I'm talking about.
That's what I'm talking about.
We are on our way
to winning this thing.
Told you. She's kind
and she's innocent.
Just because we had a small
victory in court yesterday
doesn't mean
we're out of the woods.
Son of a bitch!
Alligator pumps! I swear,
I should arrest that weatherman.
He clearly stated it was
not going to rain today.
You see, that's the problem with
what I like to call "group thinking."
We don't listen
to group thinkers.
Nope.
In fact, we don't listen
to weathermen at all.
If you excuse me, I've really
got better things to do.
Dinner with your cat?
O'Hara, are you coming?
You go. I'll catch up
with you in a sec.
You know, Shawn,
for a psychic,
you are missing something right in
front of your face. It's too bad.
You might actually learn something
about Lassiter. Maybe you don't want to.
He waxes his back?
I'm gonna go now.
Shawn, I don't care what anyone
else says. The pink shirt is working.
Okay, that was cryptic.
Not really. I'll be damned.
Who's Detective Assi?
Lassy. It's Lassiter. He must have
sent some sort of memo to Phelps.
The question is
why would Lassiter
send a letter
to the D.A.'s office?
Don't you ever watch
Law and Order?
They tend to work
together sometimes.
Right. So... So, go ahead
and check the files,
and find me that letter.
Phelps received it
on the seventh.
I've been through all of them.
There are no memos submitted into
evidence, filed on the seventh.
So, it didn't get filed.
But there is a memo.
So whatever's on that memo
is clearly worth hiding.
And she told you
this directly?
Yes, when I questioned
the defendant,
she admitted to having sexual
relations with the victim.
But not to stabbing him
with a letter opener?
Well, she appeared at the time to
be confused and had memory gaps.
She claimed never to have
seen or touched the weapon.
Even though her fingerprints
were all over it. I see.
Thank you, Detective Lassiter.
Nothing further.
Your witness.
You sure about this?
Yes, I have a very strong
feeling about this letter.
First rule of trial law, never ask a
question you don't know the answer to.
Hey, have I steered
you wrong yet? Come on.
Detective Lassiter,
did you send a letter
to the D.A.'s office
on the seventh of August?
Yes, I did.
And what did it say?
I... Objection,
lack of foundation.
I'll allow it. Go ahead,
tell the jury what it said.
It questioned
the defendant's motive.
That it was
very strong, you mean?
No, it questioned whether I believed
the defendant had one at all.
The prosecution never submitted
this letter into evidence.
So, at this point, Your Honor,
the defense calls for a mistrial.
Man, this is fun!
Approach the bench.
We may have received the
letter. I... I can't be sure.
We didn't knowingly
withhold it.
My office is
wall to wall papers.
Then go to Staples and buy
yourself some new file folders,
but until then,
you are warned.
Any new evidence must be submitted
to all parties immediately.
Do I make myself clear?
Yes, Your Honor.
And in the spirit
of that ruling,
I would like to submit
a new piece of evidence.
If this is that willy-nilly piece
of evidence that you tried to get in,
in pre-trial,
I'll tell you one more time.
I will not admit any audio-visual
evidence unless it's been authenticated.
We're talking about
playing it to him.
It's a videotape.
Hmm?
We just got our authentication
papers from the lab in Sacramento.
It is a videotape of the
defendant, Sandra Panitch,
murdering the victim,
Jackson Hale.
Judge, I argue that this tape
should not be admissible.
On what grounds?
Well, we're citing
unfair surprisery.
I... I still don't understand
why he is in this room.
He's nothing but a disruption.
Maybe someday, Phelps,
when you're a judge,
which I highly doubt
will happen,
then you can decide who's
welcome in your chambers.
Your Honor, these guys are a part
of my team, and I want them here.
Why? You used to be
a good lawyer, Hornstock.
But let's face it, if you've gotta
resort to hiring this idiot psychic
and his little sidekick...
I'm nobody's sidekick, you...
Whoa! Gus, Gus.
Come on.
Forget you.
Gus, we are all grown men
here. Let's just take a beat.
Let's...
Let's take a step back.
Mr. Hornstock, having now
seen the video in question,
I don't think I need to
tell you how damaging it is.
I strongly suggest
at this point
that you consider accepting
a plea bargain for murder two.
Your Honor, I will have to review
the tape and confer with my client.
I tell you
what, Hornstock.
I will leave murder two on the
table until tomorrow morning.
Consider that
my gift to you.
She doesn't realize
she's being taped.
No, I don't think this
is his first barbeque either,
if you know what I mean.
This high-def plasma
really makes a difference.
I see the beads of sweat
on his neck.
Look at his hair!
That's horrible!
Yeah.
Oh, wow!
Do any of you
make noises like that?
His or hers?
When she sees this, she
will certainly take the deal.
I'm not going to
take the deal.
If you don't take the deal, you
could go away possibly for life.
You do realize this?
I don't care.
I'm not gonna admit
to something that I didn't do!
Okay, I believe you. I believe
you. But I watched that tape.
And as your attorney, I am
begging you, take the deal.
Don't take the deal.
What are you doing?
You're supposed to be
on my side.
Hornstock, I am on your side.
I mean, not technically, because
of the shape of this table.
Imagine a round table. I would
have sat somewhere in the middle.
Okay, tomorrow morning when
the jury watches this tape,
we will lose this case.
This tape is not telling us
the whole truth. There's more.
I need to take this tape. You just
work on your closing arguments.
You leave the rest to me.
Quit pacing, Shawn.
You're making me nervous.
I can't afford it, Dad.
I can't afford a guilty verdict
on my record right now. I can't!
You do realize that you're
not a real lawyer? Right?
You don't have a record.
It's so weird. The prosecution
keeps treating this case
like a crime of passion,
right?
But she only knew him
for a couple of hours.
I ask you, how much passion can you
muster up for someone in a couple of hours?
Yeah, well, crimes of passion are
rarely about love or sex, Shawn.
They're closer to revenge,
sometimes hatred.
I would say that
your angry meteorologist
is the best suspect
you got going.
He didn't do it.
Yeah, I know that, Shawn.
The point is you need to find
somebody who felt like that.
Oh, Dad, believe me, there are plenty.
The guy slept with half of Santa Barbara.
We put them all on the stand. The problem
is that Sandra is the only one who was there.
You have a whisk.
I do.
And you're not looking
close enough.
Well, you know what?
It's tough, when virtually everything
imaginable is stacked against me.
I've got your ass staring me
down in the courtroom.
I've got a defense attorney who
breaks every time the wind blows,
I've got to hitch rides every
time I need to go somewhere
because, get this, there's some rogue
meter maid who's decided to have
a ticketing vendetta
against me and my motorcycle.
Well, Shawn, maybe that might not
happen if you didn't park your bike
14 feet from a fire hydrant
outside your apartment.
Dad, you've seen my street.
The parking is a joke and...
How did you know that?
Whoa, whoa, whoa. How did you
know that? Wait a second. How...
How do you know that?
Oh, look who's paying
attention now?
You tipped them off? You
tipped them off about my bike?
Who taught you
how to drive, Shawn?
Who do you represent every
time you're out on that road?
I don't represent anybody
when I go out on the road!
Dad, they took my bike!
Tell it to the embassy.
And I might not be
able to get it out of the impound.
Yeah, well, then maybe it's
time for you to consider
a real mode
of transportation, huh?
You will do anything you can
to impose your will on me.
You hated that bike. You
have always hated that bike.
And you've been especially
hard ass about it since I...
Since you what, Shawn? Since you
what? Since you had your accident?
Is that is? Is that where
your old man crossed the line?
Fine, I tell you what. I will
back off, I'm gonna lay off, man.
I'll tell you what you do.
You take me off your call list the
next time the ambulance picks you up
and brings you in that door.
All right? Fair.
Get over yourself, kid.
Or at least
learn how to park.
Shawn, what are you doing?
Do you know what time it is?
What? What time...
What time is it?
It's 9:00.
We're late for court.
I called you a million times.
Gus...
What?
Would you say anger
is a good motivator?
Did you see your dad again?
Yes, I did.
And I think
it actually worked.
Mr. Hornstock?
Your Honor, the defense
has nothing more.
Not so fast.
Excuse me?
Call Priscilla Osterman
to the stand.
What are you talking about?
She already testified.
Can we recall her?
Yes, if we have
new information,
but I have nothing
else to ask her.
Oh, trust me. I'm feeling
all kinds of good stuff here.
Your Honor, the defense calls
Miss Osterman back to the stand.
Objection.
Overruled.
I'm giving you
the teeniest latitude
providing you have some
new evidence to mine here.
Miss Osterman, I remind you
that you are still under oath.
Proceed, Counselor.
Ask her if she is
absolutely certain
that she did not sleep
with Jackson Hale.
Miss Osterman, are you
absolutely certain
you did not sleep
with Jackson Hale?
Objection, Your Honor. Asked
and answered in prior testimony.
Sustained.
I'm not kidding, Counselor,
I'm giving you
one more question,
and then
I'm shutting you down.
Did you want to?
Objection! This man
is not a lawyer.
He has no right
to address the witness.
Actually, Your Honor,
he can, under the rule 775A
of the California state
rules of evidence.
The rule gives the court
wide discretion
over the mode and order
of presenting evidence,
effective for the
ascertainment of the truth.
Precedence
Killmer v. Duchscherer.
I mean, we are trying to ascertain
the truth here, aren't we?
That is absolutely
correct, young man.
Where did you attend
law school?
Just sixth grade law,
Your Honor.
But it was
an accelerated program.
Hmm.
It is up to my discretion
to allow any testimony
that may speak
to the truth of this case.
Proceed, Mr. Spencer,
with caution.
Thank you, Your Honor.
All right.
Just warming her up
for you, bro. Yeah, go.
Hi, Priscilla.
Hi.
Everybody here
is absolutely certain
you didn't sleep
with Jackson Hale.
But Jackson Hale slept
with everybody.
Except for you.
Isn't that right?
You couldn't take it,
could you?
Him walking by
every single day
without ever noticing you.
Not once!
Repeatedly choosing
to sleep with women
like the defendant,
Sandra Panitch!
Oh, that's...
That's not true.
That video will show
Jackson Hale being murdered.
But not by Sandra Panitch.
By you.
Objection, Your Honor. I mean,
this is... It's ridiculous.
I feel the tape is the proof!
The tape is the pudding!
Your Honor, I said objection!
I demand you get him
to stop that!
Sit down. Do you need
a tutorial in rule 775?
Mr. Riggs, can you please
play the tape again?
Thank you. Just take it
back a little bit.
Forward, I'm sorry, forward.
And back. Forward. Right there!
Right there.
Right here.
That. That right there. It's a
cloud. Not a cloud, a shadow.
A shadow of a human person.
You were wearing
those glasses that night,
making it unmistakable
that you were there.
That is your shadow,
Priscilla.
You watched.
You waited,
waited for them
to drop out of frame.
Then bam on the head
to Sandra. And...
Into the heart
with Jackson!
You didn't think there was
any way you could be blamed
because clouds
don't kill people.
People kill people.
And this was
a crime of passion.
But not because he loved you.
But because he didn't.
He walked by me in the hallway
every day, like I didn't exist,
like I was invisible.
And so you proved him right,
by being invisible on that tape.
We would have been
the most amazing couple,
he just refused to see it.
He just broke my heart over
and over and over again.
So, I just broke his!
By stabbing it
with a letter opener!
Yes! Yes, I killed him!
No!
Oh.
Holy crap! Did you
just hear that?
We heard that, yes.
Sorry, Your Honor.
It's just that usually
when I do this, when things
come to me psychically,
I gotta jump through
all these hoops, you know?
I gotta find
Interim Chief Vic,
I gotta run stuff
by Lassy, there.
Sign a bunch of papers,
t's, i's, the whole bit.
It seems like we got
everything we need here.
You, the jury, the
stenographer, Mr. Riggs!
I move to remove
the defendant immediately.
And take the witness
into custody for processing.
Bailiff! Case dismissed.
You mean to tell me, our whole lives,
you've never been to a single auction?
Nope. Dude, watch
this, it's very fun.
How's it fun? You're
bidding against the public
for your own motorcycle.
What if somebody outbids you?
I've been practicing my
paddle raise, it's very subtle.
Where is this thing?
Plus now that Carter Jarecki's
wife has hired us
to consult on her divorce,
we're flush.
I can go as high
as I need to go.
Okay.
Dad?
Shawn!
What are you doing here?
I came for your auction.
What? Was there a boating
incident I didn't hear about?
A little tuna boat
get impounded?
You know,
actually, Shawn, no.
I felt bad
about those tickets,
so I'm here to get
your bike for you.
Get out of here.
Hey, Shawn! Gus! What's up?
Hey, legal eagle!
I thought I might
see you here.
Oh, you know? The name
partners were very impressed,
and they're anxious
to hire you guys again.
Especially this new guy.
What's his name?
Oh, it's me!
Hey!
Congratulations.
You got the bump!
Thank you.
We'd love to work
with you again.
So, what is it now,
"Hornstock, Hornstock,
"Hornstock, Biederman
and Hornstock"?
We had to get
wider doors, but yes.
Hey, I didn't get
to thank you properly.
So, you know,
I'm here for the auction.
I'm gonna put some money down on
that bike. Get it back for you.
Guys, really. I do. I
appreciate it, it's very sweet,
but I can stand
on my own two feet
and get my own bike back.
Shawn!
Buzz.
I believe this is yours. They
just pulled it from the auction.
Pulled it from
the auction. What?
I was... I was... I've been practicing
my paddle raise. It's a subtle move.
Yeah, you got your bike back.
It was taken care of internally.
What does that mean?
"Internally"?
I don't know. They just
gave me the paperwork.
What are you looking at?
Go home!
In between the lines
there's a lot of obscurity
I'm not inclined
to resign to maturity
If it's all right
then you're all wrong
But why bounce around
to the same damn song?
You'd rather run
when you can't crawl
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
I know, you know