Hey, Shawn, what in the world
do you think you're doing?
Hide and seek.
I don't think so.
But you said we could.
Not like that.
That's how you play.
Not in my house. Shawn, you
can't tail a suspect like that.
Look how loud you are. Your perp is
gonna hear you coming from every turn.
Those things smack
every time you take a step.
Now, if you're gonna wear them
when you compete, you gotta keep...
Compete?
On the balls of
your feet. Balls of your feet.
And you take deliberate steps.
You don't know where he is.
He shouldn't get to know
where you are.
He's invisible,
you're invisible.
Now, you've leveled the
playing field. Can I go now?
No. You're going to learn
to do the little things right.
For instance,
when you peer
around a corner,
I want you to stay
down low 'cause, you see,
they're expecting you
up here at eye level.
When you walk down a hall,
check the grains of the carpet.
We just vacuumed, right?
And never, ever again do I ever
want to hear you slam a door
when you can pull it closed.
But we're just playing.
Well, play right, Shawn,
or don't play at all.
Shawn,
he's not in here.
I don't need to
tell you how vital it is
that we maintain the utmost
secrecy on this heist.
The Attorney General does not
want his son's wedding disrupted
any more than
it's already been.
How will we explain
our presence to the press?
We don't.
Just let them stew.
Well, that's one approach.
But, if I may suggest, I once wrote a paper
regarding press releases and such and...
Sorry, your idea sounds great.
Get the board.
What are you doing?
Dude, I'm onto something big.
Tailing cops?
In a police station?
Some monumentally expensive
ring just got stolen.
I'm gonna get
us on the case.
We just got a case
five minutes ago.
Yeah, a lame one. Stolen
computers from a high school.
Come on, like, you were falling
asleep during that meeting.
This is an heirloom.
It's worth $5 million,
lifted from the hotel where they're
having the wedding. Wedding's on Saturday.
There's an open bar.
Dude, we're so there. Are
we looking at the same thing?
I told you to wait in my
office. I had a premonition.
Something sparkly.
Just over five karats,
perfect clarity,
slight inclusion.
Is this ringing
any bells for you?
Solve the case I gave you.
Then we'll talk.
In the meantime, I have a
lot of work to complete.
It's the secretary.
Pardon? The secretary.
The secretary did it.
Now, what can you tell me
about the ring I'm envisioning?
But you barely even
looked at this folder.
It's in the papers.
Where?
The signatures,
it's in her handwriting.
Look, she's faking her own signature,
and later there's evidence that it's...
I feel it in the ink.
Very bad vibes.
Strong squidish vibes.
We'll check it out. Until then,
I trust you can find the door.
But what about the ring?
Not until this one is done.
Hey, let me gather some information,
all right? Make a little headway.
Then I'll have a psychic episode that
blows the ears right off their skulls.
Shawn, I'm in
meetings all day.
I barely had time to come down for this.
We're doing what the Chief says. Period.
So sorry to have
kept you waiting.
I am Shawn Spencer, chief
psychic here at the department.
Thank you so much for helping. This
whole thing has been devastating.
My hands are still shaking.
You're doing fine.
Okay, I only have a second.
I'll need you to tell me everything
I have to know about this case
as quickly as humanly
possible, okay?
What about this guy? What's
going on with the best man?
I don't know, he's not
answering his phone or his door.
This day has just
been completely unreal.
Guys, it's going to be fine.
You're in good hands.
I have never failed a case.
I know who you are.
I read about you in the paper.
You did?
You're the sister
of the groom.
And the maid of honor.
And the wedding planner?
Correct.
That is so many hats.
You should see my closet.
I am hoping to.
But not until
I find this ring.
Well, the wedding's tomorrow.
How fast are you?
That depends entirely on how
much cooperation I receive.
Why don't you come
to the wedding?
Yeah. No, no, I couldn't
possibly impose on you. No.
Please, you're
saving us here.
You find this ring,
we'd owe you everything.
What in the hell
is going on here?
I just dropped by
to say hello.
Guys, this is head detective Carlton
Lassiter and his lovely new partner, Juliet.
His last one turned out to be his
girlfriend, so she was transferred.
I'm not sure if that was the only reason.
I'll let you decide for yourselves.
Shall we?
Sure.
If this is some sort of hazing ritual, where
we're gonna end up naked in a river somewhere,
I'll need to arrange
for a ride home.
Listen to me, Spencer.
The department's reputation
is on the line with this one.
If I catch you anywhere near this case, I
will throw every book I can find at you.
What if you find the Bible?
You going to throw that, too?
Seems a little sacrilegious
to me, don't you think?
Ow.
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
Burton Guster, Central Coast
Pharmaceuticals.
Dude, I got a suspect...
I'll call you back
later, Shawn.
No, no, you can't. I left my
cell phone in your car yesterday,
along with a tuna sandwich.
I seriously hope
you found that.
Later this afternoon, Shawn.
No, no, Gus, this happens now.
The wedding is tomorrow.
Is he coming?
Not yet.
But we're getting closer.
Thanks, Stabber.
Mandatory briefing.
Magnolia room. 15 minutes.
Excuse us, please.
Attorney General Maxwell.
Detective, I trust
we're making progress.
I am right on
schedule, sir.
I've booked myself a suite
to use as a command center.
Why?
I'll stay the night if I have
to. Keep an eye on things.
The city's not paying
for that, is it?
No?
That ring has been in
my family for 200 years.
My mother agonized over the
decision to give it to my son.
I'm not letting it
get away now.
Sir, we are checking every
person who came through that door.
Every employee.
Every guest.
Nobody checks
out of this hotel
until we're just short of going
through every piece of their luggage.
Way ahead of you, sir.
No, you're not.
What?
Can I help you, sir?
I'm just
listening.
For what?
Lyme disease.
Lyme disease?
Lyme disease, rickets, avitaminosis,
Legionnaire's, bubonic. You name it.
I want you to
listen to something.
Do you hear that?
Mmm-hmm.
We have spores in the wall.
Spores? You know
where else they are?
In the planter. You know where else?
Everywhere in the entire hotel.
Who called you? Mike?
Mike? Is this
a big joke to you?
I don't answer to Mike. Have you seen
Mike lately? Mike can kiss my ass.
I was called in by
the state inspector himself.
Are you at all aware how dangerous
this is? Hell, yes, I am!
Good. I'm glad.
I need access to this whole
place, elevator shafts, air vents,
the safe room, obviously.
The safe room
is a crime scene.
This eucalyptus
will be dead by lunch.
The safe room will be a triage unit if
I don't get those spores out of there.
Understood. Can we let the
cops finish up in there first?
Tell them to hurry.
Oh, man.
Thirteen minutes after midnight,
members of the wedding party
enter the safe room, placing the
ring into a safety deposit box,
which was slid into the safe
and closed for the night.
No sensors indicate
that either the safe door
or the lock box was opened again
until the following morning.
Please note, he has activated the time
lock, which prevents the safe from opening.
No one walks into that room again
until the following morning,
when the ring is
discovered missing.
So it definitely didn't
disappear during the night?
Or so they would
like you to think.
However, if you look closely, there
are nine glitches on this tape.
I'm sorry, glitches?
Seams, static bursts
in the image.
Someone could have tapped in an alternate
video feed of this room while it was empty.
Or, more likely,
as I believe,
someone built a scale
replica of this room.
Who laughed?
Nobody?
If somebody disagrees with
my theory, I'd like to know.
It does seem
very elaborate.
And just a bit far-fetched.
Are you a detective?
Why are you here?
You asked for
all of us to come.
Oh, well, Officer, since you're
such an expert on fetching,
why don't you fetch
me a cup of coffee?
Moving on.
All the employee alibis
check out. Except this one.
Dietrich Mannheim.
Currently
the facilities manager.
You may remember him
from the security video.
He was in the room when the ring was
placed into the safety deposit box.
During questioning,
he was nervous, evasive,
and contradicted himself
more than once.
His work computer history reveals
that he recently visited websites
for boats and expensive cars, and
he failed to show up for work.
Questions?
Is this your only lead?
His responses to my interrogation
were hostile at best.
Clarify "hostile".
Use my tone now as a guide.
Detective O'Hara,
all alone?
Well, not anymore, apparently.
Work troubles?
I'm sensing work troubles.
Here, let me read your palm.
How about just one finger?
Come, now, let me see
if I can be helpful.
Why are you here?
The Maxwell wedding.
Honestly. I was invited.
By whom?
Beth. Bethany. The bride.
Little baby B.
The B sting. Love her.
God, Dylan is so
lucky to have her.
She grounds him in ways that he
needed grounding, don't you think?
She's a good sport.
Air Supply, really?
Kidding. Just kidding.
Relax.
This is work-related.
You thought this place
would be different,
but nobody respects
your opinions.
They all think
you're too young?
Always.
You know, I think you and
I could help each other.
And how would that be?
Oh, I know things.
Things about rings.
Oh. I thought you were
here for a wedding.
I am... ish.
You first.
I just got a
message for you, Mr. Guster, and,
well, I'm afraid
it's about your cat.
My cat?
The poor thing is in the animal
hospital. They think her leg is broken.
I'll get down there later.
You're not going?
I'm very busy.
But your cat needs you for moral support.
The vet said it could be the difference.
Later.
You have to go.
Mr. Guster, I know
that you're in shock.
Don't do anything you're
going to regret forever.
I don't even...
He's not going?
Oh.
So, now I have a cat?
An orange tabby. Last Christmas, you made
her a tiny Santa hat. It was adorable.
Fantastic. I can't even
have a make-believe boy cat.
Gus, a boy cat wouldn't serve
my purposes nearly as well.
The next time I need you,
Pickles is having kittens.
Pickles?
Mrs. Pickles is her full name.
Though, I'm not actually sure
cats can marry outside of Boston.
Yeah, well,
in a related issue,
I'm blocking your number on
all the phones in the office.
If you think that will work,
I think it's endearing.
In the meantime, aren't you
the least bit curious
about who was there when they
put the ring in the hotel safe?
Wait a minute.
This is a safecracking case?
Did I forget to mention that?
What kind of safe?
The Hydra 700.
The 700 is out?
That's impossible,
nobody could crack that.
I haven't even told you about
the wall sensors.
Can we be done by 3:00?
Yes.
The safe room,
right behind that door.
What is all this? I thought
this was a safe job.
Oh, Lassiter has this insane idea
that this in an elaborate heist, right?
Like on par with Ocean's
Eleven, or Thomas Crown,
or... Oh, the one where
they kill Donald Sutherland
in the first ten minutes,
remake...
Mr. Spencer, Mr. Guster,
what a surprise.
Chief. Looking good.
You're probably wondering...
I sent an officer down to the high school
to take a look at your secretary suspect.
She cracked. He didn't even
get the first question out.
Really?
'Cause I envisioned
that being harder.
Yet I don't recall asking you to
come down here to the De La Cruz.
Well, we have
reason to believe
this case goes in a
completely different direction.
Huh.
Let me be perfectly clear.
I didn't see you
and we didn't talk.
Call me if you have something.
I love her.
Yeah.
He knows you?
I had to lay some groundwork. He doesn't
believe in psychics. This is plan B.
Chief Inspector Shawn,
how are you?
I'm undercover.
Not even the American
police know I'm in on this.
I'm sorry.
I blew it again, didn't I?
And after you brought
me into your confidence.
Bobby, it's fine.
Believe me.
These other Interpol guys are very
appreciative of what you're doing here.
How long will you need?
Just as discussed,
five minutes, tops.
You're my man.
Interpol?
That's right.
Missing Ring Division.
I believe I was recruited out
of North Africa when I was 15.
You could at least
use a British accent.
Oh, please,
Gus, I started with a British accent,
and then seamlessly slipped
into my fake American one.
Bobby gave me
some pointers.
Apparently you Americans
say "howdy" a lot.
Howdy.
What are you doing?
List. List. I made a list of suspects
after attending Lassiter's briefing.
He let you in his briefing?
He does when
you're in the airshaft.
All your suspects are
in the wedding party?
Look, the only ones who knew
they put that ring in the safe
were at the rehearsal dinner.
So, it was an inside job?
Looking like it.
You're making keys?
Gus, how else do you expect
me to get in the rooms?
Shawn, you can't do that.
Of course I can, I
worked at the Hampton Inn
for that three-day weekend
in Austin when we were 19.
I know you remember that.
Gus, this is so easy.
Try making a key.
Dude, I rule.
Nope. Innocent.
Let's move.
What are you talking about? We
haven't even stepped foot in there.
Gus, do you need
the remedial course, really?
Uncle Leo left
his wallet on the table.
Criminals are sneaky,
jaded, suspicious people.
They're smart
and defensive.
This guy has a reason
to be trusting.
Can we go now?
Shawn?
Guys, hey,
your door was open.
Oh, it was?
Yes, and I was worried that something
horrible had happened. You're okay?
Yeah, yeah.
I told you we didn't have to
come in here. They're fine.
Everybody's fine.
This is my associate, Gus.
Just call him Peter Panic.
How are you doing?
So, you're a psychic, too?
Well... Gus here
is a safe expert.
Yes, he subscribes to
The Safecracker,
a safecracking comic book.
It's an online magazine.
And it's a trade publication.
Excuse me for saying so, but how exactly
do you figure into this legal family?
I started my
criminal law degree.
Then I came to my senses, went to
Europe, painted, slept, ate, sank a boat.
Disappointed?
Besotted.
We'd like to speak to the
best man, if possible.
So would we.
Any ideas where he is?
We haven't seen him since
the night of the sixth.
Which is the night
the ring disappeared.
The florist quit.
So, after we dropped
the ring off at the safe,
we had to wrap bouquets
all night in our suite.
Everybody except Jack.
Do you think he's a suspect?
No, we just
think he's lazy.
Hey, Dad,
this is Shawn Spencer.
He's the psychic
I told you about.
I know. Let's talk.
Son, I'm very comfortable with the
current direction of the investigation.
So, let's let the real police
department do their job.
Sir, believe me,
I am only here to help.
In fact, I was actually
hoping to discuss...
I'm glad you understand.
The guy shook my hand like
I stole something.
You see? That's why I
can't do this job alone.
Wow. That is about
as orange as you can get.
Which suspect's room
is this? Lassiter's.
The head detective?
He has his own room?
Perhaps paid
for by the city.
No. No. This is going too
far. We're not staying.
Gus, we need these
witness statements.
It's not exactly like we're being
overwhelmed with cooperation here.
Oh, Lacey.
Lacey, you can
sink my boat.
Toss me the remote.
It's the bottom of the
eighth inning and so far it's been...
What do you got?
You got anything good?
I hate to say it,
but yeah.
The Attorney General has an
insurance policy on the ring.
He'll collect a cool $3 million on
it as long as it still belongs to him,
which it does only until
these two are married.
Well, well, well.
I'm supposed to knock.
Forgive me, Detective.
Detective?
Head Detective. Sorry.
I was told you wouldn't
be here until 6:00 tonight.
That's right. 6:00
tonight. Head Detective.
I changed my plan.
Please don't tell anyone.
Absolutely, sir.
Thanks. 6:00, huh?
Is there anything I can
do for you while I'm here?
As a matter of fact,
yes, there is.
We'd like a room service
menu delivered immediately.
In Lassiter's photo, there didn't
appear to be a mark on that safe.
I don't care
how good you are,
you don't crack a Hydra without
leaving some sort of visible residue.
We need to see that safe.
That's going to be
a little difficult.
How close you
need to be?
Is there a secret back door
through the kitchen?
No, we're gonna
take the air vents.
Unfortunately, both my access points
are blocked by Santa Barbara's finest.
You think I'm
going in there?
You know you want to.
Not in this suit.
Gus, do you wanna see
the safe or not?
Look, this will be easy. We take
this dumbwaiter up to the grate,
pop the screen, crawl
right through the shafts.
Three rights and a left. We check
our progress through the vents.
Isn't it kind of weird how the
body's just shoved in here?
No, what's weird is there's
a dead guy in a dumbwaiter
and we're standing here staring at it,
waiting for somebody to find us. Let's go!
This is Lassiter's suspect.
Shawn, close the hatch
and keep your voice down.
I don't want to explain
how we got here.
I just need to
see one thing.
You answered it. Hello?
Three days, Shawn.
Dad, hey, gonna
have to call you back.
No, no. You were supposed
to call me yesterday.
You were supposed to call me the day
before. We need to handle this now.
Dad, I'm a little
busy right now.
Shawn, just tell me when you are going to
come by and pick up the box of trophies?
Really tough to be sure.
Last week you were all gung-ho
about getting this stuff back.
I went upstairs,
I brought it down for you,
it's sitting in the
middle of my kitchen table.
I need my kitchen table,
Shawn.
You're right. Can I
please call you back, Dad?
How about you just
give me an answer?
Tonight.
No. Tomorrow.
Tomorrow, wonderful.
Otherwise, I am putting it outside,
and that's where it's sitting.
Now how hard was that?
So easy. Anything else?
No, unless, of course,
you need something.
Nope. I'm good. Well, actually,
wait, I do have one question.
Go ahead.
How long does it take before a
dead body starts to smell bad?
Oh, God.
Did you wipe
our fingerprints off?
Of course I did.
We were never there.
We need to call
the Chief soon.
If Dietrich was a part
of this, he's not anymore.
Why is it the Attorney
General has to call me
wondering why some civilian is wandering
around grilling his entire family?
Wait a second. The Attorney
General has your number?
What are you guys, tight?
Give it up.
What's the story?
He also told me to keep you out
of here by any means necessary,
which opens up an entire world of
exciting possibilities for me, personally.
Ow!
Gosh!
Oh, it's too much!
It's too much!
You're not going
to shoot him, are you?
I haven't decided.
Oh, my ear.
Gus, my ear.
Oh, for the love of Mike, you are not
gonna escape. Would you just give it up?
Give it up!
Check the dumbwaiter. Open the
dumbwaiter. Detective O'Hara!
Oh, my God!
Lassiter. Lassiter.
Lassy... Get over here!
Let's go. Get him
in the van.
Come on.
You two, out.
No. Don't we get to wait
around for the autopsy?
No, we'll call you
if we need you.
Detective.
Sir? Shut this
down. Keep it quiet.
Nobody in the wedding party is to know
about this. They've been through enough.
Yes, sir.
So, this is it.
Well, that ought to keep
them busy for a while.
Can we at least watch the tape in
another room besides Lassiter's?
Gus, he's not coming back.
Are you sure about that?
Yes, didn't you
check his messages?
Are you gonna have
some cookies? No.
Do you wanna finish
my banana?
I want to leave.
Look at the best man.
He's smashed.
And look at his hair.
It's horrible.
That's it?
We have to watch it again.
It's open.
It's open?
What are you doing?
Oh, what am I early?
Big Dyl,
you're right on time.
Did I forget to mention that
we're hosting the bachelor party?
No, thank you.
He says, "Uh-oh. I thought you said
you wanted it inside the piñata."
Eat. Eat like men.
You're really mad?
We have less than 12
hours to solve the case,
and you're throwing a kegger
in a police officer's room.
Why would I be mad?
Gus, his best man was a total
washout, he wasn't gonna plan anything.
We have to dig information out of
suspects, and you're wasting time.
Dylan!
Dude. You, wow!
Yes, wow!
Gus here has some questions for
you, you flaxen-haired Argonaut.
Anything for you two.
I love you guys.
I've found that they're
particularly forthcoming
with information
while in this state.
For example, I've eliminated
every suspect here.
Although there is
a guy stealing cable
and another refilling his
minibar bottles with shampoo,
but I don't think those are
gateway crimes to a jewelry heist.
Seriously. Gus, come on,
give me a kiss.
No, no, nothing weird,
on my cheek.
Get me out of here. I think
it's your turn to dig.
Do you know
who stole the ring?
No.
And to be honest,
I don't care.
I didn't even want
the damn thing.
Okay. The night that we
announced our engagement, no,
my Dad stops dinner right
in the middle of my speech.
So, he goes and gets
my grandmother's ring.
What am I supposed
to say? No?
So, now it's not about us,
it's about him again.
I mean, forget that
I just chose the person
that I wanna spend
the rest of my life with.
I don't wanna seem ungrateful,
but if it were up to me,
I'd sooner just stop looking.
Cross him off.
Dylan, how is Dad?
I mean, financially,
would you say everything is...
Okay.
So much for that.
Dylan was the only shot we had
in this room, but that's okay.
We have other suspects
in this hotel.
At least take a traveler.
Sweet nectar.
Yeah. All right.
Crazy running into you guys
here. What are the odds?
You got anything? These
girls are not criminals.
It was worth a shot.
You wanna get out of here?
Yes, I do.
So, how are you
holding up? I'm good.
My dad brought in all this
extra security for some reason.
Can he afford that?
What do you mean?
I don't know, it's just... It was a tough
year financially for a lot of people...
What are you
getting at?
I'm just making
random conversation.
Here's my bouquet.
Oh, it's fantastic.
Well, it's sub-par. I was
rushed. All that craziness.
I wish I could fix it.
Well, let's just take it out.
It's locked.
They lock up flowers?
I bet you could open it.
You have good hands.
Shawn!
Excuse me.
You left me there!
Yes, I did. And
you're very welcome.
I just got a lap dance
from Patrick Swayze!
What do you mean?
Like an impersonator?
No, I think it was
actually Patrick Swayze.
I'm going home.
We're done. All we've done is eliminate
suspects. We're back where we started.
Oh, Gus, we're fine.
We've got the whole wedding
ceremony tomorrow to solve the case.
Oh, oh, okay. So, we can do what an
entire police force can't in two hours?
Hmm.
Okay, you're right.
We should totally get
there half an hour early.
You are the most beautiful
bride in this room.
Oh, thank you.
Does anyone need help?
The bouquets
still aren't here.
We might as well
not even have the ceremony.
Okay, you, relax. Breathe.
Think happy thoughts
like puffy clouds,
mac and cheese,
Lou Diamond Phillips.
Look, it worked.
What are you doing?
Helping.
No, those bouquets
are very specific.
They look
identical, ma'am.
It's my wedding, shouldn't
I be the one freaking out?
Oh, there'll be plenty
of time for that later.
Where is it? Where?
Where's my bouquet?
She's really a very nice person
under normal circumstances.
Lace? Everything okay
up here? You all right?
Yeah. Sorry. I think I'm having
sympathy Bridezilla. I'm good now.
Great.
Emma doesn't wanna wear
the flower in her hair.
But these are
magic flowers.
Do you want one now?
I don't know what to tell you,
sir, but these are the charges.
$1,600 for a
junior suite?
With a queen bed?
Well, the room was
a small portion.
However, it's all your room
charges that drove up your bill.
I was hardly
even in the room!
I'm sorry, Detective Lassiter,
but that's what it says here.
This isn't
Detective Lassiter.
I beg your pardon?
Oh, he's a shorter guy.
Brown hair.
Suede jacket. Helped him fill the
Jacuzzi with champagne last night.
Really? If I brought this man
here, could you identify him?
Oh, absolutely. In fact, I
can tell you where he is.
He's over at
the Maxwell wedding.
The chapel is just
outside the east lawn.
I'll be right back.
"I, Dylan, take you Bethany."
I, Dylan, take you Bethany.
"To be my wife."
To be my wife.
"Confidant
of my heart."
Confidant
of my heart.
"That you will
be a faithful friend."
That you will be
a faithful friend.
"And a true and
loving companion."
And a true and
loving companion.
"I give to you my
sacred vow."
Excuse me.
I give to you
my sacred vow.
I think we should wait
until the ceremony's over.
Fine.
Nice suit. Where'd
you get that from?
Gus, don't underestimate
me, or my wardrobe.
You might want to
remove...
Don't pull that off!
Don't, don't, don't, don't.
Just slide it...
They're here for you. Not
if I solve this case first.
Good plan. You got
about five minutes.
I already know
who did it.
No, you don't.
How is that possible?
Between all that, when
you said your girlfriend
just had an aneurysm because
she got the wrong bouquet,
you had time to put all that out
of your mind and solve the case?
Gus.
What?
And now for
a moment of silence.
Gus, I seriously
do have a guess.
Probability of
being right?
I don't know,
high sixties.
Close your mouth. But
the person's in the room.
The thief
could potentially escape.
Shouldn't I stop
the wedding? No.
Under no circumstances are you
allowed to stop this wedding.
If there's any reason why
these two should not be wed,
speak now or forever
hold your peace.
I have something.
It's not necessarily marriage-related.
I hope that's not a problem.
Sir, please.
I know who
stole the ring.
You cannot do this, Shawn. This
wedding has taken over a year to plan.
What are you doing?
Radioing the Chief.
I can see it.
Chief Vick?
I can feel it.
I can now feel the ring.
It's in this room. It's in
the room. It's in this room.
They wouldn't bring a stolen
ring to the ceremony, you moron.
They would if they couldn't
get to it till today.
Lacey, I'm so sorry.
And believe me when I say, I really,
really, really wish it wasn't you.
Me?
Are you crazy?
I'm the one who's
done all the work.
Yes, you are.
And we're all very impressed, but it
was also an excellent cover, wasn't it?
You are crazy, Shawn.
And, by the way, we're
officially off for next Friday.
Oh, boy! I can see it now.
You're at the dinner table.
They're announcing
the engagement.
You're thrilled, of course. You and
Bethany have been best friends forever.
Dad... Dad has a surprise for
the happy couple. What could it be?
Wait a minute.
You didn't know the ring
was going to Dylan.
You were always your
grandmother's favorite
and you're the oldest girl.
That ring should be yours, right?
Right.
You were counting
on that ring.
It was your future.
Oh!
Sorry.
I can see you plotting.
I can see you plotting right
there at the dinner table.
But Dad...
Dad throws a curve ball.
No, it was a slider.
He's overly cautious because
sometimes engagements end.
Not you guys. It's okay.
They're not letting go of
the ring until the wedding,
which means you have a very small
window within which to grab it.
Does all this have anything to do with
why these two shouldn't be married?
No, sir. No.
It doesn't at all, actually.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Oh, boy! Oh, boy!
Oh, boy!
Of course, you insisted it be
used during the rehearsal
so then you had your chance.
While everyone else was fawning over
the ring, you made one final adjustment.
It looked like you just straightened
it out and put it right back,
but you never did, did you?
No, Lacey,
because you have magic hands,
which I was really looking
forward to on Friday.
Everyone was fooled.
Everyone was fooled,
except Dietrich Mannheim,
who hadn't yet discovered how to
use this information to his benefit.
This is first-rate
fiction, Shawn.
Unfortunately,
there's no evidence.
There would have been no evidence if
you could have gotten away that night.
But there was a problem.
Yes, you were called away.
The florist.
The florist bailed on you.
The bouquets.
You got a last minute
batch of materials,
and the bouquets would now
have to be crafted by hand.
There was no other
time but now.
You looked for a way out,
but there was none.
You had a $5 million ring that was
about to be discovered missing any minute,
hidden in your palm,
and you were gonna have to pull an
all-nighter in a room with eight other people.
You thought you could get back
into the cooler later and grab it,
but they kept
their flowers locked up.
So, you had to have your
specific bouquet, or else.
Lacey, you're not
an unreasonable person.
You're just a thief.
Or at least you were a thief,
until Dietrich Mannheim called and
told you that he was on to you.
He wanted a piece of that action,
too. Or he was going to the police.
You tried to talk him down,
but he got rough.
It got ugly.
It was all spinning
out of control.
Eventually, they were going to find
that body, so you started laying out clues.
You sent the police off
in all directions
because you'd grown up hearing
all about crime scenes.
I would say that's fortuitous, because
you knew just what to leave, didn't you?
I have worked 18 hours
a day on this wedding.
I have sacrificed
my weekends.
I will not be
treated this way.
Then show us
your bouquet, Lacey.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. She's
running? In those heels, really?
We have to chase her, too?
But we have no evidence
except for that ring!
Dude, you're next.
Come on. You're still angry,
even after I solved your crime?
Is this the man?
No.
This guy was
not in my room?
I've never seen him before.
You got a room?
Why?
We should have a party.
Get out of my sight.
Thank you, Bobby.
Interpol appreciates
both of your efforts.
I love weddings.
Don't you?
I didn't exactly think it was
appropriate for you to give the toast.
Well, the best man was unprepared.
Someone had to step in.
Besides, it was like a
practice run for your wedding.
You are not gonna
be my best man.
You bet your ass I am.
I've already picked out which
song I'm singing at the altar.
Really?
You still like
Ted Nugent?
Remind me to show you
your vows.
They're going to
make you cry.
Gus.
In between the lines
there's a lot of obscurity
I'm not inclined
to resign to maturity
If it's all right
then you're all wrong
But why bounce around
to the same damn song?
You'd rather run
when you can't crawl
I know, you know
That I'm not telling the truth
They just don't have any proof
Embrace the deception
Learn how to bend
Your worst inhibitions tend
to psych you out in the end
I know, you know