No, no, no, not in my room.
In here, in here!
Jerry, back from Paris?
- Ben, what a nightmare!
Right there! No, right there.
What is with you guys?
I've got a sandwich in there,
I want all those bags open.
We're looking till we find it...
Hey, Audrey, Uncle Jerry's back.
Sylvia...
- Benjamin!
OK, OK... Gone! Goodbye!
Brother Ben, this is the best
damn sandwich I ever ate.
It's a baguette with brie and butter.
I had four of these every day I was there.
You've got to try this thing.
Here, go ahead, eat it. Go ahead.
Go ahead!
Oh, yeah.
This is incredible, Jer!
You know what this reminds us of?
You know who likes this?
It reminds us of Ginny and Jenny
down by the river.
My God, you're right!
- Am I right? Am I right?
Oh, no wonder!
Jer, outside, outside.
Always a pleasure.
Jerry...
Leland's daughter was murdered,
and the Norwegians left.
Did they sign?
- Deal's off.
We had those Vikings by the horns!
What happened?
We're not a hundred percent sure,
they took their translator with them.
Did you say Leland's daughter
was murdered?
Yes.
I'm depressed.
I can fix that.
There's a new girl
at One-Eyed Jacks,
freshly scented
from the perfume counter.
And you, brother Jer, have
a 50-50 chance of being first in line.
I like those odds.
All work and no play
make Ben and Jerry dull boys.
That's right.
- Let's jump in the boat.
That's great huckleberry pie,
Mrs Hayward.
Thank you, James.
Well... Mrs Hayward and I are going
to say good night, James.
Good night, James.
- Good night.
Good night, dear.
- Good night, Mom.
Don't worry about the dishes,
I'll clean up.
Are you coming to church with us
in the morning, Donna?
Yes.
Nine o'clock sharp.
- OK.
Good night, James.
- Good night, sir.
Hi, sailor!
Good evening, Mr Horne.
Ben, we're not gonna go
in the casino first?
Jer, I didn't come here to lose my shirt,
I just came to take it off.
Kim, the Horne brothers are here.
- I'll tell Blackie.
I'd like to order two drinks.
One double scotch on the rocks.
And my brother would like
a double scotch on the rocks.
That's two double scotch on the rocks.
Next stop, rocket science.
Jerry...
Blackie!
- Benjamin.
"Shall I compare thee
to a summer's day?
"Thou art more lovely
and more temperate
"Rough winds do shake
the darling buds of May
"And every fair from fair
sometimes declines
"By chance or nature's
changing course untrimm'd
"But thy eternal summer
shall not fade
"Nor lose possession
of that fair thouowest
"Nor shall death brag..."
- Where's the new girl?
When you really want love,
you'll find it waiting for you.
Heads.
Come on. We'll take care of you, Jerry.
Well...
Donna, I don't think that
what we're feeling or doing is wrong.
Why not?
Because it's the truth.
Because I think it would have
turned out this way anyway.
You do?
Yes. I remember
a time in school, in the hall.
We were suddenly alone,
and we looked at each other.
I almost told you I loved you then.
It's true.
It is true, isn't it?
Oh, James. I guess because of Laura
I couldn't say anything.
I couldn't even let myself think it.
- Me, too.
Are we gonna be together, James?
Are we?
Are we, James?
Special Agent Dale Cooper.
- Hello, it's Hawk.
Deputy Hawk,
how is Ronnette Pulaski?
Body and spirit are still far apart.
- What did you find out?
Ronnette recently quit at the
perfume counter of Horne's store.
Everything else is quiet,
except there was...
a one-armed man snooping
around intensive care.
A one-armed man?
- Left.
Did you question him?
- No. I pursued, but he got away.
Maintain an around-the-clock watch on
Ronnette. We'll speak in the morning.
Got it?
Supposed to leave it
in this stupid football.
Is it in there?
Not all of it.
Cash on delivery, Bobby.
He's got a gun.
Hey, Leo.
- Hey.
Who's that?
Is someone with you?
- Never mind.
Toss it over here, quarterback.
It's empty.
Weren't you supposed to
leave something for me?
This barely covers what we paid for.
Where's the rest?
Where's the rest of the money?
- There's a...
There's a problem.
- Problem?
Laura had the other half.
- You think you got problems?
We can get it.
Wait until everything settles down.
You punks owe me ten grand.
Leo needs a new pair of shoes.
OK. We won't take delivery
on the drugs until you get the cash.
Do I look like a bank?
- I appreciate your position.
This thing with Laura,
how could I anticipate it?
Laura was a wild girl.
Tell me about it.
Maybe. Someday.
Take your hand
out of your pocket, Mike.
What is your problem, Leo?
- Problem?
You want to know about problems?
OK.
You're on the road,
driving back and forth, gone for days.
You get back, and guess what?
- What?
You find out your old lady's
been giving it away.
Yeah?
- Yeah.
Stepping out in your own
damn bedroom. That's a problem.
I guess so. I guess it is.
Do you know who?
- A man needs a clean house.
Sure. So do you know who?
I'll take care of it.
- Sure.
And this other thing,
we'll take care of it, don't worry.
We'll get the cash,
and everything will be square.
Go out for a pass.
- What?
- OK, just...
Run.
- Take it easy.
Run! Run!
Damn it, I'm done, Bobby.
Let's get the hell out of here.
Ed!
- Sorry, I didn't see it.
You stepped on my drape runner!
It was in the middle of the floor.
- Think that's an accident?
I laid those out there myself. I was up
all night working on that invention.
I'm going to have world's first
100% quiet runner.
I'm real sorry, Nadine.
- Ed, you make me sick!
I'm going to have world's first
100% quiet runner.
That's it! Exactly sixty feet, six inches.
It's perfect.
What do you think he's up to?
It beats me.
Invitation to love.
Each day brings a new beginning,
and every hour holds the promise
of an invitation to love.
Right.
Who is it?
- The big, bad bobcat.
Are you crazy?
What are you doing here?
I just passed Leo out in North Bend.
We've got at least twenty minutes.
- Where's your car?
Parked in the woods. Open Sesame!
Somebody might see me out here,
and that'd be worse.
Bobby, you cannot
come by here like this.
We can't meet, for a while.
What the hell happened to you?
Leo Johnson happened to me.
That bastard. Come here.
Bobby! If he finds out about us,
he's gonna kill you.
He'll kill us both.
If he ever does this to you again,
I'll kill him.
I mean it.
Cup of coffee.
It's not the first time,
it won't be the last,
but I'm in that doghouse again.
What happened this time?
I popped a grease gun, stepped on a
drape runner, and all hell broke loose.
I ran into Nadine in the hardware store.
All she talked about is the drape runners.
She's got one big bee in her bonnet.
Bobby sure gave me a good one?
Where do you want these rocks?
- There by the doughnuts, Deputy.
Anyone for a warm-up?
- Oh, yeah!
You bet!
- Thanks, Lucy.
Damn good coffee!
And hot!
Would everyone please take a seat?
By way of explaining
what we're about to do,
I am first gonna tell you a little bit
about the country called...
Tibet.
An extremely spiritual country,
the leader of Tibet is known
as the Dalai Lama.
In 1950,
communist China invaded Tibet.
While leaving the Dalai Lama
in charge,
they seized control of the country.
In 1959, after a Tibetan uprising
against the Chinese,
the Dalai Lama fled to India
and has lived in exile ever since.
Following a dream three years ago,
I have become moved
by the plight of the Tibetans
and filled with a desire to help them.
I also awoke from the same dream
realising I had subconsciously gained
knowledge of a deductive technique
involving mind-body coordination
operating hand in hand
with the deepest level of intuition.
Sheriff, Deputy Hawk, if you will please
assist me, I will now demonstrate.
On the day of her death
Laura Palmer wrote
the following in her diary,
"Nervous about meeting 'J' tonight."
Today we'll concentrate on the 'J's".
Harry, when I give the word,
would you read aloud each name
I've written on the blackboard?
Deputy Hawk, stand here and hold this
bucket of rocks where I can get to them.
Would you please put on
the kitchen mittens.
Deputy Andy, move down,
stand by the bottle.
Lucy, take this piece of chalk.
Not too near, Andy!
I'm getting excited.
If I hit the bottle after a particular name,
make a check on the name.
Sheriff, when you say the name, state
that person's relationship to Laura Palmer.
Ready?
- Ready.
James Hurley... secret boyfriend.
James Hurley.
Josie Packard... was instructed
in English by Laura.
Josie Packard.
So there's no check
next to either of these names?
That's correct. Please continue.
Dr Lawrence Jacoby...
Laura's psychiatrist.
Dr Lawrence Jacoby.
You did it! You hit it!
Lucy, make a note that the bottle
was struck, but did not break.
Very important.
Andy, put that bottle back
exactly where it was!
Johnny Horne. Laura was
his special education tutor.
Johnny Horne.
Norma Jennings... helped Laura with
the meals-on-wheels programme.
Norma Jennings.
Shelly Johnson...
waitress at diner, friend.
Shelly Johnson.
Sorry, Andy.
- Sweetie?
It didn't hurt.
It didn't hurt a bit.
Where there's no sense,
there's no feeling, Andy.
Coop...
Tell me...
The idea for all this
really came from a dream?
Yes. It did.
Jack with One Eye...
Maybe it's the letter 'i',
but there's no 'i' in Jack.
I think it means he only had one eye.
Sounds like Nadine,
Big Ed Hurley's wife.
No, there's a casino up north
called One-Eyed Jacks,
across the border in Canada.
We're gonna have to check that place out.
I'm going to erase this,
because it's a place, not a person.
Maybe the person
could be in the place.
So should I erase it?
- Yes.
Yes, a person could be in a place,
or yes, I should erase it?
Erase it, Lucy. Next name, Harry.
Leo Johnson...
husband of Shelly, drives a truck,
connection with Laura... unknown.
Leo Johnson.
Little Audrey Horne just walked in.
Yeah, I saw her at church.
Wonder what she's doing down here.
Hi, Audrey.
- Hi, Norma. A cup of coffee, please.
Remind me to get those 60 watt bulbs.
Thanks.
I'm gonna go say hi.
Hi.
Hi, Donna.
So my parents said they saw you
at church today. I didn't see you.
I came by because of Laura.
What do you mean?
I didn't think you liked her.
There were things about Laura
I didn't like,
but she did take care
of my brother Johnny.
I loved her for that.
Do you like coffee?
Yeah, with cream and sugar.
Agent Cooper loves coffee.
Audrey!
But Agent Cooper
likes his coffee black.
Can I ask you something?
- Sure.
Did Laura ever talk about my father?
What do you mean?
Nothing.
No, what do you mean?
He used to sing to her.
I love this music.
Isn't it too dreamy?
Hawk found this half a mile
down the tracks from the crime site.
It's a nasty piece of work.
Tell Agent Cooper
that Albert and his team are here.
Albert?
- A-l-b-e-r-t.
Do we have to stand here all day?
- No.
Albert Rosenfield.
R-o-s-e-n-f-i-e-l-d.
Sheriff, this is Lucy.
Is Agent Cooper with you?
- Yes, he is.
Are Albert and his team here, Lucy?
Yes, he is... they are.
- We're on our way.
Agent Cooper will be right with you.
- I can hear perfectly well, Curly.
Albert and his team are cream
of the crop. Albert's a forensics genius.
I wouldn't expect anything less.
But I got to warn you, Albert's lacking
in some of the social niceties.
Nobody's perfect.
- Isn't that the truth?
What kind of a two-bit operation
are they running here?
Albert, this is Sheriff Truman.
I've seen some slipshod backwater
burgs, but this place takes the cake.
What are you waiting for? Christmas?
They're putting this girl in ground tomorrow,
and we've wasted half the day getting here.
I suggest you and your team
should get started.
I'll have one of my men
escort you over to the morgue.
Results from the local
pathologist's report.
Welcome to Amateur Hour.
Looks like an all-nighter, boys.
Albert, got a minute?
I hear that you're real good
at what you do.
That's correct.
- That's good.
'Cause normally if a stranger walked
into my station talking this crap,
he'd be looking for his teeth
two blocks up on Queer Street.
Good night, Ed!
Ed, is that you?
- Yeah, honey, it's me.
Ed!
- Oh, my God.
Oh, Ed, I'm so happy, sweetheart,
I have to thank you.
Why's that?
You don't know
what you've done for me.
No, I don't.
- Oh, Ed, you big lug!
When you tracked that grease
into the house today,
you spilled some on my cotton balls.
But instead of tossing them out,
I put the greased ones on the runners.
And Ed...just listen to this.
Completely silent.
How about that?
- Oh, Ed...
We're gonna be so rich!
Everything smells like fish
around here.
Well, you could wash
your socks separately.
What did that FBI man want
up here today?
Very nice fellow.
Asked a few questions.
About what?
Well, he talked to Josie mostly.
I had a problem with a fish.
Took a liking to my percolator.
What did he want
to talk to Josie about?
Why don't you ask her?
Here's the key, the ledger's inside.
Thank you.
- You betcha.
Didn't he ask for me?
Yeah, but we said
you were on a world tour
he should contact your press agent.
Get your boots off my bed
and go to your room!
I didn't want to get mink oil
on my bedspread.
You got mink oil in your head.
Two books.
Leland...
Leland, stop it!
- We have to dance, Sarah.
We have to dance for Laura.
Leland, stop it! Give it to me.
- We have to dance!
Leland! Leland, give it to me!
What is going on?
Leland! What is going on
in this house?
Oh, God!
Laura, Laura!
Laura!
"Through the darkness of future past,
"the magician longs to see,
"one chance out
between two worlds...
"fire, walk with me."
We lived among the people.
I think you say, convenience store.
We lived above it.
I mean it like it is,
like it sounds.
l, too, have been touched
by the devilish one.
Tattoo on the left shoulder.
Oh, but when I saw the face of God,
I was changed.
I took the entire arm off.
My name is Mike. His name is Bob.
Mike?
Mike, can you hear me?
"Catch you with my Death Bag."
You may think I've gone insane.
But I promise...
I will kill again!
But it... it is Laura Palmer.
Are you Laura Palmer?
Harry, it's Cooper.
Meet me for breakfast,
7:00 am the hotel lobby.
I know who killed Laura Palmer.
No, it can wait till morning.