Diane, it is 4:28 am.
I've just been woken up by a God-awful
racket which you can probably hear.
Can you hear that?
Up until now, I've had only pleasant,
courteous service at this hotel.
It proves that once a traveller
leaves home,
he loses almost 100% of his ability
to control his environment.
Send two pairs of those silicon earplugs
I used on my trip to New York.
I didn't bring them because
I felt it was unnecessary.
However...
Coffee?
- Please.
What's with the choir practice?
- Business junket. From Iceland.
Got in about 3:00 this morning.
They're on my floor.
- Lucky you.
It'll take them a day to reset
their biological clocks.
Hope the herring holds out.
How are you?
Audrey, to be perfectly honest,
I'm tired and a little on edge.
I got a job.
- Good for you.
Now I can help you with your case.
Guess where I'm gonna...
You'll have to excuse me.
I'm late, I only have time for coffee.
Maybe I could go with you.
Wednesdays were usually a school day
when I was your age.
I can't believe
you were ever my age.
I've got the pictures to prove it.
How old are you?
- 18.
We'll see you later, Audrey.
See you later.
Bye.
See you later, sons of Odin.
How do you say that?
My brother'll love you guys.
Brother Ben, I bring you greetings
from the treeless tundra of Iceland.
We have had complaints
from nearly every guest in the hotel.
What are they on?
They are insane
for the Ghostwood Estates project.
I have had serious fun
with these Nordic animals.
And, Ben, I'm in love.
Her name is Heba.
She's a giant snow queen with a smile
like a sunrise on an ice floe.
You'd go blind looking at this girl.
Look!
See what she gave me?
A leg of lamb.
Is that beautiful?
- Jerry!
Some garlic, some fresh mint.
That's rotisserie heaven.
You gotta meet her.
- Just grab some downtime, will you?
We've laid in a gala reception
for your fair-haired boys tonight.
Twin Peaks' best and brightest.
- Holding it in a phone booth?
And if we still need a kicker to nail
the sale, I'm thinking maybe...
they might enjoy
a little road trip up to...
you know where.
Jacks! I am honoured to know you.
Ben?
Leland, why are you here?
I know there's a new investment group
arriving today.
If there's anything I can do?
Leland, the best thing
that you can do...
is follow the doctor's orders.
You need rest.
I just feel...
I just feel I need something
to occupy my mind.
Take some time off,
for God's sake.
Fly somewhere. Take Sarah.
I'm afraid to, Ben. I'm afraid.
Hawk, we're at Jacques Renault's
apartment. Get here soon.
Morning.
What have you got, Harry?
Renault's a Canadian national.
He worked the lumber fields...
until he put on a little weight
a couple of seasons ago.
Now he tends bar at the Roadhouse.
Are there any more doughnuts?
- Sure. Andy?
And a cup of Joe. I didn't get
too much sleep last night.
You do look a bit peaked.
There's a group of insane men
staying on my floor.
Jacques Renault turn up?
No one's seen him.
We checked the building and the bar.
I sent Hawk to roust his brother,
but it looks like Bernie's jumped bail.
Morning, Agent Cooper.
- Morning, Doc.
The blood on the shirt you found here
is AB negative.
It's not Laura's blood.
So, it was Renault's blood
on Leo Johnson's shirt.
Thank you, Andy.
What about Leo Johnson?
- The APB went out. Nothing yet.
Harry, could you give me
a leg up here?
Sure.
- What's Renault's blood type?
Renault's blood is AB negative.
- Thanks, Doc.
My pleasure.
Holy smoke! "Flesh World" again.
- Yeah.
Harry, remember that ad
with Ronnette Pulaski?
We traced it. It came to the magazine
in a plain envelope. No name.
The magazine's a clearing-house.
Readers write letters in response
to the ads and mail them in.
The magazine forwards them
to the advertisers. No direct contact.
Ronnette got letters at this PO box.
A local zip code.
My guess is this box will be registered
under the name Jacques Renault.
Let's see who was writing
to Ronnette. Postmarked Georgia.
Goodnight.
I don't know, the beard ruins
the effect of the lingerie.
What do you think?
The guy's no Georgia peach.
- Poor bastard.
Did you notice the picture
of Leo Johnson's truck on that page?
I love it when you cook for me.
- Leo hates my cooking.
Leo missed the boat with you, baby.
The biggest mistake of your life was
dropping out of school to marry him.
What would you do
if he walked in right now?
Come here.
Hey, Leo! How's it going, man?
What a surprise!
Now, Leo, Shelly tells me
that you don't like her cooking.
Tell you what, she and I...
we're going to sit here while you
cook breakfast for us, you hump.
If you so much as utter
one harsh syllable to this...
beautiful girl...
I'm gonna shoot
your ugly face off, OK?
Sheriff's deputy.
Do exactly what we said,
and everything's gonna be fine.
Come here.
Hi, Andy. Come on in.
- Hi, Shelly.
Do you know when Leo's back?
Is he in trouble?
- We just want to talk to him.
Is this about Laura?
- Why do you say that?
I heard him talking to Jacques
the night he left.
Jacques Renault?
Yeah. They were outside arguing.
I couldn't hear exactly, but...
they did seem
to be arguing about her.
Call us if he gets in touch.
- OK, I will. Thanks for stopping by.
How'd I do?
- You did great.
You drive me crazy.
Hello?
Hi, Leo. Where you calling from?
- Has anybody come by?
What's that?
Is anybody looking for you?
Why would anyone look for you?
- Are you sure?
You know how paranoid you get
after popping bennies.
When are you coming home?
- Soon. You OK?
Yeah, everything's fine, Leo.
Come on home.
- I miss you, Shelly.
I miss you, too.
Hey, good-looking.
- Hope you don't mind my coming.
Oh, no.
Nadine won't be back from that
patent attorney for a couple of hours.
Silent drape runners?
- She's already spending the millions.
I have to put gas in my car
like everyone else, right?
I didn't want to tell you on the phone,
but Hank got his parole.
OK.
He'll be coming home.
I mean, back.
I only saw him
a minute before the hearing.
He seemed so hopeful,
I didn't want to say anything.
You don't have to explain.
- Said anything to Nadine yet?
Haven't yet.
Waiting for me to go first?
- No.
It's just that...Nadine's not well.
What are you saying?
I don't know.
I think I do.
I don't ever want to hurt you.
- Maybe that's our trouble, Ed.
We never want to hurt anyone.
We never just take what we want.
I think that this is how it is when
you get to the end of your life,
and you don't have anything
to show for it.
Don't call me.
I mean, not for a while, OK?
OK.
I love you, Ed.
I remember when you were little.
- So did my father speak to you?
Yes, he did. And I can't tell you
how excited we are
to have you come on-board and
put in a hitch here at our flagship.
What did you have in mind?
Well, as per your father's suggestion,
starting low, aiming high,
we thought perhaps the wrapping
department. Gifts, etc.
Part-time, after school.
- No, no, no.
Emory.
May I speak frankly?
Please do.
Let's talk...
...retail.
Sales?
- Perfume.
One of our more sensitive areas.
Expensive items, customer relations.
I've got my heart set on it, Emory.
- I'd have to talk to your father.
Emory, here's what we're gonna do.
You're gonna tell my father
I'm busy as a bee wrapping boxes.
Then you'll put me to work
behind the perfume counter.
If you don't, I'll rip my dress,
scream at the top of my lungs
and tell my father
that you made a pass at me.
Does that help
clear things up for you?
Yes.
Yes, what?
Yes, Miss Horne.
Shall we start on the paperwork?
James, I got your note.
Are you all right?
- There's some things I've gotta say.
I told you that my dad died
when I was 10? He didn't die.
He was a musician.
We lived out West.
He ran off on me and my mom.
- I'm sorry.
My mom was a writer.
Poems and short stories.
She's an alcoholic.
If you have a problem with this...
I don't have a problem.
You tell me.
It's true she was out of town
this week, but...
she wasn't travelling.
What she does is
she goes to another town,
shacks up in some cheap hotel
with a couple of bottles...
picks up guys and....
It's all right.
I don't want to have
any secrets from you.
I don't want there to be any lies
between us.
Secrets kill people's happiness.
I don't want us to be like that.
We won't. We won't be.
We have to do what's right.
What you said yesterday was true.
If we don't find out
what happened to Laura,
it won't go away, our whole lives.
We will, James.
She's out there, a restless spirit.
- I feel it, too. We owe it to her.
At least they're fresh. Here, Gary.
Oh, thanks.
Here you go, Scott.
- Thank you.
There you are.
What do you wanna mark this?
- "Duplicate".
Do we have one like it?
- Yeah, the same stain as before.
Mark it "duplicate".
Red drapes.
That PO box was registered
to Jacques Renault.
Those are the letters responding
to Ronnette's ad.
Let's see if there's something
from someone we know.
Hawk, hand me that magazine.
- What is it?
Two different ad numbers
mailed to the same address.
Ronnette's and one other.
Yeah, here it is.
"Student requires education in ways
of love. Generous, mature men only."
It's Laura.
You see some identifying mark?
The drapes.
- Drapes?
Red drapes, Harry.
From my dream.
Why would an apartment dweller like
Jacques buy 50 gallons of heating oil?
To heat a log cabin.
- Harry, you're all right!
Jacques' brother mentioned
a place by the state line.
Fellas, pack a lunch.
We're taking a walk in the woods.
Madeleine!
Hi.
- Hi.
Hi, I'm Madeleine Ferguson.
My friends call me Maddy.
This is really nice of you guys,
I don't know anyone in town,
except Aunt Sarah and Uncle Leland.
And the mood at the house
isn't that great right now.
Would you like something to drink?
- A cherry Coke.
You got it.
Madeleine, if I said that you can't
say a word of this to anyone,
would that be OK with you?
Sounds like some big secret.
It is. James and I knew Laura
better than anyone did.
She was in terrible trouble,
worse than we can imagine.
What?
I'd rather not say too much
about things we can't prove yet.
You said you can't prove it yet.
We're afraid the truth
might never come out
or whoever killed her
might never be caught.
We've sworn not to let that happen.
You know who did it?
- We have some ideas.
We wanted to ask for your help.
- What do you want me to do?
Laura talked about
a secret hiding place.
Somewhere in her house,
maybe in her room.
Nobody else knew about it.
She might have left something there
that could lead us to the killer.
I'll help you.
- You will?
The day before she died,
I had a feeling Laura was in trouble.
I've always felt close to her.
That's why I came here.
You know...
I didn't really know Laura
that well, but I feel like I do.
Our folks always told us
how much alike we were.
Will you call me
if there's anything I can do?
I don't think
there'll be any problems.
Madeleine, this is really great.
Call me Maddy.
Hi.
- Hi, Norma.
We're like refugee beauty queens.
- You don't know how pretty you are.
I hope I don't chip a nail
slinging plates around.
Hi, Norma.
- Hello, Hank.
Surprised to see me?
- Yes.
That Leo's girlfriend?
- Wife.
That Leo. So impulsive.
Not much meat on her, though.
I don't expect a kiss.
I figure I gotta earn my way
back into your heart.
But, Norma...
I intend to try.
So where do I start?
Washing dishes will be fine.
Can I finish my coffee first?
Boss?
He's been spending
more of his time in his room.
It's difficult to engage him
in conversation.
Terrible mood swings.
His school attendance
has become erratic at best.
And then the fighting at the Roadhouse
and at the funeral.
Are you using drugs, Bobby?
- Nope.
Alcohol's a drug.
- That's not what he meant.
Alcohol doesn't count?
- Everybody drinks.
Are you unhappy?
- Shouldn't I be?
That's not for me to say.
Have you ever killed anybody?
- Have you?
My father has.
- During wartime.
That's different.
- From what?
Maybe I should spend a few minutes
with Bobby alone?
This is supposed to be
family counselling.
I'll need to spend time
with each member of the family alone.
Bobby first.
- Fair enough.
Whatever you say.
Bobby, let's just cut the crap, huh?
So your parents don't understand
what you're going through.
That's a good one.
Let's talk about Laura.
- OK, let's talk about Laura.
Bobby, what happened the first time
that you and Laura made love?
What the hell kind of question
is that?
Bobby, did you cry?
Did I what?
And then what did Laura do,
did she laugh at you?
Were you very sad when Laura died?
Laura wanted to die.
- How do you know that?
Because she told me.
What else did she tell you?
Did she tell you there was
no goodness in the world?
She said people tried to be good,
but they were really
sick and rotten.
Her, most of all.
Every time she tried to make
the world a better place,
something terrible
came up inside her
and pulled her back down into hell.
It took her deeper and deeper
into the blackest nightmare.
Every time, it got harder
to go back up to the light.
Did you sometimes have the feeling
Laura was harbouring
some awful secret?
Yeah.
Bad enough that she wanted to die?
- Yes.
Bad enough to drive her to prey
upon people's weaknesses,
tempt them, break them down?
Make them do degrading things?
- Yes.
Laura wanted to corrupt people because
that's how she felt about herself.
Is that what happened to you, Bobby?
Is that what Laura did to you?
She wanted so much.
She made me sell drugs
so she could have them.
This way. Through here.
Watch your step there, city boy.
- Thanks, Harry.
What is it, Hawk?
Not the cabin we're looking for.
- Maybe, maybe not.
Might wanna hang back a step, Doc.
Might want to anyway.
About time you got here.
They move so slowly
when they're not afraid.
Come on, then.
My log does not judge.
I've got tea.
I've got cookies. No cake.
That's very kind of you, ma'am,
but I don't believe...
What kind of cookies?
Sugar.
The owls won't see us in here.
A cup of tea would be very nice.
Shut your eyes
and you'll burst into flames.
Thanks, Margaret.
We'll let it steep.
Wait for the tea.
The fish aren't running.
You've been expecting us?
- You're two days late.
But that's your concern.
My log saw something.
Something significant.
What did your log see?
- Tea first, then be ready.
Thank you.
My husband was a logging man.
- Oh?
He met the devil. Fire is the devil,
hiding like a coward in the smoke.
It was the day after the wedding,
wasn't it, Margaret?
The wood holds many spirits, doesn't it?
You can ask it now.
What did you see that night?
The night Laura Palmer was killed?
I'll do the talking.
Dark.
Laughing. The owls were flying.
Many things were blocked.
Laughing. Two men. Two girls.
Flashlights pass by...
in the woods over the ridge.
The owls were near.
The dark was pressing in on her.
Quiet then. Later, footsteps.
One man pass by.
Screams, far away.
Terrible. Terrible.
One voice.
- Man or girl?
Girl.
Further up. Over the ridge.
The owls were silent.
The two girls were
Laura and Ronnette.
The two men?
Jacques? Maybe Leo?
Maybe.
Who's the third man?
Do you hear it?
This way.
"And there's always music
in the air."
Waldo.
There's film in here.
Blood.
One-Eyed Jacks.
Good evening. Mr and Mrs Showel?
- OK, go right ahead.
Good evening.
- Catherine Martell and spouse.
Go easy on the sauce tonight,
OK, Cathy?
A couple of belts and even you
might start to look good to me.
The modern age changed everything,
Mr Thorson.
But it's my guess that
there's still vestigial interest
in the folklore of Iceland.
Vestigial. Absolutely.
Heba, did you know
that was a saying?
No, Jerry.
Heba-heba.
You never heard that before?
No, Jerry.
Do you realise the incredible
potential that could result
from our taking a mutual dip
in each other's respective gene pools?
Heba, I want to cook for you.
Very, very good. That's funny.
So he says, "What do you get when
you cross a Norwegian with a Swede?"
A socialist who wants to be king!
Well, I can remember
it was somewhere in the '50s
I came through your country.
Beautiful.
Not many trees, you know, but...
Would you excuse me?
- Of course.
Meet me in my office.
Give me two minutes to break away.
Hell hath no fury.
- What?
Two minutes.
Thor, I've been meaning to ask you,
are you familiar
with the word luhamsta?
Catherine, we agreed.
No scenes in front of the guests.
Keep the melodrama to a minimum.
Next thing I know, you're polishing
my shoes with Dom Perignon.
Fill me in. What's eating you?
Why did you have this $1,000 chip
from you-know-where in your pants?
I thought you preferred women
with certain experience.
Jerry gave me that.
It's good luck. I thought I'd lost it.
I'm so relieved you found it.
Are you quite finished?
Yes.
In that case....
Let's burn the mill.
Let's do it tonight.
No, my love, we'll give Josie
one last chance to sell.
Tomorrow. Failing that...
I have retained the services
of a qualified professional.
Breath mint?
Now let me get this straight.
Your entire country
is above the timberline?
Folks, can I have
your attention, please?
Can I have your attention?
Thank you for turning out
to welcome our neighbours
from the magical isle of Iceland.
We are all Icelanders!
Ghostwood Estates is
an important part of our future,
and there's no one we'd rather have
as partners in our future than...
Dance with him.
It is serious. Dance with him.
All right!
Hey, Jerry. What's going on?
Get Jacoby, get a net,
but get him out of my life.
Jerry.
Donna? It's Maddy.
I remembered, when we were younger,
Laura hid cigarettes in her bedpost.
The top of one of the posts
screws off.
I found a tape in her hiding place.
- Leland?
I'll meet you and James tomorrow.
OK! And bring a tape recorder.
Did anyone see you come in here?
No.
You do realise the risk
if anyone sees us.
This was hidden in her desk,
where you said it would be.
Then we can proceed.
- When?
Tomorrow night.
I told you to mind the store,
not open a franchise.
Hank, I...
- Do as you're told, Leo.
Next time you'll watch me take
your chippy apart before I kill you.
Get me a beer.
- What happened?
Just get me a damn beer!
Get up and...
What are you doing?
- You're not gonna hurt me again.
Don't touch me!
Don't come near me, Leo!
You haven't got the guts.
Reach over and turn on the light.
Don't make me leave.
Please, don't make me leave.