[narrator] 'Twas a long time ago
Longer now than it seems
In a place that perhaps
you've seen in your dreams
For the story
that you are about to be told
Took place in the holiday worlds of old
Now, you've probably wondered
where holidays come from
If you haven't, I'd say
It's time you begun!
♪ Boys and girls of every age
♪ Wouldn't you like
to see something strange?
♪ Come with us and you will see
- [gate creaks]
- ♪ This our town of Halloween
♪ This is Halloween
This is Halloween
♪ Pumpkins scream in the dead of night
♪ This is Halloween
Everybody make a scene
♪ Trick or treat till the neighbour's
gonna die of fright
♪ It's our town
Everybody scream
♪ In this town of Halloween
♪ I am the one hiding under your bed
♪ Teeth ground sharp
and eyes glowing red
♪ I am the one hiding under your stairs
♪ Fingers like snakes
and spiders in my hair
♪ This is Halloween
This is Halloween
♪ Halloween, Halloween
Halloween, Halloween
♪ In this town we call home
♪ Everyone hail to the pumpkin song
♪ In this town
Don't we love it now?
♪ Everybody's waiting
for the next surprise
♪ Round that corner, man
Hiding in the trash cans
♪ Something's waiting now to pounce
and how you'll scream
♪ This is Halloween
Red and black and slimy green
♪ Aren't you scared?
Well, that's just fine!
♪ Say it once, say it twice
Take a chance and roll the dice
♪ Ride with the moon
in the dead of night
♪ Everybody scream
Everybody scream
♪ In our town of Halloween
♪ I am the clown
with the tear-away face
♪ Here in a flash
and gone without a trace
♪ I am the who
when you call, "Who's there?"
♪ I am the wind
blowing through your hair
♪ I am the shadow on the moon at night
♪ Filling your dreams
to the brim with fright
♪ This is Halloween
This is Halloween
♪ Halloween, Halloween
Halloween, Halloween
♪ Tender lumplings everywhere
♪ Life's no fun without a good scare
- ♪ That's our job
- ♪ But we're not mean
♪ In our town of Halloween
♪ In this town
Don't we love it now?
♪ Everyone's waiting
for the next surprise
♪ Skeleton Jack
might catch you in the back
♪ And scream like a banshee
Make you jump out of your skin
♪ This is Halloween
Everybody scream
♪ Would you please make way
for a very special guy?
♪ Our man Jack
is king of the pumpkin patch
♪ Everyone hail to the Pumpkin King now
♪ This is Halloween
This is Halloween
♪ Halloween, Halloween
Halloween, Halloween
[water hisses]
♪ In this town we call home
♪ Everyone hail to the pumpkin song
[all harmonising]
♪ Halloween, Halloween
♪ Halloween, Halloween ♪
[cheering]
[cackling]
- It's over!
- We did it!
- Wasn't it terrifying?
- [both] What a night!
Great Halloween, everybody!
I believe it was our most horrible yet.
Thank you, everyone.
No. Thanks to you, Jack.
Without your brilliant leadership...
- [Jack] Not at all, Mayor.
- You're such a scream, Jack!
You're a witch's fondest dream!
You made walls fall, Jack!
[woman] Walls fall? You made
the very mountains crack, Jack!
The deadly nightshade
you slipped me wore off, Sally.
Let go! [gasps]
You're not ready
for so much excitement.
Yes, I am.
- You're coming with me!
- [straining] No, I'm not!
- Oh!
Come back here, you foolish...
Ow! Oh!
Ooh, Jack, you make wounds
ooze and flesh crawl!
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you very much!
[Mayor] Hold it! We haven't
given out the prizes yet!
Our first award goes to the vampires
for most blood drained
in a single evening.
[applause]
[Mayor] A second and honourable mention
- goes to the fabulous...
- [sighs]
- ... Dark Lagoon Leeches.
- [playing down-tempo music]
- [coin clinks]
- Nice work, Bone Daddy!
Yeah, I guess so.
Just like last year.
And the year before that,
and the year before that.
- [gate creaks]
- [gasps]
♪ There are few who deny
at what I do I am the best
♪ For my talents
are renowned far and wide
♪ When it comes to surprises
in the moonlit night
♪ I excel without ever even trying
♪ With the slightest little effort
of my ghostlike charms
♪ I have seen grown men
give out a shriek
♪ With a wave of my hand
and a well-placed moan
♪ I have swept the
very bravest off their feet
♪ Yet, year after year
It's the same routine
♪ And I grow so weary
of the sound of screams
♪ And I, Jack, the Pumpkin King
♪ Have grown so tired
of the same old thing
♪ Oh, somewhere deep
♪ Inside of these bones
♪ An emptiness
♪ Began to grow
♪ There's something out there
♪ Far from my home
♪ A longing that
♪ I've never known
♪ I'm the master of fright
and a demon of light
♪ And I'll scare you
right out of your pants
[ghosts moaning]
♪ To a guy in Kentucky
I'm Mr Unlucky
♪ And I'm known
throughout England and France
♪ And since I am dead
I can take off my head
♪ To recite Shakespearean quotations
♪ No animal nor man
can scream like I can
♪ With the fury of my recitations
♪ But who here
♪ Would ever understand
♪ That the Pumpkin King
with the skeleton grin
♪ Would tire of his crown?
♪ If they only understood
♪ He'd give it all up
♪ If he only could
[gasps]
♪ Oh, there's an empty place
♪ In my bones
♪ That calls out for
♪ Something unknown
♪ The fame and praise
♪ Come year after year
♪ Does nothing for
♪ These empty tears ♪
Jack...
...I know how you feel.
[thunder rumbling]
[mechanical whirring]
[man] Sally!
You've come back.
- I had to.
- For this!
- Yes.
- Shall we, then?
That's twice this month
you've slipped deadly nightshade
- into my tea and run off.
- Three times.
You're mine, you know.
I made you with my own hands!
You can make other creations.
I'm restless. I can't help it.
It's a phase, my dear. It'll pass.
We need to be patient, that's all.
But I don't want to be patient!
- [Zero barks]
- No, Zero, not now.
I'm not in the mood.
- [barks]
- All right.
Here you go, boy.
[growls]
[snoring]
- [car rattling]
- [moaning]
Morning, gents!
[humming This is Halloween]
- [doorbell screams]
- [continues humming]
- Jack? You home?
Jack? I've got the plans
for next Halloween.
I need to go over them with you
so we can get started.
Jack, please.
I'm only an elected official here.
I can't make decisions by myself.
Jack, answer me!
[screams]
- He's not home.
- Where is he?
He hasn't been home all night.
[groans]
[yawns] Where are we?
It's someplace new.
[barks]
What is this?
[gasps]
- [wind blowing]
- Whoa!
[barks]
[yells]
♪ What's this? What's this?
There's colour everywhere
♪ What's this?
There's white things in the air
I can't believe my eyes
♪ I must be dreaming
Wake up, Jack, this isn't fair
♪ What's this?
[singing indistinctly]
♪ What's this? What's this?
There's something very wrong
♪ What's this?
There's people singing songs
♪ What's this? The streets are lined
with creatures laughing
♪ Everybody seems so happy
Have I possibly gone daffy?
♪ What is this? What's this?
♪ There's children throwing snowballs
instead of throwing heads
♪ They're busy building toys
and absolutely no one's dead
♪ There's frost in every window
Oh, I can't believe my eyes
♪ And in my bones I feel the warmth
♪ That's coming from inside
♪ Oh, look, what's this?
They're hanging mistletoe
♪ They kiss?
Why, that looks so unique, inspired
♪ They're gathering around
Hearing stories
♪ Roasting chestnuts on a fire
What's this?
♪ What's this? In here
they've got a little tree
♪ How queer
And who would ever think, and why?
♪ They're covering it with tiny things
Electric lights on strings
♪ And there's a smile on everyone
Correct me if I'm wrong
♪ This looks like fun
This looks like fun
♪ Could it be I got my wish?
What's this?
♪ Oh, my, what now?
The children are asleep
♪ But, look, there's nothing underneath
No ghouls
♪ No witches to scream
and scare them or ensnare them
[snoring]
♪ Only little cosy things
secure inside their dreamland
[sighs]
♪ What's this?
♪ The monsters are all missing
and the nightmares can't be found
♪ And in their place there seems
to be good feeling all around
♪ Instead of screams
I swear I can hear music in the air
♪ The smell of cakes and pies
are absolutely everywhere
♪ The sights, the sounds
They're everywhere and all around
♪ I've never felt so good before
♪ This empty place inside of me
is filling up
♪ I simply cannot get enough
I want it, oh, I want it
♪ I want it for my own
I've got to know, I've got to know
♪ What is this place that I've found?
What is this? ♪
Christmas Town? Hmm.
[whistle blows]
[man] Ho! Ho! Ho!
Hmm...
- This has never happened before.
- It's suspicious.
- It's peculiar.
- [both] It's scary!
- Stand aside. Coming through.
- [growls]
[grunts]
We've got to find Jack.
There's only 365 days left
till next Halloween!
Three sixty-four.
Is there anywhere
we've forgotten to check?
I looked in every mausoleum.
We opened the sarcophagi.
I tromped through the pumpkin patch.
I peeked behind the Cyclops' eye.
I did, but he wasn't there.
It's time to sound the alarms!
[alarm wails]
Frog's breath will overpower any odour.
[croaks]
[coughs, gagging]
Bitter!
Worm's wart. [gasping]
Where's that worm's wart?
[man] Sally! That soup ready yet?
Coming!
Lunch!
Ah, what's that?
[sniffing] Worm's wart! Mmm.
And frog's breath.
What's wrong?
I... I thought you liked frog's breath.
Nothing's more suspicious
than frog's breath.
Until you taste it,
I won't swallow a spoonful.
- I'm not hungry.
- [spoon clatters]
- Oops.
- You want me to starve.
An old man, like me,
who hardly has strength as it is.
Me, to whom you owe your very life!
Don't be silly.
[slurping] Mmm!
See? Scrumptious.
[gulping rapidly]
Did anyone think to dredge the lake?
[sighs] This morning.
[indistinct barking]
- Hear that?
- What?
- Shhh!
- [barking continues]
- Zero!
- [barking]
[all yelling, shouting]
Where have you been?
Call a town meeting
and I'll tell everyone all about it.
- When?
- Immediately!
Town meeting!
Town meeting tonight!
- [snoring]
- [Mayor] Town meeting!
Town meeting tonight!
[all chattering indistinctly]
- [gasps]
- [chuckles]
Listen, everyone.
I want to tell you about Christmas Town.
♪ There were objects so peculiar
They were not to be believed
♪ All around
things to tantalise my brain
♪ It's a world unlike anything
I've ever seen
♪ And as hard as I tried
I can't seem to describe
♪ Like a most improbable dream
♪ But you must believe
when I tell you this
♪ It's as real as my skull
and it does exist
Here, let me show you.
- [all gasping]
- Oooh.
♪ This is a thing called a present
- ♪ The whole thing starts with a box
- ♪ A box?
- ♪ Is it steel?
- ♪ Are there locks?
- ♪ Is it filled with a pox?
- ♪ A pox? How delightful, a pox
If you please.
♪ Just a box with bright coloured paper
♪ And the whole thing's
topped with a bow
- ♪ A bow?
- ♪ But why? How ugly! What's in it?
♪ That's the point of the thing
Not to know
- ♪ It's a bat! It's a rat!
- ♪ Will it bend? Will it break?
♪ Perhaps it's the head
that I found in the lake
♪ Listen now
You don't understand
♪ That's not the point
of Christmas Land
Now, pay attention.
♪ We pick up an oversized sock
♪ And hang it like this on the wall
- ♪ Oh, yes, does it still have a foot?
- ♪ Let me see, let me look
- ♪ Is it rotted and covered with gook?
- Let me explain.
♪ There's no foot inside, but candy
Or sometimes it's filled with small toys
- ♪ Small toys? Do they snap?
- ♪ Or explode in the sack?
♪ Perhaps they spring out
and scare girls and boys
♪ What a splendid idea
This Christmas sounds fun
♪ I fully endorse it
Let's try it at once
♪ Everyone, please
Now, not so fast
♪ There's something here
that you don't quite grasp
[all chattering indistinctly]
Well, I may as well give them
what they want.
♪ And the best, I must confess
I have saved for the last
♪ For the ruler of this Christmas Land
♪ Is a fearsome king
with a deep, mighty, voice
♪ Least that's what
I've come to understand
♪ And I've also heard it told
that he's something to behold
♪ Like a lobster, huge and red
♪ When he sets out to sleigh
with his rain gear on
♪ Carting bulging sacks
with his big great arms
♪ That is so, I've heard it said
♪ And on a dark, cold night
under full moonlight
♪ He flies into a fog
like a vulture in the sky
♪ And they call him
♪ Sandy Claws
- [applause]
- [cackles]
♪ Well, at least they're excited
But they don't understand
♪ That special kind of feeling
♪ In Christmas Land ♪
Oh, well.
[animal howls]
Hmm.
Hmm...
There's got to be a logical way
to explain this Christmas thing.
You've poisoned me for the last time,
you wretched girl!
[sighs deeply]
- [doorbell chimes]
- Oh, my head!
The door is open!
- Hello?
- Jack Skellington!
Up here, my boy!
Doctor, I need
to borrow some equipment.
Is that so? Whatever for?
I'm conducting a series of experiments.
How perfectly marvellous!
- Curiosity killed the cat, you know.
- I know.
Come on into the lab
and we'll get you all fixed up.
Hmm. Experiments?
[Jack] Zero! I'm home!
Interesting reaction,
but what does it mean?
[Sally thudding]
[band playing up-tempo music]
You can come out now
if you promise to behave.
Sally?
Sally!
- Oooh! Gone again!
- [lantern crashes]
[chalk scraping]
Oh!
[crowing]
♪ Something's up with Jack
Something's up with Jack
♪ Don't know if we're ever
going to get him back
♪ He's all alone up there
Locked away inside
- ♪ Never says a word
- ♪ Hope he hasn't died
♪ Something's up with Jack
Something's up with Jack
♪ Christmas time is buzzing in my skull
♪ Will it let me be?
I cannot tell
♪ There're so many things I cannot grasp
♪ When I think I've got it
Then at last
♪ Through my bony fingers it does slip
♪ Like a snowflake in a fiery grip
♪ Something here I'm not quite getting
Though I try, I keep forgetting
♪ Like a memory long since past
♪ Here in an instant, gone in a flash
What does it mean? What does it mean?
♪ In these little bric-a-brac
A secret's waiting to be cracked
♪ These dolls and toys confuse me so
Confound it all, I love it though
♪ Simple objects, nothing more
But something's hidden through a door
♪ Though I do not have the key
♪ Something's here I cannot see
What does it mean? What does it mean?
[doll plays a tune]
♪ What does it mean?
- [squeaks]
- [snorts]
♪ I've read these
Christmas books so many times
♪ I know the stories
and I know the rhymes
♪ I know the
Christmas carols all by heart
♪ My skull's so full
It's tearing me apart
♪ As often as I've read them
Something's wrong
♪ So hard to put my bony finger on
♪ Or, perhaps, it's really not as deep
as I've been led to think
♪ Am I trying much too hard?
♪ Of course, I've been too close to see
The answer's right in front of me
♪ Right in front of me
It's simple, really, very clear
♪ Like music drifting in the air
♪ Invisible, but everywhere
♪ Just because I cannot see it
doesn't mean I can't believe it
♪ You know, I think this Christmas
thing is not as tricky as it seems
♪ And why should they have all the fun?
It should belong to anyone
♪ Not anyone, in fact, but me
Why, I could make a Christmas tree
♪ And there's no reason I can find
I couldn't handle Christmas time
♪ I bet I could improve it, too
and that's exactly what I'll do ♪
[cackles]
Eureka!
This year, Christmas will be ours!
[all cheer]
[Mayor] Patience, everyone.
Jack has a special job for each of you.
- Dr Finkelstein!
- [wheelchair whirring]
[Mayor] Your Christmas
assignment is ready.
Dr Finkelstein
to the front of the line!
[cooing]
What kind of noise is that
for a baby to make?
- Perhaps it can be improved?
- No problem!
I knew it!
Doctor, thank you for coming.
We need some of these.
Hmm... Their construction
should be exceedingly simple, I think.
How horrible our Christmas will be.
No. Howjolly!
Oh, howjolly our Christmas will be.
Oh! Hey! [growls]
- What are you doing here?
- Jack sent for us.
- Specifically.
- By name.
- Lock.
- Shock.
Barrel.
Jack. Jack! It's Boogie's boys.
Aah! Halloween's
finest trick-or-treaters!
The job I have for you is top secret.
It requires craft, cunning, mischief.
And we thought you
didn't like us, Jack!
Absolutely no one is to know about it.
Not a soul.
[whispering] Now, you must
go to the forest.
In the forest you will see a tree.
...Christmas Town.
Ow!
- Hmm.
- And one more thing.
Leave that no account
Oogie Boogie out of this!
Whatever you say, Jack.
- Of course, Jack.
- Wouldn't dream of it, Jack.
♪ Kidnap Mr Sandy Claws?
- ♪ I wanna do it
- ♪ Let's draw straws
- ♪ Jack said we should work together
- ♪ Three of a kind
- ♪ Birds of a feather
- ♪ Now and for ever
♪ La, la, la, la, la, la
La, la, la, la, la
♪ Kidnap the Sandy Claws
Lock him up real tight
♪ Throw away the key
and then turn off all the lights
♪ First we're going to set some bait
inside a nasty trap and wait
♪ When he comes a-sniffing, we will
snap the trap and close the gate
♪ Wait, I've got a better plan
to catch this big red lobster man
♪ Pop him in a boiling pot
and when he's done, we'll butter him up
♪ Kidnap the Sandy Claws
Throw him in a box
♪ Bury him for 90 years
Then see if he talks
♪ Then Mr Oogie Boogie Man
♪ Can take the whole thing over then
♪ He'll be so pleased, I do declare
♪ That he will cook him rare
[laughing]
[smacking lips]
♪ I say that we take a cannon
Aim it at his door and then
♪ Knock three times, and when he
answers Sandy Claws will be no more
♪ You're so stupid, think now
If we blow him up to smithereens
♪ We may lose some pieces and then
Jack will beat us black and green
♪ Kidnap the Sandy Claws
Tie him in a bag
♪ Throw him in the ocean
Then see if he is sad
♪ Because Mr Oogie Boogie
is the meanest guy around
♪ If I were on his boogie list
I'd get out of town
♪ He'll be so pleased by our success
♪ That he'll reward us, too, I'll bet
♪ Perhaps he'll make his special brew
♪ Of snake and spider stew
♪ We're his little henchmen
and we take our job with pride
♪ We do our best to please him
and stay on his good side
♪ I wish my cohorts weren't so dumb
- ♪ I'm not the dumb one
- ♪ You're no fun
- Shut up!
- Make me.
♪ I've got something, listen
This one is real good, you'll see
♪ We'll send a present to his door
Upon there'll be a note to read
♪ Now, in the box, we'll wait and hide
until his curiosity
♪ Entices him to look inside
and then we'll have him one, two, three
♪ Kidnap the Sandy Claws
Beat him with a stick
♪ Lock him up for 90 years
See what makes him tick
♪ Kidnap the Sandy Claws
Chop him into bits
♪ Mr Oogie Boogie
is sure to get his kicks
♪ Kidnap the Sandy Claws
See what we will see
♪ Lock him in a cage
and then throw away the key ♪
Sandy Claws, huh?
- [cackling]
- [snake hisses]
It goes something like this.
[playing Jingle Bells]
How about it?
Think you can you manage?
A- one and a-two and a-three and...
[plays Jingle Bells off-key]
- Next!
- Fantastic!
Now, why don't you all practise on that,
and we'll be in great shape!
Sally, I need your help
more than anyone's.
You certainly do, Jack.
I had the most terrible vision.
- That's splendid!
- No. It was about your Christmas.
- There was smoke and fire!
- That's not my Christmas.
My Christmas is filled
with laughter and joy,
and this!
My Sandy Claws outfit.
I want you to make it.
Jack, please listen to me.
It's going to be a disaster!
How could it be?
Just follow the pattern.
This part's red.
The trim is white.
- It's a mistake, Jack.
- Now, don't be modest.
Who else is clever enough
to make my Sandy Claws outfit?
- [Mayor] Next!
- I have every confidence in you.
But it seems wrong to me.
Very wrong.
This device is called a nutcracker.
- Jack! We caught him! We got him!
- Perfect!
Open it up! Quickly!
- [gasps]
- [sniffs]
That's not Sandy Claws.
- It isn't?
- Who is it?
[sniffs]
Bunny!
[whimpering]
- Not Sandy Claws. Take him back!
- We followed your instructions.
- We went through the door.
- Which door? There's more than one.
Sandy Claws is behind the door
shaped like this.
- I told you!
- [choking, grunting]
[all arguing]
- [roars]
- [all gasp]
I'm very sorry
for the inconvenience, sir.
Take him home first.
And apologise again!
Be careful with Sandy Claws
when you fetch him! Treat him nicely!
- Got it!
- We'll get it right next time!
You will be a decided improvement
over that treacherous Sally.
Master! The plans.
Excellent, Igor.
[chattering indistinctly]
♪ This time
♪ Making Christmas
Making Christmas is so fine
♪ It's ours this time
and won't the children be surprised?
- ♪ Making Christmas
- ♪ Time to give them something fun
♪ They'll talk about for years to come
♪ Let's have a cheer from everyone
♪ It's time to party
♪ Making Christmas
Making Christmas
♪ Sticks and mice get wrapped up so nice
♪ With spider legs and pretty bows
♪ It's ours this time
♪ All together, that and this
♪ With all our tricks
We're making Christmas time
Here comes Jack!
♪ I don't believe
♪ What's happening to me
♪ My hopes, my dreams
♪ My fantasies
[cackling]
♪ Won't they be impressed?
I am a genius
♪ See how I transformed this old rat
♪ Into a most delightful hat
Hmm...
♪ My compliments from me to you
on this your most intriguing hat
♪ Consider though this substitute
A bat in place of this old rat
♪ No, no, that's all wrong
This thing will never make a present
♪ It's been dead for too long
Try something fresher
♪ Something pleasant
Try again, don't give up
♪ All together, that and this
♪ With all our tricks
We're making Christmas time
♪ This time, this time
♪ Making Christmas
Making Christmas
♪ It's almost here
and we can't wait
♪ So ring the bells and celebrate
♪ 'Cause when the full moon
starts to climb
♪ We'll all sing out
♪ "It's Christmas time!" ♪
[man] Kathleen. Bobby. Susie.
Yes, Susie's been nice. Nice. Nice.
Naughty. Nice. Nice. Nice.
There are hardly
any naughty children this year.
- [doorbell chimes]
- Now, who could that be?
- [all] Trick or treat!
- Huh?
Yaah!
You don't look like yourself, Jack.
Not at all!
Isn't that wonderful?
It couldn't be more wonderful!
But you're the Pumpkin King.
Not anymore!
I feel so much better now!
Jack, I know you think
something's missing, but...
- Ow!
- Sorry.
You're right. Something is missing.
But what?
I've got the beard, the coat,
the boots, the belt...
- Jack! This time we bagged him!
- This time we really did!
- He sure is big, Jack.
- And heavy!
- Let me out!
- [all exclaim]
Sandy Claws. In person.
What a pleasure to meet you!
Why, you have hands.
You don't have claws at all!
- Where am I?
- Surprised, aren't you?
I knew you would be.
You don't need to have another worry
about Christmas this year.
- What?
- Consider this a vacation, Sandy.
A reward.
It's your turn to take it easy.
- But there must be some mistake.
- See that he's comfortable.
Just a second, fellas. Of course!
- That's what I'm missing. Thanks.
- But...
You just can't...
Hold on! Where are we going now?
Oh, ho, ho! No...
This is worse than I thought.
Much worse.
I know!
[man] Me on vacation?
On Christmas Eve?!
- Where are we taking him?
- To Oogie Boogie, of course.
There isn't anywhere
more comfortable than that.
- Jack said to make him comfortable.
- Yes, he did.
[man] Haven't you heard of peace
on earth and goodwill toward men?
[all] No! [chortling]
- This will stop Jack!
- [saw buzzing]
What a joy to think
of all we'll have in common!
We'll have conversations worth having!
- [kids laughing]
- Don't do this!
Naughty children never get any presents.
I think he might be too big!
- [moans]
- No, he's not.
If he can go down a chimney,
he can fit down here!
- [grunting]
- [metal clanging]
[shouts]
[squeaking]
♪ Well, well, well
What have we here?
♪ Sandy Claws, huh?
Ooh, I'm really scared
♪ So you're the one
everybody's talkin' about [laughs]
♪ You're jokin', you're jokin'
I can't believe my eyes
♪ You're jokin' me, you gotta be
This can't be the right guy
♪ He's ancient, he's ugly
I don't know which is worse
♪ I might just split a seam now
if I don't die laughin' first
♪ When Mr Oogie Boogie says
There's trouble close at hand
♪ You'd better pay attention now
'cause I'm the Boogie Man
♪ And if you aren't shakin'
There's somethin' very wrong
♪ 'Cause this may be the last time
You hear the Boogie song
- ♪ Ooh
♪ I'm the Oogie Boogie Man
♪ Release me now or you must face
the dire consequences
♪ The children are expecting me
So, please, come to your senses
♪ You're jokin', you're jokin'
I can't believe my ears
♪ Would someone shut this fella up?
I'm drownin' in my tears
♪ It's funny, I'm laughin'
You really are too much
♪ And now, with your permission
I'm going to do my stuff
- What are you going to do?
- The best I can.
Whoa!
♪ The sound of rollin' dice, to me
is music in the air
♪ 'Cause I'm a gamblin' Boogie Man
Although I don't play fair
♪ It's much more fun, I must confess
when lives are on the line
♪ Not mine, of course
But yours, old boy
♪ Now, that'd be just fine
♪ Release me fast or you will have
to answer for this heinous act
♪ Oh, brother, you're something
You put me in a spin
♪ You aren't comprehending
the position that you're in
♪ It's hopeless, you're finished
You haven't got a prayer
♪ 'Cause I'm Mr Oogie Boogie
♪ And you ain't goin' nowhere ♪
[laughs]
[all laughing]
[band plays off-key music]
[chattering, laughter]
[all cheering]
Think of us as you soar,
triumphantly, through the sky,
outshining every star,
your silhouette
a dark blot on the moon.
You, who are our pride,
you, who are our glory,
you, who have frightened millions
into an early grave.
You, who have...
...devastated the souls
of the... living!
- Oh, no. We can't take off in this.
- [all groan]
The reindeer can't see an inch
in front of their noses.
- Phew!
- This fog's as thick as...
- Jellied brains.
- Or thicker!
There go all of my hopes,
my precious plans,
my glorious dreams.
- There goes Christmas.
- [all moan]
- [Zero barking]
- No, Zero. Down, boy.
My, what a brilliant nose you have.
The better to light my way!
To the head of the team, Zero.
- [all cheering]
- We're off!
[whip cracking]
Wait, Jack. No!
- Ho, ho, ho! [laughs]
- [whip cracks]
Goodbye, Jack.
My dearest Jack.
Oh, how I hope my premonition is wrong.
♪ I sense there's something in the wind
♪ That feels like tragedy's at hand
♪ And though I'd like to stand by him
♪ Can't shake this feeling that I have
♪ The worst is just around the bend
♪ And does he notice
♪ My feelings for him?
♪ And will he see
♪ How much he means to me?
♪ I think it's not to be
♪ What will become
of my dear friend?
♪ Where will his actions lead us then?
♪ Although I'd like to join the crowd
♪ In their enthusiastic cloud
♪ Try as I may, it doesn't last
♪ And will we ever
♪ End up together?
♪ No, I think not
♪ It's never to become
♪ For I am not the one ♪
Ho, ho, ho!
[laughs]
[loud thump]
Santa!
[boy gasps]
Santa?
Merry Christmas!
And what is your name?
Uh... uh, uh...
That's all right. I have
a special present for you anyway.
There you go, sonny. [laughs]
[woman] And what did Santa
bring you, honey?
[both screaming]
Merry Christmas!
[phone ringing]
- Hello. Police.
- [woman screaming]
Attacked by Christmas toys?
That's strange.
That's the second
toy complaint we've had.
[chuckling]
[laughing]
[growling]
Come on. [giggling]
Oh, wait.
- [quacking]
- [screaming]
Mom! Dad! Help!
[screaming]
[man screams]
[woman screams]
[both screaming]
[woman screaming]
[screaming]
[cackling]
You're welcome, one and all!
- [phones ringing]
- Where'd you spot him?
Fast as we can, ma'am.
Police. I know. A skeleton.
Keep calm. Turn off the lights. Make
sure doors are locked. Hello. Police.
[woman] Reports are pouring in
from all over the globe
that an impostor is shamelessly
impersonating Santa Claus,
mocking and mangling
this joyous holiday.
Authorities assure us that, at this
moment, military units are mobilising
to stop the perpetrator
of this heinous crime.
Jack. Someone has to help Jack!
- Where did they take that Sandy Claws?
- ... come back and save Christmas.
[alarm sounding]
Look, Zero. Searchlights.
They're celebrating!
They're thanking us
for doing such a good job!
Whoa! Careful down there.
You almost hit us!
- [Zero barks]
- It's OK, Zero. Head higher!
Are you a gamblin' man, Sandy?
Let's play!
Mmm?
My, my!
What have we here?
[whispers] I'll get you out of here.
Lovely!
Tickle, tickle, tickle.
[laughing]
What?! You try
to make a dupe out of me?!
[roaring]
[shrieks]
Who's next on my list?
Ah! Little Harry and Jordan.
Won't they be surprised?
They're trying to hit us! Zero!
Merry Christmas to all,
and to all a good night!
[all moaning]
[howls]
I knew this Christmas thing
was a bad idea.
I felt it in my gut.
Terrible news, folks!
The worst tragedy of our times!
Jack has been blown to smithereens!
Terrible, terrible news!
Attention. Attention, citizens.
Terrible news.
There's still no sign of Santa Claus.
Although the impostor
has been shot down,
it looks like Christmas will
have to be cancelled this year.
I repeat, the impostor
has been shot down,
but there's still no sign
of the real Santa.
[whimpers]
♪ What have I done?
♪ How could I
♪ Be so blind?
♪ All is lost
♪ Where was I?
♪ Spoiled all
♪ Everything's
♪ Gone all wrong
♪ What have I done?
♪ Find a deep cave to hide in
♪ In a million years they'll find me
♪ Only dust
♪ And a plaque that reads
♪ "Here lies poor old Jack"
♪ But I never intended
♪ All this madness, never
♪ And nobody really understood
♪ Well, how could they?
♪ That all I ever wanted
was to bring them something great
♪ Why does nothing
ever turn out like it should?
♪ Well, what the heck?
♪ I went and did my best
♪ And, by God
I really tasted something swell
♪ And for a moment
Why, I even touched the sky
♪ And at least I left some stories
they can tell, I did
♪ And for the first time
since I don't remember when
♪ I felt just like
my old bony self again
♪ And I, Jack, the Pumpkin King
♪ That's right
I am the Pumpkin King [cackling]
♪ And I just can't wait
until next Halloween
♪ 'Cause I've got some new ideas
that will really make them scream
♪ And, by God, I'm really going
to give it all my might
Uh-oh.
♪ I hope there's still time
to set things right ♪
- Sandy Claws!
- [growls]
You wait till Jack hears about this.
By the time he's through with you,
you'll be lucky...
The King of Halloween
has been blown to smithereens!
- Skeleton Jack is now a pile of dust!
- [gasps]
Come on, Zero.
Christmas isn't over yet.
What's that you were sayin'
about luck, rag doll?
- [Sally] Help! Help!
- [growling]
Shhh!
[Oogie] Seven!
It's Oogie's turn to boogie now.
- [screams]
- One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven! [laughs]
[Santa] This can't be happening!
Ashes to ashes and dust to dust.
Oh, I'm feeling weak... with hunger!
One more roll of the dice
oughta do it! [laughs]
What? Snake eyes?!
[grunts]
Eleven! [laughs]
Looks like I won the jackpot!
Bye-bye, doll face
- and sandman!
- [screaming]
What the...?
- [shrieks]
- Hello, Oogie.
Jack! But they said you were dead.
You must be double dead!
Oh!
[laughs]
Well, come on, bone man!
[barking]
[moaning] Ha!
Fire!
[grunts]
Jack, look out!
So long, Jack! [laughs]
How dare you treat my friends
so shamefully!
Now look what you've done!
My bugs! My bugs!
[insects continue chittering]
Forgive me, Mr Claws.
I'm afraid I've made
a terrible mess of your holiday.
Bumpy sleigh ride, Jack?
The next time you get the urge
to take over someone else's holiday,
I'd listen to her.
She's the only one
who makes any sense
around this insane asylum!
- Skeletons and boogie men!
- I hope there's still time.
To fix Christmas?
Of course there is. I'm Santa Claus!
He'll fix things, Jack.
He knows what to do.
How did you get down here, Sally?
I... I was trying to...
Well, I wanted to...
- To...
- To help me?
- I couldn't let you just...
- Sally...
I can't believe
I never realised that you...
- [Mayor] Jack! Jack!
- [Lock] Here he is!
- Alive!
- Just like we said!
Grab a hold, my boy!
Whoa!
[woman] Good news. Santa Claus, the
one and only, has finally been spotted.
Old Saint Nick appears to be
travelling at supersonic speed.
He's setting things right, bringing
joy and cheer wherever he goes.
Yes, folks, Kris Kringle
has pulled it out of the bag
and delivered Christmas
to excited children all over the world.
- [snoring]
- [sirens wailing]
[all vocalising]
- Jack!
- Jack's back!
- Jack?
- Jack's OK!
- He's all right!
- It's Jack!
♪ Jack's OK
♪ And he's back OK
♪ He's all right
Let's shout
♪ Make a fuss
Scream it out
Wee!
♪ Jack is back
Now, everyone sing
♪ In our town of Halloween
- It's great to be home!
- [Santa] Ho, ho, ho!
Happy Halloween!
Merry Christmas!
- ♪ What's this?
♪ I haven't got a clue
- ♪ Why, it's completely new
- ♪ What's this?
- ♪ Must be a Christmas thing
- ♪ It's really very strange
♪ This is Halloween, Halloween
Halloween, Halloween
♪ What's this? What's this?
[all giggling]
Careful, my precious jewel.
[Jack] My dearest friend.
♪ If you don't mind
♪ I'd like to join you
♪ By your side
♪ Where we can gaze
♪ Into the stars
[both] ♪ And sit together
♪ Now and for ever
♪ For it is plain
♪ As anyone can see
♪ We're simply meant to be ♪