Look, right there.
A chamber.
Okay.
I see it.
Go on.
Get off my foot.
Oh, will you--?
Go on.
Do you see anything?
Spiders.
Now get moving, MacGyver.
Get moving, don't dawdle.
All right.
Look.
Huh?
There.
A sigma.
Ah.
Do you recall
your Greek, MacGyver?
Sigma is the letter...
S.
Yes.
As in Solon.
It says
"Atlantis anaduotai."
"Atlantis rises."
We've found the medal.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
What?
Wait.
Oh, what, you want a photograph?
Thank you.
That's not what I had in mind.
What?
Just hang on a second, will you?
Hello.
What is it?
Uh...
Hm.
What's that?
That's neat.
Neat?
Yeah.
Huh.
At last.
At last, it's wonderful.
Let's get out of here.
All in good time.
I must take a closer look
at this ingenious...device.
Absolutely
marvelous workmanship.
Fiendishly clever.
Eh, what sort of trap
do you suppose it sets off?
No.
Hey.
I'll entertain
any ideas, MacGyver.
MacGyver.
Well, do you have
any ideas?
Oh, man.
Thousands of years ago,
before time itself
was measured,
as we know it,
there was Atlantis.
It was a great city,
dedicated to art and science.
The people of Atlantis
built their city
at the foot of a volcano,
which they used
to make heat and power.
They worshipped
a mysterious object
called the Torch of Truth,
said to possess the light
of universal wisdom.
For centuries, Atlantis
was the center of the world,
and the world was at peace.
Then, in an instant,
the volcano
that heated their homes
and powered
their machines erupted.
Now fleeing the ruined city,
a few survivors gathered
the great wealth of Atlantis,
and hid it in a place
they called the Tower of Fear.
They wrote that story in a book
made out of platinum pages.
Heh, platinum, heh, heh.
Ahem-- Yes.
Uh...
Thousands of years passed,
until 590 B.C.,
when a Greek scholar
journeyed to Egypt.
His name was Solon.
There he is.
It was there he discovered
two relics of Atlantis.
Ah, one was the platinum book,
and the other was
the Torch of Truth itself.
Solon gathered his disciples
and presented them with an Ark,
in which he'd locked
the Torch of Truth.
And taking the only key,
Solon left
with the platinum book
to search
for the Treasure of Atlantis.
And vanished... without a trace.
That is...
until five years ago,
when I found this very same key
in the ruins of Thera.
I am convinced that this is
the key to the Ark of Solon.
And I propose to follow
in his footsteps
and find the Treasure of Atlantis.
I think
we've heard quite enough.
Mister Director,
now that I have the medallion,
I'm certain
I can prove my theory.
If the Academy will,
eh, kindly, uh,
fund my next expedition.
The Royal Academy of
Archaeological Science
finances the serious study
of history.
We have no interest
in your obsession with Atlantis.
As for this artifact
it will stay right here,
as part of the Academy's
permanent collection.
No, but I beg you to reconsider.
Rest assured, we will.
In fact, I strongly recommend
that the Board reconsider
your tenure here.
Reconsider my tenure?
Ah.
Come on, MacGyver.
Still dawdling
after all these years.
You haven't changed.
What, you have?
You're the only man I know
who'd plan an archaeological dig
in the middle of a civil war.
Whatever happened
to that eager young student
at university who was so anxious
to explore ancient ruins and solve
the mysteries of the ages?
He remembers
his last experience with you.
Ha-ha-ha. You're not still
bothered by that minor mishap?
We were buried alive.
That's minor?
If I taught you
anything at university,
it's that the search for truth...
is never easy, MacGyver.
Oh.
Besides, we got out.
Thanks to you.
And the medallion proved
that Solon was at Thera,
looking for the Treasure
of Atlantis.
Professor Carson didn't think so.
Carson!
That pompous fool.
He still thinks
that Atlantis is a fairy tale.
Fairy tale, I ask you.
But I'll prove him wrong,
when we find the Torch of Truth.
You really think it's here, huh?
Oh, yes.
After Solon left on his quest,
his disciples left Athens
and sailed to England,
mm, uh, looking for refuge
in caves near E-Exeter.
Over generations
they formed a religion.
The Cult...
of Solon.
Splendid.
Yes, uh, the Cult,
or descendents of the Cult,
uh, lived peacefully
in England
for hundreds of years,
and that is
until the Romans invaded
and then they were
hunted down and slaughtered.
But a few... survivors escaped,
uh, with the Ark and the Torch,
and sailed from England.
And came to these catacombs.
And then died.
But not before hiding
the Torch somewhere down here.
I'd bet my life on it.
Them's some pretty
high stakes, professor.
Let's hope you don't
lose that bet, huh?
Oh, relax, my boy.
The soldiers don't even know
the catacombs are here.
Colonel Petrovic...
Well...
Wa...
This must be the oldest part
of the catacombs.
These must be the remains
of early Christians
who hid from the Romans.
Over centuries,
others followed,
like the Cult...
of Solon.
Professor, please.
Let's skip the lecture,
find what we came for
and get out of here.
There's a civil war
going on upstairs.
Oh, nonsense, United Nations
ordered a cease-fire.
Yeah, well, I don't
think they care.
Oh, these people never got on.
They've been waging war
amongst themselves
since the 12th century.
When I find the Torch of Truth,
we can use it to continue
Solon's quest,
and find the Treasure of Atlantis,
and there won't
be any more wars.
I can feel it.
I know it.
We're close.
Professor...
The Sigma.
It's the sign of Solon.
MacGyver...
it's...the Ark... of Solon.
Oh... Oh...
It looks so beautiful.
Yeah, it's gorgeous.
Now can we get it
and us out of here?
But just think.
Inside this Ark rests
the Torch of Truth.
Ah, yes.
"Gods march in rank."
Yes! Yes.
"And Hecate races
in the heavens,
"enters the gates of Hades,
"and the Book shall summon
the power of the ancient ones.
"Offer the Torch of Truth
to the Temple of Ages,
and the Treasure
of Atlantis...shall rise."
It's the riddle
of Solon.
Great!
Now can we go?
You are going nowhere.
What?
What is it?
Ah!
Tell me who you were spying for.
United Nations?
U.S. Intelligence?
Who?
We're not spies.
Ah, yes, you are, uh...
...historians.
Historians?
I happen to be
a professor of archaeology.
Give me a light.
Colonel...
does that box really look
like standard espionage gear?
A clever prop to lend
authenticity to your cover.
A prop?
That Ark is a priceless relic,
you buffoon.
In time of war,
the penalty for spying
is immediate execution.
What war?
This area is supposed
to be protected by the U.N.
You are remarkably
well-informed
for one who claims
not to be a spy.
I watch the news.
Then you will know
that this region
belongs to my people
and we will take it.
Even if it means
killing innocent people
who happen to live here?
We must cleanse the area.
You're talking
ethnic cleansing.
That's racial genocide.
Look, pal, the whole world
has been watching
what's been going on around here.
Now, you can call it
whatever you want.
But it's murder.
Pure and simple.
Exactly, now for the last time,
we were sent by the Royal Academy
of Archaeological Science
in London, England.
You are already dead.
It is only a question
of how you will die.
Like men, with dignity,
or screaming in agony.
Either way, you will tell me
who you are spying for.
Hey.
Stop that, MacGyver.
Ah!
Leave him.
Leave him alone.
No.
Thank you for your knife.
This will make a great cigar box.
Gentlemen...
I wouldn't come too close
to the door if I were you.
Have someone guard
the prisoners.
You, stay here.
Yes, sir.
Of all the asinine,
fool-headed behavior.
You might have been killed.
For what?
For nothing.
Well, what good is that?
Have a little faith, professor.
I'd prefer a hacksaw.
I'm sorry, MacGyver,
I'm afraid we're done for.
I should never have
dragged you into this.
Well, no one twisted my arm.
No, you don't understand.
I lied.
The Academy didn't send me.
In fact, the, uh, directors,
uh, revoked my tenure.
I mean to put it simply...
I was sacked.
Who financed the expedition?
I did, I thought
that if I could find the Torch,
prove Atlantis really existed,
then the Academy
would reinstate me.
It took all my savings
to get this far.
I could barely afford
the telegram I sent
asking you to come.
I hate to deceive you
like that, but, uh,
I had no other option.
Uh, you must believe me.
I was at the end of my rope,
MacGyver.
Oh, please understand, I mean,
y-you were the only person
that I could turn to.
Story of my life.
Anyway, it's useless,
I mean, the Ark's
in the hands of a fanatic
who thinks that it's a cigar box.
And the key that opens it
is a thousand miles
away at the Royal Academy
in London.
MacGyver, i-is there a purpose
behind these acrobatics?
Oh, I hope so.
Watch your eyes.
Bravo.
I always said you were
my brightest student.
If only you had applied
yourself at university.
Professor!
Quite right.
Carry on.
Looks like that gate's
the only way out of here.
Come on.
Put this on.
What?
I'm not leaving without the Ark.
Professor--
MacGyver, the Torch of Truth
is in that Ark.
I'm not leaving
without it.
All right.
Understood.
The final shipment of arms
is being unloaded now,
Colonel Petrovic.
Good.
A schedule has been
brought forward.
We attack in two hours.
If the prisoners are spies,
the U.N. forces
may know of our plans.
We should strike at once.
Could these men
be telling the truth?
That old chest--
It does not matter.
They are to be
executed immediately.
Those barbarians must have
tried to force it open. Look.
I don't know, professor.
This scratch
looks pretty old.
The Ark's magnetic.
Yeah, let's check it
out later, come on.
There's no engine!
That'll keep 'em out for a while.
And us in.
Shh, quiet!
Sound the alarm.
Come on, MacGyver,
they know we've escaped.
We haven't yet.
Give me a hand here.
No one left through the gate.
Search every inch of this place.
Find them and kill them.
Load it up, professor.
What?
You sure this will work?
Nope.
Good.
That's the MacGyver I know.
Open this up.
Looks like they're gonna
open the door for us.
Get some men over here!
Yes, sir.
Now what are you doing?
Trying to stop some
ethnic cleansing.
Buckle up.
It worked! It worked!
Ha-ha-ha!
I knew it would.
I always said you were
my brightest student.
It worked.
All living things
contain carbon.
In fact, the term "organic"
is often defined as
"containing carbon."
One carbon isotope present
in all living forms
is carbon-14,
which has a half-life
of 5,730 years.
Meaning
in that amount of time,
half the carbon-14
of a dead organism will decay.
By measuring the ratio
of the remaining carbon-14,
we can determine the life
of an organic sample,
such as the cloth
of an Egyptian mummy,
or the ashes of a caveman's fire.
Tomorrow I'll demonstrate
this process
in the university lab.
Hiya.
MacGyver.
Is it really you?
I think so.
How are you, Kelly?
I didn't think I'd see you again
after you left Thera.
What's it been, four years?
Five.
Ah.
This is for you, teach.
Are you finally
flirting with me?
Um...
Actually, it's a bribe.
I need your help.
Funny. Didn't think
you needed anyone's help.
You'd be surprised.
What is that?
Some kind of oxidized matter.
Yeah, it's off an artifact
Professor Atticus and I found.
"Atlantis" Atticus?
My grandfather
still talks about him,
none too fondly,
I might add.
Yeah, I'll bet.
We just got back
from the Balkans.
What was the artifact
you found?
A metal box.
An Ark.
The Ark of Solon?
Atticus thinks so.
But that's incredible.
The Ark of Solon is like
the Loch Ness Monster
of archaeology.
People think it's a legend.
Isn't it supposed to hold the
Torch of Truth from Atlantis?
Don't know.
We haven't opened it yet.
This came off a scratch
on the side.
Can you analyze it for me,
please?
Sure. I'll run some tests
in the lab.
Thanks.
Would you like to carry my books?
Yeah, sure.
What a madhouse.
How do you stand the noise?
This is the rush hour.
You should be here
when it's really quiet.
It's enough to drive you batty.
Kelly!
I'm so sorry
I missed your lecture.
It's impossible London traffic.
Hello, Simon.
Oh, do you remember--?
MacGyver.
Professor Carson.
You were at Thera
with that buffoon, Atticus.
Nearly got yourselves killed,
poking around the ruins.
MacGyver and Atticus have found
the Ark of Solon.
Isn't that amazing?
So Atticus is still hunting
for the mythical Atlantis, is he?
Heh.
The man will never learn.
But if the Ark is genuine,
and the Torch is inside,
it's the greatest find
of the century.
Where is this so-called Ark?
The Royal Academy, sir.
Well, I'll go and see for myself.
We have to run some tests.
I'll meet you
back at your hotel room.
Don't be long.
My flight back to Greece
leaves this afternoon.
Nice talking to you.
The years haven't mellowed him.
No.
That's my grandfather.
I thought he never left Greece.
I made the mistake
of telling him
that the university
had offered me tenure.
So he made a special trip
to talk me into accepting.
According to Simon, staying at
the university will mature me,
like I was a bottle of wine
or a wedge of cheese.
What's with this "Simon" thing?
He doesn't like
being called grandfather.
Says it makes him feel old.
Simon's planned my whole life.
It's all right
for him to spend his time
digging in ancient ruins,
but I'm supposed to
stay at the university
and have a solid career.
Which, roughly translated,
means a safe career.
Well, what do you want?
A challenge.
Right now teaching
is just repeating
what I already know.
I want to get out,
see the world,
learn new things.
So get out. See the world.
Learn some new things.
I don't want to disappoint Simon.
He raised me
after my parents died.
Helped me earn my Ph.D.
And I owe him so much.
But sometimes he can be so...
Demanding?
Hm. More like tyrannical.
Kelly...
It's your life.
It should be your decision.
I wish I had as much confidence
in me as you do.
I shouldn't admit this,
but when we were in Thera,
I had the most awful crush
on you.
Me? Really?
Perfect timing.
That's odd.
What?
Well, the Ark of Solon was made
around the 6th Century B.C.,
in Athens during the Iron Age.
But according to this,
the tool that dented it
was made from tin,
and judging
by these trace elements,
it came from the mines in
Cornwall during pre-Roman times.
Cornwall?
Isn't that near Exeter?
Yes.
Why, does it mean something?
I'd better get to the academy.
May I go with you?
Yeah.
So why do you think
your grandfather's
so hostile about Atlantis?
If Atlantis was real,
it would mean rewriting
the history books.
I thought that was
an archaeologist's job,
to rewrite history.
I guess some people
are frightened of change.
Yes?
MacGyver and Miss Carson
have arrived.
They're about to open the Ark.
Good.
You know what to do.
"Atlantis anaduotai."
"Atlantis rises."
The words on the medallion
and the Ark are identical.
Coincidence.
You can't expect us
to believe these two artifacts
are in any way connected.
"The gods march in rank,
"and Hecate races
in the heavens.
"Enter the gates of Hades,
"and the Book shall summon
the power of the ancient ones.
Offer the Torch of Truth
to the Temple of Ages--"
"And the Treasure
of Atlantis shall rise."
I've seen this riddle
in the caves at Exeter,
carved on an altar
by the Cult of Solon.
So the gods are these figures
on the side here?
Yes.
Hermes, Aphrodite,
Gaea, Selene,
Ares, Zeus and Cronus.
This little guy on top, um,
how do you pronounce it?
Hecate.
Demon of the night.
According to ancient legend,
she was an omen of disaster
and death.
I'm convinced that these
are really instructions
written by Solon to help find
the Treasure of Atlantis.
Addle-minded bunk.
The legend of Atlantis
is just that, a legend.
I can prove it existed.
Now, inside this Ark
is a relic of Atlantis itself.
The Torch of Truth.
Where is the director
with his key
to open the blasted
display case?
Uh, professor,
Kelly discovered something
you might want to--
Professor Atticus.
I've just been on the phone
to the Balkan Embassy.
They say that you
and Mr. MacGyver are thieves.
Oh, do you hear that, MacGyver?
First we are spies,
now we are thieves.
They claim the Ark
is a national treasure,
and demand its return.
You can't return it
to those butchers.
It belongs to the world.
You have no say in the matter.
I'll remind you,
Professor Atticus,
that you no longer work here.
Oh, Mr. Director,
this Ark contains
the missing link to Atlantis,
an unknown chapter in history.
If you'll just
open the display case
and let us get hold
of that medallion.
Excuse me, can I see that?
The medallion's magnetic.
Yeah, so's the Ark.
A magnetic lock and key.
Impossible.
The people of Solon's time
had no concept
of the physics of magnetism.
Ah, but legend says
the people of Atlantis did,
and Solon somehow must have
learned it from them.
Pure speculation.
Ha-ha-ha!
You won't think so
when you see
what's inside this Ark.
That's it, this is it.
This is it.
It works.
It works, it works.
Oh, after all
these years, MacGyver.
Ha-ha-ha!
At long last.
The Torch of Truth.
I... I don't understand.
I knew this was a waste of time.
But the Torch must be in here.
It isn't, because it never existed.
The Torch is a myth,
like Atlantis.
But the medallion
did open the Ark.
If that much
of the legend is true,
maybe the rest is too.
Look, if I could
take the Ark to Thera
and solve the riddle of Solon,
uh, I know that I could prove
that the ruined city there
was Atlantis and find the treasure.
You and MacGyver caused enough
trouble on Thera five years ago.
Simon, you told me the best tool
an archaeologist has
is an open mind.
I won't have my work
disrupted again by Atticus
and his idiotic notions
about a super-civilization.
Simon, you are still
a blinkered old fool!
I have no time for this.
I have a plane to catch
back to Greece.
Come along, Kelly,
I'll give you a ride
to the university.
I'm not going back there, Simon.
What are you saying?
I've decided
I'd like to stay here
and work with Atticus and MacGyver.
Kelly, you're a scholar, girl,
not a treasure hunter.
All my life,
I've done what you want.
I'm quite capable
of making up my own mind.
First you and MacGyver
disrupted my work on Thera,
and now you've poisoned
my granddaughter's mind.
No.
It's my decision.
Fine. Go ahead.
Throw away your academic career,
if you want.
When you regain your senses,
let me know.
I'm going back to Thera,
which I'm telling you
for the last time,
is not Atlantis,
because Atlantis never existed.
The Ark will be returned
to the Balkans immediately.
Meanwhile, I'd appreciate it
if you'd clear out
your former office,
and remove yourself
from the premises.
Professor.
Come on.
Why wasn't the Torch in the Ark?
Well, it probably was at one time.
You said the Cult of Solon
lived in some caves
near Exeter, right?
Of course.
That cut in the Ark was made
by a tool forged near there.
You mean the cult opened the Ark
and removed the Torch?
Call the police.
Hey!
A man planted on the inside
fires a tranquilizer dart,
escapes in a dummy cab
to a waiting speedboat.
I think we can safely say this
was no ordinary smash and grab.
No, this was planned
like a military operation.
Isn't that an awful lot
of trouble to go through
to steal artifacts?
The Ark and the medallion
would sell for millions
on the black market.
Inspector Rhodes,
this just came in.
Thank you.
Now, we ran your description
of the thief through Interpol.
Is this the man?
No, I-- I didn't get
a good look at him.
I did.
That's the guy.
Yannis Zavros.
A general in the Greek army,
until he was court-martialed.
For what?
He's the leader
of a militant group of fanatics
who claim Macedonia
as their birthright.
They see themselves as the heirs
of Alexander the Great.
And why would
he want artifacts?
We suspect
he's been funding his cause
by selling stolen relics on
the international black market.
His known associate
is Cyril Cleeve.
Cleeve?!
What? You know him?
I'm afraid I do.
He was a student of mine,
a few years after you.
He had no interest in history,
only in hunting treasure.
He's Lord Cleeve now.
He bought the title,
along with an estate
in Plymouth.
Rather more
respectable image
than the godfather
of artifact smugglers.
So why don't you
just arrest him?
We have no evidence.
Cleeve's always very careful
to layer himself.
He always uses a middleman
or a stooge
to do the dirty work.
By now he's probably smuggled
the Ark and the medallion
out of the country and locked in
some private collector's vault
where we'll never find them.
I had no idea that trading
on artifacts
had become such a problem.
The international trade in
stolen antiquities and fine art
is very big business,
second only to narcotics.
We just don't have the manpower
to stop every smuggler,
especially a major player
like Cleeve.
So, what, he gets off,
just like that?
Look, I don't like it
anymore than you do.
I do what I can,
but I gave up expecting miracles
a long time ago.
All right, professor,
what's going on?
MacGyver, what are you doing?
You heard Inspector Rhodes.
He said both the artifacts
were missing.
When I tried to stop
that little--
That Zavros, I saw him
drop the medallion.
Now, where is it?
Where is it?!
I hid it in my office
before the police came.
You stole
the medallion?
Oh, purely for safekeeping.
Why?
I had no choice,
MacGyver.
You don't realize
what's at stake.
I'd say about 20 years...
for robbery.
I can explain
everything.
My office is this way.
Come on. In you come.
It's been torn apart.
All right, don't touch anything.
I'll call the police.
Nonsense, this is how
it always looks!
A neat office is the product
of an empty mind!
Professor?
Just a moment, MacGyver.
Hold your horses.
Ah. There we are, safe and sound.
Just as I promised.
Now, what's going on?
Ah, yes, well, that requires
some explaining.
Yes.
We are here.
You said the riddle on the Ark
was a set of instructions?
Exactly. And if, uh,
Cleeve stole the Ark,
it can only mean
that he's after the treasure!
Is there some reason you cou--?
Is there some reason
you couldn't have told
the police that?
You heard Rhodes.
He's got his hands full.
Besides, we're running out
of time as it is.
Now, now. Where's--?
Where's my journal?
D-d-don't...
Don't, uh--
Don't touch...
anything.
What do you mean,
we're running out of time?
That's right.
In fact,
we've only got two days
to find the treasure.
I can't even find my journal.
Why only two days?
Ah! Ha.
Success.
Professor, why only two days?
Because that is when
the first line of Solon's riddle
comes true.
I copied it, uh--
Uh, from an altar I found in--
In the caves at Exeter.
Where is it?
Hm. There we are.
There you are.
"When the gods march in rank."
What does it mean?
Well, you saw the carvings
on the Ark.
Now,
as you know--
I mean, when the Romans adopted
the Greek gods,
they gave them new names.
Now, let's see, uh,
Hermes became Mercury.
Aphrodite, Venus.
Gaea, the Earth.
And Selene became Luna,
the moon.
Ares, Mars.
Zeus, Jupiter.
And Cronus, Saturn.
"The gods march in rank."
Exactly.
Now, according
to Royal Observatory records,
uh, this orbital alignment
happens only once
every five hundred years.
And it will next take place
in two days.
And that, I mean, if we are
to believe Solon's riddle,
is when the Treasure
of Atlantis rises.
But where is the treasure?
Well, legend says
that it's hidden
in the Tower of Fear.
And, uh, the Greek word
for "fear" of course, is, uh...
...Thera.
Uh, where's the picture?
There-- There--
There was a picture.
The picture.
Where's the picture?
Yes. I'll show you.
Ah, here we are.
Yes, here we are.
That's it.
And there I am, MacGyver.
There I am
with your grandfather,
and there is the Tower.
Professor, you know
that volcano is still active.
Yes, I know.
But there are ruins
near the crater.
Simon took me there once.
That's right.
And in two days,
when the planets align,
we must offer up
the Torch of Truth
to the Temple of Ages
and reveal the treasure.
And that is why it is essential
we find the--
The Torch.
But if the cult took the Torch
from the Ark,
where did they put it?
Well, they probably hid it
in the safest place they knew.
The caves of Exeter.
The cult made
these paintings of Atlantis
based on descriptions
from the platinum book itself.
It must have been paradise.
Yes.
Torch of Truth, I presume.
Yes, that's right. Yes.
It doesn't tell us much.
What does it look like?
Well, nobody knows
exactly.
I mean, these are the only
visual representations
that I've seen.
Well, how can we find
the Torch
if we don't know
what it looks like?
Well, Solon says that
it's the mirror of the world,
reflecting the past,
present, and future.
Professor, you said the cult
was driven out by the Romans.
Yes, the ones that weren't killed
uh, fled with the Ark.
But they thought Solon
was coming back
for the Torch someday.
Yes, that's right.
That's right, yes.
Well, maybe they hid it
where they figured
only he could find it.
Maybe.
Is this the same writing
that's on the Ark?
Yes, yes, this is the, uh,
riddle of Solon.
These streaks look like rust.
Iron ore.
The altar's magnetic.
Let's check it out.
Wow. I guess.
Professor, let's see the medallion.
Have you got an idea, MacGyver?
Well, if the cult took the Torch
out of the Ark,
maybe they built a bigger,
better one.
But where is it?
I think we're in it.
Are you suggesting
that this entire chamber
is a giant Ark?
This could be the key.
Then we need to find a keyhole.
Maybe not.
The Torch of Truth.
It's more magnificent
than I ever imagined.
Wait a minute.
Just wait.
I guess it's all right.
You're wrong.
These caves are full
of unpleasant surprises,
I'm afraid.
Lord Cleeve, at your service.
I owe you a debt of thanks,
Mr. MacGyver.
And you too, Miss Carson.
Now, if you'd mind
just handing over the Torch
to my partner.
Partner?
I'm truly sorry, MacGyver.
I don't like this, Cleeve.
You promised not to hurt them.
I wouldn't dream of it,
but we can hardly have them
following us, now can we?
I trusted you.
How can you do this, Atticus?
You're not a criminal.
We have what we came for.
Let's get out of here.
General Zavros has a point.
Let's go, professor.
The Treasure of Atlantis awaits.
Lord Cleeve is right.
We cannot afford
to have you follow us.
Oh, MacGyver!
Kelly, try to get this rope
over your head.
Come on.
Ohhh!
Oh!
You okay?
I can't believe Atticus
would do that.
Oh.
His passion, Cleeve's greed.
It makes sense.
I'm sorry.
I know you looked up to him.
Used to.
We did exactly
what Cleeve wanted us to.
Now he and Zavros
are going to steal
the Treasure of Atlantis,
thanks to us.
Maybe not.
Cleeve's estate.
Let's find it.
Kind of looks like
they're planning a trip.
We can't let them take off
with the artifacts.
I know.
Wait here.
Just look at it.
Unlike anything the world
has seen in thousands of years.
It is truly magnificent.
Probably the finest item
I'll ever acquire.
It should fetch millions.
Money?
Is that all that it means to you?
Money bought me my title.
This estate.
And now it'll help me
go down in history
as the discoverer
of the Treasure of Atlantis.
Sorry, co-discoverer.
You think you can buy your way
into the history books?
I wouldn't be the first.
Come in.
Anybody.
Answer me, please?
Come in, this is an emergency.
Have a sherry to celebrate.
I may be forced to work with you,
but don't expect me to enjoy it.
Please, professor,
spare me the hypocrisy.
You and I are two of a kind.
Now, Zavros,
he only wants the money
to fund his little revolution
in Macedonia.
But you and I share
the same dream,
to find the Treasure of Atlantis,
no matter what it takes,
or what the cost.
Go on.
Kelly.
Miss Carson.
Hey, now, there's no need
to be rough with her.
If she's here,
so is MacGyver.
General Zavros is right.
Where is MacGyver?
Answer him.
Tell us where MacGyver is.
I'm not going
to tell you anything.
Kelly, I-I do think
you should answer them.
I don't betray my friends.
I'll make her talk.
Hold it!
Ah, Mr. MacGyver,
we've been expecting you.
You should know
your partner here
tried to kill us.
Cleeve! Is this true?
Don't be naive.
Did you really think
I'd leave them to follow us
or call the police?
Good thinking.
We didn't come alone.
Oh, come on.
You don't think I'm gonna fall
for an old trick like that?
No!
Yeah, sure,
now who's side are you on?
Yours.
Can we discuss it later?
He's got a point, MacGyver.
Come on.
Which way?
The plane.
Oh, MacGyver...
Uh, MacGyver.
There's something
I've got to tell you.
Later. Get in.
Um...
The window!
There's no key
for the magneto switch.
That was what
I was trying to tell you.
I removed it
so they couldn't take off
with the artifacts.
That's a great idea.
Where is it?
Out there.
That's a bad idea.
They're getting away!
That was close.
Bravo.
Well done, MacGyver.
I knew you'd get us
out of that mess.
I always said
you're my brightest student.
I'm sorry.
You've every right
to be angry with me.
I was wrong.
I was foolish to think
that I could control Cleeve.
You almost got us killed!
You must believe me.
I never meant any harm
to come to you or Kelly.
The truth is, I was frightened.
I'd lost my position
at the academy.
I was desperate.
I mean, this is my last chance.
I couldn't bear the thought
of losing it.
I thought you hated
treasure hunters like Cleeve.
I do.
But finding
the Treasure of Atlantis
means more than wealth.
It would prove
that Atlantis really did exist
and there were times
when people didn't live
by war and conquest,
but worshiped peace
and knowledge.
And if we were like that once,
maybe we can be like that again.
It's a nice dream.
I'm convinced
that it can become a reality.
It's a wonderful dream,
professor.
But did it ever occur to you
that Cleeve might have
other plans for the treasure?
Do you think he and Zavros
will come after us?
Yes.
Yes, I do.
The Tower of Fear.
The Treasure of Atlantis
lies somewhere
in that crater.
Looks inviting.
The last time
they had a major eruption,
it destroyed half the island,
along with Atlantis.
Beautiful.
Simon?
Simon!
Oh, God, no.
This is Cleeve's doing.
He has a concussion,
possibly a subdural hematoma.
I can do more when we get him
to a hospital in Athens,
but he's too weak to move.
All I can do now
is make him comfortable.
Well, don't worry.
I'll stay with him.
(speaks in Greek)
Looks like he's going
to be all right.
And the doctor's going
to stay with him
until he's well enough
to be moved.
But all the maps and the charts
of the volcano have gone.
Damn.
Cleeve and Zavros are probably
in the crater by now.
Tonight the planets align,
and they'll steal the treasure.
And it's all my fault.
I wish I'd never heard
of Atlantis.
That's weird.
What?
The lid.
It's not magnetic.
How can that be?
Well, I don't know.
W-what are you doing?
Trust me, professor,
trust me.
It's platinum.
That's why it's not magnetic.
I've never seen markings
like this before.
It can mean
only one thing.
It must be a page
from the Book of Atlantis,
hidden there
by Solon himself.
Kelly, can you take us
into the crater?
Yes.
If we leave now,
we can make it before sunset.
Come on.
Well, it looks like
it was a temple.
Strange place for one.
Great place to hide
a treasure though.
Well, if there was an entrance,
it's long since been destroyed.
Here.
Let's clear it.
In ya go, MacGyver.
MacGyver.
Did you find anything?
Oh, yeah.
Bigtime.
Incredible.
Look familiar?
A Copernican model
of the solar system.
Built thousands of years
before Copernicus was born.
The planets must be orbiting
closer to the alignment.
The gravitational shift
of the alignment's
making the volcano unstable.
I hate when that happens.
Solon said,
"Enter the Gates of Hades."
Well, what are we waiting for?
Ah!
Poor devil.
What triggered it?
Do you think it's Cleeve?
Fortunately, not.
You all remember General Zavros,
my ex-associate.
You terminate all
your partnerships like this?
On the contrary.
General Zavros
did it to himself.
As you can see, greed,
heedless of caution,
is a highly combustible mixture.
I, on the other hand,
am a very cautious fellow.
So I waited for you to arrive
to show us a way past this...
impediment.
Why should we help you?
Because the length of your lives
is directly proportionate
to how useful you are to me.
MacGyver, there must be a way
we can de-activate this fire.
Well, I suggest you find it...
quickly.
Maybe the answer's
in the first line
of Solon's riddle.
What do you think?
"The gods march in r--
Rank."
Yeah.
That one.
Kelly, you wanna hand me
that platinum page?
It's a key.
Mercury...Venus...Earth...
the moon...
Well done, MacGyver.
Now I see why you were
Atticus' favorite student.
But what's this red crystal?
Perhaps it's a star.
We're not here
to discuss astronomy.
After you, MacGyver.
Keep moving!
MacGyver.
It's wonderful.
It's remarkable.
Tremendous.
Look, at long last.
The Temple of Ages!
This statue's extraordinary.
I've never seen anything like it.
I don't think it's a statue.
You're right.
I believe
we have discovered
Solon himself.
He must have been caught
in a volcanic eruption,
and covered in hot ash.
Like the bodies at Pompeii.
He's hanging on to something here.
It's the platinum book.
Yes, like the page we found
inside the Ark.
Yes, well I think
I'd better hold onto that.
Might just help defray some
of my traveling expenses.
Look!
The gods march in rank.
The riddle says
when the planets are aligned,
we'll find
the Treasure of Atlantis.
Where is it?
The red crystal.
The one in the observatory?
We forgot the second line
of the riddle.
"Hecate races in the heavens."
The planets alone isn't enough
to reveal the treasure.
It takes something more.
Hecate has to appear.
Who the devil's Hecate?
A demon of the night
who rides a chariot of fire.
There she is.
A meteor shower.
Unless I miss my guess,
the extra gravity oughta do it.
The Temple.
Where's the treasure?
Where is it?
Professor.
I'm coming.
What's the line
in the riddle about, uh,
the ancients and the Book.
"The Book shall summon up
the power of the ancient ones."
The Book shall summon the power.
The Book.
Give me the Book.
You want the treasure,
give me the Book.
These aren't book pages.
But what else could they be?
They're punch cards.
It must be an ancient...
...computer.
It's a computer,
and these cards program it.
Kelly, slide these in
where the symbols match.
Professor, let me see the Torch.
Here.
But how does it run?
A computer needs electricity.
Maybe not.
The people of Atlantis tapped
into the volcano for power.
They used geothermal technology.
You mean this thing runs on heat?
No.
Steam.
Look!
Treasure chests.
Stay back.
It's nothing but paper.
Worthless scrolls.
Where's the treasure?
I think you're looking at it.
That's right.
Solon himself said
the Treasure of Atlantis
has the power
to command men's minds.
Of course, books.
No.
It can't be true.
The Treasure of Atlantis...
is knowledge.
There has to be more.
No!
You're destroying the scrolls!
Get away you stupid old fool.
I want treasure.
We gotta go.
But all this knowledge.
We can't let it be destroyed.
Kelly, come on!
Come on, Kelly!
Forget that.
Well, that's our only way out.
Maybe we can tap into
a little geothermal power
of our own.
Geothermal power?
Professor.
Yes?
Stuff your jacket
into one of those pipes.
Put a rock on top of it.
Kelly, stand by the Torch.
Well, whatever you've got
in mind, MacGyver, hurry.
Stand back, professor.
All right, Kelly, hit it.
Shut it off, Kelly.
All right, come up here.
Professor, mind the Torch.
You all right with this?
Yeah.
Hang on.
Hit it.
All right, stop it.
All right, professor.
Your turn.
Come on.
Top rope.
Hang on.
Oh, blast.
Hold on, MacGyver.
Pull it, Kelly.
Pull!
Come on. Come on.
Thanks.
Oh.
Let's go.
Thousands of years ago,
before time itself was measured,
as we know it,
there...
was...
Atlantis.
It was a great city,
dedicated to art and science.
And the people of Atlantis lived
in high-rise buildings,
and had indoor plumbing.
They also invented
geothermal technology,
and there are
even more important lessons
to learn from Atlantis.
Now then, what are they?
Yes, Brian.
They created democracy.
Very good. Yes.
Another. Taylor.
They abolished slavery.
Excellent, excellent.
Liam.
There were no executions.
Yes, that's true.
Joanna.
Men and women
were treated as equals.
That's right, that's right.
At the back, Sam.
They believed in peace,
not war.
Absolutely right.
Now can you tell me,
what was
the Treasure of Atlantis?
Knowledge.
I can't hear you.
I still can't hear you.
Knowledge!
Absolutely correct. Knowledge.
You are all
my brightest students.