[Insects Buzzing]
[Birds Chirping]
[Train Horn Blowing]
[Horn Blowing]
[Train Clattering]
[Railroad Crossing Bell Clanging]
[Clanging Continues]
♪♪ [Rockabilly]
♪♪ [Continues]
[Elvis Presley]
♪ Train I ride ♪
♪ Sixteen coaches long ♪
♪ Well, that long, black train ♪
♪ Got my baby and gone ♪
♪ Train, train ♪
♪ Comin' round, round the bend ♪
♪ Comin' round the bend ♪
♪ Well, it took my baby ♪
♪ But it never will again ♪
♪ No, not again ♪
♪ Train, train ♪
♪ Comin' down, down the line ♪
♪ Comin' down the line ♪
[Speaking Japanese]
It's been such a long time.
It seems like we've been
on this train forever.
Hey!
Ah?
How much longer till Memphis?
Two more days.
There's a time difference in America.
♪ Train, train ♪
♪ Comin' round, round the bend ♪
♪ Round, round the bend ♪
♪ Train, train ♪
♪ Comin' round and round the bend ♪
♪ Round the bend ♪
♪ Well, it took my baby ♪
♪ But it never will again ♪
♪ Never will again ♪
♪ Ooh, wooh ♪
♪ Wooh ♪♪
[Man]
Memphis. Memphis, Tennessee.
All off for Memphis.
[Japanese]
Jun! Memphis — we're here! We're here!
[Brakes Squealing]
And two days early too.
[Man On P.A.]
Attention, passengers.
City of New Orleans
now departing for Batesville...
Winona, McComb and New Orleans.
Track 3. All aboard.
[Bell Tolling In Distance]
[Train Horn Blows]
[Horn Blowing]
Aah!
[Echoing]
Great echo.
[Men Chattering]
[Speaking English] Hi.
Yeah.
[Japanese]
It's a lot different than Yokohama station.
I like Yokohama station better.
It's modern.
Are you kidding?
Memphis station is a lot better.
It's antique and has a nice atmosphere.
I like Yokohama station better.
Modern atmosphere.
I like it here better.
Uh, excuse me. Excuse me.
Y'all got some... matches?
"Matches"?
Yes. Matches.
Oh! Matches.
Matches.
Yes, please!
[Japanese]
A light.
[Japanese] Thanks.
[Japanese] You're welcome.
Hey. He spoke Japanese.
[Japanese]
Thank you very much!
[Man On P.A.]
Attention, passengers.
The River Cities,
originating in Kansas City,
has been delayed in
Carbondale, Illinois.
She will be arriving 5:05 p.m. on Track 3.
[Japanese]
Sun Studio's at 706 Union Avenue.
But you know, I still would rather
go to Graceland first...
Elvis's house.
Sun Studio first.
[English]
Carl Perkins, Howling Wolf...
Jerry Lee Lewis, Roy Orbison...
[Japanese]
they all recorded there.
Not just Elvis.
Carl Perkins.
Yeah, but Elvis is still the King.
[Sighs]
Okay, okay.
Graceland first,
just to get it out of the way.
Then we'll go to Graceland first?
Great!
Let's go.
Wait.
Maybe we should go to Sun Studio.
No. Graceland.
- [Children Shouting In Distance]
[Dog Barking]
[English]
"Chowser Street."
[Vehicle Horn Honking]
[Japanese]
Look! Sun Studio.
I thought we were going to Graceland.
Yeah, so did I.
[Woman]
Hi. How y'all doin' today?
Would you please organize yourselves
in a little line right here?
Tour's about to begin.
The Sun Record Company
in Memphis, Tennessee...
was first opened by radio announcer and record
engineer Sam Phillips in the year 1952.
His first objective was to record
some of the race music...
that had come up from the Delta,
but was being recorded up north.
Sam thought — and I quote — "Well, why should they have to
go up north to record it when I can record it right here?"
Well, it was right here in this very room where Mr. Phillips
recorded the likes of Howlin' Wolf, Rufus Thomas...
Charlie Feathers, the Prisonaires,
James Cotton, Johnny Cash...
Billy Lee Riley, Carl Perkins, Roy Orbison,
Jerry Lee Lewis...
and, of course, the king of rock and roll
himself — Elvis Presley.
In June 1953, this young man just graduated
from Humes High School...
and he found his way on over
to Sun Studio and recorded a song...
that he said was for his
mom's birthday, but
his mom's birthday was
months away, so...
Anyway, Sam finally found a song he liked
and he said — and I quote —
"That's what I like. That's
what I'm lookin' for.
That's more like it. Y'all
keep playin'." End quote.
Well, they were excited. They got a song
that was soon played on the radio...
by deejay Dewey Phillips in the year 1954,
probably July 9 or 10.
He would have to play that song somewhere
between seven and 11 times that night.
Well, the switchboard stayed lit up there.
People wanted to know
if he was black, if he was white.
White callers would call.
Black callers would call.
The bottom line was
the song was gonna be a hit.
[Rapid Chattering In Japanese]
She talks so fast.
I'm all worn out.
Not Graceland right now.
Is that okay?
Yeah. It's okay with me.
But I was sort of looking forward
to Graceland.
Really? I thought you didn't want to go.
Let's just walk around.
Okay.
Hey, my turn in front.
[Children Chanting Jump Rope Rhyme]
[Fishing Reel Spinning]
[Man]
Jesus. What am I — fuckin' stupid?
Hi. Fish?
Uh, no. Just...
[Fly Buzzing]
Mmm! Cadillac.
[Train Horn Blows In Distance]
[Siren Wailing In Distance]
[Dog Barking In Distance]
Elvis Presley.
[English]
King.
[Japanese]
Carl Perkins was better.
Elvis.
Carl Perkins.
[English]
King.
[Tires Screeching In Distance]
You know, Memphis does look
like Yokohama.
Just more space.
If you took away
60% of the buildings in Yokohama...
it would look like this.
This doesn't look anything like Yokohama.
This is America. And the city of Elvis.
We didn't have Elvis in Japan.
This is nothing like Japan.
[English]
Tobacco.
[Woman] Oh, fuck. Don't get in
my brother's shit like that.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
[Man] What the fuck is wrong with you?
Come jumpin' down my collar.
[Woman]
You got a lot of nerve —
[Arguing Continues, Indistinct]
[Japanese]
Look! A hotel.
Looks like a fun one.
Should we stay there?
[Man] Hey, silver fox!
Where's the fire? Where you goin'?
♪♪ [Radio: Man Singing Soul]
Well, what about on Jupiter?
At the time of his death,
if he were on Jupiter, uh...
Elvis would've weighed 648 pounds.
648?
Damn.
Hi! Good night!
Good night. How may I help you?
Um, we would like
most cheap room, please.
Do you have?
All our rooms for two people
are the same rate.
Oh.
[Japanese] What'd he say?
I'm not exactly sure.
I'm sorry. That is too expensive.
Our rooms are $22 per night.
For two.
Pay in advance.
Ah. I see.
[Japanese]
I think it's $22.
Okay.
Ten, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19...
Twenty-two.
Okay. Thank you.
This night, $22.
Thank you.
[Loud Ding]
Room 27.
And don't forget to, uh,
help 'em with the luggage.
Thank you.
Good night. Have a nice job.
Good night. Have a nice night.
[Girl]
Thank you!
[Out Of Breath]
[Japanese]
There he is again.
Yeah, and no Carl Perkins.
[Switch Clicks]
[Water Faucet Turns On, Off]
[Exhales]
No TV.
[Footsteps]
Ah! Yes, hello! Thank you!
Please wait.
Yeah, sure. You're welcome.
Please wait. Thank you.
[Train Horn Blowing In Distance]
Please. This plum from Japan.
Please.
From Japan?
Yes. This plum from Japan.
Thank you.
- [Door Opens, Closes]
[Fly Buzzing]
[Camera Motor Whirs]
[Shutter Snaps, Motor Whirs]
[Japanese]
Watch it.
Jun, why do you always take pictures
of the rooms we stay in...
and never what we see outside
while we travel?
Those other things are in my memory.
The hotel rooms and the airports
are the things I'll forget.
Yeah. I guess so.
Oh. Did I show you my
important discoveries?
[Clattering In Corridor]
[Bellhop, Muffled]
Room 25.
Look at him.
Hmm?
[English]
King.
Study his face carefully.
Now look at this.
This guy was an ancient
Middle Eastern king.
Looks just like him, right?
Elvis as the Buddha.
[Laughs]
[Both Chuckling]
And ta-da!
[English]
Special!
[Japanese] The Statue of Liberty
in New York — she's Elvis too.
See?
Mmm.
Elvis was even more influential
than I thought.
That's right.
There's one more.
Here. Look.
Madonna looks like Elvis too.
Oh, no, not Madonna.
Give me a break.
[Sighs]
♪♪ [Radio: Funk]
Well, I don't think
you should eat that thing.
Yeah, you're probably right.
You gonna eat it?
No. I ain't gonna eat that thing.
Hey. That's my plum.
Jun, why do you always have
such a sad face?
Are you unhappy?
I'm very happy.
That's just the way my face is.
[Sucking Air]
[Exhales]
Can't I do anything to cheer you up?
[Laughs]
Now you look a little happier.
Wait. Let me light it for you.
Thanks.
So now do you feel a little happier?
I feel the same.
I was already happy.
Don't you think you wear
too much lipstick?
Mmm.
[Purse Clatters]
[Quiet Chuckle]
[Blowing]
[Train Horn Blowing In Distance]
What are you looking at?
Memphis.
Is it like Yokohama
with 60% of the buildings gone?
No, nothing like that.
This isn't Yokohama.
[Train Horn Blowing]
[Jun]
This is America.
What are you thinking about?
To be 18...
feels cool.
And so far from Yokohama.
It feels cool to be in Memphis.
[Chuckles]
Nothing on now.
[Girl Moans Quietly]
[Moaning Louder]
[Girl Moaning]
[Both Gasp Quietly]
[Both Exhale]
Mitzuko.
Hmm?
Do women always worry
about their hairstyle?
What are you talking about?
In all the times we've made love —
And this is number 11...
I've never once
thought about my hairstyle.
[Sighs]
Eleven?
And if that's what you're thinking,
try shaving first next time.
It hurts my face.
But I just shaved two days ago.
[Sighs]
[Switch Clicks]
[Roy Orbison On Radio]
♪ ...that cat called Domino ♪
♪ Domino, Domino ♪
♪ Well, Domino
Go, man, go ♪
♪ Domino, they love you so ♪
♪ Get out of the way
Here comes Domino ♪
♪ Domino, Domino ♪♪
[Radio D.J.]
Thank you, Mel. [Chuckles]
That's Mel, our engineer.
Just coffee, huh?
[Chuckling]
I love ya.
Well, yes, sir, that's another classic
from Mr. Roy Orbison...
along with the Roses — previously known
as the Teen Kings for you trivia fans —
With "Domino" here.
You're on the air until dawn.
It's 2:17 right here in Memphis, Tennessee.
Right now, here's another one recorded at
Sun Studios, this time by the King himself.
That's right. Mr. Elvis Presley...
with one of my personal
early, early morning favorites...
"Blue Moon."
[Elvis Presley]
♪ Blue moon ♪
Jun.
Hmm?
♪ You saw me standing alone ♪
♪ Without a dream in my heart ♪
Hold me.
♪ Without a love of my own ♪
♪ Blue moon ♪
♪ You knew just what
I was there for ♪
[Continues On Radio]
♪ You heard me say a prayer for ♪
♪ Someone I really could care for ♪
♪♪ [Vocalizing]
♪ Without a love of my own ♪
Damn.
You'd think they could get
me a new uniform, man.
This one is shot to hell.
Look at this.
Well, you should do like I do.
Should go over and buy
your own damn clothes...
over at Lansky's or somewhere like that.
I mean, you know, it's like they say —
"The clothes make the man."
I mean, look at that damn hat
on your head.
You look like a damn
mosquito-legged chimpanzee.
I mean — [Laughing]
♪♪ [Vocalizing Continues]
[Birds Chirping]
[Train Horn Blowing In Distance]
Mitzuko.
Wake up. It's morning.
[Moans]
The hotel is on fire.
[Mitzuko]
Mmm.
Don't you want to go to Graceland?
Home of Elvis Presley.
[Moans]
Let me sleep.
It's my favorite thing — to sleep.
You sleep too much.
You spend half your life in your dreams.
Yeah.
But sleep is wonderful.
And when you're dead,
you don't get to sleep ever again.
Which means no more dreams.
Don't forget these.
Those? But they belong to the hotel.
In America, towels are included
in the price of the room.
Everyone knows that.
Well, they won't really fit in here.
That's because you have
a hundred T-shirts in there.
I only brought two shirts.
Get rid of some T-shirts.
No way! They're part of my collection.
We're not getting rid of any of these!
Never, never, never! Never!
Okay then. Go ahead.
But not both of them.
Pack the one I used.
The one I used is drier.
Yeah, but mine's cleaner.
You didn't take a bath.
Pack it neatly.
[Bells Tolling In Distance]
[Gunshot]
Was that a gun?
Probably. This is America.
That's everything, isn't it?
Did we forget anything?
[Man On P.A.]
please pick up the white courtesy phone.
- [Woman] The deceased is your husband?
[Woman #2] Sì.
[Woman #1]
Can you sign right here, please?
And again here.
[Airplane Taking Off]
Please sign here.
[Man On P.A.]
Full boarding call, Flight 203.
And over here.
[Man #2 On P.A., Indistinct]
And here also.
And once more.
Thank you.
[Woman On P.A.]
Otis Johnson.
Otis Johnson, please meet your party
at ticket counter —
[Woman On P.A.] Midwestern Air Flight
310, with connections to Cleveland —
[Speaking Italian, Shouting]
Hello! It's me!
In Memphis!
Memphis!
In the south of the United States,
in Tennessee!
[Children Shouting,
Chattering In Distance]
We had a little trouble —
Some stupid thing with the airplane! Yeah!
Yeah! A little problem!
Don't worry!
Tomorrow, we've got a connecting flight...
and we arrive in Rome
the day after tomorrow!
[Women Chattering, Laughing]
I don't know!
How should I know
where I'll stay tonight?
I'm okay!
[Quietly]
That's just the way life is.
- [Airplane Taking Off]
Ciao! Ciao!
[Woman On P.A.] ...please pick up
the nearest white courtesy phone.
[Indistinct] Please pick up the nearest
white courtesy phone.
Thank you.
You have a great day too.
[Man] Damn, baby!
Why you wanna do this to me?
Baby, I'll give you all the oil you need.
Just do the right thing.
- [Radio: Man Announcing Baseball Game]
Send a letter to the congressmen.
Get a petition goin' around.
Get on the phone and try to get
some real men in this government of ours.
Mickey Mantle.
Tim McCarver president. Sure.
Now you're talkin'. Now you're talkin'.
You can do it, Lester.
You could organize this thing.
You got some spare time,
you can change history.
You really think I could?
Mm-hmm.
Think I could get it done?
Sure is.
Why don't I get it on and get out
and write some letters, telegrams.
Go get on and do it.
Let me give it a try.
We'll get a petition —
You can do it, Lester.
Letters to senators and congressmen.
Well, hello, doll.
Hello.
What can I do you for?
I would like to buy this newspaper.
Well, now you should buy
this one here as well.
The Tri-State Defender.
No, thank you.
I think I need only this one.
Well, you know, you only need one leg
to get around on, if that's all you got.
But it sure helps having two.
Now, doesn't it?
Oh, well, yes.
This one too.
How about some magazines?
We got all kinds of beautiful
magazines here, you know.
No.
You know them people
who just buy a little paper or two?
They make it real hard for an honest man
to stay in business sometime.
Okay. Give it to me.
This one here has all those high fashions
from abroad...
from New York and everywhere.
Now just hold on a minute, sugar.
See what I got here now.
What do we got?
Movie magazine, home magazine...
muscle magazine, ladies magazine.
And this one here tells you
all about the United States.
No, thank you. No, no.
[Vehicle Horn Honking In Distance]
[Children Shouting, Chattering]
[Footsteps]
[Siren Wailing In Distance]
[Train Horn Blowing In Distance]
[Radio: Big Band, Slow Tempo]
We were supposed to meet.
With me?
I'm not from here. I'm from Rome.
It's Rome. Right.
I'm here by accident.
No accident.
What do you want?
I know about you and the King.
The king?
- Yeah. Graceland.
I don't understand.
I have a very important message
I'm supposed to deliver.
Okay.
It was almost a year ago this very night.
I was drivin' back to Memphis...
and all evening I kept passin' hitchhikers.
And the strangest thing —
This only dawned on me gradual...
Was that they all looked like
the same person.
As I was approachin' Memphis,
I passed another one.
So I decided to stop and pick him up.
And right away, the door opened up,
and this hitchhiker got in.
And he was sittin' there next to me,
and all of a sudden he said...
[Lowers Voice]
"Thank you kindly, sir, for picking me up."
When I heard that voice,
real polite-like...
it struck me somewhere
real deep inside.
'Cause I recognized that voice.
Couldn't place it though.
So we're comin' in to Memphis, I tell him
I'll drop him anywhere he wants.
Then he asked me
if I knew where Graceland was.
Of course I knew where Graceland was.
Everyone knows where Graceland is.
And he said I could drop him off
anywhere near there.
And then it hit me... right there.
I knew that voice.
It was the King himself.
The king?
Had the voice of Elvis.
Elvis Presley?
As sure as I'm sitting
right in front of you.
And I drove down
Elvis Presley Boulevard.
And right in front of Graceland —
And I stopped...
and, sure enough to God, it was him.
And he was young too.
He was young and beautiful-lookin'
like in 1956.
And then he just...
turned to me, and he said...
"Excuse me, sir,
but in a year from now...
you're gonna do me a favor.
And I said, "Of course, sir,
I'll do you a favor."
And-And I — "Just tell me what it is."
And he said...
With a smile in his eye,
and he-he reached inside of his coat.
And he said, "When you meet
that girl from Rome...
I want you to give this to her."
I swear to God this is true.
And then he just disappeared.
He was gone.
It was Elvis.
It was the King.
And then I — I was sittin' over there,
and I saw your back.
And even from there, it struck me
that-that you were the one.
I knew it was you.
And as sure as sunlight...
I knew I was meant to give you...
Elvis's comb.
A comb?
This is Elvis's comb.
You mean Elvis Presley, the dead singer...
said to you to give this comb to me?
Mmm.
- I-I did forget one thing.
What?
Well, he also said that you should give me
a $20 delivery fee.
Well, we-we discussed it,
and he said that-that I could accept 10.
Okay.
- This is a very funny story.
I know.
I — I liked it. Very amazing.
Uh-huh.
But I don't believe it.
This is $10 for the good story.
Mmm.
And this is $10 for you to go away.
[Door Closes]
That's for two cups of coffee —
Yours and the gentleman's.
[Train Horn Blowing In Distance]
Excuse me, ma'am. If I could just have
two more minutes of your time.
I have no time anymore.
Just two more minutes.
[Dogs Barking In Distance]
- [Vehicle Approaching]
Taxi!
[New York Accent] I don't wanna stay
in this fleabag hotel anyway.
Like — I'll just, like, wander the streets all
night and, like, probably get killed or somethin'.
I mean, like, what do you care?
You know, thanks for nothing, mister.
Oh, my — Miss, are you all right?
I didn't see you come in the door.
Are you sure you're okay?
- Sì.
Gee, I'm real sorry. I guess it's, like,
not my day or something.
I'm really sorry.
Don't worry.
- "Air Combat"?
Sì.
- [Dog Barking]
[Cat Meowing]
[Woman]
Oh. Here.
Thank you.
Are you all right?
Uh...
no, I'm not all right.
This is, like, the worst day
in my entire life.
[Night Clerk] Just a minute.
Come on back over here.
Listen, I can make an exception.
This is one of those nights.
We're not that busy.
And after all, I can give you a room
for a share.
I mean, it's only gonna be
for one night, right?
Really? Um, you would do that for me?
Excuse me. I don't feel like being alone,
and I would stay only one night.
Would you like
to share the room with me?
Uh, you wanna share the room with me?
- [Man Outside Shouting] Man, fuck you!
Okay, 'cause I don't like
to be alone either...
and, you know, like,
then I'll have someone to talk to.
Yeah, that would be really neat.
You see? It worked out after all.
And I don't have to give her no discount.
That will be $22 in advance, please.
Oh, uh, we'll even up the bill
in the room. Okay?
[Night Clerk]
Thank you very much.
By the way, are you all right?
I feel a little discombobulated.
Yes. I know the feeling.
[Loud Ding]
Room 25 for the lovely ladies.
[Bellboy Exhales]
Thank you.
You're welcome, my dear.
Have a nice night.
Room 25.
[Curtains Sliding]
Thanks.
I like very much your hat.
I don't really like it.
Oh, no, it looks good on you.
Thanks.
What a dump.
Not even a television.
[Electricity Buzzing]
[Exhales]
Fuck this.
So, you know the guy with the red suit,
right? The guy downstairs, right?
He said I couldn't stay here because I only
had enough money for half a room...
and I'd have to find a roommate
and everything.
Then he, like, starts this big argument
with me, you know?
Then, like, all of the sudden,
I, like, bang right into you.
It's so funny when
things happen like that.
I mean, I can't believe it.
It's, like, so strange.
I don't know.
I'm really gonna miss Memphis though.
I really like it here. I had a pretty
good time here and everything.
And, like, my brother lives here too.
See, we moved from New Jersey.
He opened this barber shop, and
it's really nice and everything.
He's, like, really great.
I'm really gonna miss him.
But I feel so bad and everything 'cause I
didn't even call him and tell him I'm leaving.
It's, like, what am I, fuckin' stupid? You
don't call your brother and say good-bye?
[Sighs] Like, now he's gonna find out
from Johnny if I don't reach him first...
but everything was so emotional
and fucked-up with me and Johnny.
I don't know.
I feel so bad and everything.
But who is Johnny?
Johnny? Oh, he's my boyfriend.
Well, he was my boyfriend until today.
Well, until this morning.
See, that's why I'm leaving Memphis.
I just can't be with him anymore, you know.
I just gotta get away from him, you know.
I just have to leave here before he winds up
doing something really crazy or something.
I don't know.
[Sighs]
I'm gonna miss him.
I guess I still really love him.
Did you ever think to marry him?
Marry him?
Well, I don't know. He, like, wants to
marry me, but there's, like, just no way.
I'm just not ready yet anyway...
and I wouldn't marry him
'cause he's so damn stubborn.
And he gets real quiet and everything.
I never know what he's thinking.
Then he gets really paranoid.
I don't know.
I just can't take it.
He works in this cotton warehouse,
and he hangs out with these black guys...
and they call him Elvis.
Wait. Like Elvis Presley, the singer?
Yeah, right, but not that he looks like him
or anything, or that he even likes him even.
But he's got, like, this dark hair, right, like
in a D.A., you know, like that, like Elvis.
And I don't know,
I think it's really funny.
But he really hates it when
they call him that. He's really cute.
He's from England.
Well, you know where that is, right?
Oh, yes, during Carnival —
He's got the cutest accent.
You know the way they talk over there?
I just love the way they talk.
I love the way he talks
when he does talk.
I mean, he never says anything.
How am I supposed to know what he's
thinking if he never fuckin' says anything?
Maybe I talk a lot or something...
but, you know, at least it's better
than not talking at all.
I don't know. I don't know why
I attract these guys.
Maybe that's my problem. I should look for another
type of boyfriend that talks more than I do.
- Well, I guess that's kind of impossible. [Sighs]
[Train Horn Blowing In Distance]
It's, like, what am I, fuckin' stupid?
I'm still in love with him anyway.
[Sighs]
[Train Horn Continues Blowing]
Sometimes even the greatest love
can last only one week.
Yeah.
Where are you planning to go now?
Well, I got this girlfriend, you know.
She lives in Natchez.
Natchez?
- Yeah, that's in Mississippi.
She's got this baby and everything,
and I haven't met the baby yet.
Well, I haven't met
the husband yet either.
Well, anyway, I guess the baby
must be at least two now.
And she said I could come and stay with her for
a while, 'cause I could probably get a job.
'Cause she works in this beauty salon,
so that'll be really good, you know.
This way I could, like, save a little money
and, like, get on my own two feet...
like, decide what I'm gonna do
with my life.
So that'll be really good, you know.
Like, try a different town for a while.
Maybe I'll have better luck.
[Train Horn Blowing]
[Dee Dee]
I don't know.
[Radio] ♪ There's a cat in town
that you might know ♪
♪ He goes by the name of Domino ♪
♪ A long key chain
and a diamond ring ♪
♪ A blue sports car
He's a crazy king ♪
Do you mind if I tell you a story?
You mean, like a bedtime story?
Yeah, that would be really great.
'Cause if I'm alone, I usually
go to sleep with the radio on.
I hate it when it's quiet. I don't know.
It makes me nervous or something.
[Fly Buzzing]
And you know my brother Charlie?
Well, he used to tell me bedtime stories
all the time.
So I guess this would be
kinda like that, right?
Yeah, I would really like that.
That would be really great.
Does that mean yes?
Okay. Well, this is a story
that a strange man I met told me today.
He was driving in a car...
and exactly one year ago...
he was seeing
many "hi-chiking" people.
Many what people?
But — Hitchhiking people.
But they all
were the same person really.
So he stopped his car...
just before Memphis...
to give a ride
to this mysterious person, and...
Wait a minute. Is this the one where the guy has
to go to Graceland and it turns out to be Elvis?
I think I heard this one
a hundred times.
I think almost everybody in Memphis
has picked up Elvis's ghost hitchhiking.
- [Mitzuko Moaning, Muffled]
Wait.
- [Moaning Continues]
Shh!
Listen.
- [Moaning Continues]
[Whispering]
They're fucking.
[Moaning Intensifies]
Do you mind turning on the radio for a
little while? It helps me to get to sleep.
No, I don't mind.
- [Buzzing Continues]
Is it okay if I leave the light on?
Oh, go ahead.
[Clicks, Static]
♪ Oh, Domino, Domino ♪♪
[Radio D.J.]
Thank you, Mel. [Chuckles]
That's Mel, our engineer.
Just coffee, huh?
[Chuckling]
I love ya.
Well, yes, sir, that's another classic
from Mr. Roy Orbison...
along with the Roses — previously known
as the Teen Kings, for you trivia fans...
With "Domino" here.
You're on the air until dawn.
It's 2:17 right here in Memphis, Tennessee.
Right now, here's another one recorded at
Sun Studios, this time by the King himself.
That's right, Mr. Elvis Presley...
with one of my personal
early, early morning favorites...
"Blue Moon."
♪ Blue moon ♪
♪ You saw me standing alone ♪
♪ Without a dream in my heart ♪
♪ Without a love of my own ♪
♪ Blue moon ♪
♪ You knew just what I was there for ♪
[Dogs Barking In Distance]
- ♪ You heard me saying a prayer for ♪
Whoa. Where am I?
- ♪ Someone I really could care for ♪
[Barking Continues]
You? What are you doing here?
Well, I — I don't rightly know myself.
♪♪ [Continues]
Excuse me.
- [Elvis] Excuse me, ma'am.
No, I was saying to her,
"Excuse me."
Uh, no, really.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Uh, I must've got
the wrong address or somethin'.
No, I — I'd better be goin'.
I gotta go.
- ♪♪ [Continues]
[Dogs Continue Barking]
♪ Without a love of my own ♪
Dee Dee! Wake up, Dee Dee!
- What?
Look! Quick! Quick!
- ♪♪ [Continues]
Do you see?
What'd you wake me up like that for?
Jesus. I only just got to sleep too.
I coulda had a heart attack
or something.
♪♪ [Vocalizing]
♪ Without a love of my own ♪
♪ Blue moon ♪
♪♪ [Vocalizing]
♪ Without a love of my own ♪♪
- [Birds Chirping]
[Dogs Barking]
[Train Horn Blowing In Distance]
Oh. Good morning.
[Announcer On Radio] ...Memorial
Hospital shortly after midnight.
Police are on the lookout for three suspects
described as male, in their early 30s...
two white and one black.
The suspects are armed
and extremely dangerous.
And now the weather update
for Memphis.
Today will once again be hot and humid.
Look for that mercury to rise —
Are you sure you don't want
any of those magazines?
No, really.
You sure?
Please!
'Cause, like, magazines
are real expensive...
and I could read 'em at the station
and on the train and stuff, you know.
'Cause I have a pretty long ride
and everything.
Um, oh, uh, Luisa, about the money
for the room, um, well...
Money? Oh, right.
You need some money.
No! I'm supposed to give you money.
Take it.
200 — No.
[Gunshot]
What was that, a gunshot?
[Bell Tolling In Distance]
Maybe a .38.
Uh, let's just get out of this dump.
[Kissing]
[Footsteps Departing]
[Billiard Ball Clatters,
Falls Into Pocket]
[Man]
Close that old pro.
Oh. Damn.
Fuckin' bollocks.
[Pool Players Chattering]
If you lose your money —
[Continues, Indistinct]
Here, there's 10 you got —
Take 10 back.
- You're on.
Rack 'em up, Earl. Rack 'em up.
Yo, yo. You're down.
[Coin Drops]
Well, Rich, no, I-I'm being very
nice to you. Don't worry about it.
That's how I want it.
- [Pool Players Continue, Indistinct]
[Jukebox Whirring, Clicking]
[Man] Uh, yeah, I'll take that 10.
Bet you he beat you.
[Needle Sets On Record]
♪♪ [Funk]
[Man]
♪ Whoo ♪
♪ It's the Memphis train, whoo ♪
♪ Sho 'nuff, it's the Memphis train ♪
♪ Whoo, look out now ♪
♪ Train number one is gone ♪
[Pool Player] Right there.
♪ Train number two is gone ♪
♪ Train number three has been gone ♪
♪ How long must I wait for you ♪
♪ Look out now, whoo ♪
♪ Aw, shucks, now ♪
♪ Whoo ♪
♪ It's the Memphis train ♪
In the corner.
Thanks.
♪♪ [Continues]
Shit.
Lucky shot, man.
I don't know, man.
Some days just go like that.
Huh. Everybody I know needs a job.
Seem like everybody in this town
is out of work.
I don't know what you bitchin' about.
You lucky you had a job in the first place.
♪ Train number one has gone ♪
♪ Ow, train number two is gone ♪
- [Train Horn Blowing In Distance]
♪ Train number three is real gone ♪
Far as your old lady leaving you —
[Chuckles]
I don't know what to tell you.
Why don't you go back to England
or wherever the hell you come from?
Ain't they got enough women
over there?
♪ How long must I wait for you ♪
You know, if it wasn't for her,
I wouldn't even live in this fucking town.
♪ Oooh whee, the Memphis train ♪
♪ Don't lose him now
Don't lose him ♪
- ♪ Oooh whee ♪
[Glass Shatters]
♪ The Memphis train ♪♪
Hey! What's the matter with Elvis?
Don't call me Elvis.
- ♪ The Memphis train ♪♪
If you can't use my proper name...
why don't you try Carl Perkins Jr.
Or something?
I mean, I don't call them
Sam and Dave, do I?
Hey, man, my name is Dave.
- ♪♪ [Jukebox: Funk]
His name is Dave.
Look, it's all right, man. He's cool.
- [Man] ♪ My Lord ♪
He's cool.
♪ Baby ♪
♪ Oh, Lord ♪
♪ Listen ♪
♪ You go where you wanna go ♪
♪ And you stay as long as you please ♪
[Dave]
Go ahead.
- ♪♪ [Continues]
Oh, man! Shit.
What the fuck you doin'
with that, Elvis?
Is that thing loaded?
Shit, man!
The motherfucker's loaded!
What the fuck you doin' with that?
Ain't she a beauty?
I don't know. I might have to use it
on my landlord... or somebody.
Look, put that shit away, man.
Ain't no landlord around here right now.
♪ I worked too hard for these pennies ♪
Come on, man! Cut that shit out!
That shit ain't funny, man!
Y-Y-You actin' like an asshole
or somethin'.
♪♪ [Continues]
Hey, everybody,
check your guns at the bar!
[Gun Clatters On Bar]
Elvis, you asshole!
What the fuck's wrong with you?
You know what?
I saw on the television the other day
where those Chine...
Over there in China, they's all
wantin' to eat macaroni and cheese.
Don't you think that's kinda odd,
what with all the Chinese food they got?
Uh... yeah, I, uh —
I didn't hear about that.
I guess I must have missed that program.
Like I said, I was just passing by.
I saw you was in here cleaning up,
and it just sorta hit me...
How's about a haircut?
This is the first one I ever had
at nighttime like this.
Well, listen, I usually
don't cut hair at night.
So, uh, next time you come back
during the daytime, okay?
[Blows]
[TV Playing, Indistinct]
Aaah! Don't start no shit now.
[Phone Ringing]
Could be her.
Boy, I got somethin' for you.
Hello.
Yeah, Will? This is Ed.
Oh, Ed. Yeah, what's happening?
I'm over at Shades.
Your friend Elvis is over here actin'
stupid, waving a gun around and shit.
Yeah. Man, w-we both been having
a pretty fucked-up day.
Yeah. Yeah, I heard y'all got laid off.
Yeah, it's one of them
seniority things and shit.
I hear that.
Yeah, well, look, anyway, man, um, I think
you'd better get over here and get him...
before some real shit happens.
Yeah, okay.
Maybe you'd better come
with somebody else too.
Like who?
I don't know, man.
Bring one of his own damn people.
Who the fuck am I gonna bring?
I guess I could bring
his brother-in-law, Charlie.
[Engine Stops]
[Emergency Brake Sets]
[Man, Woman Arguing, Indistinct]
- I don't care!
Shut up, girl!
Hey. Hey, Will, um —
What?
You think maybe I should
wait in the truck?
This isn't really
a familiar neighborhood for me, and, uh...
Come on, Charlie.
They let white folks in there.
I know, but you said Johnny has a gun.
If they see me in there,
they may think I have a gun.
If they don't know I'm his brother-in-law.
Aw, shit, Charlie!
[Arguing Continues, Indistinct]
♪♪ [Jukebox: Blues Ballad]
♪ Where can my baby be ♪
♪ Lord, where can she be ♪
♪ And I'm amazed ♪
- ♪♪ [Continues]
Oh, come on, Al. Give me me gun back.
Might have to pawn it
to pay my tab.
I'll think about it.
♪♪ [Continues]
Yo, Ed.
Shit.
♪ Just won't let me be ♪
♪ Wake up restless nights ♪
Oh, sh — I'm sorry, man.
Come on, Johnny, man.
Let's chill out.
I brought Charlie, man.
Charlie.
I'm cool. I'm completely cool.
[Earl]
Don't need that kind of shit in here.
♪ Tryin' to lose
this pain in my heart ♪
- ♪♪ [Continues]
Sorry.
♪ I begin to get rough ♪
♪ Instead I want you to love me
love me, love me ♪
Now get this thing outta here.
It's loaded.
Don't know why you hang around
with this Elvis dude anyway, man.
♪♪ [Continues, Muffled]
Stylin' shirt, Charlie.
Really?
Here. Take this shit.
What are you, fuckin' crazy, Johnny?
What are you doing with that thing?
Hey, let's go for a spin in Earl's Caddy.
Uh-uh.
Don't you even think about it.
Don't even look at Earl's car.
Just get your crazy English ass
in the truck.
You'd best straighten up, Johnny.
Go for a spin in Earl's Caddy.
Who's Earl?
[Engine Starts]
Hey, Will, think you could just
drop me off now?
I should go home.
I'm kinda tired.
What, and abandon your own brother-in-law
on a terrible night like this?
Me and Will losin' our jobs
and everything.
Well, no, I don't wanna do that, but...
Attaboy, Charlie!
I knew you were with us
all the way.
Us brothers, we gotta stick together.
Ain't that right, Will?
Yeah — Oh, yeah.
Right.
Okay then.
Isn't there a late-night liquor store
a couple of blocks up here?
Yeah.
[Engine Knocking]
[Engine Knocks, Stops]
I'll get right with you, man.
I got to check this damn fan belt.
[Door Buzzer Buzzes]
- [Toilet Flushes]
One bottle or two?
Just get one, man. I mean, you're drunk
already, and I'm not gonna have any.
Right.
How you doin'?
Two bottles of Butcher's.
Jesus, Johnny!
Hey, make 'em quart.
[Door Buzzer Buzzes]
Uh, that'll be 22.17.
Hey, fella.
You wanna buy that,
or you gonna play with it all night?
Niggers, man.
You gotta watch 'em every second.
I'm guessin' these two bottles
are on the house. Am I right?
Johnny, what are you doin'?
Shut up and grab the bottles.
Sonny boy, I'm the man
that's gonna make you use that gun.
Holy shit. You killed him!
You fucking killed him!
Shit, man, we best
get the fuck on outta here!
[Starter Cranking, Engine Starts]
What is wrong with you?
Why'd you have to kill him?
Shut up, Charlie.
I only winged him.
[Engine Knocking]
Goddamn it, Johnny!
You're stupid, Johnny.
And what if you did kill that guy?
We all go to prison.
I didn't kill the guy.
[Sighs]
Jeannie's gonna kill me.
[Will, Johnny Laughing]
What are you laughin' at, huh?
How do you think Dee Dee's gonna react?
Damn, I'm glad I'm not married.
[Sighs]
Dee Dee walked out on me.
This morning.
Before I found out about being laid off.
She's gone, man.
She left you?
Wow. She didn't even tell me.
My own sister.
What, she's supposed
to ask your permission?
No, it — That's not what I meant.
I'm sorry, Johnny.
Really, I...
Just...
She'll be better off without me.
Now she probably will be.
Fuck it, man.
You probably better off without her, man.
All she did was run her mouth.
Hey, she's my sister.
I don't care. It's the truth, man.
That woman talk, talk, talk, man,
like a radio that never turns off, man!
She's not like that all the time.
It's only when she's nervous.
Well, she must be nervous all the time.
Last time I saw her, it was...
Yakety-yakety yada-yada-yada —
All right! All right!
Woman never stopped talking.
Just drop it, will ya!
"Butcher's"?
[Train Horn Blowing]
- [Tires Screeching]
So, what are we gonna do?
We can't just keep riding around
all night like this.
Can we?
What do you think, Johnny?
Man, I fucked up.
I really love that girl.
I know you do.
It's all right, man.
[Radio Clicks On, Stations Changing]
[Radio D.J.]
"Domino" here. You're on the air till dawn.
It's 2:17 right here in Memphis, Tennessee.
Right now, here's another one recorded at
Sun Studios, this time by the King himself.
That's right, Mr. Elvis Presley...
with one of my personal
early, early morning favorites...
"Blue Moon."
♪ Blue Moon ♪
- ♪ You saw me standing alone ♪
This one's for you, Elvis.
Thanks a bunch, Will.
♪ Without a dream in my heart ♪
♪ Without a love of my own ♪
♪ Blue moon ♪
♪ You knew just what I was there for ♪
♪ You heard me saying a prayer for ♪
[Continues On Radio]
♪ Someone I really could care for ♪
♪♪ [Vocalizing]
Damn.
You'd think they'd get
me a new uniform, man.
This one is shot to hell.
Look at this.
Well, you should do like I do.
Should go over and buy
your own damn clothes...
over at Lansky's
or somewhere like that.
It's like they say —
"The clothes make the man."
I mean, look at that damn hat
on your head.
You look like
a damn mosquito-legged chimpanzee.
I mean — [Laughing]
♪ Without a love of my own ♪♪
[Radio D.J.] Oh, it's 2:20 in the a.m.
right here in Memphis.
Say, do you like seafood?
Well, guess what.
There's a brand-new fast-food seafood
restaurant right here in Memphis.
You probably heard the name already.
That's right — Jiffy Squid.
Fresh, juicy squid dipped in —
Jiffy Squid?
Rolled in herbs and spices, served with a tangy
sauce with their own secret ingredients.
Jiffy Squid!
Turn that damn thing off!
You're listening to Tad T. Tyler,
the man who brings you wall-to-wall...
[Dogs Barking In Distance]
Jiffy Squid.
[Barking Continues]
Danger! Danger!
Will Robinson! Will Robinson!
Shut the fuck up.
Hey, my brother-in-law, how you doin'?
Man, your breath.
What have you been drinkin'?
Smells like kerosene.
Listen, I got to ask you this favor.
We, uh...
We in a little trouble...
and we need a place
to stay invisible for a little while.
You know, just till it get light out.
Trouble?
Here we go again.
That's par for the course, Will Robinson.
Please, man.
Just for a little while.
Don't tell your sister 'cause, if you do,
we'll both be in trouble.
Not a word. Ever.
Room 22.
- That room?
That room.
Don't make no noise.
Thanks, man.
Mm-hmm.
Thanks a lot.
I'm gonna remember this.
Shit. I'm sorry, man.
Man, you got a curse on you...
as sure as the moon
rolls around the world.
It was just an accident.
I'm sorry.
You gotta clean that up.
[Sighs]
[Dog Barking]
[Barking Continues]
Shh-shh-shh-shh.
- [Can Rattling]
[Loud]
Fuck is the light in this place?
[Door Closes]
Here's a light.
[Lightbulb Pops]
Damn, Charlie.
I'm glad you don't cut my hair.
No TV?
[Exhales]
Hey, Will, what's this chain for?
That's 'cause...
you in the kinky sex room, Charlie.
Really?
Christ. There he is again.
I — I can't get rid
of that fucking guy.
Turn it around, Charlie, would ya?
It's just giving me the creeps.
There's a chair over there.
[Fly Buzzing]
[Burps, Exhales]
I mean, shit,
why is he fucking everywhere?
It's a black hotel...
a black neighborhood.
There's black dudes workin' on the desk.
You know, why don't they
have a portrait of...
Otis Redding or...
Martin Luther King?
[Sighs]
Huh?
That's 'cause this a white-owned hotel.
They just got the brothers
workin' here.
Yeah, I see what you mean.
Don't worry.
Next time, Johnny, we gonna ask
for the Malcolm X suite.
- [Train Horn Blowing In Distance]
That's right.
Hey. I hope you dropped
the empty one.
[Train Passing]
[Will Chuckling]
- [Will] Way to go.
[Johnny] All right, Charlie.
[Sighs]
Say, do you have any more
of those Japanese plums...
or any other exotic fruits
from around the globe?
You ate my only plum.
Remember?
- [Siren Wailing In Distance]
Mmm. Yeah.
[Siren Fades]
[Urinating]
[Charlie]
Oh!
Hey, Will.
You know, until that...
That bellboy was teasing you...
it never occurred to me.
You're Will Robinson.
You know, just like that kid
on the Lost in Space show.
No shit, Einstein.
[Johnny]
What's the Lost in Space show?
[Urinating Continues]
Oh, man, it was this —
Y — They had...
You didn't have that
on television in England?
- [Urinating Continues]
Great show.
It was a really stupid show...
with these dumb white people
marooned on another planet...
with this robot that kept sayin',
"Danger, Will Robinson!"
And this fruity professor or somebody.
[Charlie]
Dr. Smith.
Yeah. Dr. Smith.
And June Lockhart was on it.
You know. Lassie's mother.
Anyway, it was this family —
The Robinsons.
Get it? Like Robinson Crusoe?
And the main kid was named
Will Robinson.
I guess I missed
that bit of American culture.
Well, you damn sure
didn't miss much!
- [Urinating Continues]
What? You didn't like that show?
That used to be one of my favorites.
[Will Scoffs]
Figures.
[Fly Buzzing]
That's how I feel in this place...
with you two fuckin' snowflakes
hidin' in this place.
[Toilet Flushing]
Lost in space!
[Will]
Shit.
Fuck you, Will.
You gonna start that racist shit again?
It ain't our fault.
We didn't choose to be white.
Right, Charlie?
Yeah.
I mean, no.
[Burps]
Shit.
[Radio Announcer] ...Vance Liquor
Store manager Mitch D'Annunzio...
was critically wounded in the shooting.
He was taken to Baptist Memorial Hospital
shortly after midnight.
Police are on the lookout for three suspects
described as male, in their early 30s...
two white and one black.
The suspects are armed
and extremely dangerous.
And now the weather update.
[Train Whistle Blowing In Distance]
[Will Snoring]
- [Dogs Barking In Distance]
[Train Passing]
[Snorts, Coughs]
Oh, shit. Where are we?
Oh, damn.
I was hoping I dreamed all this shit.
[Will Continues Snoring]
Hey, Johnny...
where do you think Dee Dee went?
I don't know.
She said something about
a girlfriend in Natchez.
Where is Natchez?
Louisiana?
No, its, uh —
It's in Mississippi, I think.
Right down there on the river.
It's really too bad.
You know, I mean, with your wedding
anniversary coming up and everything.
Look, Charlie...
there's something I gotta tell you.
Me and Dee Dee...
you know, we were
never actually married.
What?
She never told me that.
I wanted to marry her...
but you know Dee Dee.
She always said we'd have to wait
and see how things went.
Great.
[Sighs]
[Shouting] You mean after all this shit,
you ain't even my fucking brother-in-law?
[Exhales]
Jesus Christ.
Do you know, uh...
What am I, fucking stupid?
[Sighs]
We'd better get rid of that gun, man.
[Vehicles Passing Outside]
Yeah.
[Bell Tolling]
[Gun Hammer Cocking, Clicking]
[Shuddering]
[Hammer Cocks]
Jesus!
[Grunting]
[Gunshot]
[Bird Wings Flapping]
[Bell Continues Tolling]
- [Pigeons Cooing]
[Cat Meowing]
[Dogs Barking In Distance]
Damn. That's just gotta be Room 22.
I just know it.
Check it out.
Yeah, but that sounded like a gunshot.
You want me to go check it out now?
Yeah. Check it out right now.
[Tires Screeching]
[Vehicle Approaching]
[Vehicle Horn Honks]
You fuckin' shot me!
I don't believe this!
You're not even my brother-in-law,
and now you fuckin' shot me!
[Whimpering]
Uh, excuse me.
[Footsteps Running]
[Train Horn Blows]
[Bell Tolling In Distance]
[Japanese]
Wow.
We saw Graceland this morning...
and by tonight we'll have seen
Fats Domino's house in New Orleans!
[Footsteps]
Uh, excuse me.
Is this the train to Natchez?
Oh, yes! Matches!
One moment, please!
Hey.
Oh, uh — [Chuckles]
No. Never mind.
Thanks anyway.
[English]
Thanks anyway!
[Woman On P.A.]
Attention, passengers.
This is the final boarding call
for Flight 607.
Final call for Flight 607 to Rome
now departing from Gate 6.
[Groaning]
Shut up, man.
[Groaning, Screaming]
Oww!
Are you fuckin' stupid? Oww!
[Groaning, Screaming]
You got him?
Oww, it hurts!
[Groaning]
I need a — I need a doctor.
Don't worry, Charlie.
A lot of doctors in Arkansas.
Arkansas?
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. Shh!
- You hear that?
[Sirens Wailing In Distance]
What, the train?
- [Train Horn Blowing In Distance]
No. Sirens.
I can hear a train.
- [Train Horn Continues]
- [Sirens Approaching]
I hear the sirens.
Shit.
[Screams]
Oww! Shit!
[Groans]
[Starter Cranking]
- [Sirens Wailing]
[Train Horn Blowing]
[Engine Starts]
[Groans]
[Groaning Continues]
[Siren Approaching]
[Siren Wailing, Fading]
- ♪♪ [Saxophone Blows]
[Man] All aboard.
[Man]
♪ Train I ride ♪
♪ Sixteen coaches long ♪
♪ Well, that long, black train ♪
♪ Carry my baby from home ♪
♪ Train, train ♪
♪ Comin' on round the bend ♪
♪ Well, it took my baby ♪
♪ It's gon' do it again ♪
♪♪ [Continues]
♪ Train, train ♪
♪ Comin' on down the line ♪
♪ Well, it's bringin' my baby ♪
♪ 'Cause she's mine, all mine ♪
♪♪ [Continues]
♪ Shhhh ♪
♪♪ [Fades]
♪ Shhhh ♪♪
[Insects Buzzing]
[Train Horn Blowing, Faint]
[Train Approaching]
[Train Horn Blowing]
[Train Passing Into Distance]
[Train Horn Blowing, Faint]