[engine humming]
[humming grows louder]
[engine roaring]
[phone rings]
[rings]
Yeah.
[woman on phone, indistinct]
Oh. Hello, Aunt Lotte.
[speaking foreign language]
Don't speak to me in Hungarian, please.
No, I haven't heard from them...
not for ten years.
Yeah, I got your letter.
Speak English, please.
[Hungarian continues]
Yeah, my little cousin Eva.
Yeah, I know. She's gonna come here,
and she's gonna stay overnight.
When is she coming?
Today? Straight from Budapest today?
[sighs]
[Aunt Lotte continues]
Oh, no! No, I never agreed to that.
[sighs]
I can't possibly babysit her for ten days.
No, look. It's disrupting my whole life.
I don't even consider myself
a part of the family.
Do you understand?
[Aunt Lotte continues speaking Hungarian]
No, I'm sorry you have to
go into the hospital.
Yeah.
[sighs] Yeah.
- Good-bye. Bye.
Okay. Bye-bye.
Bye.
Damn.
Sh... [imitating percussion]
[footsteps]
[footsteps continue]
[rhythm && blues on tape recorder]
[man] ♪ I put a spell on you ♪
[continues]
♪ Because you're mine ♪
♪ Stop the things you do ♪
[singer laughing] Watch out!
♪ I ain't lyin' ♪
♪ Yeah, I can't stand ♪
♪ Whoo ♪
♪ No runnin' around ♪
♪ I can't stand ♪
♪ I know you're puttin' me down ♪
♪ I put a spell on you ♪
♪ Because you're mine ♪
♪ Whoa, yeah ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
[continues]
[fades]
[exhales]
[imitating percussion]
[knocking on door]
Yeah?
Jesus.
Hello. I'm Eva Molnar.
Yeah, no kidding.
Are you Bela Molnar?
No.
I used to be. Call me Willie
if you gotta call me something, all right?
[speaks Hungarian]
Oh! Don't speak Hungarian at all.
Only English, all right, while you're here?
Only English.
[door creaking]
Yeah, well, come in!
Tomorrow I must go to Cleveland
in Ohio by train.
Yeah, well, you can't go
to Cleveland in Ohio tomorrow.
Aunt Lotte has to go
into the hospital for ten days.
So you can stay here tonight, and I don't
know what you're gonna do after that.
For ten days?
Yeah.
Ten days?
[Eva exhales]
[child crying]
[car tires screeching]
[Willie sighs]
[phone rings]
Willie?
[rings]
Willie.
Hello?
Yes, he's sleeping.
What? Excuse me?
I don't understand.
Yeah, I am his cousin.
I am really his cousin.
Excuse me?
Could you speak a little slower, please?
Yes. Courguy?
Okay. I will tell him.
Who rang?
Yes, the telephone rang.
No, I mean, who was on the phone?
Courguy. He said his name was Courguy.
What?
He said his name was Courguy.
I don't know anybody named Courguy.
That's what he said his name was.
Don't answer my fuckin' phone, all right?
Courguy.
Hey, Eva? You goin' out?
Yeah.
Look, um, Clinton Street
is two blocks south of here.
I wouldn't go any further south
than Clinton Street.
Why?
It's really dangerous there.
I can take care of myself.
Man, listen. You come here, you don't know
what's going on in this city.
You never been here before.
You come and stay in my apartment.
I don't even want you here, and you're just,
like, "Yeah, I know what's going on."
You think
you're so motherfucking together.
I'm going alone.
Oh. Okay. Go alone.
[opens, closes oven door]
You sure you don't want a TV dinner?
Yes. I'm not hungry.
Why is it called "TV dinner"?
Um, you're supposed to eat it
while you watch TV.
Television.
I know what a TV is.
Where does that meat come from?
What do you mean?
What does that meat come from?
I guess it comes from a cow.
From a cow?
It doesn't even look like meat.
[sighs] Eva, stop bugging me, will you?
You know,
this is the way we eat in America.
I got my meat, I got my potatoes,
I got my vegetables, I got my dessert.
And I don't even have to wash the dishes.
[knocking]
[Willie] Yeah.
[Eva] Hi.
Hey, Willie. How you doin'?
Hey, man. How you doin'?
Pretty good.
I didn't know you had company.
That's my cousin.
Yeah?
She's from Hungary.
She's cute.
Shut up, man.
Hi.
I'm Eddie.
Eva.
How do you do?
Okay.
Hungary?
Yeah.
You been here in, uh, New York, uh, long?
For two days only.
You like it?
Yes.
I'm going to Cleveland in about a week.
Cleveland. It's a beautiful city.
Yes?
Yeah.
It's got a big, beautiful lake.
You'll love it there.
Have you been there?
No, no.
[Willie] Who's running in the second race?
Ah, we have Indian Giver, Face the Music,
Inside Dope, Off the Wall,
Cat Fight, Late Spring,
Passing Fancy, and, uh, Tokyo Story.
Tokyo Story. It's a good one.
That's what I like to hear.
It's a good one.
Get off my shirt, man.
Oh, sorry.
Who's in the third?
Song and Dance,
Last McCoy, the Real McCoy,
Square Deal, Female Touch.
That's a good one. Female Touch.
I don't want to bet on that race.
Are we gonna take Eva?
No, we're not gonna take Eva.
He bugs me.
You should come with us.
You'd have a good time.
Is it nice?
Oh, it's fun, yeah. Yeah.
Okay. I'm ready.
Why don't we take Eva with us?
Huh?
Why don't we take Eva?
I don't want to take Eva with us.
She'd have a good time.
Look, Eva, stay out of trouble, all right?
Just stay here while I'm out.
All right?
Let's go, man.
Why don't we take her with us?
Come on, man.
Bye.
See you later, Eva.
I'll see you again sometime.
[crowd cheering]
[announcer on TV] The ball is in the air.
It's pass interference,
and the ball will be spotted at the 15.
So, you see the guy who's got the ball?
Mm-hmm.
That's the quarterback.
He can either hand off to one of the runners
or he can pass it downfield.
It's kind of like, you know, he's, um...
[announcer]
The ball is in the air, just out of the left...
He's, uh, like the general, you know.
He's sort of like... he's in charge of the offense.
The quarterback is in charge
of the whole offense.
[announcer continues]
[announcer #2] That'll make it first down,
Cincinnati, at the San Francisco 15.
Clock running.
So what does the quarterback do
when he becomes the defense?
What?
What does the quarterback do
when his team becomes the defense?
The quarter... [sighs]
The quarter... The quarterback's
not on the defense ever. Uh...
I... Uh, I don't know how
to explain this to you.
[announcer #1] That's a close one.
Just watch the game.
[announcer #1] The closest men
were two offensive linemen.
I think this game is really stupid.
That really shouldn't be a penalty
for throwing the ball away.
The Bengals get a break here.
Watch this pass rush.
[announcers continue]
[eerie sounds on TV]
[man on TV] That recording was made
by Krell musicians a half a million years ago.
[Willie scoffs]
Now if you will follow me, I will show you
some of their other remaining artifacts.
[eerie sounds continue]
Krell metal.
Try your blaster there, Commander.
[rhythmic pulsing]
[man #2] This spot should be molten.
[man #1] It's not even warm, huh?
And no trace of radioactivity.
[slide whistle tooting]
[cartoon music playing]
[whistling]
[cartoon character whimpering]
[man] Shh. In there.
Hello, Mae.
I've got a bone to pick with you.
[character shuddering, muttering]
[whistling]
[bell clangs]
- Ouch! Oh!
Uh-huh!
[footsteps]
Do you have a vacuum cleaner?
What?
It's really dirty in here.
Do you have a vacuum cleaner?
What do you want? A vacuum cleaner?
Don't open that. Oh, man.
The vacuum cleaner's under the bed.
I told you not to open that.
Close the bott...
The bottom one first,
and then the top one.
Mmm.
It's under the bed.
Where? Oh.
Willie, can you help me change the bag?
It looks full.
I'm sure it's fine.
It hasn't been used in years.
It looks dirty.
Eva.
Are you sure?
You know, you don't say...
Like, it's really too formal to say,
"I want to vacuum the floor.
I want to use the vacuum cleaner."
Oh. What do you say?
Well, you say, um,
"I want to choke the alligator."
So if somebody comes in here, you know,
you say, "I'm choking an alligator."
Okay.
I am choking the alligator right now.
[motor running]
[cards slapping on table]
[low vocalizing]
Ba-boo, ba-boo. Nothing.
[clicks tongue] Man.
[humming]
[continues]
Hi, Willie.
Hello, Eva.
How you doing?
Okay.
Where'd you get all that stuff?
I thought you didn't have any money.
I got this stuffwith no money.
This one is especially for you.
TV dinner.
[chuckling]
Thanks.
Whew! Ah, you're all right, kid, I think.
I think you're all right, kid.
[chuckles]
Damn.
So I've been losing all afternoon here.
I've been winning.
Yeah.
[rhythm and blues playing]
♪ I know you're puttin' me down ♪
♪ I put a spell on you ♪
♪ Because you're mine ♪
♪ Whoa, yeah ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
[door opens]
Oh, hi.
♪ Stop the things you do ♪
What the fuck is that?
[singer laughing] Watch out!
♪ I ain't ly... ♪
I really hate that kind of music.
It's Screaming Jay Hawkins,
and he's a wild man, so bug off.
[laughs]
So, uh...
um, I got something for you.
What is it?
It's a present.
Present?
Mmm.
Thanks.
What is it?
It's a dress?
Yeah.
Oh, thank you.
I think it's kind of ugly. Don't you?
No. I bought it.
Why don't you try it on?
I don't really wear this style.
You... You know, you come here,
you should dress like people dress here.
I'll try it on... later.
Hey. Leave me some Chesterfields.
Can I get them in Cleveland?
Yeah, yeah. You can get 'em in Cleveland.
They taste good there, like here?
It's the same Chesterfields.
Yeah?
All over America, yeah.
All right.
[Willie chuckles]
[suitcase latch clicks]
So, you're sure you don't want me
to come with you to the station?
Mm-hmm. I would like to go by myself.
Oh.
So, I don't know. Take care of yourself.
Okay.
Good-bye, Willie.
So, Eva...
Yeah?
Uh, I don't know.
Maybe I'll see you again sometime.
Yeah, maybe.
Oh. Hi.
Eva.
This dress bugs me.
I'm leaving. I'm going to Cleveland.
It's a beautiful town.
[Eva chuckles]
Well, good-bye.
Well, it was nice meeting you.
Yeah, it was nice meeting you too.
[floorboards creaking]
[knocking]
Yeah?
Hey, Willie.
Hey, man.
How are you doin'?
I'm all right.
I saw Eva. She's going to Cleveland, eh?
She's gone, man.
Oh, yeah.
You see the... the dress I got her?
It's beautiful, right?
Yeah. Beautiful dress.
Yeah.
You want a beer?
[cards shuffling]
I'll bet a deuce.
And a deuce.
Enough for me.
I'm in.
Give me three.
I'll stay with these.
Give me one.
Dealer takes two.
All right. I'll bet a pound.
Your five, and five.
And five more.
Oh, I like this.
I'm in.
Full house.
I thought you were bluffing.
Oh, man. So did I, believe me.
You know, I don't believe this, man.
Every time Eddie deals, Willie wins.
Every time Willie deals, Willie wins.
Hey, that's right.
What are you saying?
I'm saying that you're winning
two out of every five hands,
and they're always the same two hands!
Two out of every five hands. That's right!
You sayin' I'm cheatin' then?
I'm not saying you're cheating, man.
We're not saying you're cheating.
Then what are you saying?
All I'm saying is that every time
we go around, you win...
What are you doing with the money, man?
I don't have to listen to this.
What are you talking about?
You're saying I'm cheating?
I don't have to stay here.
We're playing a fucking game here, man!
Get your fucking hands off me!
What the fuck? Hey.
You're his fucking partner too, right?
I never met the guy.
I'm never playing with you again.
Get out of here, man!
And you two, man... you just sit there, right?
What, he's leaving too?
Yeah, he's leaving, yeah.
You picked up on that, huh?
Both of you, man,
you just sit there, you know.
You don't fuckin' stick up
for yourselves or nothin', man!
I don't know what the fuck
is the matter with both of youse.
And you let those animals
in your fucking house too, right?
[muttering]
Willie, what are we stoppin' in here for?
We gotta watch those guys.
They knew somethin' was up.
Tomorrow we got the track,
then with this, we're doin' pretty good.
What's your brother-in-law's name? Max?
Yeah.
Can we borrow a car from Max?
Yeah, I guess.
Hey, what do we want a car for?
You want to leave town because of those guys?
No! Those guys are a bunch of lightweights.
I don't care about them.
I just want to get out of here and see
something different for a few days, you know?
Yeah? I don't know.
Hey, where would we go?
Hey, Willie, where would we go?
I don't know.
Hey, Eddie.
Eddie!
Willie! What's that... What do you want?
Oh, I don't want nothin'.
Think this thing's gonna make it
to Cleveland?
Yeah, it'll make it to Cleveland.
Well, if it don't, we'll just ditch it,
you know, take a bus back.
Won't Max mind?
What can Max do about it?
Hey, pull over over here.
Yeah? Why?
I want to talk to this guy.
Yeah?
Excuse me.
Sir?
Sir!
What do you want?
Could you come here a minute?
Could you come over here a minute?
I'm just waiting for the bus.
I want to ask you directions.
What?
Just come here, so I don't have to yell.
Can you tell me which way is Cleveland?
Give me a break, man.
I'm just going to work.
Where do you work?
In a factory.
Let's go.
I don't know, Willie.
Ah, the poor guy. God.
You shouldn't have given him
such a hard time.
Can you imagine working in a factory?
No, I can't.
Now I feel bad.
Nah, don't feel bad.
Hey, Eddie.
Ah, cut it out, Willie.
Willie, when we get to Cleveland,
where are we gonna stay?
With your cousin Eva and, uh, your aunt?
No.
Do you think your cousin Eva
will remember me?
I doubt it, Eddie.
How much money we got?
Oh, we got a lot.
How much is a lot, Eddie?
We got a lot. We got almost $600.
You're all right, Eddie.
You know?
We're a couple of rich men now.
This is terrible, Eddie.
The weather's getting worse.
Look at all the snow here.
You think we're in Ohio yet?
Nah, I think we're still in Pennsylvania.
Say, Willie.
Yeah?
You know, last year,
before I met your cousin,
I never knew you were from Hungary
or Budapest or any of those places.
So what?
I thought you were an American.
Hey, I'm as American as you are.
Does Cleveland look a little
like, uh, Budapest?
Eddie, shut up.
Willie? You asleep?
No, I'm not asleep.
[sniffs, sighs]
[dog barking]
Who are you?
Hi.
Who is there?
It's me, Bela.
You don't remember me?
Bela Molnar. I'm your nephew.
No, I don't see you about ten years.
How can I... thinking of you?
You happy to see me?
I am very happy to see you.
Yeah.
Who is that fella?
This is my friend Eddie.
I'm glad to see you.
Hi!
I'm glad to see you too. Come on in.
Okay.
Come on in.
Thank you. Thank you.
[man on TV]...after these messages.
[man 2 on TV]
Research shows that Lysol spray...
[man on TV] My father's gonna kill me!
[speaking Hungarian]
Oh, we're not really hungry.
Goulash, chicken paprika.
[Hungarian continues]
Do you have any beer?
No. [speaking Hungarian]
Take off your hat.
[Hungarian continues]
She called you "Bela" outside?
Skip it.
Oh, thanks.
You're welcome.
[Hungarian]
Thank you, Aunt Lotte.
Thanks.
[Hungarian]
It's delicious.
Okay. Thank you very much.
[Hungarian]
You're looking really good, Aunt Lotte.
Thank you very much.
[Hungarian]
Where's Eva?
Eva's working in a hot dog stand.
What time does she get out?
[Hungarian]
We gotta pick her up at, uh...
10:00.
Okay?
Yeah, that sounds good.
You like it?
It's very good. Yeah, it's delicious.
[Hungarian]
Thank you. [Hungarian]
[man on TV] As for you, you're confined
to campus again for the rest of the semester.
Al, pack your things.
I'm calling your father to come get you.
[man 2 on TV] No. No, hold it.
Now, look. Eric is the cause of this whole thing.
Now, what's gonna happen to him?
Man, eat your soup.
[man on TV]
You just haven't figured out the system.
Here she comes.
May I help you?
Yeah.
Willie! Eddie!
I told you she'd remember me.
I can't believe it!
What are you guys doing here?
Well, we're on vacation, like, you know.
Really?
Yeah.
You came from New York?
Yeah. We have a car and everything.
Oh, yeah?
We borrowed it.
[chuckles] Are you in trouble?
Mm-mmm. No.
How did you guys find me here?
We went to Aunt Lotte's house,
and she told us that you were here.
Oh. You already saw her, huh?
Yeah.
So, can you stay for a few days?
Yeah, we could. Why not? I don't know.
Yeah.
Oh, I'm so happy to see you.
You want a hot dog?
No, no.
No.
You already ate, right?
Yeah.
So, I have a little more work to do...
like, 20 minutes.
Can you wait for me?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah. We came to pick you up.
All right. I'll hurry up. Okay?
Yeah, but I think we should wait in the car,
'cause I don't like it in here.
Neither do I.
Yeah?
All right, I'll hurry up.
Okay.
Just 20 minutes.
Yep.
Come on.
I told you she'd remember me.
Well, good.
[footsteps]
[man] So, anyway...
anyways, it seems it's in the cards that I might
be getting a raise down at the gas station.
Uh-huh.
Hey, you said you'd go with me
to the movies the other night.
You wanna go see Space Wizards
or that foreign flick down at the Olympia?
Uh, Days Without Sun. You wanna see that?
I don't know. Isn't there a kung fu movie?
I can go and check. We'll see.
Yeah, check and call me up. Okay?
Yeah.
All right. Bye.
Bye, Eva.
[Eddie] Hi.
How's it goin'?
[Eddie] How you doin'?
[engine starts]
[TV: dramatic music plays]
You know, while we're in Cleveland, Willie,
why don't we go see the Cavaliers?
Oh, they have a terrible team.
Well, so what?
They're like 0 and 48
or something like that.
Yeah, but we're not doing anything.
Well, what do you wanna do?
I don't know.
I'm going to the movies.
[speaking Hungarian]
What?
[Hungarian]
What are you telling me?
I know what I wanna do.
No, you don't tell me what to do.
I'm not a baby.
I don't need them to babysit me.
[Hungarian]
No, I don't need them to babysit me.
I'm a big girl. All right?
Uh, hey. Hey, hey. Hey, Eva.
Why don't we just...
[Hungarian]
Aunt Lotte? Aunt Lotte, please.
We could go to the...
We came all this way to see you.
We could go to the movies with you, right?
All right. Okay.
It could be fun. No?
All right. I just don't understand
why she's treating me like a baby.
[speaking Hungarian] "Baby."
What... Are we going to the movies?
Go ahead! Go ahead.
Hey! Are we gonna go to the movies?
[TV: m a n] A blank screen on which to project
the images so ably de vised by our friends...
[movie: man, woman shouting, grunting]
[movie: blows landing]
[movie: shouting, grunting continues]
[movie: man groaning]
[movie: blows continue landing]
[movie: dramatic music plays]
[movie: shouting resumes]
[movie: blows resume landing]
[movie: man shouts]
Well, thanks for the ride, fellas.
[Eddie] Hey, thanks for paying for us too, Billy.
Okay. Hey, uh, Eva,
you wanna walk me to my door?
Okay.
I'll be right back.
"Eva, do you wanna walk me to my door?"
[Willie scoffs]
Man, what are we doing here?
[Eddie] I don't know.
[sighs]
Hey, Willie.
What?
You wanna stick around much longer
here in Cleveland?
Why? You wanna go?
I don't know. Yeah. Kind of.
We could go back tomorrow
or the next day or somethin'.
You know, it's funny.
You come to someplace new,
and everything looks just the same.
No kiddin', Eddie.
Whew. It's so cold here.
Yeah. I kinda wanna get out of here.
Wish Aunt Lotte would just speak English.
She's so stubborn. It's funny.
Just like the rest of the family.
[mutters] Yeah.
Is that guy Billy all right?
Yeah, he's a nice friend.
Yeah.
Let me tell you a joke. All right?
Mm-hmm.
There's three guys
and they're walking down the street.
One guy says to the other one,
"Hey, your shoe's untied."
He says, "I know that."
And they walk... No.
There's two guys,
they're walking down the street,
and one says to the other, "Your shoe's untied,"
and the other guy says, "I know that."
They walk a couple blocks further,
they see a third friend, and he says,
"H... Your shoe's unti...
Your shoe's un..."
Uh, I can't remember this joke.
[both chuckle]
But it's good.
I'm sure.
Yeah.
It's a pretty good game, right?
I am the winner.
Hey, now, that's three times in a row
you've won.
I am lucky in card. I win every time.
That's amazing.
[phone ringing]
[Eva] I'll get it.
Hello? Hi.
How you doing, Billy?
I'm okay.
Oh, yeah. Shit, I forgot. I can't.
My cousin and his friend are leaving tomorrow.
I gotta be with them tonight.
No, I really should.
Oh, come on, Billy!
You can understand that, can't you?
Oh, don't give me that. [groans]
You know they're not more important.
It's just that they're leaving.
Come on, Billy.
God!
Just call me next week. All right?
We'll talk about it.
Okay? Bye.
I am the winner.
[Eddie] Oh, not again.
So, you guys wanna go see the big lake?
[Willie] Anything but this.
Well, I don't know...
Come on, Eddie.
Go and jump in the lake.
Aunt Lotte!
[Eva] Let's go.
You'll play later with me?
Yeah. Yeah.
I wanna win at least once.
Okay. I give you a chance, let you win.
[Eddie] We'll see you later.
Okay.
[wind whistling]
[engine idling]
Well, this is it. Lake Erie.
[Eddie] Man, look at all this snow.
Man, it's... it's beautiful.
[Eva] It's not always frozen.
[Willie] So...
It was really nice of you guys
to come all the way here to see me.
Hey, it was nice of you to be here.
[Willie] Eddie!
Oh. We just... You know, we thought
we'd come out and see how you were doing.
[Eva] Oh.
[Eva] It's kind of a drag here, really.
Well, good-bye... again.
Good-bye, Eva.
So, if you guys win a lot of money at the racetracks,
you should come and try to kidnap me.
Yeah. We'll take you someplace warm.
This place is awful.
[Eva, Eddie chuckle]
See ya.
Bye, Eva.
It was nice seeing you again.
[doors close]
[engine starts]
How much money we got left?
We got a lot.
Count it.
Hey, Willie, why are you
always telling me what to do?
It seems like if I don't tell you what to do,
you don't do anything at all.
I wanna know exactly how much we got.
We got $550 left.
Which means we spent 50.
You ever been to Florida?
Florida? Yeah, it's beautiful down there.
Uh-huh.
You know, white beaches, girls with bikinis.
Yeah.
Cape Canaveral, Miami Beach.
Cape Canaveral! Miami Beach! That's right.
They got pelicans down there, and flamingos...
all those weird birds.
You been there?
Nah, I never been there.
You're a jerk, Eddie. You know that?
No, come on.
What do you say we go down to Florida?
Yeah?
Yeah. Go back, pick up Eva,
drive down to Florida.
We got the car.
Yeah? You're not kidding?
No.
Well, hell,
it beats going back to New York.
That's a good idea.
I'd like to go to Florida.
Yeah, you never been there. Right?
No.
[Eddie] Where's the next exit?
I don't want you to take her away!
[speaking Hungarian]
Don't worry.
We're going on a little vacation.
Come on!
We'll be back soon.
[Hungarian continues]
Good-bye.
[engine starts]
[Hungarian continues]
Good-for-nothing... [Hungarian]
You son of a bitch.
God, I'm so glad.
Thank you guys for rescuing me.
I can't believe we're going to Florida.
You bring your little bikini along?
Sure.
[Eddie chuckles]
[Eva]
There are alligators in Florida, right?
[tape recorder: rhythm && blues playing]
Not that.
It's Screamin' Jay.
Aw, that's awful.
You're the same. He's my main man.
[continues]
[Eddie, Willie chuckle]
- ♪ 'Cause you're mine ♪
Yeah, I like this.
You like this stuff?
Thank you, Eddie. Back me up.
♪ Stop the things you do ♪
It's horrible.
[singer laughs] Watch out!
♪ I ain't lyin' ♪
This is drivin' music!
This is nice.
- ♪ Yeah, I can't stand ♪
♪ Whoo, no runnin' around ♪
[music continues]
I haven't heard it in a long time.
♪ I know you're puttin' me down ♪
♪ I put a spell on you ♪
[vehicle passes]
Now we look like real tourists.
Pretty classy.
[engine starts]
[knocking]
Eva, I want you to stay down until the motel guy
comes out and goes back in his office.
Why?
Why pay for three people? It's fine.
I thought you guys said you were rich.
Shh! Get down. Get down.
Hey. How you doing?
Hi there. How are ya?
Fine.
Wait till he goes in and then come around
the other side. Room number three.
Number three?
Yeah.
Man, I'm beat.
I'm so tired.
What, you finished the peanuts?
Yeah.
Then what'd you pack 'em for?
Jesus, Eva!
The idea was for you to sneak in.
You understand?
I don't care.
This looks familiar.
This is for you.
Huh?
Oh, no. I'm not sleeping on that.
One of you guys can sleep there.
I'm taking the bed.
I fell asleep
waiting out there in the car.
Now I'm cold.
I want a comfortable bed, at least.
Amazin'.
[sighs]
Hey, that water smells funny.
Uh-uh-uh. I'm not gonna sleep on this cot.
[Eva chuckles]
You guys think it's so funny.
No, it's... They're good, you know.
Yeah, yeah.
I love you guys...
but this is a bitch.
[Eva] Can we all go to the beach tomorrow?
[Willie] After we go to the track.
Hey, Willie, we should
check out the dog races.
I don't like the idea of dog races.
[Eddie grunts]
[Eva] Be quiet so I can sleep.
Yeah, go to sleep so we can start
enjoying our vacation. All right?
[Willie sighs]
It's okay.
Looks very nice.
I'll forgive you guys.
[Willie chuckles]
Hey, Willie, man,
let's check these dog races out.
I got a good feeling.
I feel like we're gonna make a lot of money.
Really?
Yeah. It's one of those feelings.
Yeah.
Uh, yeah, maybe it's a good idea.
I don't know.
[Willie sighs]
[Willie] Dog races. [grunts]
[Eddie sighs]
[Eddie] Have sweet dreams.
[Eva] Good night.
[groans]
Willie?
Mmm.
Willie. Eddie?
Shit.
Fuck!
That's nice.
They could have left a fucking note.
Shit.
Can't fucking believe it.
Vacation starts great.
[birds calling]
[car doors opening, closing]
Where the fuck have you been all day?
You didn't even leave me a note.
I'm here alone in the middle of nowhere.
I don't know anybody.
And you can't do that much...
leave me a note when you leave.
[muttering] Shut up, Eva...
Don't tell me to shut up! What is this?
I thought we were going to Miami.
This is nowhere.
Man, you said you had a good feeling. Right?
I had a good feeling, Willie.
"Good feeling" is supposed to mean
that something's supposed to happen.
Not just like this...
You can't win 'em all, Willie.
What's going on?
You take me to dog races and then you say,
"You can't win 'em all"?
It's the name of the game!
What's going on?
Nothin'.
Nothin's going on.
Just lost almost all our money.
At dog races?
You lost all the money?
Yeah.
God.
I'm sorry.
What are we gonna do now?
Look, Willie, let's get outta here.
We got 50 bucks. Let's go back to New York.
I'm not goin' back to New York with no money.
What do you wanna do?
I wanna go to the track
and I wanna bet on horses, not on dogs.
I knew you were gonna say
something like this. Come on.
I have this terrible feeling
if we go back to the track.
Your feelings haven't been
doing us any good.
This is a great vacation.
Oh, shut up, Eva. Come on. Let's go.
Anything you say, Willie.
Anything you say.
Eva, what are you doing?
What do you mean?
You're not coming with us.
What?
She should come with us. It'll be good luck.
She's stayin' here.
Willie, I think she should come with us.
She's stayin' here!
Get out. Get out!
I'm sorry, Eva.
You're the same. Just go.
I'm sorry.
Willie, she's been in the motel all day.
We should take her with us.
[vehicle passes]
Yo, little freak,
where the fuck you been at, man?
Where you been at, man?
Wha...
Shit, man...
Yo, I mean, you the freak, right?
You got the hat on, man.
I see the dome piece on your top, man. Listen.
You're supposed to take this shit, man.
You make me miss my motherfuckin' sniff, man.
Here, take this shit, man. You tell Rammell
that I ain't down with this no more.
You cool? You clean?
There you go. Good-bye. Peace.
No shit.
[people shouting in distance]
Willie? Eddie?
Whew.
[Eddie, Willie chanting]
Eva?
I told you horses, not dogs.
You don't ever listen to me. Right?
Horses. Horses. Definitely horses.
Give me that. Give me that!
Get the fuck outta here!
Come on. [laughs]
Hey, it's dark in here.
You see Mighty Joy?
Did you see Mighty Joy?
[imitates speeding engine]
Yeah, it was great. He was great.
Think I'll shed some light
on the situation.
Huh.
[spits]
Come on, you idiot!
Hey, look at this.
What is that?
My God, Willie!
What is that? What does it say?
[exhales]
It's from Eva. It's in Hungarian.
What does it say?
Aw, this is stupid.
She's goin' to the airport.
We can't let her go to the airport. She's really...
Where did she get all this money?
I don't know where she got the money.
We should get her, eh?
Yeah.
All right, that's fine. Let's go.
All right.
We'll leave this place, eh?
Where did she get all this money?
Are you packed?
Yeah. I'm ready to go.
Is this Eva's hat?
It looks like Eva's hat.
Where'd she get that hat?
Willie, come on, will ya?
Let's get outta here.
You got all the money?
Yeah, I got everything.
Take the bottle.
Don't you want your peanuts?
Why should I want the peanuts?
There's nothin' in it.
[typing on keyboard]
Yes, there is one remaining flight
to Europe today.
It leaves in about 45 minutes.
You have plenty of time to board.
It's a flight to Eastern Europe...
to Budapest.
To Budapest?
There's a flight from here to Budapest?
Yes, there is.
That's the only flight to Europe you have?
Well, it's the only flight we have today.
We have several tomorrow.
I can check on those for you.
[typing]
Yeah, we have a flight to Madrid
at 12:20 p.m.
We have a flight to Paris at 2:05.
Although you will have to wait
until tomorrow.
What time does the plane leave again?
The flight for Budapest departs
in about 44 minutes.
Hmm.
...are talking about, sir.
Shall I explain it more clearly?
You're a whack-off. You know that?
You have a nice day too, sir.
What's goin' on, Willie?
This jerk says she was just here.
Yeah?
She's got on... He thinks she got on some flight.
So? What do you got a ticket for?
I had to buy the ticket so I can
get on the plane to take her off the plane.
Here. Take this.
When's the plane?
In, like, five minutes.
You'd better hurry up.
All right, meet me at the car in ten minutes.
I'll be back at the car. Don't worry. I'll be there.
You all right?
Yeah. I'll see you later.
All right.
I'll be at the car.
[woman on PA] Your attention, please.
Royal Airlines Flight 904,
nonstop service to Budapest
is now ready for immediate departure,
gate seven, concourse A.
[jet approaching]
Oh, Willie.
I had a bad feeling.
Damn.
[engine starts]
What the hell are you gonna do
in Budapest?
[scoffs]
[whispers] Shit.
[rhythm && blues playing]
♪ I put a spell on you ♪
♪ Because you're mine ♪
♪ Stop the things you do ♪
[laughs] Watch out!
♪ I ain't lyin' ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ I can't stand, whoo ♪
♪ No runnin' around ♪
♪ I can't stand ♪
♪ No puttin' me down ♪
♪ I put a spell on you ♪
♪ Because ♪
♪ You're mine ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
[grunts]
♪ Stop the things you do ♪
[laughs] Watch out!
♪ I ain't lyin' ♪
♪ Ohh, ohh ♪
♪ I Iove you ♪
♪ I love you anyhow ♪
♪ I don't care if you don't want me ♪
♪ I'm yours right now ♪
♪ I put a spell on you ♪
♪ Because you're mine ♪
♪ Mine ♪
♪ Mine ♪ [screaming]
♪ Oh, you're mine ♪ [grunting]