Evening, Holly G.
Afraid you're under arrest.
On what charge?
Stealing my heart.
God,
I love a man in uniform.
Hey, boyfriend.
Hey, yourself.
Where's my file?
I love you, Lucas Buck.
I know you do, darling.
Where's the file?
Almost got caught
sneaking it out.
Birth record on
one Caleb Temple.
Good work.
So what's this baby
to you, anyway?
I told you. I'm investigating
the mother's suicide.
Hmm.
What's "hmm"?
Nothing.
Where we going?
I'm taking you home.
Home?
But you promised we'd go
dancing or maybe take
a swim under Johnson Bridge.
No, not tonight.
You're the father,
aren't you?
What?
That baby's yours.
Don't be crazy.
All week it's been:
"How's the baby doing?
Did you check on the baby?"
You're Caleb Temple's father.
Put on your seat belt.
If you really loved me...
you would have told me
the truth.
You got
an overactive imagination.
You stop lying!
Hey, calm down, will you?
I will not!
And I ain't keeping
your dirty little secret,
neither.
You used me.
And I'm gonna tell everybody
what you've done.
Everybody's gonna know
about that baby.
Holly, I don't want things
to end this way.
So I've changed my mind
about that swim.
What you hunting, Caleb?
Wild boar.
Me, too.
Got him!
My boar's dead.
Mine got away.
Your friend's
quite a shot, ain't he?
Well, he's the best.
The best man
don't always win.
Boone, would you mind
if I gave Caleb some tips?
No, sir.
Why don't you run home
and pick up some flowers
for your mama on the way?
On me.
But we're practicing
for the contest.
I don't think Boone here needs
any more practice, do you?
Go on, Boone.
So where'd you get that thing?
Five-and-dime?
My daddy
gave it to me.
I guess it's serviceable.
If you know how to work it.
I can work it just fine.
Prove it.
Anybody could hit that thing.
What about a man's target?
How about...
...that crow?
Think you could reach him?
I don't kill nothing
I don't eat.
Hell, cherry farmers
around here kill them
by the handful.
Pests, vermin.
Ruin a whole crop
if you let them.
Well, he didn't do
nothing to me.
I get it.
He's a little too far for you?
That's all right.
No, he's not too far.
Go on, Mr. Crow. Long life.
Nothing to worry about
from this little fellow.
I got him.
Well, all right.
See, I hit him dead on.
What are you doing?
Taking off a claw.
You've earned yourself
a talisman.
I don't want that thing.
What do you mean?
You killed it, you own it.
You made me.
Son, nobody makes anybody
do anything they don't want
to do in the first place.
I ain't listening to you
no more.
Caleb?
I ain't listening to you
no more.
Now, you for example...
are a fall color,
so you would do well
with our Autumn Glow.
Mrs. Gallagher?
Yes?
It's Gail Emory.
A friend of Holly's.
Will you ladies
give me a moment?
Surely.
Gail Emory.
You remember me?
Of course I do.
Well, all grown up.
And with a perfect
summer complexion.
You look wonderful.
I wasn't even sure that...
I mean you look great.
Thank you.
I'm so happy to see you.
What brings you back to town?
My cousin, Caleb Temple.
I'm sure that you heard
what happened to
his father and his sister.
Yes. What an ugly mess.
I thought maybe if I knew
a little more
about his past...
I would be able to help him
through this, so...
I understand that Holly was
working at the hospital
when his mother died.
Why don't you come inside,
Gail?
You and Holly
were friends in what?
Fourth grade?
That's right.
Then you probably remember
our house during
its avocado period.
All greens and oranges.
Lots of changes since then.
This is exactly
as Holly left it.
She doesn't live here
anymore?
Holly's dead, Gail.
It's been over
10 years now.
Car accident.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Gallagher.
It's all right.
I like to show people
this room...
because I think it says
more about Holly...
than I ever could.
There's
her nursing certificate...
and her commendation
from the Ladies League.
Holly had great potential.
Everyone thought she was
going to conquer the world.
And so did I.
Would you like some lemonade?
Sure.
Yes, Miss Welsley.
All right, Miss Welsley.
We'll send you
our sample pack right away.
Thank you for calling.
Was Holly seeing anyone
when she died?
She was very popular.
But there was no one serious.
Are you sure?
You're a romantic,
aren't you?
Just like my Holly.
Have some lemonade.
You gonna shoot me, too?
Hey.
How long you been here?
Long enough.
What happened today, Caleb?
Nothing.
Well, you're not sleeping.
I didn't wanna
shoot that crow, Merly.
I swear.
I just...
Something came over me.
Lucas is a part of you,
Caleb.
The sooner you accept that,
the better.
Does that mean
I gotta be like he is?
No. But you can't
run from him.
Guess I can't run from you,
neither.
Do you get smarter
when you die?
I don't know.
I'm scared, Merly.
So am I.
Barbara Joy?
Now look what you
made me do.
Now, what are you doing?
Righting
a centuries-old wrong,
I'm told.
Ben Junior's been getting
some flack about
this damn thing at school.
It ain't P.C.
If you're here to see him,
you're two weeks early.
I'm here to see your husband.
About what?
How about taking off
those glasses?
He's in the shop.
Waylon?
Well,
if it ain't Deputy Dawg.
It's nice to see you, too.
Watch out there, Son.
Sorry, Daddy.
Hey, Ben. How you doing?
All right, I guess.
What else do you say, Son?
I'm fine,
thank you for asking.
How are you?
I've been better.
Son, would you mind if I talk
to your stepfather
for a minute alone?
He's a big boy now.
He can hear anything
you've got to say.
I really don't think
that's a good idea.
Weekend father
laying down the law.
Okay, Benji, run up and ask
your mama to hustle us up
some sandwiches.
Yes, sir.
Private enough for you?
Your wife's wearing
dark glasses.
And you're wearing
rayon pants.
You're here to
dissect her wardrobe?
How you two
been getting along?
Excuse me, Deputy...
but since when was that
any of your business?
She's the mother
of my child.
Well, that may be,
but she's my wife now.
Well, that don't give you
any reason to mistreat her.
She call you up here?
No.
Is this police business?
Well, not yet.
Well, then...
I guess you ain't got
a leg to stand on.
Benji, get the deputy here
some ice.
He walked into a door.
Hey, Sheriff. What is
an eight-letter word
for "snoop"?
"Intruder"?
Has to end in a "Y."
Reach for the stars, Floyd.
Hello, Miss Emory.
I see my tax dollars
are hard at work.
Sounds like we're in
for an exposé.
You want me to pad
some expense reports for you?
I'd rather you answer
a few questions...
about Holly Gallagher.
Now there's a name
from the vault.
"Every time I see
your angelic face...
"my heart sings with the joy
of a thousand trumpets."
So I was a lousy poet.
What's the point?
You were seeing her
when she died.
Jealous?
We had dinner
a couple of times. Sweet girl.
Little obsessive.
I suppose
you found the body.
Wrong. Her car went off
the Johnson Bridge,
we never found nothing.
How hard did you look?
We had all kinds of divers,
ma'am.
Hell, even used
coast guard radar.
No luck.
The coast guard?
Slow news day?
What the hell
happened to you?
Nothing.
Look,
there's no mystery here.
But if you try
and invent one...
Holly's mother's the one
who's gonna suffer.
She's put this behind her,
I suggest you do the same.
Holly was a nurse
at the hospital when
Caleb's mother died.
I'm aware of that, ma'am.
She was also my friend.
Would you get out of the way,
please?
Floyd, I believe I've found
your magic word.
What's that?
Busybody.
Who done this to you, Ben?
Waylon Flood.
Family dispute?
Yeah, you could say that.
You want me to handle it?
No.
Well, people lose
respect for you,
they lose respect for me.
And I can't have that
in my town.
I'll take care of it, Lucas.
You'd better.
Can't we all just get along?
We live in a violent world...
but that doesn't mean
we need to succumb
to our basic instincts.
People like
Martin Luther King...
Gandhi and
Robert E. Lee all believed...
there was a peaceful solution
to every problem.
Yes, Charlotte?
I thought Robert E. Lee
was a general
in the Civil War.
Well, yes, he was, darling.
But only because
he was pushed.
Boone Mackenzie,
would you come here a moment?
This is yours, isn't it?
Well, what's happened
to your penmanship?
I had a blister.
Well, Boone, I'm afraid all
these outside activities...
are getting in the way
of your work.
I'm sorry, Miss Coombs.
But it's better now.
Good.
Then maybe we'd like to take
another pass at this.
But we've got practice.
The contest is tomorrow.
Well, I'm aware
of that, Caleb...
but I think this is
more important, don't you?
No.
It's okay.
I'll catch up with you later.
Hey, hotshot.
Leave me alone.
On your way to practice?
I wouldn't want to
interfere with that.
Practice is an important part
of the victory equation.
Of course,
there is another part.
What?
The right tools.
Well, what are you
waiting for? Pick it up.
Whose is it?
Yours, of course.
I felt so bad about
what happened yesterday...
I didn't want us getting off
on the wrong foot.
Here.
Feels good, don't it?
Much better than this
old branch you were using.
It's so light.
It's more then that, Son.
It's your ticket to glory.
What say we take it
for a test drive?
Water's real muddy.
The vehicle's only down there
about 15 feet.
I can't believe
they couldn't find it.
Maybe they didn't look.
Or maybe the Sheriff
just wants to let
sleeping dogs lie.
You have a problem
with this?
No.
Just leave my name
out of the papers.
All right, T.J.
Let's do it.
Can you help me
with this door?
Sorry, ma'am. I knew Holly.
There's nothing in here.
How tall was she?
Holly?
Little bit shorter
than you, I reckon.
She was shorter.
She wasn't driving.
I ain't shooting
no more crows.
Of course not.
Playtime's over.
And now that you've got
the right equipment...
all you're missing is
the fire in the belly.
A what in the belly?
The will to win, Son.
The burning desire to conquer.
You know how you find it?
No.
By letting go.
Let go of your fear...
see yourself in
the winner's circle,
and there you are.
Now who's the best shot
out here?
Josh is pretty good.
Then you set up next to him
and I'll teach you...
a little something
about psychological warfare.
Go on.
Hold on, boy.
Don't just slink
over there.
It's not who you are,
it's who people think you are.
Give him some attitude.
First shot will be
the most important.
'Cause that's the one
he'll be watching.
Use the equipment,
trust the sights.
And let go.
Whoa!
What'd I tell you?
Nice shot, Caleb.
Thanks.
Don't thank him.
Just smile like it's
the easiest thing
in the world.
Let's see it again.
It works.
Of course it works.
Wow, two in a row.
Still...
What?
...Boone's better then me.
Well, if you believe that,
you ain't got a chance.
Gotta put Boone in his place.
But he's my best friend.
No room for friendship
on the battlefield, Son.
He'd gladly beat you,
wouldn't he?
I guess.
Close your eyes.
Go on.
Now, picture Boone's face
up there on that target.
You see him?
Yeah.
Okay. Now...
if he was really
your friend...
would he want to
humiliate you...
in front of all those people
tomorrow?
No.
If he was really your friend,
he'd be trying to help you,
wouldn't he?
I guess.
He's your enemy, Caleb.
Never forget that.
He's your enemy.
Now, open your eyes.
And meet your new best friend.
Don't you worry,
Mrs. Balstrap.
I'm sure the dentist
will know what to do.
No, I would not advise
trying to take
the braces off yourself.
Look,
could you hold on a sec?
Doc, I got a lady
on the phone here...
whose son fell off his bike,
landed on his face...
and mashed his braces
up into his gums.
Now, what do I tell her?
Get him to a dentist.
That's what I've been
telling her.
She's fighting me.
Mrs. Balstrap...
the doctor here says you
should get Clarence...
to the dentist
as soon as possible.
Well, now I don't know
about that.
All right. Bye.
She says she can't afford
any more dental work.
She wants to know if Lucas
will loan her the money.
What a world.
Ben?
Well, Sheriff's out, Doc.
I came to see you.
Well, sit down.
Your ex-wife came to
see me again.
She had some
pretty serious bruises.
I'm gonna kill that
son of a bitch...
Now, hold on.
I'm not here to make
the situation worse.
Your wife is an adult.
If she wants to
change her life, she will.
Your son doesn't have
any choice in this.
Did he hurt my boy?
Not physically. No.
But if that man is his
only role model...
he's gonna think
that kind of behavior's okay.
Well, I see him
twice a month.
Have you talked to him
about this?
No.
Spousal abuse is
a learned behavior.
Your son needs to know that
what's happening is wrong...
and it won't be tolerated.
Well, I've wanted to spend
more time with him.
But Barbara Joy just...
She doesn't have
much respect for me.
This might be an opportunity
to change that.
I could throw Waylon's
sorry ass in jail.
Well, that's your call.
But if you do, he may end up
looking like the victim.
Talk to your son, Ben.
Talk to him.
Gail?
Mrs. Gallagher.
I'm kind of busy right now.
We need to talk.
All right. Come on in.
Thin mint?
No, thank you.
I went to Johnson's Bridge
this afternoon.
What on earth for?
To find Holly's car.
It was only in 15 feet
of water.
You had no right to do that.
You don't want to know
what happened?
I know what happened.
Lynda Lee,
how may I help you?
I can't talk to you right now.
I can't talk.
I'll have to call you back.
Why are you
doing this to me?
Her body wasn't in the car,
Mrs. Gallagher.
But more importantly,
I don't think
that she was driving.
What difference
does it make?
Holly is dead.
I would just appreciate it
if you would just...
Janice?
You said this would
only take a minute.
I'm sorry.
Miss Emory
was just leaving.
Mrs. Gallagher,
I'm sorry to call you back.
I'm sorry,
what kind of place is this?
It's a sanitarium, ma'am.
We have a question
about Holly's medication.
Yeah, right.
Ain't you got nothing better
to do than annoy people?
I've come to apologize,
Waylon.
Is that so?
Yeah, I believe
I mishandled things.
Well, you got that right.
So, what do you got
to say to me?
I ain't got nothing
to say to you.
This is for my son.
I'm sorry I asked you to leave
earlier today, Son.
Waylon here was right, you are
old enough to hear this.
What is this garbage?
I'm afraid your
stepfather here is a coward.
He thinks that the way to
control people is by
bullying them
and beating on them.
You're on my property, Deputy.
But I'm here to tell you that
all that's gonna stop now.
'Cause you don't deserve it.
And neither does your mother.
Get out of here, boy. Git!
You go on, Son,
and you tell your mama...
that everything's gonna be
fine now.
All right, now we can
either talk or you can
try hitting me again.
Hell, Ben,
what kind of choice is that?
It's yours.
Look.
Maybe I have been a bit harsh.
I've had a lot of pressure
in the business.
You tell Sheriff Buck that
I appreciate the warning...
and I won't ever lay a hand
on Barbara Joy again.
And you gonna stop
bullying my boy?
Yeah, yeah, sure.
Hell, these are the hands
of an artist.
Then I guess
we're done talking.
Holly?
It's Gail.
Gail Emory.
Gail?
Gail Emory?
Do you remember me?
Is he here?
Who?
My boyfriend.
Who's your boyfriend, Holly?
"Every time I see
your angelic face...
"my heart sings with the joy
of a thousand trumpets."
What happened, Holly?
He's here.
Evening, Holly G.
Afraid you're under arrest.
On what charge?
Stealing my heart.
Why didn't you tell me
she was still alive?
Now, don't take it
personally.
Nobody in town knows.
That's the way Holly's mama
wants it to stay.
I think she invested so much
of herself in that child...
the thought of living
with her this way was
just too much to bear.
Four minutes
without oxygen.
That's all it took,
a lifetime of dreams
washed away.
You were driving the car,
weren't you?
I've tried to do
the right thing.
I found this place for her.
Visit at least once a week.
You were driving the car.
And I want to know
what happened that night.
Get in the car.
I don't need
a demonstration.
Words are cheap, Miss Emory.
If you really want to know
what happened...
I'm gonna have to show you.
Awful lot of people in there
saw you come out here with me.
Then you don't have anything
to worry about, do you?
Get in.
Put on your seat belt.
You like dancing?
Holly sure did.
She could dance up a storm.
Where are we going?
That's funny. Holly asked me
the same question.
I thought we'd retrace
the steps of
that fateful night.
I believe I could drive
this road with
my eyes closed.
I'm not impressed.
Have faith, Miss Emory.
See, that was Holly's problem.
She lost her faith.
Slow down.
No faith in me.
No faith in love.
And mostly,
no faith in herself.
Were you playing this game
with her, too?
No game. We were past that.
She realized it was
over between us.
And she wasn't wrong.
Enough.
Open your eyes.
She grabbed the wheel...
Open your eyes!
I couldn't control the car.
You see?
She wanted us both to die.
Why?
Because she was a romantic,
Gail.
And so am I.
Next up, Caleb Temple.
Doing real good, Caleb.
That practice sure paid off.
And now up is
Boone Mackenzie.
That was a good shot, too,
honey.
Nice shot.
Nice try.
It's okay.
We're both in the lead.
Don't you want to win?
Of course. But if I don't,
your winning is just as good.
Come on, honey. Come on.
Go ahead.
Dad?
Hi, Son.
What you doing here?
I just wanted to tell you
that it meant a lot to Mama...
your coming by the hospital
to see Mr. Flood.
Well, I'm real sorry
about what happened.
It meant a lot to me, too.
I appreciate that, Son.
You'd do the same for me,
wouldn't you?
Well, I guess
I'll see you around, huh?
Yeah, I believe
you will.
Now trying to break the tie,
Caleb Temple.
Better luck next time,
Caleb.
Now shooting his final round,
Boone Mackenzie.
I don't want this no more.
I ain't winning your way.
Well, Caleb, your call.
Just remember,
a good loser,
is still a loser.
In the final round,
Boone Mackenzie leads
Caleb Temple 30-23.
Caleb Temple needs a bulls-eye
to win the match.
Don't worry, darling.
He can still win.
Boone Mackenzie
wins the match, 30-28.
Good.
Well done, Boone.
Good shooting.
Stupid game.
Congratulations, Boone.
Thanks. You had me scared.
You had me scared, too.
But I took my best shot,
and that's what counts.
Sorry about the way
I treated you, though.
It's okay.
But will you still go
boar-hunting with me?
If you'll help me
with my handwriting.
All right.
Hello, Gail.
Are you here
for a consultation?
I saw Holly.
I'll bet you didn't know
she was a dancer.
Did you know that?
She had so much talent.
She still may.
Did you know that
she finished first...
in her class
in nursing school?
Number one.
Smart girl, my Holly.
Then why don't you
bring her home?
Holly may be different,
but she's still your daughter.
And I'm sure she still wants
to make you proud.
There's my phone.
Another customer
dreaming of a makeover.
Another chance
to be perfect.
Goodbye, Mrs. Gallagher.
Goodbye, Gail.
Okay, let's try it again.
The three most important
vital signs are:
I'll give you a hint.
The first two are:
pulse rate
and body temperature.
And the third is...
Lucas Buck.
Good girl.
Blood pressure is right.
You are my
perfect little girl.
Aren't you?
Perfect in every way.
Children are a puzzle,
aren't they?
You give and you give
and you give and you give,
and what do you get back?
Nothing.
He shot that crow,
didn't he?
Big deal.
Even Ben's son could do that.
Where did I go wrong?
Honey...
that's the question
on everyone's lips.