Previously on American Gothic:
I want the boy.
Caleb isn't going anywhere
until I say so.
This document grants me
sole custody of Caleb.
And I'd like you to sign it.
Happy birthday.
Are you a ghost?
No.
Angel?
I'm your family.
Be careful, Caleb.
Someone's at the door.
No more running, son.
Caleb!
A 10-year-old boy
with a 30-minute start.
I want him back by sundown.
Does Caleb know
his father's dead?
I don't see how he could.
He's been running all night.
Look, whatever you think
about Lucas, he's helped out
a lot of folks in this town.
How's that?
By giving them
a second chance.
The Sheriff is after me.
He thinks he's my daddy.
And what do you think?
I think he's crazy.
What do you want with him?
I'm just doing my job, ma'am,
got to protect my people.
Like my parents?
They died in a fire, ma'am.
No, they died because they
were trapped in a building.
Someone had locked them
in there.
You really my cousin?
Yeah.
I live in you, Caleb,
and so does your father.
Merlyn, look out.
Hello, Mr. Wills.
I'm Dr. Crower.
Feeling all right?
TV in my room's broke.
We'll have to get it
fixed for you.
This is Dan Truelane,
our anesthesiologist.
So you're
the dream master, huh?
Oh, yeah.
It's a very
simple procedure,
Mr. Wills.
Laparoscopic surgery...
four little holes,
we take out
the gallbladder...
you'll probably be home
in the morning.
Do I get steak and eggs
for breakfast?
Well, I don't know
about that.
You really had us worried,
son, running off like that.
You almost gave
your cousin, Gail,
a heart attack.
Where are we going?
To the hospital.
The doctor just wants
to check you out...
and make sure
that everything is all right.
Yeah, a quick checkup,
you'll be on your way.
On my way where?
My place.
I got a wicked
electric train set.
And you know
what I like for breakfast?
Apple pie and ice cream.
Sound good?
I really want
to stay with Dr. Matt.
Son, you had your stay
with the good doctor
and you ran away.
If he'd been looking out
for you better...
none of that business
in the woods
would've happened.
Yes, sir,
with your family gone now...
it's time you start trusting
the man with the star.
Okay, Mr. Wills,
I'm gonna place
this mask on you...
and I want you to start
counting backwards from 10,
all right?
Sure that thing
ain't broke, too?
Well now,
if your head explodes,
we'll know.
Ten, nine, eight...
Hey, you with us, bud?
Yeah.
I was just...
I'm wondering about Caleb.
Caleb's fine.
Meanwhile, it's showtime.
I'm gonna scrub.
I tell you about
my pool table?
Look, I'm his family now...
and until there's a hearing,
he can stay wherever
he wants to stay.
A hearing?
The state welfare bureaucrats,
you mean?
Ms. Emory, you been
in the big city too long.
The beauty of a small town
like Trinity is that
we take care of our own.
And the beauty of big cities
is that people
can take care of themselves.
If you want to stay
in the hospital tonight,
Caleb, that's fine.
In fact, I might
just stay there with you.
Well, won't that be cozy?
Just the two of you.
In intensive care.
Hospital can be
a mighty cold place, son.
I don't like trains
and I hate apple pie.
Well, fine. You just get
a good night's sleep.
Tomorrow we'll ask my friend
Judge Halpern...
to figure out
the living situation
on a temporary basis.
I'll walk you in.
No, that's all right.
I'm sure
you have other duties.
Well, sure.
I reckon I do...
but this is a pleasure.
Give it up.
Ma'am?
I'll just wait out here, then.
You can wait all you want,
but I'm staying
at the hospital with Dr. Matt.
You sure, son?
Well, okay, then.
You get up there
and see Dr. Matt.
See how he's doing.
All right.
Make sure that line's
clear over there.
His heart rate's up.
Let me look at his eyes.
Code blue!
Dr. Williams, can I see you
down here, stat?
Yes, sir.
He's having a seizure.
What's his oxygen?
Ninety-five percent.
I need 10 ml IV Valium. Now.
Just hold him down,
hold his head.
Where's the Valium?
What have you done
to that man?
Stay out of this room.
Get the boy out of here!
It's all right, Gordy,
it's all right.
It's all right. That's it.
This how you treat
all your patients?
He had a seizure.
Of course he did,
he's an epileptic.
According to whom?
Tell me, Harvard, what is
the proper procedure for
anesthetizing an epileptic?
There's nothing
on this man's chart
about epilepsy.
Oh, really?
Daniel, can you confirm that?
"Subject to
Jacksonian seizures.
Check with
attending physician
before anesthesia."
That wasn't there before.
Are you sure, Doctor?
Not having one of them
blackouts now, are you?
Would you get out of here
before I call security?
You hang in there, champ.
You're gonna be okay.
Sleep well.
Enjoy your stay.
This wasn't here, Matt.
Look, I don't know what
that son of a bitch did...
but I'm telling you,
that wasn't there before.
Well, it's there now.
What you gonna do
When Death comes creeping
in your room
What you gonna do
You gonna pray to the Lord
Oh, please deliver me
What you gonna do
When Death comes for you
There is a heaven
and there is a hell
But the fires of hell
burn on in brimstone
Is your soul on fire,
Daniel?
What do you mean?
I'm just teasing.
Come on children
And look
into Satan's casket
And stare
into the face of sin
You've got to rise
and see the face
of your tormentor
You coming?
It's for kids, Cheryl.
Come on.
Come on, you're afraid
of what you might see?
Look, you go on.
Come on, children,
and look into
Satan's casket
Oh, yes
Quite a show.
Leave me alone.
That was some
pretty nasty business
at the hospital, Daniel.
I'd hate to see
a fine churchgoer
like yourself...
punished for
another man's crime.
That was just a taste
of how irresponsible
that Doc Crower can be.
Things happen.
Well,
what's happening tomorrow
is a little custody hearing...
and I'd like to count
on your support.
I think it's only right
that the custody judge
be made aware...
of the good doctor's history,
don't you?
If this is about Caleb,
you don't have anything
to worry about.
Dr. Crower is not looking
to be his daddy.
But I am.
And in order to make
that happen, I'm going
to need your testimony.
Help put
the good doctor's character
in perspective for the boy.
Anyone ever tell you...
that talking in church
was a sin?
Come on, people
Come up and see
the reflection of the devil
in your own eyes
Beautiful wife
you got there.
Newlyweds, aren't you?
Children, you don't want
your souls a-burning today
What were the two of you
talking about?
Who?
Lucas Buck.
Mr. Trinity, godfather
to half the children
in this town?
Yeah, well, he won't
be godfather to our children.
We're gonna have
the most beautiful kids
in the world.
And the smartest, too.
Yeah.
If they take after you.
Daniel.
Hmm?
Is there a problem
between you and the Sheriff?
No...
We had a close call
in the operating room today...
and the Sheriff
just happened to come
in in the middle of it.
He seems like
a pretty nice guy, I mean,
he has a nice smile.
I hadn't noticed.
You must've been studying
him pretty close.
Silly.
Jesus!
Hold on!
You okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Yeah. Stay here.
Damn bird came out of nowhere.
You folks need a hand?
South Carolina, southern
hemisphere or northern?
Southern.
Well now, you'd think so,
but it's northern.
Now, Tropic of Cancer.
Who can come up here
and show me...
Caleb Temple.
Well, it's about time
you got here.
We're so glad
you're back with us,
safe and sound.
Aren't we, people?
Yes, Ms. Coombs.
Now, you go on
and take your seat, Caleb.
I know you had a rough time,
but maybe for show-and-tell...
you could share your adventure
with Sheriff Buck.
It wasn't no adventure.
We heard he saved your life.
Well, he didn't.
Well, you go on
and sit down, okay?
Now, you're the famous
reporter from Charleston,
aren't you?
No, not so famous,
just a reporter.
Nonsense.
"Local Girl Makes Good."
I read that story.
Hey, people, how about
if Ms. Emory tells us...
her adventures
as a newspaper reporter.
You know, I have to go.
No, please,
Ms. Emory, please.
Please, Miss Emory.
Come on.
You're such a wonderful
role model, especially
for the little girls.
Okay.
Well...
Well, reporters
get to write about...
what they really care about,
you know, like...
well, the environment,
for instance.
Okay, they could...
If they're concerned
about the environment
they could write about that...
or politics...
What is your favorite subject,
Ms. Emory?
Crime, actually.
Really?
How would you kids
like to hear some
true crime stories?
You know something?
I really don't think...
Yeah!
Okay.
Well, you know,
I've been in a lot of
very scary situations.
Just last month
I had to go undercover.
Hey, babe. How you doing?
More presents.
Who's this one from,
Aunt Molly, Aunt Sara?
I hope there's something
to eat in it, I'm starved.
I haven't made lunch yet.
Oh, that's okay.
I'll just nuke something
from last night.
Wait.
I'm dying to open this.
Honey, I'm back on call
in half an hour.
Dan, come on.
We promised we'd open
all our presents together.
It'd be bad luck
to change now.
That was five toasters
and three Crock-Pots ago.
Okay, come on.
How marvelous.
Who's this from?
"With best wishes
for a successful marriage.
Warmest regards, Lucas Buck."
Oh, man.
Yeah, it'll look great
in the garage.
Applesauce...
and tapioca.
Man, hospital food
really bites.
Where you gonna live,
now your house is gone?
Don't know.
They're having some kind
of meeting on it today.
Maybe I could stay with you.
I don't know.
My folks might not like that.
Well, I don't need
my own room or nothing.
My daddy says,
"The apple don't fall
far from the tree."
What's that mean?
I guess he's afraid
you're like your daddy.
I gotta go.
You know how I lost my house?
How?
Burned it down.
Caleb.
Merlyn?
Where you going?
Come on, Caleb. Follow me.
Come this way, Caleb.
Caleb.
Follow me, Caleb.
Stop the presses! Lucas Buck's
been elected Sheriff.
Merlyn?
You here?
Hope you ain't mad at me.
Come on, Merlyn.
Don't touch that, Caleb.
Not now, not ever.
I just wanted to fix her eyes.
Don't need fixing.
She can see just fine.
How'd you know my name?
Everybody knows
your name, Caleb.
Now, I didn't mean
to scare you, Caleb.
And you're welcome to
look around. Just be careful
what you touch.
Hey, I'm leaving now, honey.
Look, I left some of
that pasta salad for you
on the table.
You like this color, Danny?
Yeah, it's very pretty.
Look, anyway,
I've gotta go prep
Mrs. Hardaway...
for tomorrow
morning's surgery.
Forget old Mrs. Hardaway.
Come to me, Daniel.
Cheryl, I really...
Cheryl, I really
don't have time.
What is it with you?
I've got to get to work.
Startle you, Dan?
Didn't mean to.
Used to be the front porch
was where friends gathered,
kind of a public space.
What have you done?
You like my little gift?
It was actually
for both of you.
That mirror's changing her.
Come on, don't be so dramatic.
Some men might
appreciate that change.
But if you don't,
all you've got to do is
help me out at this hearing...
and I'll make sure
Cheryl straightens right up.
Fair?
You want me to lie
about my friend.
On the contrary...
I want you
to tell the truth...
about Matt Crower's
curious past.
See you there.
Why aren't you in school?
It's lunch.
Well, I don't see you eating.
I ain't hungry.
You lose something?
Them masks for Halloween?
They're from Africa.
Supposed to
represent the spirits
of my dead ancestors.
Pretty cool, huh?
You ever seen one?
One what?
Ghost.
Have you?
Maybe.
Well, then maybe I have, too.
Man by the name
of Andrew Vantage...
built this house
150 years ago.
Got the land cheap.
Know why?
Swamp?
This used to be a graveyard.
Holy ground.
But I've had lots of folks
stay here over the years...
and nobody's complained yet.
Grab three plates.
Have some bread.
Then you can help me.
Help you what?
Make soup.
Come on, sit down.
Who's that one for?
Ghosts have to eat, too,
don't they?
You know,
I want to help him, Matt.
But I want to do
the right thing.
I just don't know
what that is.
It's whatever Caleb wants.
Exactly, but...
he seems to think
you're the only one
he can trust.
Well, I don't think
I'm an option, I mean...
I'll do whatever I can
to see that
he gets a good home...
but no judge
would grant me custody.
I basically
live at the hospital.
Maybe you could take
Caleb back to Charleston,
you could start over.
Judge might like the idea
of a new environment.
No, his friends are here,
his school.
Well...
all we're talking about
in the hearing
is a temporary resolution...
till the Child Services
people get into it.
Any temporary situation
is fine by me...
as long as
it doesn't include
Lucas Buck.
Why is he after Caleb,
anyway?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe he wants a protégé.
Imagine a man like that
raising you.
Better be careful, Harris.
That stuff will kill you.
Well, it's organic.
I meant the tomatoes.
You know, folks
used to believe
they were poison apples.
I didn't know
you were a gardener, Lucas.
I've been known
to pull a few weeds.
Yeah, for me,
it's therapeutic.
Plant a seed,
watch it grow.
Feel like you're giving
a little something back.
Kind of like campaigning,
then getting reelected,
huh, Judge?
I meant to thank you
for that contribution, Lucas.
Now you can.
What's on your mind?
Caleb Temple.
You read my report?
Well, I glanced at it.
Good.
I just want to make sure
we're on the same page.
The boy's had a rough time,
you know. He lost his father,
his sister.
He's gonna be all alone,
Harris. He's gonna need
proper guidance.
Well, I understand
a cousin's in town.
That's true, and under
normal circumstances...
she would be
the logical candidate
for custody...
but unfortunately,
she is a bit unstable.
Never recovered
from the loss
of her parents.
Things like that
could confuse a child.
That's exactly
what I'm getting at.
Caleb has this notion...
that he ought to
stay with this doctor
he hardly even knows.
Fella's even more dangerous
than his cousin.
He likes his cocktails.
Got you.
At any rate,
after much soul-searching,
I've decided to step up...
and offer my home
to the boy.
Well, that's certainly
admirable of you, Lucas.
I didn't know
you liked children.
I feel it's my duty
as a concerned citizen.
The youth of today
represent the future, Judge.
And I believe we must do
everything in our power...
to make sure they are given
the right tools for survival.
I understand.
So, I can count on you
to support me on this?
I'll do the right thing.
Let's go over it once more.
The patient came
in complaining of right upper
quadrant pain after eating.
Gallbladder ultrasound
was positive for stones.
No allergies.
Alkaline phosphatase
mildly elevated.
Normal bilirubin.
Okay, then we're covered.
No, I'm not really concerned
about being covered, Danny.
Patient's gonna be fine,
I just want to find out
what went wrong.
Oh, man.
There was nothing
on Wills' chart
about epilepsy.
And all of a sudden there was,
and now my ass is in a sling.
Says who? What's going on?
Everything okay at home?
Yeah.
Everything's fine.
You got a job?
This is a boarding house.
It may be
a non-profit organization,
but that's not on purpose.
I don't have any money.
Look,
don't you worry about that.
You a good worker.
You know, it's no shame
to lose someone you love,
Caleb.
It happens. All the time.
Now come on,
I want you to do me a favor.
Smells good.
I think you added
the missing ingredient, Caleb.
What?
Compassion.
Now you know
that big white house
over on Jackson?
I want you
to take some of this
over there. All right?
All right.
Caleb.
What you been doing?
Making soup.
Wow.
It must be good.
You know, our mamas
were really good cooks.
I bet you take after them.
Did you know my mama?
I think so.
I was pretty young then...
when I moved away.
But I can see her face.
Maybe it's just
from snapshots,
or old movies, you know?
I wish I remembered better.
You look like her.
Yeah?
Thank you.
Say, you want
a ride somewhere?
No, thanks.
Okay.
Well, I'll see you
after school, then.
Cheryl, I'm home.
Honey?
Damn that Lucas Buck.
I want that damn thing
out of here. You hear me?
You mess with Lucas Buck,
and you're a dead man.
Honey, listen, this thing
is getting out of control.
Lucas Buck is a real man.
Cheryl, listen to me.
He ain't nothing like you,
Danny boy.
What is wrong with you?
What, are you stupid?
Or do you just look that way?
That's it.
No, don't. Please.
No! No!
Don't, please! No, Daniel!
It's okay.
It's okay, baby.
I tried to stand up to him...
but he just kept
coming after me.
And then he sent
that mirror...
then all this stuff
happened to us.
He wants me to destroy Matt
at this hearing.
And if I don't...
I'm gonna lose you.
I don't know what to do, baby.
I don't know what to do.
And how long...
have you been with
the Charleston Post,
Ms. Emory?
About seven years, Judge.
It's the best job
in the world.
But you'd be willing
to take on
this responsibility...
if I think that
this is the best thing
for Caleb?
Yes.
I can give you my
financial records, if...
No, that won't be necessary.
I'm sure you make
a good living. Thank you,
Ms. Emory.
Ms. Coombs?
Thank you, Judge.
I'd just like to say,
for the record...
that I admire
Ms. Emory tremendously.
I mean, when she told
my class about...
living in a crack house
for two weeks...
just to do
a first-person story,
and how scary it was...
they were all very impressed.
I know I wouldn't have
that kind of courage.
Thank you, Ms. Coombs.
May I say
something else, Judge?
As Caleb's teacher...
I know that
he's a wonderful boy who needs
a firm hand of discipline...
and you won't find
a firmer hand
than Sheriff Buck.
Before the Sheriff speaks,
perhaps we should hear
what the boy has to say.
Caleb, where would
you like to go?
Guess I'd like to stay
with Dr. Matt.
Judge, may I?
Go ahead.
Judge, I'd like to guide
Dr. Truelane through some
important information...
about his colleague,
Dr. Crower.
Why don't you just
ask me directly?
Because I follow
proper procedure. Don't you?
Now then, Dan, how long
have you known Dr. Crower?
Since he came to Trinity.
Six, seven months.
Long enough, then.
You two ever
drive to work together?
Car pool?
He doesn't have a car.
Why not?
How would I know?
Well, as your friend
and colleague...
did he ever share
the reason with you
that he does not drive?
No.
You two ever go out
for drinks together?
I don't drink.
What about Dr. Crower?
I've never seen him drink.
He ever mention to you
a time when he did?
I don't remember.
At the hospital fundraiser,
maybe?
Yeah.
He told me how difficult
it had been for him
to quit drinking.
Most people
can take it or leave it,
wouldn't you say?
I guess so.
But he found it hard to quit.
So that could only mean, what?
He's an alcoholic?
That's not for me to say.
Could it be that Dr. Crower
advised you to treat
a Jacksonian epileptic...
with a nearly fatal anesthesia
because he's still drinking?
That's not for me to say.
I see. So his drinking
doesn't affect his work?
I never said
he was an alcoholic.
Well, did he ever say it?
Yes, but...
Then he's an
admitted alcoholic?
Yes, but he's sober now.
I mean, he hasn't had a drink
since...
Since his wife
and daughter died?
No, you're twisting my words.
How did they die?
Didn't they die
in a twisted heap of metal on
the Massachusetts Turnpike...
after the good doctor
had had too many Chablis
or martinis or whatever?
Now, ain't that the truth?
Yes...
that's the truth.
Well, now...
that's a tragedy.
I guess that's it, Judge.
Well, now, Caleb...
you got yourself
some fine kinfolks
in your cousin, Ms. Emory.
And although she lives
in a very picturesque
and exciting world...
I don't think
it's quite the one
for a 10-year-old boy.
What about Dr. Matt?
The problem is...
is a doctor works long hours.
And a young boy needs somebody
to look after him full time.
That's why
I'm awarding custody...
to someone well-known
in this community...
and someone known
as a caretaker for the needy.
A very fine person,
Ms. Loris Holt.
What?
That's my decision for
Caleb's temporary custody...
pending review by the state.
Caleb, I want to thank you
for that soup you brought
over to me the other day.
It made me feel better
than I've felt in a long time.
Ms. Holt has a mighty fine
boarding house.
She makes a mighty fine
cup of soup.
Yes, sir, she does.
Now, you okay with that, son?
Yes, sir.
I want to thank all of you
for coming.
Daniel.
I don't blame you for this.
You told the truth
and I won't forget about that.
Now go on back to your wife.
Have you lost your mind?
Maybe.
We've had a long and mutually
profitable relationship,
Harris.
Had, Lucas.
See, I've got
advanced prostate cancer.
Maybe I should've started
my organic gardening
a little earlier.
I see. Now you're worried
about meeting your maker...
and all that hooey,
is that it?
Least I'm off the hook
with you, Lucas.
Think so?
I'll be the judge of that.
Soon as you're well enough
to be moved...
we're getting out of here.
We'll go up north...
or down to Atlanta.
Yeah.
A buddy of mine
from med school...
he got into
reconstructive surgery,
I'll give him a call, and...
No.
Honey?
I think I'm okay.
No, let me.
I don't believe it.
How do I look?
You look beautiful.
I don't want to run.
We didn't do anything.
You didn't do anything.
I sold out a friend, Cheryl.
I know you told the truth.
If he's your friend,
he knows that.
Give me a big piece, Rose.
You're greedy.
Better save some
for the other boarder.
The mystery boarder?
How about some cake?
Okay.
Thank you.
So you're
the new mystery boarder.
Howdy.
I picked up some stuff
on my way home to celebrate.
Root beer?
Is this what Yankees
eat at parties?
You calling me a Yankee?
Well, you are.
I guess I am.
Is that a problem for you?
Nope.
Good.
Where's your room?
It's upstairs
in case you need me.
Only in case.
Mine's up in the tower
in case you need me.
Only in case.
You gonna pray
to the Lord
Oh, please deliver me
What you gonna do
When Death comes for you
Caleb?
Aren't you gonna
say good night?
Hey.
I got a new room.
I can see that.
Not mad at me anymore?
I never was.
Open the door.
And there's all the people.
I can't feel you, Merlyn.
Well, I can feel you.
What do I feel like?
Like family.
Good night, Merlyn.
Good night.