I've heard it said...
that the American dream
is a thing of the past.
That the basic tenets of home,
job, and family
are slipping away.
Well, not in my town.
Where I come from,
that dream is still a reality.
Course,
you have to know who's boss.
For those who follow my lead,
life can be a paradise.
But for those who don't,
it can be a mighty rough road.
Daddy,
what should I wish for?
What should I wish for,
Daddy?
Salvation.
Merlyn.
What do you think
I should wish for?
Don't get her going.
It's all right,
you don't have to tell me.
I know.
I'm blowing out
my candles now, Daddy.
Someone's at the door.
No.
She ain't gonna
do this again.
Someone's at the door.
Shut up!
It's okay, Daddy.
Just give her a minute...
Someone's at the door.
...and things
will be all right.
Someone's at the door.
I said shut up!
Leave her alone,
she can't help it!
Someone's at the door.
Shut up, dammit!
Make her stop!
It ain't her fault!
The hell it ain't!
Every damn problem
in our miserable lives
is her fault!
Someone's at the door.
It's okay, Merlyn.
Take it easy.
Take it easy, Merlyn.
Someone's at the door.
Stop!
Daddy, what are you doing?
I said stop!
Daddy, no!
Don't run away from me.
Merlyn, open the door.
Come back here, girl.
Come on, open the door.
Come on.
Someone's at the door.
Open this door, boy!
Open up, boy.
Someone's at the door.
Open up right now!
I can still hear you, girl!
Someone's at the door.
Come on, Merlyn,
we gotta go.
Come on, Merlyn.
Please, Merlyn, come on!
All right, you stay here,
but don't open the door.
Don't open the door,
understand?
I'm gonna get help.
Merlyn, stay there,
I'll be right back!
Don't open the door!
Someone's at the door.
Ten long years, Merlyn.
Ten years of hell
you've put us through.
No more running, son.
Someone's at the door.
This here's for your mama.
Caleb, wait!
I'll handle this.
Listen to me.
I want you to stay right here.
Attaboy.
Merlyn.
Merlyn... Merlyn...
Someone's at the door.
Merlyn.
Merlyn, honey,
can you hear me?
Someone's at the door.
Yes, darling.
But we don't have to worry
about that no more.
I wanna see my sister.
Is she all right?
Deputy! Keep that monster
away from my boy.
You folks see me in back?
Actually, no, Sheriff.
Danielle, let's give
these boys some room.
How's the job working out, D?
I don't know
what you said...
but the station's offering me
a hell of a deal.
Is there any other kind?
Badge, on or off?
Off. We know who's boss.
All right, then,
the body of
Merlyn Ann Temple...
16-year-old child...
beautiful child,
was discovered this evening
at approximately 9:55 p.m.
Cause of death appears to be
a blunt instrument
to the head.
I have the sad duty
of reporting...
that the victim's father
is our prime suspect.
We have no motive
at this time,
but we do have a witness.
The surviving child,
Caleb Temple...
as he has been left
without a family...
I am hoping our community will
support me...
in shepherding him
through these dark days ahead.
Sheriff,
where is the child now?
We have him
safely in custody...
and as soon as
we're able to...
get an account...
Lucas.
It appears that
the boy was slightly injured
in the melee...
and has been taken
to the hospital.
He won't be there long.
This is Danielle Davenport,
live, News 22, from Trinity.
Back to you, Bill.
Thank you, Danielle.
Just wait here.
The nurse will be with you
in a minute.
Their whole family's been
troubled since the beginning.
Don't get me started
on her mother.
Whole family's crazy.
It's just a shame.
I remember when
they brought her in...
So sad.
She had two kids.
I know.
She's such
a pretty little thing.
Folks. Bar's closed.
Let's get you out of here.
Do you have
any other relatives in town?
Child welfare
talk to you yet?
Gumball?
Your hand's gonna
be fine, Caleb.
And nothing else
that happened tonight
is your fault.
I'm down the hall
if you need me.
That my sister down there?
Yes, it is.
I want to see her.
That's not a good idea.
Why not?
Because it won't help.
Do you know it's my birthday?
No, I didn't.
Well, it is, and I think
I got a right to see
my sister on my birthday.
Dr. Crower.
Sheriff's here.
Give me two minutes.
On whose authority
is he with you?
Hi, Sheriff.
Situations like this,
child welfare grants
the doctor in charge...
temporary custody.
These folks seen
your driving record?
Forgive me,
alcoholism is just
a disease now, right?
Like the common cold,
only more colorful.
What do you know about me?
Yankee blue blood,
Harvard Med...
came to town last fall,
been causing trouble
ever since.
"Let's build a new hospital,
let's clean up Goat Town...
"let's drown the poor
in biscuits and gravy."
You ain't exactly
been shy, Doctor.
And I thought
the Southern Sheriff
was just a cliché.
I want the boy.
Question him tomorrow.
This ain't about questioning,
I'm family.
Not according to his file.
You're a good man, aren't you?
I don't know what that means.
Anything happens
to that child, you will.
Caleb isn't going anywhere
until I say so.
You got him
till noon tomorrow.
Hey, Sheriff.
Drive safely.
Lucas,
I'm having a hard time.
That so?
You've done a lot for me,
and I figure that I owe you.
You got your lucky pen?
Yeah.
Write that down.
What I'm trying to say is...
I saw you.
I saw what you did
to that girl.
I didn't mean to,
I just, I thought
you might need some help...
and that's what...
What color is this gun?
What?
What color is the gun?
I don't...
The answer's as plain
as the nose on your face.
It's a gray gun.
A ray gun?
A gray gun, Lucas!
It's a gray gun!
That's right, Ben.
It's gray.
But isn't it possible
that my idea of gray...
and your idea of gray
might differ?
Yeah, I guess so.
All depends on
your perception, right?
Get out of the car, Ben.
Get out of the car.
Now, I believe...
you need a drink.
You have a bottle on me,
and while you're sipping...
you think about
what you saw tonight.
All right, Lucas,
I'll do that.
The world can be
a beautiful place, Ben.
You just got to know
how to look at it.
Fulton County Hospital,
children's ward.
Dan, can you track down
some files on Caleb Temple's
parents for me?
I'd have to
check the basement.
Great, thanks.
I hate the basement.
Have you ever been
to the basement?
Sorry, Caleb, but...
Caleb?
I'm sorry, Merlyn.
I should've been there
to protect you.
Caleb.
You don't need this.
You got water, pajamas,
extra blanket...
and a genuine
Elvis pillowcase.
Make you sleep like a king.
I got something else
for you, too.
Is that your mom?
You know a lot of folks
that's died?
I guess I have.
Family?
My wife and daughter.
Where do you think
they are now?
I don't know.
I keep forgetting
they're gone.
Family stays with you, Caleb.
You think about them...
you dream about them.
That keeps them alive.
I dream about Mama a lot.
Never met her,
but made a wish
about her tonight.
A wish to have her back.
Maybe I didn't have to.
You get some sleep.
Hello, Ben.
Conducting a raid?
I wasn't aware they allowed
law enforcement
in places like this.
I'm off-duty.
Lucky me.
Rack your balls?
What are you doing here,
Selena?
Trolling.
Well, you can do that
in a nicer neighborhood.
Well, I have certain needs
that can't be...
fulfilled uptown.
This just ain't my game.
I can see that.
Need a teacher?
You made this happen,
didn't you?
You make everything happen.
This document grants me
sole custody of Caleb.
And I'd like you to sign it.
I ain't signing nothing.
You care about his future?
Too late for salvation,
my friend.
Not for me.
You know,
you may have a point.
You miss your wife, Gage?
She was quite a woman,
wasn't she?
Some would say a saint.
Get out of here.
But I guess she just wasn't
cut out for mothering.
Get out!
So she did
the honorable thing.
She took her life.
Which spared her family
her pain...
and set her son free.
There must be
some salvation in that.
Goodbye, Gage.
Dan said
you wanted some files.
Right, thanks.
Were you here
the night his mom died?
Yeah, right out on the floor.
What happened?
Well,
day after Caleb was born,
she started acting crazy...
convinced somebody was gonna
steal her baby.
We tried to
get a hold of the father...
but that little girl
was throwing a fit...
and he couldn't get away.
Merlyn?
See, she had been
traumatized by something
earlier in the year.
Nobody knew why,
but she'd just
go off sometimes.
Caleb's mama
was kicking up such a fuss,
we had to call the Sheriff.
And he no sooner got in
that room before she threw
herself out that window.
God.
Yeah. Course, after that,
Caleb's daddy
wasn't ever the same.
Blamed hisself.
He really blamed that girl.
Is that why the Sheriff
is so interested in Caleb?
Lucas is interested
in everybody.
Caleb, wake up.
Caleb.
He's coming.
He's coming, Caleb.
Caleb, he's coming.
Hey, Sheriff.
Evening, Wendy.
You and your husband
get into that house?
Sure did, and don't you worry,
we're gonna pay you back
as soon as...
I'm not worried.
What part of
our earlier conversation
didn't you understand?
I was just dropping off
a present for the boy.
Heard it was his birthday.
You can drop it
at the desk...
on your way out.
Help me a sec.
Caleb's mom died
from massive head injuries...
You ever sleep?
...but her body was filled
with puncture wounds.
I thought you was
looking for relatives.
Why was she so cut up?
Glass from the window.
Right.
But if you're gonna
kill yourself...
by jumping out of a window,
don't you open it first?
Was the Sheriff
the only one in the room
when this happened?
Careful, Matt.
Mr. Buck's been around here
lot longer than you have.
Excuse me, are you Dr. Crower?
Yes.
I'm Gail Emory.
Caleb Temple's cousin.
So when did you see him last?
Actually, we've never met.
Well, he's a great kid.
He's bright, sensitive.
You don't have to
sell me, Doctor.
Sorry.
It's just that you may be
all he's got left.
I don't mean to scare you.
No, I don't scare.
He was up pretty late.
Don't wake him.
Can you come back later?
Say, noon?
Promise.
Okay.
Who's feeling happy today?
Me!
I am!
What's the matter, Josh?
I miss Caleb.
Well, I'm sure we all do...
but can't you put on
your happy face
for our special guest?
That's better.
We're ready for you,
special guest.
Hi, kids.
Hello, Sheriff Buck.
I'm sure you all know about
what happened last night.
Caleb Temple needs
our support, so...
who wants to be deputized?
All right, then.
Miss Coombs,
may I see you in private?
How much did he tell you?
Everything.
Son of a bitch.
Where is he now?
Dropping off my car.
You let him drive your car?
Needed a wash.
Well, I wasn't going to
take him to my apartment.
How was he?
Short.
I told you to
test his loyalty,
not his endurance.
You work your way,
I'll work mine.
Besides, that deputy
ain't your problem.
What do you mean?
How much do you love me?
Depends.
Caleb's cousin's in town.
What?
Little bird told me
she popped into
the hospital this morning...
very concerned about
her kin.
Hell.
Looks like you left some food
on your plate, darling.
Want me to clean it up
for you?
I'm here, Mom, Dad.
I always wanted to come back.
Guess I was just too afraid.
There's a little boy here
who's in the same situation
I was.
And he's gonna have
a lot of questions.
Questions I don't think
that I can answer.
Maybe if I understood
what happened to you.
I need to know the truth.
Please help me.
'Cause this time,
I'm not leaving
till I find it.
Hey, Temple,
you got a visitor.
Hi, Gage? I'm Dr. Crower,
I was wondering if I could
ask you a few questions...
about your wife.
Gage?
Open the door.
Ten-four, Healy out.
Station clear.
Cammalous said it looked like
Gage had been dead for hours.
Probably did
the state a favor.
You got no conscience
about anything, do you?
Conscience is just the fear
of getting caught, Ben.
I can't be part of this
no more.
That so?
What was that?
Problem.
Open the hood.
Come on, Ben.
I ain't got all day.
We may have popped a hose.
Check it out.
Why don't you
just come out here
and help me?
Because somebody's
gotta start the engine.
What are you doing?
Get in there
and find out what's wrong.
I don't see any hose.
Hell.
What's this?
That's probably clogged.
Give me your pen.
Come on, Ben.
Well, I can't find it.
Your lucky pen's missing?
Yeah.
I wonder where it went.
Oh, my God.
Hey, you didn't have anything
to do with Gage's death,
did you?
No, not you.
Not my trusty deputy,
my faithful sidekick.
You'd never do
anything like that.
You know I wouldn't!
Just because it was your pen,
your lucky, monogrammed,
platinum pen...
that still don't mean
you did it, right?
Now, I was with Selena Coombs
all night long.
That sweet little
school teacher?
But I saw her today...
and she told me she spent
a quiet evening at home
grading papers.
She wouldn't lie.
Why are you doing this to me?
Just another lesson
in perception, Ben.
All guilt is relative,
loyalty counts...
and never let your conscience
be your guide.
You coming?
Dr. Crower says no one
is to see the patient
until he gets back!
Caleb, you awake?
Sheriff, please!
What kind of drugs
they give you, boy?
Where is he?
I don't know, he's...
Bitch.
Did you check
the emergency room?
Yeah, I've been all over,
Matt. He's gone.
You have no idea
where the Sheriff went?
I don't wanna know.
Dr. Crower, somehow I think
Caleb may have gone home.
I should never have left
that hospital this morning.
It's not your fault.
Caleb was my responsibility.
Let's just hope
that we find him
before Lucas Buck.
He's the Sheriff?
Yes.
I don't know why
Caleb is so important...
Lucas Buck is the name of
the man who found my parents
the day they died.
Merlyn?
Happy birthday.
Are you a ghost?
No.
Angel?
I'm your family.
You're talking.
In life, you were my voice...
and now you must hear me.
Your father's coming.
But I thought he was in...
You have the locket?
Yes.
Open it.
Why?
Because you need
to know the truth, Caleb.
Open the locket.
Now turn around.
"...until finally,
the wolf arrived at
the grandmother's house."
Is that where Daddy is?
Daddy will be home soon,
Merlyn.
"Now, when he got to
the front door, the wolf
looked into the forest...
"to make sure
that no one had seen
him coming"...
Hello, darling, mother here?
Mama. Someone's at the door.
What do you want here?
You know what I want.
We talked about it.
Now, I've told you
that you should
stay away from me.
This isn't about you.
Please,
just stay away from me.
It's about me.
It's about family.
Please.
No!
Why?
Because you need
to know the truth, Caleb.
Be careful, Caleb.
Someone's at the door.
No more running, son.
Look here, boy.
There's only two roads
in this world...
and if you're listening
to anyone but me...
you're on the wrong one.
That's his car.
Caleb,
you're gonna have to trust me.
That's good liquor
you're wasting there, son.
I ain't your son!
I beg to differ.
Where's Caleb?
Where is he?
Where's the boy?
I know who you are!
Caleb!