Previously on American Gothic.
I'll handle this.
Someone's at the door.
Deputy! Keep that monster
away from my boy.
I have the sad duty
of reporting...
the victim's father
is our prime suspect.
I want the boy.
Caleb isn't going
anywhere until I say so.
This document grants
me sole custody of Caleb.
And I'd like you to sign it.
He's coming.
Are you a ghost?
No.
Angel?
I'm your family.
Be careful, Caleb.
Someone's at the door.
No more running, son.
That's good liquor
you're wasting there, son.
I ain't your son.
I beg to differ.
Caleb!
The water truck
should be there...
Hold the water truck.
Deb, the farm house is toast.
We got a 10-year-old boy
with a 30-minute start.
I want him back by sundown.
The man who comes through
for me wins a steak dinner.
What the hell is this,
Sheriff, High Noon?
This boy isn't a criminal.
He's just running...
because he's lost
his family and he's scared.
He's running, Doctor,
because you couldn't
keep him in your hospital.
And I couldn't keep you out.
You want to do something
for this boy...
just leave him the hell alone.
We're wasting time.
I don't believe we've met.
Not officially, anyway.
Gail Emory.
And I know we have.
Where you been
all these years, missy?
Lose your car keys?
Lucas, she's Caleb's cousin.
Was I talking to you?
If you're looking
for the mall,
it ain't built yet.
I'm coming with
you to find Caleb.
Got the family nose
for news, do you?
If that's what it takes
to get your attention.
Ma'am, you already
have my attention.
That's Sheriff Lucas Buck.
That's Buck with a "B."
Gentlemen, we have an
esteemed member of the press
joining us this afternoon.
Please make her feel welcome,
and feel free
to sing my praises.
Sadly, the good doctor...
will be needed elsewhere.
Something's
up at the hospital.
I have to get back.
Go ahead. I'll be fine.
That boy is gonna need medical
attention as soon as
he's found. You understand me?
Howdy, boys. Meet Dr. Crower.
Get, get. Let's go.
Get out there, come on.
Does Caleb know
his father is dead?
I don't see how he could,
he been running all night.
You have to understand, ma'am,
when something like this
happens to a child...
you just can't...
When I was 8 years old...
I lost my parents.
I do understand.
Shoot. Course you did.
Then you know how traumatic
something like this can be.
I believe Caleb
burned down his house
as a cry for help...
to protest
the loss of his sister.
Well, that's one theory.
You got a better one?
Maybe he just wanted
to get away from you.
Must be tough working
for a man like that.
Or maybe not.
Look, whatever you think
about Lucas, he's helped out
a lot of folks in this town.
How's that?
Well, by giving them
a second chance.
After high school,
I went down to Georgia,
run fullback.
Junior year,
I blew my knee out...
and the same week,
my girlfriend got pregnant.
So suddenly I had
no scholarship, no money,
and a baby on the way.
So he gave you a job?
Not only that, he paid
for my damn wedding.
Course, now I'm divorced,
and hardly ever see my kid...
but still I can't
forget what...
Lucas done for me.
You're a loyal man.
Well, you got to be.
No matter what it costs you?
Dr. Truelane to O.R. please.
Dr. Truelane to O.R.
You the coroner?
Yes. Yes, ma'am, I am.
I got Lucas' message.
How much time will you need?
Look, I don't usually
work this way.
I understand. How much time?
Well, I suppose an hour
would keep things within
the realm of possibility.
An hour for two autopsies?
You're faster than I am.
You make sure
the doctor doesn't disturb me.
Honey, I'm craving
medical attention.
I'm coming for you, boy.
Deputy, thanks for the ride.
Say, Doc.
Are you gonna be examining
Mr. Temple's body
any time soon?
That's up to the coroner.
Oh, yeah. Right.
Why?
It's nothing really, but...
I mean, I don't know
if you happen
to know how he died.
I found the body.
Then so you do
know about the...
The pen in his windpipe?
Yeah. The pen.
Yeah, what about it?
Well, now,
this was a suicide, right?
It looks that way.
Well, did anybody happen
to mention to you
who the pen belonged to?
No.
Well, it was mine.
Now, you got to believe me
when I say that I didn't
have anything to do...
with Gage's death.
I swear, I'd never
do nothing like that but...
I loved that pen.
I see.
And I'd really
like to get it back.
And how did Mr. Temple
get ahold of it?
Well, now, I don't know that.
But I swear I had nothing
to do with it.
You got to believe me.
I believe you, Ben...
but I'm not the one
you have to convince.
Look, I'm meeting
the coroner this afternoon.
When he's done
with his autopsy,
I'll see what I can do.
Okay, Doc.
I appreciate that. You know...
it was kind of like
a lucky charm, you know.
My mom gave it to me.
Well, you take care of
yourself, Doc, and everything
is going to be fine.
And don't worry about the boy.
We're gonna find him.
Everything is going
to be fine.
Everything
is going to be fine.
I'll call you when
I'm finished.
All right.
Oral report to be transferred
to short-form protocol.
I, Curtis Z. Webb,
performed autopsy
on the body of...
Gage Temple at 10.30 a.m.
From the anatomic findings
and pertinent history
I ascribe the death to...
suicide.
And I'm a lying
sack of goat manure.
I, Curtis Z. Webb...
performed autopsy
on the body of...
Merlyn Ann Temple at...
11.00 a.m.
From the anatomic findings
and pertinent history...
I ascribe the death to...
"massive head trauma."
God forgive me.
Someone's at the door.
Merlyn?
Is this what I look like?
You look the same.
I don't feel the same.
Caleb, it's nice
to see you again.
For me, too, Merly.
The sheriff is after me.
He thinks he's my daddy.
What do you think?
I think he's crazy.
This whole thing is crazy.
He wants to raise
you in his image, Caleb.
You can't run forever.
Why not? I don't need him.
I don't need nobody.
I'm gonna make
it hard for them.
I'm going to a secret place.
Caleb.
That's where I'm going.
And this sweatshirt ought
to give them dogs something
to look for downstream.
Get it?
That's why I got
to go upstream.
I'll paddle my way to hell
and back to get away
from that sheriff.
You want to come with me?
Be careful, Caleb, you may not
like what you find up there.
All right, then.
I'll tell you what
I find, I guess.
See you later, Merlyn.
This isn't exactly
an emergency.
I'm sorry.
I guess I got
a little hysterical.
How did this happen?
Well, you know kids,
sometimes they like
to roughhouse.
A child did this?
Well, I'm a school teacher,
Dr. Crower?
And I was wrestling
with one of my boys...
on the playground
and he got a little frisky.
Must have been
a pretty big boy.
I'm going to give
you a tetanus shot.
Will it be painful?
Not really.
Hip?
That'd be fine.
Someone once told me
that you should always
make yourself laugh...
when you're getting a shot.
That way, you don't
feel the pain as much.
But I think in life,
you have to take
the good with the bad.
Do we have a choice?
Always have a choice, Doctor.
Which one would you prefer?
I'm gonna need you
to turn around.
Silly me.
Everything all right?
Heaven.
All right. Hurry up. Hurry up.
You sure work fast, Doc.
I know I work fast.
Why don't you try
doing the same?
Where are they going?
Down the hall for pick up.
Oh, no.
Let me get out of here.
Don't.
Don't bury...
Don't bury the truth.
You sure we're going
the right way?
We're moving away from town.
Caleb wouldn't go back there.
Town means hospital.
Dr. Crower seems to think
the boy only ran
because you scared him.
That doctor should
take a pill.
If Caleb had been
with me last night, none
of this would have happened.
What do you want with him?
I'm just doing my job, ma'am.
Got to protect my people.
Like you did my parents?
I believe your tone
has offended someone.
For almost 20 years now,
I've questioned
how my parents died.
And last month
I finally got
the coroner's report.
You're the one who found them.
How come you never
contacted me?
They died in a fire, ma'am.
Did you really want
the grisly details?
No, they died
because they were
trapped in a building.
Someone had locked
them in there.
Miss Coombs, I really
have to get going.
I'm sorry.
Here I am going
on about me and...
you've got all these
wounded souls to heal.
Is this your family?
Beautiful ladies.
Yes, they were.
Past tense?
Doctor, I am so sorry.
I had no idea.
That's okay. That's fine.
Now, if you don't mind.
Am I interrupting something?
No.
You feel better.
Is the coroner here yet?
Just left.
I thought he was doing
the autopsies on the
Temple girl and her father.
Yeah, I thought so, too.
But he just got the bodies...
and hauled them out of here.
And what are we gonna
do with this?
Sorry, Dan. I would have
been there. That woman
just wouldn't leave.
Not that it wasn't
enjoyable on some level.
Keep it on
a superficial level.
I've heard stories about
her that would make
your toes curl.
Come on with it, girl.
They really burying
these two side-by-side?
Yeah. First thing
in the morning.
That's foul.
Just 'cause he killed her,
don't mean they can't share
the same worms.
No offense, Daddy,
but this ain't your best work.
I only had two hours.
You know, Sheriff
put in a rush.
"Rest in Pease."
Rest in pease?
You got him resting
in peas, Daddy.
I'll rest you.
Well, we'll fix it tomorrow.
Come on, Teapot.
I got a shovel at home
with your name on it.
If you ever kill me...
hope you'll do it
with something cleaner
than a shovel.
How about a pen?
What... What are you...
Hey!
Sheriff?
Dogs found this
about a quarter of a mile
downriver.
Smart boy.
What are you doing?
Praying.
Merlyn?
I used to be able
to feel the sun.
I miss it.
Why are you still running?
Daddy is dead, Merlyn.
Seen his grave.
Yours, too.
Everybody is dead.
Not everybody.
I ain't going in there.
That man needs your help.
He's a monster.
No.
Can you understand
his pain, Caleb?
He's just hurt.
I would think
you could understand
that, Caleb.
Look...
I want to free you.
But if you don't...
Don't do that.
Listen, I'm gonna free you.
We're gonna be friends,
right, if I do?
Sorry I ran out on you...
but I didn't know
what you was all about.
God, you're freezing.
Can you walk?
We got to find you a doctor.
Sol.
Sol?
You don't have
to pay me nothing.
I guess we could
use some food.
All right, Sol, I'm gonna
get us some food
and try to find you a doctor.
I'll be back with help, Sol.
I promise.
No one knows why
these things happen.
And maybe it's not
our job to ask.
But, like the Reverend said,
we can take comfort
knowing that...
Gage and Merlyn
are in a better place.
I plant this tree
in their memory, hopeful
that someday it might...
capture the spirit
of the family.
Thank you all for coming.
Thank you, Sheriff.
How well did you know
Gage Temple?
Not too well.
He pretty much
kept to himself.
Neighbors said he was
a quiet man, never gave
anyone any trouble.
Getting all the facts, ma'am?
What's happening with Caleb?
A crew has been
out since dawn.
Now that we know
where he's traveling...
we could have
your little cousin
back home in no time.
Can we offer you
a ride back to town,
Miss Emory?
No, thank you.
Want to make sure
you're taken care of.
Tourists are our lifeblood,
right, Ben?
Is that why they keep
disappearing?
Fire up the car.
You know, according
to my editor...
this county is like
the Bermuda Triangle
of tourism.
We rank lowest
in serious crime
in the entire state, ma'am.
And highest
in missing persons.
Last spring, there
was a reporter
from the Miami Tribune.
He came up here
to investigate.
And he hasn't been
heard from since.
Well, this is
a recreational area.
Between the woods
and the beaches,
accidents happen.
Maybe he was a poor swimmer.
Or maybe he was just
a poor judge of character.
Good day, Sheriff.
Sorry, I didn't get
to meet your little friend.
You will.
Hello.
Hello?
Yes, sir?
Is your father home?
Daddy.
We're eating cake.
What kind of cake?
Goat cheese.
Mr. Webb?
Yes, sir.
I'm Matt Crower.
I missed you yesterday.
Right, the new doctor.
Could we have a word?
Go on to your mama, Taylor.
She's a sweet girl.
Yes, she is.
A little slow.
How can I help you, Doc?
I was curious about the result
of your autopsies...
on Gage and Merlyn Temple.
Thank you.
Eli, food.
This here is Eli.
He's my sweetie pie.
He's our big boy.
Why did you release
their bodies
from the hospital so early?
You know the amazing
thing about goats?
They'll eat anything.
Most self-sufficient
creatures in the world.
Feed them shoes,
get back milk.
Mr. Webb...
That nanny over there
is expecting. Should have
kids by Christmas.
The Temples
were buried this morning.
How did you have time
to complete your work?
The girl took a shovel
to the head, am I right?
According to the Sheriff.
And the father was found
with a pen in his throat,
self-inflicted.
Is that your finding?
Well, there was blood
all over his hand.
What about the angle of entry
or the depth of the wound?
You know what I love
about these animals?
They accept things
as they are.
You didn't do any
autopsies, did you?
I take pride
in my work, Doctor.
But sometimes,
other forces prevail.
Girl died of head trauma.
Father was a suicide.
I accept that.
And I suggest you do the same.
Mr. Webb...
Lucas Buck was the last person
to see these people alive.
He was also the last person
to see Caleb Temple's mother
before she died.
That's three members
of the same family gone.
Why are you protecting him?
Because I have a family, too.
Caleb.
You really my cousin?
Yeah.
How come I
never heard of you?
I left town a long time ago.
Before you were born.
You working with the Sheriff?
No.
I'm here to help you.
Well, I don't need no help.
I need a ride.
Get in.
Daddy, why do you put trees
on these things?
Supposed to represent death...
and rebirth.
It's also easy to paint.
So, what do you think?
I liked him better in "pease."
Get my coat, girl.
Daddy...
what was you saying
about rebirth?
This wasn't no bigger
than a shrub a minute ago.
God. Come on, Teapot.
I can get it.
Holy Mother of God.
No, I said come on. Teapot!
Rita, I'm going
to need an ambulance.
They'll never find him.
I got to take you.
Hold off, Rita.
Caleb, I can't let
you leave again.
If anything happens...
But look, the man
is expecting me.
Look, he even
gave me some money...
for food.
You got to trust me.
I won't run away, I promise.
This is the guy.
What guy?
Rafael Santo.
He's a reporter
my editor told me about.
He's been missing for months.
I thought you said
his name was Sol.
Who cares what his name is.
We gonna help him or not?
This son of a bitch
is really beginning to irk me.
Well, don't doctors
usually talk to the coroner
after there has been a...
suicide?
Yeah, but my coroners
don't usually talk back.
Hey, Sheriff,
got your chocolates.
Glad to hear it, Louise,
you have
a killer birthday, now.
Maybe Curtis thought
he was doing you a favor.
Are you defending him?
No, I'm just...
Don't drop
the loyalty ball, Ben.
Feeling better, Albert?
Appreciate
you straightening things
out with my boss, Lucas.
You bet. This coroner made
a big mistake, Ben.
And if you don't see that,
you don't see much.
I'm not being disloyal, Lucas.
I'm just trying to clarify.
That's all.
Good.
Because if this doctor
gives me anymore trouble...
you're gonna shoot him.
Damn.
Thank you.
Hey, baby.
What's the matter?
Eli.
Lunch time, Eli.
You told me this was handled.
Well, I'm sorry, Lucas,
but I just couldn't hurt him.
So you kept him as a pet?
I liked him, okay?
To tell you the truth,
he kind of liked me.
This is a real problem,
Selena.
Well, look...
if the doctor finds him
before we do, maybe
it's not such a bad thing.
Rafael hasn't been
eating lately...
and I've been kind
of worried about him.
Rafael is a reporter.
He's gonna report things.
He won't say a word.
Really? What did you do?
Bite off his tongue
in a fit of passion.
Mr. Santo, can you hear me?
Okay, you're going
to be all right.
I'm here to help you, okay?
He's hypothermic.
I don't think he's
gonna make it to the hospital.
Is there anything
we can do for you?
It's Spanish.
Sol.
Sun.
Matt, he's freezing.
Where do you want them?
Here, can you cover him up?
Sure.
Caleb, come here.
Do you think you can
get up there and pry off
one of those boards?
Well, if this is what
Sol wants, this is what
Sol is gonna get.
Y'all were right.
Sol is warming right up.
That was just what
you needed, huh, Sol?
Matt?
Look. Look at this.
Just what you needed.
What's the matter with him?
He's gone, Caleb.
But he can't be,
I got you here in time.
You did everything
that you could.
This wasn't supposed
to happen.
It wasn't supposed to happen.
Caleb.
Caleb!
Well, now, look
who's found our fugitive.
This the man?
What are you doing here?
I might ask you
the same question.
I've been hunting
this fellow for months...
ever since he attacked
and robbed Miss Coombs.
Wait a minute.
This man is from
the Miami Tribune.
And somebody has been
keeping him here.
That someone
was his partner, ma'am.
His partner in crime
obviously double-crossed him.
What partner?
You have this person
in custody?
Well, we did...
till we buried him
this morning.
Afraid Gage Temple
was more dangerous
than anyone realized.
I'm gonna need
that for evidence.
Merlyn!
Merlyn, you lied to me.
You said I could
help that man.
You did help him.
You gave him what he needed.
He didn't need to die.
I don't want to see you
no more, you understand?
You're dead. Dead as he is.
I live in you, Caleb.
And so does your father.
Just get out of here,
will you? Leave me alone.
Merlyn, look out.
Merlyn!
Merlyn.
Merlyn, you all right?
Merlyn!