It's clear, come on.
...six and seven...
and eight...
and nine and ten.
Oly oly oxen free.
Caleb.
I'm not laughing.
Come on, y'all, where are you?
Sutpen's gonna get you.
Sutpen's gonna get you, Boone.
Mama. How long
is dinner gonna be?
I'm thawing
the chops right now.
There's corn to think about.
Maybe a fresh garden salad.
How would that strike y'all?
Honey, we don't know
about all that. We just
wanna know when we'll eat.
If you'd fix the electric
so I could do more
than one thing at a time.
Damn those
juvenile delinquents.
What's going on out there?
Come on, kids,
I'm not gonna scold you.
I can hear you.
Sked!
We just don't want to see
anybody getting hurt.
One of these days,
I gotta take all the doors
off these old things.
Good idea, Carter. That is
about the worst thing that
could happen in this world.
A child trapped in an icebox.
Hello, Sheriff.
Yes, sir.
Every parent's nightmare,
losing a child.
What is it, Lucas?
No, it's just that
you remember when there was
that unpleasantness...
with Wash Sutpen's
little girl,
don't you, Carter?
Yeah, sure. How could
I forget what you done for me?
Glad your memory
serves you, my friend.
Then you haven't
forgotten about
your part of the bargain.
I guess I knew
a payback was coming.
What do I owe you, Sheriff?
I'm not sure.
Know what? I know.
I could use another
girl around the office.
You know, making the coffee,
doing the filing,
being my little gofer.
How old is your Poppy now?
She just turned 15 last month.
Darn. Child has to be
16 to be legal.
Then there's
Jimmy Lee Branson's daughter.
She just turned...
I brought a parental consent
form. And don't you worry.
I'll personally take her
under my wing. Now,
you take your time, Carter.
I won't need it till Friday.
Tomorrow?
I tell you what.
I'll give you till midnight.
You made a deal.
Now you gotta live by it.
How much is the rent?
$550 a month.
And it's got AC?
That it does.
Although all utilities
are not included.
I'll be leaving town
for a spell, so you'll be...
No, that's fine.
You got a deal.
Hello?
Hello, Gail.
Hi, Barton.
You got my message?
Yeah, and I'm not
too thrilled. I need you
back here on the city desk.
I know. I modemed you
that welfare piece
that I owed you...
and I'm down here.
I'm working on something.
You gotta cut me
some slack, okay, Barton?
Something's going on
down here.
No, I gotta call you back.
And what will your project be
for the science fair, Boone?
Me and my daddy are
gonna show how come
venison tastes best...
if you get a good clean
head shot and don't ruin it.
Caleb, would you like to
tell us about your project?
Mine's about weather.
That's a little bit vague.
What kind of weather?
Violent weather that changes
quick and destroys things.
Good. Caleb Temple: weather.
And remember
the rules, people.
All materials for
your project must be
common household items.
No buying stuff at
the hobby store.
Caleb, honey?
Ma'am?
Everyone else will be bringing
their parents with them
to the science fair...
so if you'd like to bring
someone with you, say,
Sheriff Buck, that'd be fine.
I'm sure he'd be
more than happy to help you
with your weather project.
If my daddy was still alive,
I wouldn't have any help...
and I don't need none,
now he's dead.
Hello?
Anybody here?
Hold on. I'm coming.
289. Nice little engine.
It's a bit underpowered,
to my way of thinking,
but it's nice.
My pony's fine. It's
my air conditioner
that needs work.
Like the sign says,
we fix anything.
It's probably the compressor
or the relay.
We'll get it so
you're freezing to death
in no time at all.
How much is that gonna be?
You're gonna have to
talk to Mr. Bowen.
He takes all the money.
I just do the work,
you know how it is.
You must be Gail Emory.
How do you know?
Some people match
names to faces.
I match them to the cars.
My Mustang?
No, this wagon.
I remember when it came in.
The boss tried to sell it
to Stevie Broadbent...
but Stevie thought
it was jinxed...
on account of the way
your parents passed on.
Can I talk to your boss?
I'm the boss.
No, no. I mean, when my
parents' car came in.
That was Wash Sutpen.
He's long gone.
He's dead?
He is...
He's unavailable.
Hey, if you're looking
for a car, I got
a really nice '78 Monaco.
No.
Did you deposit
the day's receipts?
What there was of it.
What about TJ?
Remember to pay him?
Course I did.
"Mr. Fixit"...
will you please take
a look at this wiring?
Yes, sir, every
parent's nightmare.
Your part of the bargain.
How old is your Poppy?
I brought
a parental consent form.
I'll personally take
her under my wing.
That's midnight tomorrow.
Bye, Daddy. Bye, Mama.
Where do you think
you're off to?
The library, Daddy.
Not tonight. Not a chance.
But it's Friday night.
It's not like I'm
going out to drink beers.
She's got a point there,
Daddy.
I wouldn't say it if
there wasn't a reason.
We'll make it
up to you, sweetie pie.
All right.
What has gotten into you,
Carter, tonight?
You're as jumpy
as a toy poodle.
Nothing.
It's nothing to worry about.
What is that, Carter?
What?
This? Oh, it's nothing.
It's something
the Sheriff wants, that's all.
Sheriff Buck?
What does he want?
He offered Poppy
a job after school.
That's a news item. How come
you kept it all to yourself?
I've got my reasons.
Later, Carter.
You made a deal.
Now you gotta live by it.
I'll give you till midnight.
Etta?
Etta.
What are you doing down here
in the middle of the night?
Just trying to stay
ahead of things. You know how
the laundry piles up.
Laundry's like
death and taxes, Etta.
We sure could
use a brighter light
down here, Daddy.
Etta!
Hold on, Etta. I'm coming.
Need some help there, Carter?
Lucas, what are
you doing here?
What are friends for, Carter,
if not a bit of illumination
in times of darkness?
Plus, we had a deadline.
Midnight, remember?
Etta's hurt bad.
Not that bad, Carter.
Two hairline fractures
in her ankle, dislocated hip,
shock to the heart.
But Etta's got a strong heart.
We hope.
There are two hairline
fractures in the ankle here.
And you've dislocated
your right hip joint.
Plus a shock to the heart.
That right?
That's right.
You have a strong heart,
though, Mrs. Bowen.
You should be out of here
in the morning.
Damn that Buck.
I should have known.
Should have known what?
Nothing. Forget it.
You're saying
the Sheriff did this?
I don't know. But he's always
there when trouble starts.
Sounds like a mutiny.
You won't find no
mutiny here, Sheriff.
Not after all you've
done for Carter.
What do you want?
Just paying
a courtesy call, Harvard.
I don't suppose they
taught you that up north.
Then do Mrs. Bowen a courtesy.
Make it brief.
Carter.
I just want to say I'm sorry
about all this, Lucas.
Me, too, Carter. I was
kind of surprised when
you didn't make that deadline.
Look, let's forget
about Poppy.
I understand.
I've got something else
for you now.
Anything, Lucas.
Just tell me.
I got this friend of mine
coming in tomorrow...
on the 5:42 out of Columbia...
and I was hoping
you could pick him up for me.
I got this Chamber
of Commerce meeting...
That's it?
Why didn't you say so?
Heck, I'd be glad to
do it for you, Lucas.
And I knew I could
count on you, Carter. You just
tote him back to your place...
and I'll swing by and get him
when I get a chance, okay?
You bet you, Lucas.
It's a done deal.
Hi, Caleb.
What are you trying to do?
Make a tornado, but this
dang thing ain't worth a dang.
I got a book on tornadoes and
freak storms you can borrow.
I don't want a book.
I want a project that works.
Boy's right. Any sissy
can do a book report.
You spying on me?
Heck, no, that ain't my style.
What's the trouble, bub?
I'm trying to make a tornado
chamber, but it looks like
I ain't getting very far.
It's a sorry tornado
that comes out of a blender...
unless you're making good old
Doc Crower a frozen daiquiri.
A what?
Never mind.
Tell you what, get
a sheet of plexiglas,
big bunch of dry ice...
and one of them
one-horse motors. Then you
got yourself a tornado.
That's fine, Caleb, but you
need to know why things are...
what makes them work.
It's not as much fun,
but it's what separates
the men from the boys.
You need that book,
you just holler.
All right.
Here, son. You go out and
buy yourself what you need.
I can't.
It's against the rules.
Against the rules for
a fellow to help a boy
with his homework?
I'm gonna have to have
a little talk with Ms. Coombs.
Look out.
Mommy.
Honey, take this.
Quick, hide it.
Mommy, is everything okay?
Where's the fire, Ms. Emory?
Ms. Emory?
Are you following
me around, ma'am?
Yeah, right.
No, really, I come out here
on a 6-13 and here you are.
Now, maybe I'm paranoid,
but I think that
you're watching me.
I think you're
flattering yourself.
So, what's a 6-13?
Report of an intruder,
stealing stuff.
I didn't steal anything.
Did I say you did?
Although the junkyard
is closed, so technically,
you are intruding.
Look at that. They match your
fair complexion perfectly.
Thanks. They make me sneeze.
They're not for you, anyhow.
Poor Carter Bowen's wife
got quite a shock.
I'm sure
she'll appreciate them.
Are you hiding something?
No.
Come on, now, Ms. Emory.
There's no perjury out here.
What could I possibly
be hiding from you?
Your true feelings, perhaps?
Who is that, Daddy?
Wash Sutpen. A man I knew
a long time ago.
You mean, "Sutpen
the junkman, something
in his head"? That one?
I'll be damned.
Wash, we weren't
expecting seeing you
until 1999 or so.
Sheriff Buck pulled
a few strings. Here I am.
Damn, you look the same.
You truly do.
How'd you do it?
Prison food, Carter.
And a clear conscience.
Now you, on the other hand...
The cares of family life,
you know how it is.
Yeah, I remember.
Is that little Poppy?
This is Wash Sutpen,
my old boss.
Something I made for you
on the inside.
My, I had no idea
so much time had passed.
Really? It's for me?
Say thank you, Poppy.
Thank you.
It's a little young for you,
but like I said...
time goes by
a lot faster out here.
We gotta get going.
Remember, your
mama's laid up at home.
Good to see you out, Wash.
Good, Carter? It's a good
deal better than that.
It's called living.
Why won't you tell me
who's coming for supper?
Now, Etta, the point of
a surprise is surprise.
I don't want you to think
I'm not grateful.
Those flowers are
so beautiful they just
brighten up the whole house.
You hear that, TJ?
Maybe someday
you'll have a house like this.
Maybe Carter will give it
to you as a wedding present.
Yeah, when pigs fly.
Hi, Mama.
Lucas Buck,
is that Wash Sutpen?
Hasn't aged a day, has he?
Don't know how he does it.
I don't want that man
in my house.
Now, that's hardly
taking an enlightened
view of rehabilitation.
I promised Lucas.
It's just for supper.
Carter, I am not
happy about this.
If you say he's okay,
then he's okay.
He won't be with you
more than a couple of days...
until I get him settled
over in Goat Town.
You didn't say nothing
about him staying.
I'm sorry, Carter. Is someone
using your extra room?
Well, no.
All right, then.
Another problem solved.
With Etta laid up,
you can probably use
the extra help anyway.
Wash Sutpen
ain't no freeloader.
You know, it's my job to keep
an eye on parolees in Trinity.
So let's enjoy ourselves
while we're at it.
There's baby backs with
all the fixings and a bucket
of frosties in the kitchen.
You just set right there
and let me get it for you.
I can get it myself,
or my husband can.
Let me earn my keep.
It's been 17 years since
I've had the privilege
of waiting on a lady.
For me, I would like
a little something.
A plate with
all the fixings and
an icy cold beer coming up.
Thank you kindly.
But hold the beer.
I'm on Darvon.
Can I ask a question?
Go right ahead.
What's it like to kill a man?
Poppy, he don't
wanna talk about that.
Voilá.
It's the pig picking cake
old Mrs. Eanes used to make.
She's dead, you know.
Sure ain't nothing like
pig picking cake.
I don't mind talking about it,
ma'am. It's a fair question.
Didn't feel good or bad. I was
merely protecting my family.
Against who?
Fellow who was taking
liberties with my daughter.
Turned out it was
the wrong man, though.
She was smart and pretty,
just like you.
Carter sure thought so.
No, I didn't.
Your daddy used to work for
Mr. Sutpen right about the
time all this was happening.
Before he met your mama
he had something
of a crush on that...
Anyway, everybody
deserves a second chance.
That's right. Everybody
So what happened next?
I lost everything.
My wife, my business...
and my daughter.
Who'd like some whipped cream?
Hey!
You're just in time.
Am I? Maybe I'm too late.
What are you talking about?
I'm just getting it going.
You're going the wrong way.
It's just a science project.
Five, four, three...
two, one. Stand back.
Caleb.
Tornado time.
Dang! Would you
look at that, Merly?
That little toy
is growing on you.
I was just thinking.
About what?
About you, protecting
your family like that.
That was heroic.
Too bad I shot
the wrong man, but well...
Did you find the secret yet?
There's a secret?
Yeah.
Come, sit here.
Where's the secret?
I'll show you.
You smell nice.
You didn't tell me
what it's for...
the little compartment.
You already know
what it's for.
I'm gonna go to bed now.
The secret to crabbing
is to be real gentle.
That's what my granddaddy used
to say. He was a professional.
Professional what?
Crabber.
What about your daddy?
Was he a crabber?
No. He was a newspaperman.
I'd rather go crabbing
than deliver the papers.
He was an editor, and my mom
was his editor-in-chief.
They worked hand in hand
until the day they died.
How'd they die?
There was a fire
in the printing room.
Was it an accident?
I don't know. I'm not sure.
You know, maybe someday
you could help me find out.
Why me?
Because you're my cousin.
Because you know how to
ask all those tough questions.
Maybe someday I'll be
a newspaper reporter.
Maybe you will.
Hey. Hey.
You got one.
Oh, he's a nice one. Good job.
Well, thank you.
Hello, Mr. Sutpen.
Brought you something,
being as it's so hot.
Thank you.
I've always liked these
better than those ones
that you gotta push up...
and the paper gets all sticky.
My friend Lois,
she likes the ice...
You'll feel the breeze on your
skin better if you're still.
Really?
That way you feel
the completeness of it all.
The cool wind
blowing over your body.
The sound of a wind chime...
tinkling from far away.
Close your eyes.
Now open your mouth
just a little bit.
Keep your eyes closed, because
this is the best of all.
That's nice.
Hey, Carter.
I'm gonna go see
if Mama needs anything.
You want some lunch?
No.
Where'd that come from?
Sheriff helped me.
I see.
It's very impressive.
Yeah, it is.
Did you get that book
that I left you?
"Bernoulli's Principle. "
Even if I did read
this thing to the
beginning to the end...
I still couldn't have
made that thing.
Maybe not.
But at least you'd understand
why it works.
That man spent his entire life
trying to explain things...
that couldn't be
explained, Caleb.
I'm sure it wasn't easy. But
nothing worthwhile ever is.
Maybe I'll take a look at it.
Couldn't hurt.
And then maybe you could
explain some of that to me.
Got you now, girl.
Oh, you scared me to death.
I'm sorry.
What are you two
doing down there?
Nothing, Daddy.
You go on in the house.
You get on back to the house.
Go on!
We were just swimming.
Yeah, you was just swimming.
Damn. This is a fish stick.
How you been, Carter?
Not very well, Lucas.
It's Sutpen. He's been
worrying little Poppy.
Well, she is a healthy-looking
girl. Probably got a lot
of time on her hands, too.
She's only 15.
Sit down, Carter.
Order the fish sticks.
Excuse me.
Sheriff...
the thing is, I come upon
them swimming.
I want him gone.
You can't arrest a man for
swimming, not even in Trinity.
But, Lucas...
But nothing.
I offered my help,
you rejected it.
I wanted to take Poppy under
my wing, you wouldn't have it.
I guess it's time for a father
to do what he's gotta do.
Wouldn't you say?
That was very
informative, Boone.
Caleb, you ready?
This here is
a tornado chamber.
It's gonna show you
how a funnel cloud forms.
See?
He's a real corker,
isn't he? Put that
together all by himself.
This ain't right.
Sure it is, boy.
You're doing fine.
No, sir.
Ms. Coombs? I bought this
here tornado chamber.
And I'm disqualifying myself
from the science fair.
She said
you couldn't do that.
Well, I'm surprised at you,
Caleb Temple.
Whatever possessed you
to cheat?
Caleb, forget about
the equipment.
That's not important.
Tell them about
Bernoulli's principle.
Who the heck is Bernoulli?
Bernoulli's principle says
the inside of a tornado
has very low air pressure.
The pressure is
differential is what
causes all the damage.
Weather can be determined
by analyzing
the barometric change...
as the temperature drops.
So open your windows when
there's a tornado warning...
or your house could explode
from inside and out.
What the hell
are you doing up?
Can't sleep. You?
I'd sleep fine if you'd
just get the hell back
where you came from.
I ain't going back there,
Carter. I done my time.
You touch that little
girl again, you gonna wish
you was back in solitary.
You better get
some rest, friend.
You're coming unglued.
Are you ever coming to bed?
Not tonight, I ain't.
Caleb.
You did real good.
I'm proud of you.
We're all proud of you.
You was there? And Mama?
We were all there, Caleb.
I knew it.
I could feel it, Merlyn.
I was happy.
Poppy?
Poppy!
Poppy, open up in there!
Etta?
Etta.
Etta!
I just can't get my head
around what's happened.
Poor old Mr. Bowen.
I know, son.
It's probably time
you started thinking about
moving up in the world.
I can't stay here.
That's where you're wrong.
Trinity needs things repaired.
Hell, we need a "Mr. Fixit."
You could start
your own business.
I ain't got
that kind of money.
Now, a low interest loan
could be arranged...
particularly if something came
on the market at a good price.
I always wanted to own
my own business.
That's the spirit.
Down the road,
maybe I'll ask you
for a small favor.