What was it? A meteorite?
A visit from inhabitants of the cosmic abyss?
One way or another, our small country
has seen the birth of a miracle - the Zone.
We immediately sent troops there.
They haven't come back.
Then we surrounded the Zone
with police cordons...
Perhaps, that was the right thing to do.
Though, I don't know...
From an interview with
Nobel Prize winner, Professor Wallace.
Why did you take my watch?
Where are you going, I'm asking you?
You gave me your word, and I believed you.
All right, you're not thinking about yourself,
but what about us?
Did you think about your child?
She's just getting used to you,
and you start it again!
You've made an old woman of me.
You've ruined my life.
Not so loud, you'll wake up Monkey.
I can't wait for you forever. I'm going to die!
You wanted to start working.
You've been promised
normal, respectable work.
I'll be back soon.
You'll be back in prison!
Though this time,
you'll get 10 years, not five.
And for 10 years, you will have nothing.
Neither your Zone, nor anything else.
And I'll be dead in the meantime.
Oh, God. For me, everywhere is a prison.
- Let me go.
- No.
Let go, I said.
Go! And may you rot there!
Damn the day I met you, you bastard!
God himself has cursed you
by giving you this child!
And me too, because of you, you scoundrel!
My dear, our world is hopelessly boring.
Therefore, there can be no telepathy
or apparitions or flying saucers,
nothing like that.
The world is ruled by cast-iron laws,
and it's insufferably boring.
Alas, those laws are never violated.
They don't know how to be violated.
So don't even hope for a UFO,
that would have been too interesting.
And how about the Bermuda Triangle?
You're not going to deny...
I am. There is no Bermuda Triangle.
There's only Triangle ABC that equals
Triangle A-prime, B-prime, C-prime.
Do you feel the boredom
contained in this assertion?
To live in the Middle Ages was interesting.
Every home had its house-spirit,
and every church had its God.
People were young!
Now every fourth is an old person.
It's so boring, my angel.
But you said that the Zone
was the product of a superior civilisation...
it must be boring too,
all those laws, triangles,
and no house spirits,
and no God, that's for certain.
Because if God is also a triangle,
then I don't know what to think.
It's for me! Great!
Goodbye, my dear friend.
This lady was so kind
as to agree to go with us to the Zone.
She's a very courageous woman.
Her name is...
I beg your pardon, your name is...
Are you really a stalker?
Wait, I'll explain everything.
Go.
What a cretin!
You did get drunk after all.
Me? What do you mean?
I had a drink,
like one-half of the population does.
The other half gets drunk,
including women and children.
I just had a drink, though.
Damn it, what a mess.
Go on, drink. We've got time.
How about one for the road?
What do you think?
- Take it away.
- I see. Dry law.
Alcoholism is a scourge of mankind.
All right, we'll drink beer.
Is he with us?
Never mind, he'll sober up.
He needs to go there too.
Are you really a professor?
If you don't mind.
Then let me introduce myself. My name is...
Your name is Writer.
Well done. And what is my name?
Yours? Professor.
I see. I'm a writer,
so, naturally, everyone calls me
Writer for some reason.
- And what do you write about?
- About the readers.
Obviously, there's nothing else
one should write about.
One should write about nothing at all.
And what are you? A chemist?
A physicist.
That must be boring too.
Searching for the truth.
It's hiding and you keep searching for it.
You dig in one place. Eureka!
The nucleus is made of protons.
You dig in another. Great!
Triangle ABC equals
Triangle A-prime, B-prime, C-prime.
With me, it's quite different.
While I am digging for the truth,
so much happens to it
that instead of discovering the truth,
I dig up a heap of, pardon...
I'd better not name it.
You're lucky!
But imagine some antique pot
displayed in a museum.
It was used in its time
as a receptacle for leftover food,
but now it's an object of universal admiration
for its laconic pattern and unique form.
Everyone goes, "Oh!" and "Ah!"
And suddenly it turns out
that it's not antique at all,
that some joker has palmed it off
on the archaeologists
just for fun.
Strange as it may seem, the admiration
dies off. Those connoisseurs...
Is this what you think about all the time?
God forbid!
In fact, I don't think much.
It's not good for me.
It's impossible to write,
thinking all the time of success or failure.
But if no one is going to read me
in a hundred years,
why the hell should I write at all?
Tell me, Professor, why did you
let yourself get mixed up in all this?
What do you need the Zone for?
One could say that I'm a scientist.
But what do you need it for?
You're an "in" writer.
Women must be running after you in flocks.
My inspiration has been lost, Professor.
I go begging for it.
Have you been used up?
What? Yes, I suppose, in a way.
Do you hear it? Our train.
- Have you taken the roof off the car?
- Yes, I have.
Luger .
If I don't come back, call on my wife.
Damn it, I forgot to buy cigarettes.
Don't go back.
- Why?
- You must not.
- You're all like this.
- Like what?
Believing such nonsense.
Well, I'd better save it for a rainy day.
Are you really a scientist?
Down!
Don't move!
Go and look. ls there anyone there?
Move it, for God's sake!
There's no one there.
Go to the other exit.
Where on earth did you look, Writer?
Take a look around, please.
- You didn't forget the jerry can?
- No. It's full.
Everything I told you before
is a lie.
I don't give a damn about inspiration.
How would I know
the right word for what I want?
How would I know that actually
I don't want what I want?
Or that I actually don't want
what I don't want?
They are elusive things.
The moment we name them,
their meaning disappears,
melts, dissolves like a jellyfish in the sun.
My conscience wants vegetarianism
to win over the world.
And my subconscious is yearning
for a piece of juicy meat.
But what do I want?
- World domination.
- Quiet!
Why is there a diesel locomotive in the Zone?
It services the outpost.
It won't go any further.
They don't like going there.
Take your places! Everybody here?
The guards have arrived.
Tell them to turn the TV off.
Hurry!
Go and look to see whether
there's a trolley on the tracks.
- What trolley?
- Go, go...
Go back, I'll do it.
The 'yew; ca“!
Give it to me!
Get rid of your knapsack, it's hampering you.
You can travel light, if you wish,
as if you were going for a stroll.
If someone gets hit,
don't shout or rush about.
If they see you, they'll kill you.
When everything settles down,
crawl back to the outpost.
They'll pick you up in the morning.
Can they catch up with us?
They fear it like the plague.
Fear what?
Here we are,
home at last.
How quiet it is.
This is the quietest place in the world.
You'll see for yourselves.
So beautiful here. Not a single soul.
What about us?
Three men can't spoil the place in one day.
Why? They can.
It's strange that the flowers don't smell.
Or have I...
Do you feel anything?
The bog stinks, that's what I feel.
No, that's the river. There's a river here.
There was a flower bed nearby,
but Porcupine had trampled it down.
The smell lingered for many years though.
Why did he do it?
I don't know.
I asked him why, too.
And he said, "You'll understand later."
I think he just came to hate the Zone.
Porcupine, that's his name?
A nickname, like yours.
He had been taking people to the Zone
for years, and no one could stop him.
He was my teacher. He opened my eyes.
He was called Teacher then, not Porcupine.
Then something happened to him,
something broke in him.
Though I think he was punished.
Will you help me?
Tie those strips of bandage to the nuts.
And I will go for a walk.
I need to do something.
Don't go anywhere.
Where's he going?
He wants to be alone, I suppose.
Why? Even with the three of us together,
I feel uncomfortable.
A date with the Zone. He's a stalker.
And what does that mean?
You see, being a stalker
is some sort of calling.
- I thought he'd be different.
- Like what?
Well, you know, the Leatherstocking Tales,
Chingachgook, that sort of thing...
His background is even more frightful.
Several times in prison,
then he was harmed here.
He has a mutant daughter,
"a victim of the Zone" as they call it.
They say she's got no legs.
And what about this Porcupine?
What do you mean, "was punished"?
Or was it just a figure of speech?
One day Porcupine returned from here
and got rich overnight.
- Fabulously rich.
- You call that punishment?
A week later, he hanged himself.
Why?
Quiet!
What was that?
Presumably a meteorite fell here
about 20 years ago.
It had burned down the settlement.
They searched for this meteorite
but never found it, of course.
Why "of course"?
Then people began disappearing here.
They came here and never returned.
So it was concluded
that this meteorite was not really a meteorite.
At first,
they circled the place with barbed wire
to scare off the inquisitive.
All this gave rise to rumours
that there's a place in the Zone
where wishes come true.
Naturally, they began to guard the Zone
like the apple of their eye.
Who knows what kind of wish
someone might cherish.
What was it if not a meteorite?
I told you, no one knows.
And what do you think?
Nothing. Or anything.
A message to mankind,
as one of my colleagues says.
Or a gift.
Some gift.
Why on earth would they do it?
To make us happy.
The flowers are blooming again,
but they don't smell for some reason.
Sorry for leaving you two here,
but it was too early to go anyway.
Did you hear it?
Maybe someone lives here?
Who?
You told me yourself
about some tourists camped here
when the Zone originated.
There's no one in the Zone
and there can't be.
Well, it's time.
How are we going to get back?
- Here, you don't get back.
- What do you mean?
We'll go as we agreed.
I'll direct you.
Any deviation
from my directions is dangerous.
The first landmark is that last pole.
You go first, Professor.
Now you.
Try to follow in his footsteps.
My God! And where are...
Did they remain here like that?
Those people?
Who knows?
I remember them packing at the station,
getting ready to come here.
I was just a boy.
We all thought then that
somebody wanted to conquer us.
You first, Professor.
Now you, Writer.
Your room is over there. We'll go this way.
Why were you hiking up the price?
It's so close at hand.
Yes, but the hand has to be very long.
We don't have such a hand.
Don't! Leave it alone!
Don't touch it!
Don't touch it, I said!
Are you crazy? What's the matter with you?
This is not the place for leisurely strolls.
The Zone wants to be respected.
Otherwise, it will punish.
Don't you ever try it again.
Have you no tongue or what?
I warned you, didn't I?
Is that where we're going?
Yes. Go up, then go in and to the left.
Only, we are not going this way.
We'll go around.
Why?
People don't go this way.
In the Zone, the longer way means less risk.
And to go straight ahead is fatal?
He told you it's dangerous.
- And making a detour's not dangerous?
- It is. But they don't go this way.
What do I care that they don't?
What if I take a chance...
Listen, what's the matter with you...
To go all the way around!
When everything's so close.
There are risks everywhere. What the hell!
You're being very flippant about this.
I'm fed up with all those nuts and bandages.
You can do as you wish, but I'm going.
- You're insane.
- It's you who are...
May I?
The wind is getting up.
Can you feel it? The grass...
All the more so.
What do you mean?
- Wait!
- Keep your hands off!
Professor, be my witness,
I didn't send you there.
You go of your own will.
Of my own will. What else?
Nothing. Go.
May God bring you luck.
Listen!
Should you notice something,
or just feel something,
go back at once, or...
Just don't throw iron poles at me.
Stop! Don't move!
- Why did you do it?
- Why did I do what?
- Why did you stop him?
- I thought it was you.
What's up? Why did you stop me?
- I didn't stop you.
- Who did it then? You?
Who the hell knows?
Congratulations, Mister Shakespeare.
To go straight ahead is frightening,
to go back is embarrassing.
So you gave yourself a command.
Fear has made you come to your senses.
- What?
- Stop it.
- Why have you emptied the bottle?
- Stop it, I said!
The Zone is a very complicated system
of traps, and they're all deadly.
I don't know what goes on here
in the absence of people,
but the moment someone shows up,
everything comes into motion.
Old traps disappear and new ones emerge.
Safe spots become impassable.
Now your path is easy,
now it's impossibly confusing.
That's the Zone.
It may even seem capricious.
But it is what we've made it
with our condition.
It happened that people had to
stop halfway and go back.
Some of them even died
on the very threshold of the room.
But everything that's going on here
depends not on the Zone, but on us!
So it lets the good ones pass
and kills the bad ones?
I don't know.
I think it lets those pass who
have lost all hope.
Not good or bad but wretched people.
But even the most wretched will die
if they don't know how to behave.
You have been lucky, it just warned you.
I suppose I'll wait for you here
until you come back happy.
It's impossible!
I've got sandwiches, a flask...
You won't last even an hour here without me.
Besides, here you don't go back
the way you came.
Anyway, I'd prefer...
Then we're going back right away.
I'll return your money minus a certain sum
for the trouble, so to speak.
Have you come to your senses, Professor?
All right. Go on, throw your nut.
Part Two
STALKER
Where are you? Come here!
Are you tired?
Oh, God!
Judging by his tone,
he's going to start sermonising again.
Let everything
that's been planned come true.
Let them believe.
And let them laugh at their passions.
Because what they call passion
actually is not some emotional energy,
but just the friction between
their souls and the outside world.
And most important,
let them believe in themselves.
Let them be helpless like children,
because weakness is a great thing,
and strength is nothing.
When a man is just born,
he is weak and fragile.
When he dies, he is hard and insensitive.
When a tree is growing,
it's tender and fragile,
but when it's dry and hard, it dies.
Hardness and strength
are death's companions.
Pliancy and weakness are expressions
of the freshness of being.
Because what has hardened will never win.
Come here! We're progressing well.
Soon we'll come to a dry tunnel,
after that, it will get easier.
Knock on wood.
- Are we on our way already?
- Of course. Why?
I thought you just wanted
to show us something.
- What about my knapsack?
- What about it?
I left it there. I didn't know we were going.
- There's nothing we can do about it.
- No, we have to go back.
- It's impossible!
- I can't do without my knapsack!
Can't you understand that no one here
has ever come back the same way?
Forget about your knapsack.
What have you got in there, diamonds?
Don't you remember where you're going?
The room will give you anything you want.
Really. it will drown you in knapsacks.
How far is it, this room?
If you go straight, about 200 metres,
but there's no going straight here.
Let's go.
Give up your empiricism, Professor.
Miracles are beyond empiricism.
Remember how St Peter
was nearly drowned?
Go, Writer.
Go where?
Up these stairs.
Professor, where are you?
Here's the dry tunnel!
You call this dry?
It's a local joke.
Normally you have to swim here.
Wait, where's the Professor?
- What?
- The Professor has disappeared!
How could this happen?
He was following you all the way.
He probably lagged behind and lost his way.
No, he didn't lose his way!
He must've gone for the knapsack!
He won't be able to make it now.
Shall we wait for him?
We can't. Things change here
every minute. We'll have to go.
Look! What is it? How could it be?
- I already explained.
- What did you explain?
It's the Zone, don't you understand?
Let's go, quick. It's...
There he is!
I'm certainly grateful to you that you...
How did you get here?
Mostly I had to crawl up here on all fours.
Incredible.
How did you manage to overtake us?
What do you mean, "overtake"?
I came back here for the knapsack.
And how has our nut got here?
My God, that's the trap!
Porcupine put this nut here on purpose.
How could the Zone let us through?
Oh, God, I'm not going
to take one more step until...
I don't like it.
That's it. We rest.
But stay away from this nut, just in case.
Sorry, but I thought that the Professor
wouldn't be able to make it.
You see, I...
I never know beforehand what
kind of people I'm taking with me.
Everything becomes clear once it's too late.
What's important is that the Professor's
bag with his underwear is safe.
Don't stick your nose in someone's
underwear if you don't understand it.
What is there to understand?
Binomial theorem?
Some psychological abysses!
You have a bad reputation at your institute.
They don't give you money for expeditions.
So you decide to pack a knapsack
full of manometers and other shit,
penetrate the Zone illegally,
and put all these miracles to an algebra test.
No one in the world
has ever heard of the Zone.
So we'll create a sure sensation.
The television, fans raving
and bringing laurel wreaths.
Here our Professor appears, all in white,
and declares, "Mene-mene, tekel, upharsin."
Everyone gaping
and shouting, "He deserves a Nobel Prize!"
You lousy scribbler,
a homespun psychoanalyst.
You're only good for painting walls
in public toilets, you and your big mouth.
No good. Too sluggish.
You don't know how to do it.
All right. I'm going to get a Nobel Prize.
And what are you after?
Want to bless mankind
with the pearls
of your purchased inspiration?
I don't care a damn about mankind.
Of all your mankind
I'm interested only in one man. Myself.
Whether I'm worth anything
or I'm just shit like others.
And if you find out that you're really...
You know, Mr Einstein,
I have no wish to argue with you.
Truth is born of argument, damn it!
Listen, Chingachgook.
You've brought many people here.
Not as many as I would like.
That's not the point. Why did they
come here? What did they want?
Happiness, I guess.
Yes, but what kind of happiness?
People don't like to talk about
their innermost feelings.
And it's neither your business nor mine.
In any case, you've been lucky.
As for me, I haven't seen
one happy man in my life.
Me neither.
They return from the room
and I lead them back,
and we never see each other again.
It's not as if wishes come true immediately.
Have you ever wished
to use this room yourself?
I'm fine as I am.
Listen, Professor.
Speaking of purchased inspiration,
let's imagine that I enter this room
and return
to our God-forsaken town a genius.
A man writes because he's tormented,
because he doubts.
He needs to constantly prove
to himself and others
that he's worth something.
And if I know for sure that I'm a genius,
why write then?
What the hell for?
Well, I must say,
that we exist for...
Will you be so kind as to leave me alone?
Let me get a wink, I haven't slept all night.
Keep your complexes to yourself.
In any case, all this technology of yours,
all those blast furnaces, wheels,
and other bullshit
are only designed in order
to work less and eat more.
They are all just crutches, artificial limbs.
And mankind exists in order to create
works of art.
Unlike all other human activities,
this one is unselfish.
Great illusions! Images of the absolute truth!
Are you listening to me, Professor?
What unselfishness are you talking about?
People still die of hunger.
Have you just landed from the moon?
And they are considered to be
our smart aristocracy!
You're not even capable of thinking
in abstractions.
Are you going to teach me
about the meaning of life?
And also how to think?
It's useless.
You might be a professor,
but you're an ignorant one.
"And there was a great earthquake.
"And the sun became black
as sackcloth made of hair.
"And the moon became as blood.
"And the stars of heaven fell to the earth,
"as a fig tree casts its unripe figs
"when shaken by a great wind.
"And the sky was hidden
like a scroll when it is rolled up.
"And every mountain and island
was moved out of its place.
"And the kings of the earth and the great men
"and the rich and the chief captains
"and the strong and every free man
"hid themselves in the caves
and among the rocks of the mountains.
"And they said to the mountains
and to the rocks, 'Fall on us
"'and hide us from the face of
Him who sits on the throne,
"'and from the wrath of the Lamb.
"'For the great day of His wrath has come,
"'and who is able to stand?”
"And that very day two...
"Two of them
"were going to a village
which was about 60 stadia from...
"named...
"and they talked with each other
about all these things.
"And while they were conversing
and discussing,
"He Himself approached
and began travelling with them.
"But their eyes were prevented
from recognizing Him.
"And He said to them, 'What are these words
"'you are exchanging with one another,
and why are you sad?'
"And one of them, named..."
Are you awake?
You were speaking of the meaning
of our life,
of the unselfishness of art.
Take music, for instance.
It is connected to reality
less than anything else,
or if connected at all, it's done mechanically,
not by way of ideas,
just by a sheer sound,
devoid of any associations.
And yet, music, as if by some miracle,
gets through to our heart.
What is it that resonates in us
in response to noise brought to harmony,
making it the source of the greatest delight
which stuns us and brings us together?
What's all this needed for?
And most importantly, who needs it?
You would say, "No one. And for no reason."
Unselfishly.
No.
I don't think so.
After all, everything has some sense.
Sense and reason.
Do we have to go there?
Unfortunately, yes. There's no other way.
It looks morbid, don't you think, Professor?
I don't feel like going first.
And Chingachgooks can never be volunteers.
I think we'll have to draw lots. Do you mind?
For this, I'd rather have a volunteer.
Have you got matches?
Thanks.
The long one will go.
Take one.
The long one. No luck this time.
Why don't you throw
one of your nuts at least?
Sure. As you wish.
One more?
All right. I'll go.
Hurry up, Professor!
There's...
There's a door here!
Go that way! Open the door and go in!
Me? Do I have to go in first again?
You've drawn the lot.
Go! People don't wait here.
What have you got there? No guns here!
You'll get yourself killed, and us too!
Don't you remember the tanks?
Drop it, I beg you.
Don't you understand?
If something happens,
I can save you, but not this way.
I beg you!
Who are you going to fire at?
Go, we haven't got much time!
There's water here.
Hold on to the handrail and go down.
But don't go anywhere! Wait for us outside!
I hope you haven't got anything like that?
- Like what?
- Like a gun.
No. As a last resort, I've got an ampoule.
- What ampoule?
- Implanted ampoule. Poison!
Oh, God. Did you come here to die?
No, it's just in case.
Writer! Come back!
Come back!
Do you want to get yourself killed?
I told you to wait by the exit!
Stop! Don't move!
That's all your pipe.
- Why?
- You should've gone in there first.
He was so scared
that he went the wrong way.
One more experiment.
Experiments, facts,
truth of the highest order.
There's no such thing as facts.
Especially here.
All this is someone's idiotic invention.
Don't you feel it?
But you, of course, must find out
whose invention it is.
And Why?
What good can your knowledge do?
Who's going to get a guilty conscience
because of it? Me?
I've got no conscience. I've just got nerves.
Some bastard would criticize me,
I'd get wounded.
Another would laud me,
I'd get wounded again.
I would put my heart and soul into it,
they'd gobble up both my heart and soul.
I would relieve my soul of filth,
they'd gobble it up too.
They're all so literate.
They've all got sensory deficiency.
And they're all swarming around,
journalists, editors, critics,
some endless women.
And they all demand, "More, more!"
One hell of a writer am I, if I hate writing.
If it's constant torment for me,
a painful, shameful occupation,
like squeezing out haemorrhoids.
I used to think that someone would
get better because of my books.
No, nobody needs me!
Two days after I die, they'll start
gobbling up someone else.
I wanted to change them,
but it's they who have changed me.
Making me in their own image.
The future used to be just
a continuation of the present,
with all the changes looming
far beyond the horizon.
Now the future and the present are one.
Are they ready for it?
They don't want to know anything!
All they know is how to gobble!
Gosh, how lucky you are!
My goodness, now,
you're going to live a hundred years!
Yes. But why not forever?
Like the eternal Jew.
You are probably a fine man.
I didn't have any doubts.
I can imagine what torture it was
for you being in there.
This pipe is a horrible place!
The most horrible in the Zone!
It's called "the meat mincer,"
but it's much worse than any mincer.
So many people have perished there!
Porcupine sent his brother to die there.
The boy was so delicate, very talented.
Here, listen to this.
"So summer is gone
Leaving no epitaph
"it's still warm in the sun
Only that's not enough
"All that true could have come
"Like a five-fingered fluff
Folded into my palm
"Only that's not enough
"No evil was slighted in the good aftermath
"The world was festively lighted
Only that's not enough
"Life forever was tucking
Caring, making me laugh
"I was really lucky
Only that's not enough
"No leaves ever seared
No limbs broken rough
"Day, like glass, washed all clear
Only that's not enough"
Good, aren't they? That's his verses.
Why do you fidget? Fussing all the time?
- I'm just...
- I get sick just looking at you!
I'm so happy! It's not often that
everyone who goes makes it.
You did everything right.
You're good, kind, honest people.
I'm proud that I was right about you.
Look at him! He's happy
that everything ended well!
Fate! Zone! I'm a fine man, he says!
You think I didn't see how you
shoved the two long matches at me?
- No, you don't understand...
- Of course, how could I?
I'm sorry, Professor, no of fence meant,
but this fool has chosen you
to be his favourite.
Come on, it's unfair!
And me, a second-rate creature,
he shoves into that pipe!
Meat mincer! To think of such a word!
What right have you got to decide who lives
and who goes into the meat mincer?
You've chosen it yourself!
What? One long match out of two long ones?
The matches are nothing.
The Zone had let you through earlier,
under the nut,
so it became clear that only you
could go through the meat mincer.
- And we just followed you.
- Well, it's too much...
You can't even imagine how dangerous
it is to make a mistake here.
But someone had to be first!
Yes? No, it's not a clinic!
You see, someone has to go first!
Don't touch it!
- Yes?
- Laboratory nine, please.
Just a minute.
- Hello?
- I hope I'm not disturbing you.
- What do you want?
- Just a few words with you.
You've hidden it. I've found it.
The old building. Bunker four.
Do you hear me?
I'm alerting security immediately.
You may do it. You may inform on me,
you may set my colleagues against me,
but it's too late.
I'm now a stone's throw from that place.
Do you realise that's the end of you
as a scientist?
Well, you may rejoice!
So you realise what will happen if you dare?
Trying to scare me again?
All my life I've been afraid of something.
Even of you.
But now I'm not afraid of anything,
I assure you.
Oh, God, you are not even a Herostratus.
It's just that you've always wanted
to make my life unbearable
because 20 years ago I slept with your wife.
And now you're delighted
that you've got even with me.
Well, go and do your vile thing.
Don't you dare hang up on me!
Prison is not the worst thing awaiting you.
The worst is that you'll never be able
to forgive yourself for this.
I already see you hanging from your braces
in your prison cell.
What are you up to, Professor?
Do you realise what will happen
when everybody believes in the room?
And all come rushing here?
It's only a matter of time.
If not today, then tomorrow!
And not just tens of them, thousands!
Unfulfilled emperors,
great inquisitors, fuhrers,
self-appointed benefactors
of the human race!
And they'll come not for money
or inspiration, but to change the world!
I never bring people like that here.
You think I don't understand that?
What on earth can you understand?
You're not the only stalker on Earth.
No stalker can know
what those you lead bring with them
and what they take from here.
And the number of unmotivated crimes
is on the rise!
Isn't that your doing?
Take coups d'état by the military,
or the mafia penetrating governments,
aren't they all your clients?
Or lasers and all those super-bacteria,
all that filth, kept for the time being in safes?
Will you please stop this
sociological diarrhoea?
Can you really believe in all those fairy tales?
Not in the good ones, no!
But in the bad ones, certainly!
Come on!
A human being is not capable
of such hatred or love
that would extend over
the whole of mankind.
Well, money, a woman,
maybe a desire for revenge.
Let my boss be run over by a car,
that I can understand.
But ruling over the world! A just society!
God's kingdom on earth!
These are not just wishes,
this is ideology, action, concepts.
Unconscious compassion
is not ready for realization yet,
as a regular instinctive impulse.
There cannot be happiness
at someone else's expense.
I can see quite clearly now
that you plan to overwhelm
mankind with good deeds.
As for me, I'm not a bit worried
about you or myself,
and least of all about mankind.
Because you're not going
to achieve anything.
At best, you'll get your Nobel Prize.
Or rather you'll get something
absolutely incongruous,
something you don't even think about.
Something like this telephone.
You dream of one thing,
but you get quite another.
Why did you do that?
Telephone. Electricity.
Look, very good sleeping pills.
They don't make ones like that any longer.
Why so many of them here?
Maybe we'd better be going?
It'll be dark soon, difficult to get back.
By the way, it's absolutely clear to me
that all this poem reciting
and making detours
is just a form of apologizing.
I can understand you.
Difficult childhood, bad environment.
But don't have any illusions,
I'm not going to forgive you.
Will you please stop it? Do me a favour.
Professor, come here, please.
Wait a minute. Don't be in a hurry.
I'm in no hurry whatsoever.
I know you're going to get mad.
Anyway, I must tell you.
We are now on the threshold.
This is the most
important moment of your life.
You must know that
your innermost wishes
will be made real here.
Your most sincere wish! Born of suffering!
No need to say anything.
You just have to
concentrate and try to recall your whole life.
When a man thinks of the past,
he becomes kinder.
And most important...
Most important...
You have to believe!
Now you can go.
Who wants to be the first?
NEWS you'?
Me? No, I don't want to.
I understand, it's not easy, but it will pass.
I doubt
that it will pass.
If I begin recalling my life,
it's very unlikely I'll get any kinder.
Besides, don't you feel
how shameful the whole thing is?
Humiliating yourself, snivelling, praying?
What's so bad about praying?
It's just your pride speaking.
Calm down, you're not ready yet.
It happens quite often.
Maybe you first?
Yes, me.
We see before us
the Professor's new invention!
An appliance exploring human souls!
A soul metre!
It's only a bomb.
What?
You must be kidding.
No, it's just a bomb. 20 kilotons.
What for?
I assembled it with my friends.
With my former colleagues.
This place will never bring
any happiness to anyone.
But if this thing gets into the wrong hands...
Though, I'm not sure any more.
We came to the conclusion then
that we shouldn't destroy the Zone after all.
Even if it's some miracle,
it's still part of nature,
and therefore, a hope in a sense.
They had hidden that bomb,
and I've found it.
The old building, bunker four.
I suppose there must be a principle.
Never do anything that can't be undone.
I understand everything,
I'm not some maniac.
But as long as this pit lies open,
accessible to any scum,
I can get no peace, no sleep.
Or maybe, my innermost won't let me do it?
Poor man, some problem
he's invented for himself.
Give it to me!
You're a civilized man, aren't you?
- Why? What's the matter with you?
- You, lousy hypocrite.
Why? What have I done to you?
He wants to destroy your hope!
That's all people have got left on this earth!
It's the only place they can come to
if there's no hope left for them.
You yourself have come here!
Why destroy hope then?
Shut up!
I can see through you.
You don't give a damn about people.
You just make money, using our
anguish!
It's not even the money.
You're enjoying yourself here.
You're like God Almighty here.
You, a hypocritical louse,
decide who is to live and who is to die.
He deliberates.
Now I see why you stalkers
never enter the room yourselves.
You revel in all that power,
that mystery, your authority!
What else is there to wish for?
It's not true! You... You're mistaken.
A stalker must not enter the room.
A stalker must not even enter the Zone
with an ulterior motive.
Remember Porcupine?
Yes, you're right, I'm a louse.
I haven't done any good in this world,
and I can't do any.
I couldn't give anything even to my wife.
I can't have any friends either.
But don't take what's mine!
They'd already taken everything from me
back there, behind the barbed wire.
So all that's mine is here.
You understand? Here! In the Zone!
My happiness, my freedom,
my self-respect, it's all here!
I bring here people like me,
desperate and tormented.
People who have nothing else to hope for.
And I can help them!
No one else can help them.
Only I, the louse, can!
I'm so happy to be able to help them
that I want to cry.
And that's all. I don't want anything more.
I don't know. Maybe.
Anyway, excuse me, but...
You're just God's fool.
You have no idea what's going on here.
Why do you think
Porcupine hanged himself?
He came to the Zone
with a mercenary motive.
He made his brother die
in the meat mincer because of money.
I know. But why did he hang himself?
Why didn't he come here again,
not for money, but for his brother?
As a way of repenting.
He wanted to... I don't know.
He hanged himself a week later.
Because he realised that
not just any wish comes true here,
only your innermost wish.
Not what you would shout
at the top of your voice.
What comes true here is
only what's in line with your nature,
with your essence,
of which you know nothing.
But it's there, in you,
directing you all your life.
You didn't understand anything,
Leatherstocking.
It wasn't greed that finished Porcupine off.
He was crawling in this puddle,
begging to bring his brother back.
But what he got was only money,
and he couldn't get anything else,
because render unto Porcupine
the things that are Porcupine's!
And things like conscience, anguish,
they are just inventions.
He realised that and hanged himself.
I'm not going to your room.
I have no wish to pour my filth
over somebody's head.
Even yours.
And then to put my neck into
the noose, like Porcupine.
I'd rather drink myself to death
in my mansion, in peace and quiet.
You don't understand anything
about human beings, Chingachgook,
if you take people like me to the Zone.
And something else.
Why do you think this miracle really exists?
Who told you that wishes
actually come true here?
Have you seen a single man
who's been made happy here?
Was it Porcupine?
As a matter of fact,
who told you about the Zone,
about Porcupine, about that room?
He did.
Then it makes no sense to me at all.
What's the use coming here?
It's so quiet.
Can you feel it?
What the heck... Why not chuck it all?
Take my wife, Monkey, and move over here.
For good.
There's no one here.
No one can hurt them here.
So you're back.
Where did you get this?
He got attached to me.
I couldn't leave him there.
Well, shall we go? Monkey is waiting.
Are you coming?
Do any of you need a dog?
I've got five of them at home.
You love dogs, then, don't you?
What?
That's very good.
All right, let's go.
You can't even imagine how tired I am.
God only knows!
Calling themselves intellectuals,
those writers and scientists!
Don't get so excited.
They don't believe in anything.
They've got the organ with which
one believes atrophied for lack of use.
Stop it. Come on. Go to bed. Don't lie here.
It's too damp here for you.
You shouldn't lie here.
Take it off.
Oh, God, what people.
Calm down, it's not their fault.
You ought to pity them,
not be angry with them.
Haven't you seen them?
They've got empty eyes.
The only thing they can think about
is how not to sell themselves too cheaply!
How to get as much as possible
for their every emotional movement.
They know they were
"born for a purpose," "called upon."
After all, they live "only once."
Can people like that believe in anything?
Stop it, calm down.
Try to sleep, will you? Go to sleep.
And nobody believes.
Not only those two. Nobody!
Who am I going to take there?
Oh, God.
And what's most awful
is that no one needs it.
No one needs that room.
And all my efforts are just in vain.
Why do you say that? Stop it.
I'm not going there with anybody again.
Do you want me to go with you?
Where?
You think I've got nothing to ask for?
No.
- You can't go there.
- Why not?
No, no.
What if it wouldn't work with you, either?
You know, my mother was against it.
You've probably noticed already
that he's not of this world.
All our neighbourhood laughed at him.
He was such a bungler, he looked so pitiful.
My mother used to say, "He's a stalker,
"he's doomed, he's an eternal prisoner!
"Don't you know what kind of children
the stalkers have?"
And I... I didn't even argue with her.
I knew it all myself, that he was doomed,
that he was an eternal prisoner,
and about the children.
Only what could I do?
I was sure I'd be happy with him.
Of course, I knew I'd have a lot of sorrow too.
But it's better to have a bitter happiness than
a grey, dull life.
Perhaps, I thought it all up later.
But then he approached me and said,
"Come with me."
And I did, and never regretted it.
Never.
We had a lot of sorrow,
a lot of fear, and a lot of shame.
But I never regretted it,
and I never envied anyone.
It's just our fate, our life, that's how we are.
And if we hadn't had our misfortunes,
we wouldn't have been better off.
It would have been worse.
Because in that case, there wouldn't
have been any happiness.
And there wouldn't have been any hope.
"I love your eyes, my darling friend
"Their play, so passionate and brightning
"When a sudden stare up you send
"And like a heaven-blown lightning
"It'd take in all from end to end
"But there's more that I admire
"Your eyes when they're downcast
"In bursts of love-inspired fire
"And through the eyelash goes fast
"A sombre, dull call of desire"
The End