[Girl Narrating] My mother died
of pneumonia when I was just a kid.
My father had kept their wedding cake
in the freezer for ten whole years.
After the funeral,
he gave it to the yard man.
He tried to act cheerful,
but he could never be consoled...
by the little stranger
he found in his house.
Then one day,
hoping to begin a new life...
away from the scene
of all his memories...
he moved us from Texas
to Fort Dupree, South Dakota.
I'll give you a dollar
to eat this collie.
I ain't gonna eat him for a dollar.
I don't think he's a collie, either.
Some kind of dog, though.
Watch your head.
Hey, Woody.
Gimme a cigarette.
Woody wouldn't
give me a cigarette.
Ever notice he don't talk much?
Yeah, he's not a talker.
You got that.
[Muttering Quietly]
[Narrator]
Little did I realize that what began...
in the alleys and back ways
of this quiet town...
would end in the badlands of Montana.
No, they wouldn't fit.
How do you know? You haven't tried 'em on.
I know. What size are they?
Your size.
Come on. Gimme a dollar for 'em.
No.
Cost 20 new.
Why don't you see
if they fit you?
[Dog Barking]
[Whistling]
This lady don't ever pay her bills.
She gonna get in trouble
if she doesn't watch out.
I throwed enough trash
for today, Cato.
I'll see you in the morning.
Catch.
What do you mean?
[Chuckles]
Hi. I'm Kit.
I'm not keeping you from anything
important, am I? No.
Just thought I'd come over
and say hello to you.
I'll try anything once.
What's your name?
I said mine.
Holly.
Well, listen, Holly...
you, uh, I don't know,
want to take a walk with me?
What for?
Oh, I got some stuff to say.
Guess I'm kinda lucky that way.
Most people don't have anything
on their minds, do they?
Oh, incidentally,
my last name is Carruthers.
Sounds a little too much
like "druthers," huh?
It's okay.
Yeah, well, nobody asked me
what I thought.
They just hung it on me.
You still in school?
Nah. I got me a job.
Doing what?
Well, I don't mind
gettin' up early, so...
I got a job throwin' garbage.
[Man] Holly!
I'm not in love with the stuff, okay?
That's my father. I gotta run.
Hey, wait.
When am I gonna see you again?
Well, I know what
my daddy's gonna say.
What?
Can I be honest?
Sure.
Well, that I shouldn't be seen
with anybody that collects garbage.
He'll say that?
Yeah.
Now, what's he know
about garbage, huh?
Nothin'.
There you go.
Well, I mean,
there's nothing he wants to know.
I gotta run.
Who was that?
Just some boy.
Is that gonna kill the grass?
[Laughing]
You got some on my feet!
What'd he want?
He was just asking if we needed
any yard work done.
I said no...
and for him not to bother us.
Heard the news, Kit?
No.
Been in all the headlines.
What's that?
You've been fired.
Ain't that a helluva note?
Yeah, how about that?
Oh. I won't be needin'
my keys anymore.
I'll just leave 'em
where they'll be handy.
I've got my dog.
[Typewriter Keys Clacking]
[Man]
Have you ever held another job before?
Yeah, I used
to throw trash for the city.
And you lost that one?
Yeah, I wouldn't be here if I hadn't.
Why did you leave?
Just felt like it.
What kind of work do you think
you'd be qualified for?
I just got to get this.
Well, I can't think of anything
at the moment.
I want you to write me out
a slip, though...
provin' I came down here.
I think we can get you something
working cattle over at the pens.
Well, what the hell.
Just hope there's a breeze.
[Holly Narrating] He was handsomer
than anybody I'd ever met.
He looked just like James Dean.
Hi.
Well, stop the world.
Hey, quit my job.
Great.
Seemed like the right move.
What you doin'?
Spanish.
How do you say "quit my job"
in Spanish?
Something mi trabajo.
Well, I'm going to work
as a cowboy now.
Thinkin' about it.
It's a routine, like anything.
What do you think?
I don't know.
Yeah, well...
at least nobody can get on me
about wearing these boots anymore.
You wanna go for a ride?
Well, I got homework.
Bring it along.
Somebody dropped a bag
on the sidewalk.
If everybody did that,
the whole town would be a mess.
[Child Chattering]
Hi.
You're a redhead.
I know.
Anybody ever call you Red?
Yeah, but I don't like it.
Why not?
I just don't.
I have a headache.
Oh, yeah?
[Horn Honks]
Can I come around
and see you tomorrow?
Okay.
[Holly Narrating]
Kit went to work in the feedlot...
while I carried on with my studies.
Little by little, we fell in love.
As I'd never been
popular in school...
and didn't have
a lot of personality...
I was surprised that he took
such a liking to me...
especially when he coulda had any other
girl in town if he'd given it half a try.
He said that I was grand, though,
that he wasn't interested in me for sex...
and that, coming from him,
this was a compliment.
He'd never met a 15-year-old girl
who behaved more like a grown-up...
and wasn't giggly.
He didn't care
what anybody else thought.
I looked good to him,
and whatever I did was okay.
And if I didn't have a lot to say,
well, that was okay too.
What a nice place.
Yeah, the tree makes it nice.
And the flowers.
Let's not pick 'em.
They're so nice.
It's your play.
Of course, I had to keep all this
a secret from my dad.
He woulda had a fit,
since Kit was ten years older than me...
and came from the wrong side
of the tracks, so-called.
Our time with each other was limited,
and each lived for the precious hours...
when he or she
could be with the other...
away from all the cares of the world.
[Coach's Whistle Blowing]
My stomach's growlin'.
[People Shouting, Chattering]
There's an old Fudgsicle.
You want it?
No.
Somebody else is gonna get it.
[Laughs]
I don't care.
Kids eat that kinda stuff in Korea.
In the stench and slime
of the feedlot...
he'd remember how
I'd looked the night before...
how I ran my hand through his hair
and traced the outline...
of his lips with my fingertip.
He wanted to die with me...
and I dreamed of being
lost forever in his arms.
The whole time,
the only thing I did wrong...
was throwing out my fish
when he got sick.
Later I got a new one, but this incident
kept on bothering me, and I turned to Kit.
Well, he was sick.
You couldn't do much about that.
I guess not.
So?
Well, it scared me.
Ah, don't worry about it.
I didn't mind tellin' Kit
about stuff like this...
'cause strange things
happened in his life too...
and some of the stuff
he did was strange.
For instance, he faked
his signature whenever he used it...
to keep other people from forging
important papers with his name.
And as he lay in bed
in the middle of the night...
he always heard a noise like somebody
was holding a seashell against his ear.
And sometimes he'd see me comin'
toward him in beautiful white robes...
and I'd put my cold hand
on his forehead.
Did it go the way
it's supposed to?
Yeah.
Is that all there is to it?
Yep.
Gosh, what was
everybody talkin' about?
Don't ask me.
Well, I'm glad it's over.
For a while I was afraid
I might die before it happened.
Had a wreck
or some deal like that.
Did you see where that tree
fell in the water?
Yeah.
River must've washed
the roots away.
You don't care
about anything I say, though.
You know what I think?
What?
We should crunch our hands
with this stone.
That way we'd never forget
what happened today.
But it would hurt.
Well, that's the point, stupid.
Don't call me stupid.
Okay, but I'm gonna keep it
for a souvenir.
Well, maybe one that's lighter.
[Holly Narrating] Kit made a solemn vow
he would always stand beside me...
and let nothin' come between us.
He wrote this out in writin',
put the paper in a box...
with some of our little tokens
and things...
then sent it off in a balloon
he'd found while on the garbage route.
His heart was filled with longin'
as he watched it drift off.
Something must've told him...
we'd never live these days
of happiness again...
that they were gone forever.
[No Audible Dialogue]
Then, sure enough, Dad found out
I'd been runnin' around behind his back.
He was madder
than I'd ever seen him.
As punishment for deceivin' him,
he went and shot my dog.
He made me take extra music lessons
every day after school...
and wait there
till he came to pick me up.
He said that if the piano
didn't keep me off the streets...
maybe the clarinet would.
Sure is pretty.
What did you come out here for?
I wasn't aware
there was any law against it.
You know Holly?
Well, she means
an awful lot to me, sir.
You know, before I met her...
nobody could ask me
how I was doin' with my girl.
Matter of fact,
I didn't really have one.
Is that right?
Yeah.
It okay, me leanin'
on your Willys here?
Look, I got a lot of respect
for her too, sir.
That's about as good a one
as I know to tell you.
Well, it's not good enough.
What do you think would happen to her
if she stuck around with a guy like you?
She'd get along okay.
And if she didn't, why...
she could just take off.
Just take right on off.
I wouldn't mind.
I'd always tell people I deserved it.
I don't want you
hangin' around anymore.
I don't wanna see you again.
Understand?
You somethin'.
Takes all kinds, sir.
[Kit]
Hi.
What are you doin'?
I got a gun here, sir.
It's always a good idea
to have one around.
What do you think you're doin'?
Go on, get outta here.
[Exhales Sharply]
I got it all planned...
and, uh, I'm takin' Holly
off with me.
Okay, boy.
I'm turning you over
to the authorities.
What for?
Coming onto my property
with a gun.
No, you're not either.
Yeah? Why not?
'Cause I can't allow it.
Hey!
Hey, wait a minute!
Suppose I shot you?
How'd that be? Huh?
Want to hear
what it sounds like?
[Holly] Kit? Kit!
Hey, where are you goin'?
Daddy!
Daddy?
This is Holly.
Are you gonna be okay?
I came in the front.
How bad off is he?
I can look and see.
We better call the doctor.
Listen, I'll say how it happened.
The part I saw.
Well...
I don't think that'll work.
He don't need a doctor.
Are you sure?
If you don't believe me,
see for yourself.
I found a toaster.
Don't worry, honey.
I'm gonna...
Listen, maybe we oughta
tell somebody about this.
You said that once already.
Too late now.
Why?
They're not gonna listen to me.
You either. You kiddin'?
Suppose the neighbors
heard the noise.
It wouldn't be funny.
Listen, uh,
I'll be back after a while.
Oh, uh, if you wanna call
the police, that's fine.
Just won't be so hot for me.
Uh, my girl Holly and I
have decided to kill ourselves.
Same way I did her dad.
Big decision, huh?
Uh, the reasons are obvious.
I don't have time
to go into 'em right now.
But, uh, one thing, though:
He was provokin' me
when I popped him.
That's what it was like: "pop."
Well, we're sorry.
I mean, uh, nobody's comin'
out of this thing happy...
especially not us.
I can't deny we've had fun, though...
and, uh...
that's more
than I can say for some.
That's the end of the message.
I run out of things to say.
Thank you.
[Kit's Voice] My girl Holly and I
have decided to kill ourselves.
Same way I did her dad.
Big decision, huh?
[Holly Narrating] Kit left a record
playin' over and over...
for the district attorney to find.
He was gamblin' for time.
[Kit's Voice Continues On Record]
♪♪ [Female Choir Singing In German]
♪♪ [Continues]
Kit made me get my books from school
so I wouldn't fall behind.
We'd be startin' a new life, he said,
and we'd have to change our names.
His would be James.
Mine would be Priscilla.
We'd hide out like spies
somewhere in the north...
where people didn't ask
a lot of questions.
I coulda snuck out the back
or hid in the boiler room, I suppose...
but I sensed
that my destiny now lay with Kit...
for better or for worse...
and that it was better to spend a week
with one who loved me for what I was...
than years of loneliness.
How you doin'?
I'm fine.
Kinda tired.
Yeah, me too.
We hid out in the wilderness
down by a river...
in a grove of cottonwoods.
It being the flood season,
we built our house in the trees...
with tamarisk walls and willows
laid side by side to make a floor.
There wasn't a plant in the forest
that didn't come in handy.
We planned a huge network
of tunnels under the forest floor...
and our first order of business
every morning was to decide...
on a new password for the day.
Now and then we'd sneak out at night
and steal a chicken or a bunch of corn...
or some melons
from a melon patch.
Mostly, though, we just lay
on our backs and stared at the clouds.
And sometimes it was like bein'
in a big marble hall...
the way we talked in low voices
and heard the tiniest sound.
They hadn't found but one set of bones
in the ashes of the house...
so we knew they'd be lookin' for us.
Kit made sure we'd be prepared.
He gave me lectures
on how a gun works...
how to take it apart
and put it back together again...
in case I had
to carry on without him.
He said that if the devil came at me,
I could shoot him with a gun.
One day I carried 30 pounds of wood
a distance of five miles.
Another day,
while hiding in the forest...
I covered my eyes with makeup...
to see how they'd come out.
♪♪ [Rock 'n' Roll]
♪ Love, mm-mm ♪
♪ Love is strange, yea-yea ♪
♪ Lot of people, mm-mm ♪
♪ Take it for a game ♪♪
We had our bad moments,
like any couple.
Kit accused me of only being
along for the ride...
while at times I wished
he'd fall in the river and drown...
so I could watch.
Take a break, Red.
Life of Riley, huh?
Mostly, though,
we got along fine...
and stayed in love.
One of the chickens
died last night.
I almost stepped on him.
"The Kon-Tiki's motion
was a little different...
from what it usually was
in such conditions.
We had become sensitive to changes
in the rhythm of the logs.
I thought at once of suction
from the coast, which was drawing near...
and was continually
out on the deck and up the mast."
He was nervous.
"Time passed.
At dawn, just before 6:00...
Torstein came hurrying down
from the masthead.
He could see a whole line of small,
palm-clad islands far ahead."
I grew to love the forest.
The cooing of the doves
and the hum of dragonflies in the air...
made it always seem lonesome,
like everybody's dead and gone.
When the leaves rustled overhead...
it was like the spirits
were whisperin'...
about all the little things
that bothered 'em.
One day, while taking a look
at some vistas in Dad's stereopticon...
it hit me that I was
just this little girl...
born in Texas...
Hi.
Whose father was a sign painter...
who had only
just so many years to live.
It sent a chill down my spine,
and I thought...
"Where would I be
this very moment...
if Kit had never met me...
or killed anybody?
This very moment.
If my mom had never met my dad.
If she had never died.
And what's the man I'll marry
gonna look like?
What's he doin' right this minute?
Is he thinking about me now,
by some coincidence...
even though he doesn't know me?
Does it show on his face?"
For days afterwards,
I lived in dread.
Sometimes I wished
I could fall asleep...
and be taken off
to some magical land...
but this never happened.
[Ethereal Voice Whispering]
I know the stars...
and I saw the trees.
I knew the frog...
and I send the breeze.
♪♪ [Female Choir Singing In German]
[Kit Imitating Birdcall]
What?
Get out of here! Run!
Somebody's comin'!
Hide!
[Ethereal Voice] Come hide
in the trees. The branches...
Come hide...
[Several Voices Whispering]
♪♪ [Female Choir Singing In German]
Hey.
Hey-o.
Holly?
Get in the car, Red.
Well, you don't need this.
Kit felt bad about shootin'
those men in the backs...
but he said they'd come in like that,
and they would've played it...
as down and dirty as they could.
And besides, he'd overheard 'em
whisperin' about...
how they were only interested
in the reward money.
With lawmen
it would have been different.
They were out there to get a job done,
and they deserved a fair chance.
But not a bounty hunter.
We went to hide out with a friend of Kit's
from the days of the garbage route.
How you doin', Cato?
Not bad.
Take that son of a bitch.
What you been doin'?
Runnin' this place
for a fella in town.
It's nothing much to speak of.
Well, I don't notice us
hustlin' trash either.
Where did you get them antlers?
They come with the house.
Oh, Cato,
I want you to meet my girl...
Holly Sargis.
Hi.
Did you hear
about the guy at the nuthouse...
that walked around naked
except for hat and gloves?
This nurse came up
to him and said...
"You can't walk around that way."
And the guy says...
"It's okay.
Nobody comes around here anyway."
And the nurse says...
"Well, what do you have on
the hat and gloves for?"
And the guy says,
"Well, you never know."
Isn't that funny?
Yeah, I guess.
[Kit]
She plays clarinet too.
Don't you get bored around here?
Yep, sometimes.
The other day, though...
an old boy plowing in the field
over there found some old coins.
Old Spanish coins.
That's what he told you, huh?
Nope. No.
He showed me one.
What'd they look like?
Well, kind of round, like so...
and gold.
Where at?
Right over in that field over there.
I'll show you if you want.
Let me finish my supper.
Well, we're thinkin' of goin'
down to Texas.
Holly wants to visit
some of her people down there.
But after that, I don't know.
They say Mexico's nice.
Kit, maybe I'd better get a shovel.
Okay.
I'll catch up with you.
I found a lid.
It was layin' on the ground over there.
Put that down. It's dirty.
[Laughing]
[Holly] You missed!
You're a pissant.
Hey, you're throwing big ones!
Ho! Ho!
Cato?
The shovel's in the truck.
Kit never let on why he shot Cato.
He said that just talkin' about it
could bring us bad luck...
and that right now we needed
all the luck we could get.
[Kit]
You never told me about her.
Look at all this junk.
How's he doin'?
[Kit Exhales]
I got him in the stomach.
Is he upset?
He didn't say anything
to me about it.
Bunch of junk.
He stole that cage.
I saw him doin' it.
What you lookin' in there for? Can't
afford any of that. I'm just lookin'.
[Kit] Why don't you go in there
and keep him company for a while?
Hi.
[Weakly]
That your spider in there?
In that bottle?
Yeah.
What do you feed him?
Flies.
Grasshoppers,
when I can catch 'em.
Does he bite?
He ain't never bit me.
[Car Horn Honking]
Hi.
Where's Cato?
Well, he's gone.
Gone?
Yeah.
Where?
He said not to tell.
Oh, yeah?
He said for you
to give us a lift into town.
You're the ones
with the Studebaker, aren't you?
I need to pick up something in the house.
I can't allow that.
What?
You go in there, I'll have to kill you.
What's going on?
Can't afford to take chances.
Come on outta there, young lady.
Let's us go out in this field here.
Come on.
Ah, skip that. I'm gonna have
to keep my eye on you, though.
Okay.
You don't mind?
Hi.
What's gonna happen
to Jack and me?
Have to ask Kit.
He says "frog," I jump.
Okay.
[Holly] What's your friend's name?
Jack.
Hmm.
You love him?
I don't know.
I gotta stick by Kit.
He feels trapped.
[Girl]
I can imagine.
[Holly] Well, I've felt that way.
Hadn't you?
Okay. Come on, you two.
Down in the cellar.
Go on.
Hey.
Do you promise to stay there for an hour?
Yeah.
You expect me to believe that?
I'm gonna shut the door.
Think I got 'em?
I don't know.
Well, I'm not goin'
down there and look.
[Holly Narrating] Suddenly I was
thrown into a state of shock.
Kit was the most trigger-happy
person I'd ever met.
He claimed that as long as you're playing
for keeps and the law's coming at you...
it's considered okay
to shoot all witnesses.
You had to take the consequences,
though, and not whine about it later.
He'd never seemed
like a violent person before...
except for once, when he said
he'd like to rub out a couple of guys...
whose names
he didn't care to mention.
It all goes to show
how you can know a person...
and not really know him
at the same time.
We're in for it now...
if they catch us.
What did you put him in there for?
Just to keep him out of the sun.
At this moment,
I didn't feel shame or fear...
but just kind of blah...
like when you're sittin' there
and all the water's run out of the bathtub.
Are you tired?
Yeah.
Yeah, you look tired.
Listen, honey,
when all this is over...
I'm gonna sit down
and buy you a big, thick steak.
I don't want a steak.
Yeah, well, we'll see about that.
Hey, look.
They're probably gonna
blame that on me too.
Bastards.
The whole country
was out lookin' for us...
for who knew
where Kit would strike next?
Sidewalks cleared out.
Stores closed their doors
and drew the blinds.
Posses and vigilance committees...
were set up
from Texas to South Dakota.
Children rode back and forth
to school under heavy guard.
A famous detective
was brought in from Boston.
He could find no clues.
People left their lights on
when they went to sleep.
My clarinet teacher said
I probably wasn't responsible...
but others said I was.
Then, on Thursday,
the governor of Oklahoma sent out...
the National Guard to stand watch
at the Federal Reserve Bank in Tulsa...
when word got out
that Kit meant to rob it.
It was like the Russians had invaded.
We needed supplies, so we went to a
rich man's house. - [Doorbell Rings]
Kit figured it'd be safer and quicker
than shoppin' in the downtown.
A maid came to the door.
[Kit] Hi.
I'm here to check the meter.
My tools are in here.
Oh, this is Holly.
She's from Texas.
Later we found out she was deaf,
and we hadn't even known it.
Excuse me.
Hi.
Yes?
This your place?
Yes.
Sorry to barge in on you.
Anyone else here besides you two?
No.
Good deal.
[Airplane Passes Overhead]
Oh, we're on the run...
and, uh...
we'd like to hang out here
for a while.
Couple hours, maybe.
How'd that be?
Stay as long as you like.
[High-pitched Tone Droning]
Next time I ring,
that means it's time to clear out.
I left Kit in the parlor and went
for a stroll outside the house.
The day was quiet and serene,
but I didn't notice...
for I was deep in thought...
and not even thinkin'
about how to slip off.
The world was like a faraway planet
to which I could never return.
I thought,
what a fine place it was...
full of things that people
can look into and enjoy.
Listen to your parents and teachers.
They got a line on most things,
so don't treat 'em like enemies.
There's always an outside chance
you can learn somethin'.
Try to keep an open mind.
Try to understand
the viewpoints of others.
Consider the minority opinion...
but try to get along with the majority
of opinion once it's accepted.
Of course, Holly and I have had fun,
even if it has been rushed.
And, uh...
so far, we're doin' fine.
Hadn't got caught.
Excuse the grammar.
Hi.
Kit's downstairs
playin' with the Dictaphone.
Sometimes he acts like there's
somethin' wrong with his bean.
Hope nothin'
ever goes wrong with mine.
You think he's crazy, huh?
I don't know.
He's kinda odd.
They claim I got him wrapped
around my little finger...
but I never told him
to shoot anybody.
Gosh, I like your house. Thank you.
[Doorbell Rings]
Hi.
Hi. Uh, Mr. Scarborough here?
Yeah.
The thing about him,
he's down with the flu. He's sick.
Really?
Yeah.
I'd invite you inside,
except it's contagious.
Don't want to start an epidemic.
No, of course not.
Uh, it's only,
he called last night...
and asked if I could come by.
Well, he-he didn't have it last night.
What's that?
Well, I'd...
I'd like to leave a message...
if that's okay.
Sure.
[Writing]
[Paper Tears]
Uh, you have to excuse me now.
I have to go back inside.
Bye.
Hey, Tex, we're outta here!
Hi. Whatcha doin'?
Just thinking.
Yeah, good a way to kill time as any.
She okay?
Yes.
Good.
Oh, uh, we're gonna take
the Cadillac for a while.
How'd that be?
Fine.
Don't worry.
I won't let her drive.
Oh, and, uh, here.
Here's a list of everything I borrowed.
Car's on there too.
Okay, ma'am, let's go.
Out that way.
Go on.
You're my friend, aren't you?
Yes.
Okay. No monkey business, now.
Groceries.
[Kit] That guy could sell that list
I gave him as a sample of my handwriting.
Hey, why are you always walkin'
ahead of me?
Well, why are you
always walkin' behind me?
Don't!
Anybody ever done that to you before?
No.
Positive?
Yes.
Guess there's no way
I'll ever know for sure.
That guy must pay through the nose
to keep this place up.
Lawn. Gas and electric.
Bagworms.
Plus the upkeep on the cars.
Yeah, you get
a little money in your pocket...
and you think
all your problems are solved.
Well, let me tell you,
they're not.
I'd like to get outta here.
As soon as I start the car.
[Engine Starts]
And fix my hat.
[Holly Narrating] Fearin' there'd be
roadblocks on the highways...
we took off across that region
known as the Great Plains.
Kit told me to enjoy
the scenery, and I did.
"Rumor:
Pat Boone is seriously
considering giving up his career...
so he can return to school full-time
and complete his education.
Fact: Pat has told intimates...
that so long as things
are going well for his career...
it's the education
that will have to take a backseat."
I don't blame him.
"Rumor: Frank Sinatra
and Rita Hayworth are in love.
Fact: True.
But not with each other."
Yeah.
Through desert and mesa...
across the endless miles
of open range...
we made our headlong way,
steerin' by the telephone lines...
toward the mountains of Montana.
Kit would sometimes ram a cow
to save on ammo, and we'd cook it.
Once we had to eat
a bunch of salt grass.
It tasted like cabbage.
For gas we used the leakage
from the valves of the pipelines...
we found along the way.
"Drip gas" is what it's called
in that part of the country.
Little by little,
we approached the border.
Kit was glad to leave South Dakota
behind and cursed its name.
He said that if the Communists
ever dropped the atomic bomb...
he wished they'd put it
right in the middle of Rapid City.
That's Montana over there.
[Kit]
I never been to Montana.
Acquaintance of mine's
been there, but I hadn't.
Never had any reason to.
[Holly]
State bird's the meadowlark.
We lived in utter loneliness,
neither here nor there.
Kit said that "solitude"
was a better word...
'cause it meant more exactly
what I wanted to say.
Whatever the expression,
I told him we couldn't go on...
livin' this way.
Why not?
I mean, I'm havin' fun.
At least I'm not bitchin'.
Well, I feel kinda like
an animal livin' out here.
There's no place to bathe and...
not any place to get
anything good to eat.
Well, I'll catch you a big trout
soon as we get to the mountains.
Everybody loves trout.
I'm serious.
In the distance, I saw a train
making its way silently across the plain...
like the caravan
in The Adventures of Marco Polo.
It was our first taste
of civilization in weeks...
and I asked Kit
if we could have a closer look.
Before we left, he shot a football...
that he considered excess baggage.
Afterwards, he took and buried
some of our things in a bucket.
He said that nobody else
would know where we'd put 'em...
and that we'd come back someday
maybe and they'd still be sittin' here...
just the same,
but we'd be different.
And if we never got back, well...
somebody might dig 'em up
a thousand years from now...
and wouldn't they wonder.
[Horn Blaring]
Maybe we shoulda tried to hop it.
It was goin' too fast.
Yeah, I coulda pulled the car
up on the tracks, slowed it down some.
Yeah, then we'd be stuck here.
Well, maybe we oughta be stuck here.
I'm not sayin' I know.
You're crazy.
Kit took the bottle
and spun it around...
leaving to fate
which direction we should take.
Well, maybe the slope here
is throwin' it off some.
We ought to find a more flat place.
How about over here?
Aw, forget it.
It doesn't matter.
If I'm worth a damn,
I'll pick the right direction.
If I'm not, well, I don't care.
See what I mean?
No. Well, I shouldn't
expect miracles, should I?
We'll keep on headin'
for that mountain.
Just remember
I said it wasn't such a hot idea.
We took off at sunset...
on a line toward
the mountains of Saskatchewan...
for Kit, a magical land
beyond the reach of the law.
He needed me now more than ever,
but somethin' had come between us.
I'd stopped
even payin' attention to him.
Instead I sat in the car
and read a map...
and spelled out
entire sentences with my tongue...
on the roof of my mouth,
where nobody could read 'em.
That night we moved
closer to the border...
and clear across the prairie,
at the very edge of the horizon...
we could make out the gas fires
at the refineries at Missoula...
while to the south we could see
the lights of Cheyenne...
a city bigger and grander
than I'd ever seen.
I felt all kind of things
lookin' at the lights of Cheyenne...
but most important,
I made up my mind to never again...
tag around with the hell-bent type...
no matter how in love
with him I was.
Finally, I found the strength
to tell Kit this.
I pointed out that
even if we got to the far north...
he still couldn't make a living.
I can get a job with the Mounties.
Northwest Mounties.
Hell, I got all the qualifications.
I can ride and, uh, shoot...
and, uh, I don't mind the cold.
In fact, I kinda like the cold.
What?
Nothin'.
I was just runnin' off at the mouth...
as usual.
I'm sorry. I wasn't listenin'.
Hey, man, don't lip it.
Well...
you know, they'd probably ask
to see your driver's license...
before they'd hire you.
Well, I'm not gonna
let that stop me.
You smoke Pall Mall?
Yeah.
Ah, you haven't seen me when
I'm goin' after something, honey.
Tough.
[Scoffs]
♪♪ [Ballad On Radio]
Hey, don't touch that. Nat "King" Cole.
♪ You turned to me ♪
♪ The gypsies say ♪
♪ And I know why ♪
♪ A falling blossom ♪
♪ Only touches lips that lie ♪
♪ A blossom fell ♪
♪ And very soon ♪
♪ I saw you kissing someone new ♪
♪ Beneath the moon ♪
♪ I thought you loved me ♪
Boy, if I could sing a song like that.
♪ You said you loved me ♪
If I could sing a song
about the way I feel right now...
♪ We planned together ♪
It'd be a hit.
♪ To dream forever ♪
♪ The dream has ended ♪
♪ For true love died ♪
♪ The night a blossom fell ♪
♪ And touched two lips that lied ♪
♪♪ [Continues]
Kit knew the end was coming.
He wondered if he'd hear
the doctor pronounce him dead...
or if he'd be able to read what the papers
would say about him the next day...
from the other side.
He dreaded the idea of being
shot down alone, he said...
without a girl
to scream out his name.
Then, for an instant, the sight
of the mountains in the dawn light...
got his hopes back up.
God, what a sight.
Hey, tell me this, honey:
What does a little Texas girl
like yourself think of a sight like that?
♪ The dream has ended ♪
♪ For true love died ♪
♪ The night a blossom fell ♪
♪ And touched two lips ♪
♪ That lied ♪♪
Love this air.
Mornin'.
Uh, you got any gas?
Maybe.
Well, I'm sorry, sir,
but we got to ask you for it.
We're about out.
We been drivin' all night.
Actually, I don't even have time
to explain it to you.
[Man]
Well, what I got, I can't spare.
Just a second, now.
That's your truck, isn't it?
You didn't walk out here.
It's mine, all right.
Well, listen, I'm gonna
swap you my Cadillac.
Now, don't worry.
You're gettin' a fair deal.
Hell, ask anybody. What's the Blue Book
value on this thing, Mildred?
[Man]
Who are you?
The name's Carruthers.
Believe I shoot people every now and then.
Not that I deserve a medal.
Kit?
[Pistol Cocks]
Okay, friend.
Start runnin'.
Give me a chance.
[Kit]
Go on, git!
Boy, I had a feelin' today
was gonna be the day.
Helicopter.
Yeah.
He's not gonna take us for any ride.
Let's make a run for the car.
I don't want to.
Have you got a better idea?
I just don't want to go.
What?
What is wrong with you?
Huh?
What is the matter with you?
I don't know what to make
of people like you.
I really don't.
You want a second chance,
then listen.
12:00 noon,
Grand Coulee Dam...
New Years Day, 1964.
You meet me there.
Now, you got that?
♪♪ [Choir Singing In German]
Hey! Anybody here?
Hi.
Say, you got any shells
for a Savage?
.300 Savage?
Nope.
Damn. I pissed all mine away
shootin' up bottles.
Hey, you wanna fill 'er up for me?
Please?
[Exhales]
If you want any of that junk, it's yours.
[Horn Honking]
[Shots Fire]
[Cattle Mooing]
[Horn Honking]
[Shots Firing]
[Glass Shatters]
[Holly Narrating] Many times I've wondered
what was goin' through Kit's head before they got him...
and why he didn't make a run for it
while he still had the chance.
Did he figure
they'd just catch him the next day?
Was it despair?
He claimed to havin' a flat tire...
but the way he carried on about it,
I imagine this is false.
[Shot Fires]
Hi.
[Man]
Hold it right there.
I coulda held off an army if I coulda
got behind a boulder up in the mountains.
Oh, yeah?
As long as my ammo held out.
Right there is where you caught me.
We did it, Ray.
You better not leave
that Cadillac sittin' out here.
Put your hands
back of your head.
Now put the other one on yourself.
Hell, he ain't no bigger than I am.
Look at that.
You're gonna give me
a cauliflowered ear, Sheriff.
He should've thought about that
before he got caught...
shouldn't he?
Hup!
Think I'll take the juice?
Beats me.
Say, what kind of rifle was that
you were shootin' at me?
Thirty aught six.
You ever had to open up
like that before?
Nope.
Well, you boys have performed
like a couple of heroes...
and don't think I'm not gonna
pass it around when we get to town.
You tossed my hat out the window.
[Sheriff]
Wanna sue me?
No.
[Deputy] Kit?
Kit, I got a question for you.
You like people?
They're okay.
Then why'd you do it?
I don't know. I...
I always wanted to be a criminal,
I guess. Just not this big of one.
Takes all kinds, though.
You know who that
son of a bitch looks like?
You know, don't you?
No.
I'll kiss your ass
if he don't look like James Dean.
[Man]
How you doin' there, Kit?
[Kit] Fine as can be expected.
Just locked up. Can't move.
That's a nice little coat you got on there.
You think?
It's leather. Hey.
Now, looky here.
Here's the real prize.
I must've had this about ten years.
Looky there.
Who's gonna get it?
[Man #2] Give me that son of a bitch.
There you go.
[Man #3] Where are you from?
South Dakota. Where you from?
Here.
Want a comb?
[Man #4]
Joni James is from South Dakota.
Yeah, I know.
She got outta there too.
[Man #5]
Kit, who's your favorite singer?
Eddie Fisher. Who's yours?
Eddie Fisher.
Damn. You want a pen?
[Man #6] How old are you?
Don't you read the papers?
[Men Chuckling]
You ever been married?
No, I haven't.
[Man #7] Hey, Kit?
Yeah?
You afraid of death?
[Kit]
I haven't thought about it much.
[Man, Indistinct]
[Kit] Say again?
[Indistinct]
Yep.
Hey, Tom, I don't mean to tell you how to run
your show here, but these cuffs are pinchin' some.
What do you say now?
I need to get your signature
on some paperwork here, Kit.
Well, I'll have to read it first.
Suppose I could get a Coke while I do?
Sure thing.
Come on.
You boys keep out of trouble.
[Man] Don't worry about us.
[Tom] Holly's over here, Kit,
if you want to see her.
Sure.
[Tom] I give him the papers to sign.
I'm gonna get him a Coke.
You want to give me
a little slack there?
Hi.
[Soldier]
Double-time, push!
Don't worry, now.
I'm gonna get you off these charges.
There's a whole lot of other boys
out there waitin' for you...
and you're gonna have a lot of fun.
Boy, we rang the bell, didn't we?
I'll say this, though:
That guy with the deaf maid?
He's just lucky he's not dead too.
'Course, uh,
too bad about your dad.
Yeah.
We're gonna have to sit down
and talk about that sometime.
There you go, Tom.
Thank you.
Thank you very much, Chief Sims.
Sorry if I caused you any inconvenience.
You didn't cause me any trouble.
Thanks anyway.
Well...
Kit.
Tom.
Good luck.
Thank you.
I mean it.
I know. Good luck to you too.
Now we go.
Okay. Thank you.
Come on, Red.
Kit and I were taken back
to South Dakota.
They kept him in solitary,
so he didn't have a chance...
to get acquainted
with the other inmates...
though he was sure they'd like him,
especially the murderers.
Myself, I got off with probation
and a lot of nasty looks.
Later I married the son
of the lawyer who defended me.
Kit went to sleep in the courtroom
while his confession was bein' read...
and he was sentenced
to die in the electric chair.
On a warm spring night,
six months later...
after donatin' his body
to science, he did.
Sir, where'd you get that hat?
State.
Boy, I'd like
to buy me one of them.
[Soft Chuckle]
You're quite an individual, Kit.
Think they'll take that
into consideration?