This is the Ardèche River
in Southern France.
Less than half of a mile from here
three explorers set out a few days
before Christmas in 1994.
They came along this way.
They were seeking drafts of air
emanating from the ground -
which would point
to the presence of caves.
Eventually they sensed
the subtle airflow
and began clearing away rocks,
revealing a narrow shaft
into the cliff.
It was so narrow that a person
could barely squeeze through it.
They descended into the unknown.
They were about to make
one of the greatest discoveries
in the history of human culture.
At first, the cave did not appear
to contain anything special,
aside from being
particularly beautiful.
But then, deep inside,
they found this.
It would turn out
that this cave was pristine.
It had been perfectly sealed
for tens of thousands of years.
It contained cave paintings
dating back 32,000 years.
In fact, they are the oldest
paintings ever discovered.
More than twice as old
as any other.
In honour of its leading discoverer,
Jean-Marie Chauvet,
the cave now bears
the name Chauvet Cave.
This is road in the Ardèche Gorge,
leading to the cave.
It is early spring.
We've been given
an unprecedented endorsement
by the French Ministry of Culture
to film inside the cave.
From the first day
of its discovery
the importance of the cave
was immediately recognized
and access was shut off categorically.
Only a small group of scientists
is allowed to enter.
They are archaeologists,
art historians, palaeontologists
and geologists among others.
They are here
to perform their studies
during a few short weeks
at the end of March
and the beginning of April.
This is one of the rare times anyone
with the exception of two guards
is allowed inside the cave.
The cave is like a frozen flash
of a moment in time.
The reason for its pristine condition
is this rock face.
Some 20,000 years ago,
it came tumbling down
in a massive rockslide,
sealing off the original
entrance to the cave,
creating a perfect time capsule.
A wooden walkway leads
to the entrance of the cave.
The narrow tunnel,
through which the discoverers crawled,
has been widened and locked
with a massive steel door,
like a bank vault.
Once we pass through this door
it will be locked behind us,
so as not to compromise
the delicate climate inside.
For this first exploration
into the cave,
we are using a tiny,
non-professional camera rig.
In this narrow holding room,
we are fitted with sterile boots
and given safety instructions.
- We have this.
- Good.
Once you've set this on the rock,
you don't touch it.
Clottes was the first scientist
to inspect the cave
a few days after its discovery.
For five years,
until his retirement,
he served as head
of the scientific team.
Our guide leads us down
the first sloping tunnel,
which ends in a vertical drop
to the cave floor.
Since our film crew has been
limited to a maximum of four,
we must all perform
technical tasks.
Our time in the cave
has been severely restricted.
I will take one light as well.
So it's 3.05.
We have one hour.
Apart from time contrictions,
we're not allowed to touch anything.
Or ever step off the
2 ft wide walkway.
We can use only 3 flat
light pannels,
powered by battery belts.
When they made the passageways,
they protected the stalagmites.
It's a nice touch.
Moving along in a single file
the film crew will have no
hiding places
to get out of the shot.
The first large chamber
we come to
is the original entrance
to the cave.
In prehistoric times,
before the rockslide,
daylight must have
illuminated this.
On the left,
right inside the cave,
you could see the entrance.
The archaeological entrance.
People came into the cave, level.
Not like us down a ladder.
The cliff collapsed.
Then we've got
the rubble from the cliff.
From outside you can't see it,
from the inside you can.
Over there you have the dots.
The red dots.
Those are the ones I first saw
when I came to the cave.
Big dots made
with the palm of a hand.
Here we have a big
cave bear skull.
Male, probably.
You'll see many others.
In this big chamber,
which is really huge,
the biggest in the cave,
there are no paintings,
except right at the end.
This is probably relevant.
When the entrance was still open,
there must have been
some light here.
Or they would have been
painting in complete darkness.
This is a cave bear
painted in black.
The paintings look so fresh
that there were initial doubts
about their authenticity.
But this picture has a layer of
calcite and concretions over it
that takes thousands of years to grow.
This was the first proof
that it was not a forgery.
A beautiful horse here,
one of the most beautiful in the cave.
It looks like it could
have been made yesterday.
See how fresh it looks!
Here, behind the horse,
are two mammals. Big mammals.
Here you can see
cave bear scratches.
These scratches do not
have the same colour.
They might have been made
5-10,000 years earlier.
Here's one of the great
spots in the cave,
the famous Panel of the Horses.
It has the size of a small recess
and through that hole there
water comes out,
gurgling after a week of rain.
That may explain why the animals
were painted around that hole.
It's one of the great
works of art in the world.
For these palaeolithic painters,
the play of light and shadows
from their torches
could possibly have looked
something like this.
For them the animals perhaps
appeared moving, living.
We should note that the artist
painted this bison with 8 legs,
suggesting movement,
almost a form of proto-cinema.
The walls themselves
are not flat,
but have their own
three-dimensional dynamic,
their own movement,
which was utilized by the artists.
In the upper left corner is
another multi-legged animal.
The rhino to the right seems also
to have the illusion of movement.
Like frames in an animated film.
The painters speak to us from
a familiar, yet distant universe.
But what we are seeing here
is part of millions of spatial points.
Today, scientists have mapped
every millimetre of the cave,
using laser scanners.
The position of every feature
in the cave is known.
This is the shape of the cave
in its entirety.
From end to end,
it is about 1300 ft long.
This map is the basis
for all scientific projects here.
We are working to create
a new understanding of the cave.
Through precision,
scientific methods.
But that's not the main goal.
The main goal is to create stories
about what could have happened
in that cave in the past.
It is like you're creating
the film directory of Manhattan.
4 million precise entries,
but do they dream or cry at night?
What are their hopes?
What are their families?
You will never know
from the film directory.
We'll definitely never know
because the past is lost.
We will never reconstruct the past.
We can only create a representation
of what exists now, today.
You're a human being,
I'm a human being.
When you come to the cave,
of course there are some things...
I have my own background...
What is your background?
I used to be a circus man,
but switched to archaeology.
Circus? Doing what?
Lion tamer?
Well, not a lion tamer.
Mostly unit cycles and juggling.
When I first entered the cave,
I had a chance to stay five days.
It was so powerful.
Every night I dreamt of lions.
Every day was the same
shock for me.
It was an emotional shock.
I'm a scientist,
and a human too.
After 5 days, I decided
not to go back to the cave.
I needed time to just relax
...and to absorb it.
You dreamt not of paintings of lions,
but of real lions?
Both. Definitely.
And you were afraid
in your dreams?
I was not afraid, no,
it was more...
A feeling of something powerful
and deep.
A way of understanding
that was not direct.
Silence please.
Please don't move.
We're going to listen to
the silence in the cave.
And perhaps we can even
hear our own hearts beat.
These images are memories
of long forgotten dreams.
Is this their heartbeat
or ours?
Will we ever be able to understand
the vision of the artists
across such an abyss of time?
There is an aura of melodrama
in this landscape.
It could be straight
out of a Wagner opera.
Or a painting by
German romanticists.
Could this be our connection
to them?
This staging of the landscape
is an operatic event.
It does not belong
to the romanticists alone.
Stoneage men may have had
a smilar sense of inner landscapes.
It seems natural that there is
a cluster of palaeolithic caves
right around here.
The Chauvet Cave is right here
at the top of this cliff.
The cave is also associated
with this natural feature.
This beautiful arch called Pont d'Arc.
Maybe the Pont d'Arc,
in the mythology of the people,
was not only a landmark,
but a mark in their imagination
and their stories and mythology.
An important way for them
to understand the world.
But what kind of world
was it for palaeolithic people?
35,000 years ago,
Europe was covered by glaciers.
In this glacial Europe,
you must imagine a dry climate.
Cold, but with sun,
that is important.
In this place, you have to
imagine rhinos along the rivers.
In the forest you had
megaloceros deer.
Horses, raindeer, bisons,
and antelopes.
It was very rich.
The biomass in this part of Europe
was very important
for the development of humans,
but also for carnivores.
So imagine lions, bears,
leopards, wolfs, foxes...
in very large numbers.
And among all these carnivores
and predators - humans.
Does the way they set up fires
in the Chauvet Cave
offer evidence that they cast
their own shadows
against the paintings of horses
for example?
The fires were necessary
for looking at the paintings.
And maybe for staging
people around them.
With the flames and moving light
you can imagine people dancing.
Fred Astaire!
The image of him
dancing with his shadows
is a very strong image
of human representation.
A representation of
a white wall and a black shadow.
The presence of humans in the cave
was fleeting like shadows.
Bear skulls everywhere.
These skulls belonged
to the cave bear.
A species like the mammoth
and the wooly rhino
that vanished from
the face of the earth long ago.
Tens of thousands of years
of patient water dripping
has left a thick coating
of calcide on this skull.
It now has the appearance
of a porcelain sculpture.
In all this menagerie of bones,
there's not a single human specimen.
Scientists have determined
that humans never lived in the cave.
They used it only for painting
and possibly for ceremonies.
Michel Philippe has studied
the bones of the Chauvet Cave.
Caves constitute a favourable place
for the preservation of bones.
There are many bear bones,
99 percent of the finds.
There are also some wolves,
two skulls and several bones.
We have a few ibexes
with magnificent skulls
in the wet sand with calcide.
Quite lovely.
When you shine light on it,
calcite crystals glisten.
There are some horses as well.
There's a cave hyena.
There's also an eagle skeleton.
A golden eagle.
Practically whole, but it
may be a little more recent,
carried in by water and
wedged against the big rocks.
So, it's bones are spread out
over ten ft in length.
Our goal is not only
to say what bones there are.
We also try to understand
if they lived there,
if they were moved,
how they were transported.
Did the bears bring the bones?
There are several bones
that have been chewed on,
so it could have been the bears
or the hyenas.
All the scientists are lodged
in a neaby sports complex.
Although they all have
their special fields,
they compare and combine
their findings.
We were interested
in the work of these two.
Carol and Giles, can you explain
what you are doing here?
In the cave, we are trying to
reveal contours of underlying designs
that are hard to follow
with the naked eye.
Because we are not supposed
to touch the wall,
we take a series of photos
that we put together
in a mosaic.
We are trying to achieve
a maximum of detail.
Then we take a transparency
and put it on top of the photo.
Then we trace
the underlayer of engravings.
Later, we return to the cave.
We check against the contours
all the designs we can see.
And all the markings
of the bears as well.
So that we can understand
each figure and event.
We have bear scratches,
and a magnificent drawing
of a mammoth done by finger,
and other scratches
done over the mammoth.
Their succession is important
for understanding what took place.
On the computer
one can see three phases.
The first dates 40,000 years
back in time.
The one when the bear
scratched the walls.
Then a second phase
with drawings stretching
over 8 ft in height.
Therefore made with a stick.
Followed by the main phase
some time around 33,000
years ago or less.
It starts with the scraping
of the wall
to get to the wide of the rock.
After that the first figures
were put in place.
The two rhinos attacking
one another at the bottom.
After that came the three bulls.
Finally, it ended with
a series of horses
going from top to bottom.
And in the final phase,
I did this very beautiful horse
that confronts the viewers
when they arrive in the cave.
When you do a synthesis
of the composition,
there is a kind of dynamic,
circular movement
going from the bottom
to the right,
towards the centre like a circle.
It obviously creates
a very strong dynamic
reinforced here by the oblique
movement of the horses.
It's the force of the contrast,
the fact that they've played
with the contrast
and with the shape of the wall.
It's like an easel.
They've used the surface,
made use of the material,
and mixed materials
to create this very strong impression.
By comparing all the paintings
in the cave
it seems certain
that the horses of this panel
were created by
one single individual.
But in the immediate vicinity
of the horses,
there are figures with animals
overlapping with each other.
A striking point here is that,
in cases like this,
after carbon-dating,
there are strong indications
that some overlapping figures
were drawn almost
5000 years apart.
The sequence and duration of time
is unimaginable for us today.
We are locked in history,
and they were not.
Despite this blurring of time,
and the anonymity of the artists,
there's one individual
who can be singled out.
Dominique Baffier is a scholar
of palaeolithic culture.
Here on the right,
she examines the cluster of palm prints
with her colleague Valérie Feruglio.
We are currently working
on this large panel
that was covered
with positive handprints.
Weve been able to put forward
as evidence
the number of positions
the individual assumed,
and his movements.
He started by crouching,
and then he stretched out to reach
to his highest palm prints.
This panel is comprised of
the prints of a single man
who must have measured
roughly 6 ft tall.
A single human.
One 1.80 m tall.
That's big.
- Only one person?
- One person!
A person measuring 6 ft.
You'll notice on these prints
a very significant detail.
He has a slightly crooked little finger.
And that's extraordinary,
because it gives a physical reality
to a prehistoric individual
who 32,000 years ago
came to the cave before us.
Even more surprising are
traces of him deeper in the cavern.
We'll be able to recognize him
by his crooked little finger.
Because he printed his hand
farther in the cave.
So we can follow
this man's path.
Mme Baffier took us on a tour.
She serves as a custodian
of the cave.
Her rules of engagament
are strict, but entirely reasonable,
given the precious and fragile nature
of this unique place.
You have cave bear tracks.
The forepaws and hindpaws.
These are the longest
cave bear tracks
currently known in any cave.
It's very sparkly,
there are crystals that glitter.
Here at this junction
we have the panel of the panther.
You can see the drawing
of a panther,
which is the only one know in
palaeolothic wall painting to date.
Here we've arrived at a place
where concretion growth
has been very important.
On the ground and walls,
you can see that rimstone
calcite ridges
have covered everything
in sparkling formation.
A kind of cascade.
With waves.
Here you have a bear vertebra,
which is entirely coated
in calcite,
and held by calcite crystals.
In front of us, on the wall
you also have an overflowing
draperylike concretion.
And here a kind of niche
where you can see the traces
of ancient red paintings,
which have been washed away
by water sievage.
And this is where you find
extremely original images.
Like this insect-shaped one.
Or this one,
shaped like a butterfly.
Or a bird in flight...
that you also find
on this rock pendant,
hanging from the ceiling.
Large and very small.
Coupled with two vertical
ochre stripes
that follow the pendant's contours.
Here we are in front of
the large panel of red paintings.
Also an extremely
intriguing item.
This mount of stones
didn't fall from the ceiling.
It was prehistoric man
who brought the stones here.
But we do not know why.
On this panel you have
a little rhinoceros
with a large horn
and a stripe on the abdomen.
Also, you have
a whole series underneath
of positive handprints.
And over there
you can see the hand of the man
who printed his palms
in the first room of the cave.
Because you can recognize
his crooked little finger.
In other words,
we've followed him here.
Here are some animals,
and here the front of a big rhinoceros
with a very large horn.
Here you have torch white marks.
The men would light their way
with a torch.
And when the wood
was burnt down,
they would scrape the torch
against the wall
to rekindle the flame.
The traces are fresh.
Because you can see these
small fragments of coal that have fallen.
One of these tiny fragments
was tested by radiocarbon dating.
This torch was swiped
28,000 years ago.
Here we have a painting
that is quite interesting.
Bacause it represents a couple
of now extinct cave lions.
Here is the male.
He is behind, the larger one.
He's outlined in a single stroke,
more than six ft in length.
In front you have the female.
She is smaller and seems
to rub her flank against the male.
This representation of the cave lion
has allowed us to shed light
on a mystery,
because archaeo-zoologists didn't know
if the cave lion had a mane
like the lion today,
living in Africa.
This representation of a cave lion,
more than 30,000 years old,
shows us that they
didn't have a mane.
Look at the outline of his head,
which is clearly delineated.
This is wihout a doubt a male,
because we have the scrotum
right here under the tail.
This is one of the most beautiful
panels in the cave.
Along with the lion panel
at the far end.
And here we can see
the technique of prehistoric man.
But you can also see their
key knowledge of the animal world.
They tell us stories.
Here you have
an ensemble of horses.
But their open mouths suggest
the animals are whinnying.
That is to say that these images
become audible to us.
You see that the two rhinos
are fighting.
You can see all the signs of
fury towards each other.
The movement of their legs,
which are thrown forward,
and you can almost
hear the sound...
of their horns colliding
in the movement of the fight.
Here you have another story,
a story of lions.
A male courting a female
who is not ready for mating.
She sits and growls.
You can hear the female growling.
She's raising her lips,
she's baring her teeth.
She is not happy.
And here you have
the flight of this bison.
We hear the hooves.
We can make out multiple legs
indicating its movement.
It is escaping from this alcove,
following this auroch.
Mme Baffier takes us down to
the fartherst chamber of the cave.
The mysterious Chamber
of the Lions.
There is a serious level
of toxic CO2 gas
emanating from the roots of trees,
which seeps down into the cave
through the porous limestone.
Our time is even more constricted
in this location,
and there is no possibility
to get close to the paintings.
There are things you won't
be able to show in your film,
and you won't be able to see.
You can't get closer.
That is the case with these
absolutely marvellous paintings.
This grouping of lions.
It is especially the case
with this rock pendant,
where the lower portion of
a woman's body has been painted.
You have her pubic triangle,
and her legs that seperate,
starting at the knee,
which diverge
and are reminiscent of the
well-known stoneage statuettes
from archaeological digs in the
Swabian Jura in Germany.
We can only see part of this
lower half of this female body,
because we cannot access
the other side of the pendant.
You cannot walk on these grounds,
because they are too fragile.
Your would destroy
the charcoal remains.
You would destroy the tracks left
by the bears and the humans.
You'll have to make do
with this partial image.
If you completed the other
half of this female body
with its other legs symetrically,
you could see that it is
connected to a bison head
that would have
a somewhat human arm.
Here we are
some 30,000 years later
with a myth that has endured
until our day.
We can also find this association
of female and bull
in Picasso's drawings of
the Minotaur and the Woman.
This is the only partial
representation of a human in the cave.
For the time being,
the other side of the rock pendant
must remain unreachable for us.
The people who created this
are equally enigmatic.
Of the few things they left behind,
practical items like flint tools
can be more easily read.
The local museum is filled
with artefacts from the region.
We have made excavations
on the site...
Jean Michel Geneste can only
lead us to a handful of findings
from the Chauvet Cave.
We have only2-3 boxes
in this area.
To shed light on
the enigmatic female image,
he has prepared similar figurines
from other regions.
You can see the likeness
in this Willendorf Venus.
It's a copy made in limestone,
found in Austria
from the same period.
In Chauvet, only the lower
part of the belly is preserved.
It's embedded in a bison.
There seems to have existed
a visual convention
extending all the way
beyond Baywatch.
No clear male representation
has been found,
but this lion man comes
from a site in the Swabian Alps.
It's an amazing mixture of
an anthropomorphic shape,
a human body, and the head of a lion.
Is is the spirit
of a lion in a man?
Is it a composed creature,
a new being?
Such equations can be pondered.
What the people who lived
in this valley left behind,
is their great art.
It was not a primitive beginning,
or a slow evolution,
it rather burst onto the scene
like a sudden explosive event.
It is as if the modern
human soul had awakened here.
Even more astonishing
to consider is that
at the time Neanderthal man
still roamed this valley.
But there must have been
other forms of artistic expression,
like music for example.
For this, we had to
look around in nearby regions.
Southwestern Germany
30-40,000 years ago
was connected to this valley
through an icefree corridor.
It should also be noted
that the Alp Mountains
were covered by 9000 ft of ice,
binding so much water
that the sea level was
300 ft lower than today.
A  hunter could have walked
from Paris to London
crossing the dry seabed
of the English Channel.
Walking 400 miles in this direction
woud lead you to the
Swabian Alps in Germany.
In the museum of Blaubeuren,
are replicas of the best-known
palaeolithic Venuses.
But this one, the Venus
of Hohle Fels, stands out.
Found in 2008, it is
sensational for its age.
Venus from Hohle Fels
is probably the oldest depiction
of any kind of figurative object
we know at all.
It's the earliest representation
of a human being,
and it's the absolute root of
figurative depiction as we know it.
Later on, we see a range
of animals being depicted.
The animal depictions
in ivory here.
Or the fabulous depictions
from Grotte Chauvet
of mammoths and lions.
We can see a very clear connection
between the Swabian finds
and the depictions in Chauvet.
It's also fascinating that,
at this time 40,000 years ago,
we see evidence for
musical instruments,
a range of personal ornaments.
Mythical depictions
that clearly show
that these people
had a religious concept
evolving the transformation
between humans and animals.
This is the original statuette
carved from a mammoth tusk.
If we look at the Venus of
Hohle Fels a bit more closely,
we can see very clearly
that the figurine has no head.
Instead of a head,
the figurine has a ring.
It was perhaps worn at times,
suspended on a string.
The sexual attributes are key
which clearly link this depiction
to ideas of reproduction,
fecundity, sexuality.
Ideas that are absolutely essential
to all of humanity.
Also today.
It's also important to realize
that at this time
much of Europe was
occupied by Neanderthals.
We're dealing with the
critical phase in human evolution
where two forms of humans
are testing their boundaries.
What we find,
over and over again,
is that Neanderthals,
although very sophisticated,
never have this kind of
symbolic artefact.
Ever.
This small ivory mammoth was
also found near Hohle Fels Cave.
This beautiful horse
comes from the same rigion.
They also found
fragments of flutes.
We asked Dr Conrad
to show us an original.
The ivory flute
is a remarkable artefact
that Maria Malina discovered
a few years back.
It's extremely important
that we realize that archaeology today
is not a heroic adventure
with spades and picks,
but high-tech scientific work
that's done with indredible detail.
Millimetre by millimetre
the sediments are removed
in these deposits in Chauvet
between 30-40,000 years ago.
This detailed work allowed Maria
to identify a whole range of finds,
which she was able to piece together.
You can explain
how that worked out.
We did an inventory
of all the artefact pieces.
Some of the pieces came
from the 70's,
from the first years of excavation.
They were really small pieces,
which you can see in this picture.
The tiny ivory pieces remained
unexplained for three decades.
31 pieces had a
very significant look.
We found pieces with
a part of the finger holes
and with notches on the side.
I thought that these pieces
could be part of an ivory flute.
An important question was
how the flute was made.
You can see, on the long axis,
a split running along the flute.
Inside the two halfs,
they'd hollowed out the flute.
These little notches along the axis,
along this split,
helped to refit the two halves
together very precisely.
This flute is only one of eight
recovered from SW Germany.
The caves here have no paintings,
but yield many other
objects of art.
In this cave,
the Geissenklösterle Cave,
many important findings
from the Ice Age were made.
We found small ivory statues
of bears and mammoths.
Very tiny mammoths,
very lovely.
In 1992, I was part of
the excavation team.
People lived here
30-40,000 years back in time.
At that time,
it was very cold here,
because the Alp Mountains
were covered by a glacier
about 2500 metres thick.
In the valley down there,
raindeer and mammoths roamed.
It was very cold.
That's why I'm dressed up
like an Inuit.
We presume that Ice Age
people were clothed this way.
In raindeer fur, and in
boots made of raindeer fur
and raindeer leather.
Otherwise you couldn't
stand the cold.
One of the most important finds
we made in this cave
was a tiny flute made
out of the radius of a vulture.
An astonishing fact is
that it's pentatonic.
The same tonality
we're used to hearing today.
If you like, I'll try to
play a tune for you.
I reconstructed the instrument,
tried to play some tunes
and came across this one.
Sounds a bit like
Stars Bangled Banner.
Back in France,
near Chauvet Cave,
explorers using more
primal techniques
in search of still hidden
underground chambers,
roam the landscape.
Professional cave explorers
have techniques for finding
underground chambers.
There are air currents, so they use
the back of their hands
or their cheeks,
to feel for a faint draft of air
that may be coming
out of a cave.
I'm trying to do
things differently.
I have the habit of using
my sense of smell in my profession.
I sniff the smells coming from
the interior of the cave.
Here I couldn't smell anything
except the exterior landscape.
Outside you can smell
the earth, the wild thyme,
the ivy...
You can smell a range of things,
but nothing specific
related to a cavern
that's been closed
for thousands of years.
This is my personal technique,
because I design perfumes.
It's a way to experience it
in a different manner.
I have always created perfumes.
I was the president of the
French society of perfumers
for some years.
There are plans to build
a theme park for tourists
with a precise replica of
the cave a few miles from here.
This replica may even contain
a recreation of the odor
of the prehistoric interior.
Evidently, the odor you can smell
right now is quite attenuated.
It's very subtle.
There are not
many emanations,
but our imagination permits us
to try to reconstruct the scene.
The scene with its odors
from 25,000 years ago
with all the animals
that would have been there.
Bears, wolves, perhaps
even rhinoceroses and men.
The presence of their lives,
meaning burnt wood, resins,
the odors of everything
from the natural world
that surrounds this cave.
We can go back
with our imagination.
With his sense of wonder,
the cave transforms
into an enchanted world
of the imaginary
where time and space
lose their meaning.
These crystal formations
take thousands of years to grow.
The artists of the cave
never even saw them,
as many of them only
started to form
after the landslides sealed
the entrance.
In a forbidden recess of the cave,
there's a footprint of an
8-year-old boy
next to the footprint
of a wolf.
Did a hungry wolf
stalk the boy?
Or did they walk together
as friends?
Or were their tracks
made thousand years apart?
We'll never know.
Dwarfed by these large chambers,
illuminated by all
the wandering lights,
sometimes we were overcome
by a strange, irrational sensation.
As if we were disturbing
the palaeolithic people in their work.
It felt like eyes upon us.
This sensation occured
to some of the scientists,
and also the discoverers
of the cave.
It was a relief
to surface again above ground.
Back outside, we asked
Jean Michel Geneste
about hunting techniques
of palaeolithic people.
Millennia before the invention
of bow and arrow.
The original Chauvet Cave people
had a lots of large game.
They hunted everywhere
in France and Europe.
In their settlements we found
a lot of bones
of reindeer, bison, horses,
and sometimes mammoths.
They had developed
very special hunting techniques.
The original spearpoint system
is very ingenious.
It's a spearpoint on a wooden shaft.
The spearpoint is tied
firmly to the shaft.
The system uses a fork
with a piece inside.
So it's very strong.
It was developed and made
to kill bison or horses like that.
It's very aggressive, strong,
and powerful.
This kind of weapon was
thrown not only by hand,
because it wasn't
very effective.
We suspect that in the beginning
of the Upper Palaeolithic
they developed a
spear throwing technique.
At the tip, the spear thrower
is provided with a hook, a tooth.
The elongated handle
gives the spear a lot of power.
It increases precision
and targeting accuracy.
I will show you.
You see the spear
with the flint point.
There must be a small
depression at the back of the spear.
We suspect they sometimes
used feathers to maintain direction.
I will try to show you
how to kill a horse.
His efforts may not look
very convincing,
but this is a powerful weapon.
Spearheads have been found
deeply embedded
in the shoulder blades
of horses and mammoths.
It flies 30 metres
in a straight line.
The palaeolithic men were
better than you, I guess.
It could be difficult for
me to kill a horse with this.
By mid-April, scientific research
has ended for the year.
Now we are allowed
full access to the cave.
But even that is restricted
to a single week, 4 hrs a day.
The famous cave of Lascaux
had to be shut down,
because the breath
of scores of tourists
has caused mould
to grow on the walls.
We enter Chauvet Cave,
aware that this may be
the only and last opportunity
to film inside.
The mystery of the minotaur
and the female began to unfold
when our guides allowed us
to mount a small camera
on the stick with which
we reached out.
The bison seems to embrace
the sex of a naked woman.
Traditional people, and they think,
people of the Palaeolithic,
probably had two concepts that
changed our view of the world.
The concepts of fluidity
and permeability.
Fluidity means that
the categories we have,
man, woman, horse, tree etc.,
can shift.
A tree can speak, a man can get
transformed into an animal,
and the other way around,
given certain circumstances.
The concept of permeability is
that there are no barriers
between the world where we are
and the world of the spirits.
A wall can talk to us,
or accept us, or refuse us.
A shaman can send his spirit
to the world of the supernatural.
Or he can receive visiting
supernatural spirits.
If you put the two
concepts together,
you realize how different
life must have been
from the way we live now.
Humans have been
described in many ways.
For a while, it was homo sapiens
and it still is homo sapiens,
the man who knows.
I don't think it's
a good definition at all.
We don't know,
we don't know much.
I would say
Homo Spiritualis.
The strongest hint
of something spiritual,
some spiritual ceremony
in the cave,
is this bear skull.
It has been placed
dead center on a rock,
resembling an altar.
The staging seems deliberate.
The skull faces
the entrance of the cave.
Around it fragments
of charcoal were found,
potentially used as incense.
What exactly took place here
only the paintings could tell us.
If you want to have
an understanding of it,
you must go out of the cave.
You must start from the cave
and then go outside.
How far outside?
Where would you go?
I would say everywhere...
A look at the different cultures
would be a good way
to better understand
how different cultures
could have coped with rock art.
In Australia, in North America,
or in South Africa.
Aboriginees in Australia,
who lived until recently
almost like Stoneage people.
They used to paint
and create rock art
until the 1970s.
In some places, I think
there still are traditions
of creating rock art.
Of course, it has changed
since the beginning of the century
when they were discovered.
It can show us different ways
of looking at rock art,
that are not our way
of looking at rock art.
Do you have an example?
In Northern Australia in the 1970s,
an ethnographer was in the field
with an Aboriginee
who was his informer.
Once they came to a rock shelter
that contained beautiful paintings,
but they were decaying.
The Aboriginees became sad
when they saw
the paintings decaying.
In that region, there is a tradition
of touching up the paintings.
Time after time.
So, he sat down and started
to touch up the paintings.
The ethnographer asked the question
all Westerners would ask,
"Why are you painting?"
The man answered,
and his answer was troubling,
because he answered,
"I am not painting."
"It's the hand of a spirit
that is actually painting now."
The hand of a spirit?
The man is a part of the spirit.
Do you think the paintings
in Chauvet Cave
were somehow the beginning
of the modern human soul?
What constitutes humanness?
Humanness is the ability
to adapt to the world.
Man needs to adapt to
the landscape and to other beings,
animals and human groups.
And to communicate.
To communicate by inscribing
memories on specific, odd things
like walls, pieces of wood...
An invention made
by the Cromagnon.
How about music?
Yes, songs, mythology, music.
The invention of the
figurative representation
of animals, of man, of things
is a way for humans
to communicate with the future.
A way of evoking the past
and transmitting information
by means better than language.
Signs instead of
oral communication.
This invention still holds
in our world today.
This camera for example.
On the Rhône River is one
of the largest nuclear power plants
in France.
The Chauvet Cave is located
only 20 miles as the crow flies
beyond these hills
in the background.
A surplus of warm water
that was used to cool these reactors
is diverted half a mile away
to create a tropical biosphere.
Warm steam fills
enormous greenhouses.
And the site is expanding.
Crocodiles have been introduced
into this brooding jungle
and warmed by reactor water,
man, do they thrive!
There are already
hundreds of them.
Not surprisingly, albinos swim
and breathe in these waters.
A thought is born
in this surreal environment.
Not long ago,
a few ten thousand years back,
there were glasiers here,
9000 ft thick.
Now a new climate
is steaming and spreading.
Fairly soon these albinos
might reach Chauvet Cave.
Looking at the paintings,
what will they make of them?
Nothing is real.
Nothing is certain.
It is hard to decide
if these creatures are
dividing into their own doppelgänger.
And do they really meet,
or is it just their own imaginary
mirror reflection?
Are we possibly
the crocodiles who look back
into an abyss of time,
when we see the paintings
of Chauvet Cave?
English subtitles by:
SuBVersion