You've planned this
from the beginning.
In one month, you're going
to force the responsibility
of the factory shutdown
on me, right?
Hurry and close down
that distressed factory.
You have no right
to order me around.
Why don't you quit
and find another job?
Or will you rebuild
the factory?
Are you going
to be our coach?
I won't allow you to
play baseball, anymore.
You're going to work.
I'm going to work
you to the ground.
I'll create my own destiny.
What are you doing?
I found it!
Mom thought it was
unusual, and bought it.
How nostalgic.
Is that for the factory chief?
Forget it!
She hates fish...
Does milk go with toast?
She didn't like
your meddling.
All the more reason
I want to do it.
l was a catcher
so it's a habit.
Good morning.
Will you have some toast?
I'm not hungry.
Do you have a fever?
This town makes me
lose my appetite.
She's back.
Good morning.
Why are you
all gathered?
It's our morning exercises.
Forget it. Get to work.
You must participate
or it won't look good.
I don't want to.
Please!
We're all here.
The radio exercises
shall begin!
Breathing exercises...
Arms and legs...
Please join us!
It feels good!
What an
invigorating morning!
Please give us our
morning instructions!
Be prepared. I'm
reorganizing this factory.
As of today, we'll
do things my way.
Let's play ball!
Excuse me...
What is it?
You said you're
reorganizing...
Do as you please, but...
Speak clearly!
You're wasting time.
I'm sorry.
Basically, what are
you going to do?
There's only one of
two reasons for the
operating deficit.
Either internal or external.
It is clearly an
internal cause.
What is that
internal...something?
In other words, the
cause lies internally.
So...?
It's you people.
Are we the cause?
Acknowledging it
won't help!
I've examined the
company's financial
statements and books.
Cost management
does not exist!
It's those difficult
words again...
Productivity and earnings
are low. The cause
is reckless operating costs.
I have a headache.
It's a long-standing system.
It can't be changed
so easily.
I'll change it.
You're only here
for one month.
Don't cause trouble.
It's an inconvenience.
I won't allow complaints.
I've decided.
Why are you
being so obstinate?
You've been acting
strange, since yesterday.
Did the main
office order this?
No, they haven't
no reason why they would.
That's crap!
She's being
obstinate, after all.
Reorganizing...
Is it possible?
We'll begin with
simple matters.
For example, a cut in
wages...the part-timers
I feel sorry for
the old ladies...
Think about yourself.
She said cut in wages
Wages...Us...?
Who's the baseball
team's manager?
I am...I'm the general affairs
manager, so the uniforms
and stuff are my job. That's
why I'm the team manager.
I'll make it easy for you.
Team expenses are
unnecessary. Cut it.
Dissolve the team.
It's not your
decision!
Why must it be dissolved?
That's why productivity
has been declining.
Say it in laymen terms!
Frankly, your work is
poor because you play
baseball all the time!
Now I'm satisfied!
That won't help!
Are you denying
the employees
any recreation?
You have no right!
Poor workers have no
right to claim recreation!
What are we going to do?
We've been doing
what's expected.
I wonder?
It's just that there
isn't much do.
You knew.
The deficit is due to
the employment
of unnecessary staff.
This factory must rearrange
its personnel.
Is someone to be laid off?
Lay off? Dissolving the
baseball team?
Is someone going
to be fired?
Dissolve the team...?
Not play baseball?
If l get fired, there's no job.
Think about baseball.
They are one and the same.
If you get fired, you
can't play baseball.
Damn!
Quiet down!
Let's create a union.
A union?
Let's do it!
You're a paragon
of laborers.
What is the procedure...?
What is the cost?
Let's make a flag.
A spring offensive!
What is the purpose
of a union?
They perform labor-management
negotiations.
I don't understand,
but let's do it.
Please do it, Manager.
Leave everything to me.
She's a very capable
woman. She can't
be treated like mackerel.
No one will be fired and
we'll play baseball...
As long as we don't
go bankrupt.
Pardon me.
Manager, I'll be leaving.
You may stay here.
We're colleagues.
How is the international
telephone circuit service?
We obtained authorization.
We've started sales
to circuit companies
that service Japan
and America.
I'm glad.
I understand you'll
be involved in the
personnel shuffle, Manager Nagamine.
He'll be the head
of this audit office,
as of next week.
Movement is so
troublesome.
I'd like to do it
numerous times...
Of course, only if it's
an advantageous move.
Let me get to the point.
The director wanted me
to recruit top-notched staff.
That's why she's here.
I'll be in charge of
the new Thailand Marine
Product Factory.
I want you to be
my right hand man.
Me?
You'll get busier. This will
be the nucleus
of the company. I believe
it's an advantageous move.
I accept.
Please get Mr. Iwase
a cup of coffee.
As a colleague...
I'd like your opinion.
It's regarding
the dissolution
of a local factory...
Factory Chief!
Please wait one moment.
Are you going home?
It feels like a drama,
walking like this.
Silently walking is
like a love drama.
What do you want!
I want to talk to you.
Don't get personal.
It's not about you.
It's the baseball club.
What's so funny!
Let's have a drink.
We can discuss it here.
Please...please have
a drink with me.
I beg you.
How's this place?
This is all you've got.
Busted!
Please go in.
Welcome, Manager.
The Factory Chief, too?
Your name is
Kubota Nagisa, right?
A single woman
from Tokyo...
The whole town is
talking about you...
I'm thrilled to tears.
Please have a drink.
Please be good to my son.
Son?
She's Naoto's mother.
What a small town.
Is he working hard? Isn't
he playing baseball all day?
Your son's not alone.
I'm totally disgusted!
Shall I fry some fish?
No, thank you very much.
I have some fine fish today.
Mackerel sashimi...
Mackerel?
No! No!  Anyway, we can't.
Please enjoy.
I have sake.
I've made my decision
on the baseball team.
It's being dissolved.
That would be unwise.
Baseball is all they've got.
It's like their lover.
I feel sorry for them.
Please reconsider
it, for their sake.
You like it, too...
I love it.
Think of it as a
lost love, and give it up.
Aren't you concerned
about the personnel
arrangement? That's
higher priority.
That's true, but...
Losing baseball is
a bigger problem...
I'm restructuring in
the next few days!
Please have another drink.
May we have more beer?
I'm serious.
I'm doing it.
You're so stiff.
Let's sing a song.
How about a duet?
I've just decided
on the first lay off.
Who is it?
A karaoke freak with
a disgusting smile.
Me?
Cut out that weird,
disgusting laughter!
What's the status on
the baseball team?
No problem.
Complete breakdown
of negotiations!
You have no right
to say anything about
the baseball team.
Don't speak like that to her.
Be quiet, you old hag.
How dare you
speak to me like that!
You call yourself a mother?
You only know how to
waggle in front of men!
Why did you do that?
Stop nagging!
Say something.
Your woman's crying.
Stop it!
Stop beating him!
That's enough!
Everyone's so selfish.
You're cruel!
Why did you do that?
Fool!
That's a normal
occurrence at his place.
When he was young, his
father was heavily
in debt and disappeared.
Since then a lot of different
men started to hang around.
His mom gives money
to men and gets dumped.
The shop is
deep in debt.
Naoto's repaying the
debts with his salary.
Oh, I'm so sad. I don't
want to hear his story.
I'm only here to work.
I don't care about
his family situation.
That's true, but...
I'm not interested.
It's so boorish.
I agree.
It's Sunday and you're
reading a comic?
There's no baseball
practice and l don't
have any friends.
Go out with the manager.
He's probably
bored at home.
Forget about him.
You can't be picky here.
Play with me, then.
I'm very picky.
What's with you?
I heard you fought
with your mom again.
The manager was hoping
you wouldn't get violent.
He's seriously
worried about you.
Stop mentioning
the manager.
Is someone
going to be fired?
If we lose someone,
we can't play baseball.
What a silly look.
Welcome.
Reservations
under Iwase.
I've been waiting for you.
Please come this way.
Your guest has arrived.
Please enjoy.
What a nice restaurant.
This place is recently
very popular.
Didn't you know?
I haven't been reading
any magazines lately.
Do you like it?
There's no karaoke...
What would you like
to drink?
I'll have the same.
I feel at ease.
The Australian beef is
really having a rough time.
Don't you know?
What happened?
Seiyo Shoji began
a monopoly and
adjusted the market price.
I think the price will rise.
That was your specialty.
What was our
food division doing?
Manager Nagamine
is changing positions,
so they're  busy with
the replacement candidates.
It'll either be Mr. Nakano
from Osaka or Mr. Ichmura
from the textiles division.
I see.
Aren't you getting
any information?
The main office is
making their move.
I'm living in the
country, so...
This is the menu...
I'll have...
I understand.
How about you?
I'll have the same.
Don't pity me.
I haven't given up, yet.
I'm going to do it!
I don't want other people
manipulating my destiny.
What is it?
I was offered a position...
in the audit office.
It's very close to the
Board of Directors.
Really?
I may have to
liquidate your factory.
Are you joining
hands with Nagamine?
No, with advancement.
Thank you for waiting.
Please take your napkin.
Competition at work doesn't
affect our relationship.
I know that, but...right now,
I can't be calm.
Remain calm.
Don't act like an average
woman would.
Why can't I?
What shall I do?
I'll eat it.
Nice pitch.
It has a lot of spirit.
Should we be
playing baseball?
Be quiet! We'll get
out of shape.
One more!
What happened
to the restructuring?
She hasn't said anything.
I guess it's not happening.
I gave it to her straight.
Did you really?
I'm worried.
When the machines
stop at 5 p.m.,
We're having a meeting
Everyone must gather.
This is it.
It's a showdown. So what
if there's a restructuring.
Let's fight.
We'll show her!
Who is that?
Oh, no! She's here.
Is everyone here?
Nobu will be
here soon.
A girl came to see him
from Tokyo, and they're
fighting outside.
Be quiet!
The reason for this meeting
is to have you understand
the situation of this factory,
and to discuss a strategy.
This indicates the amount
of sales necessary to
increase the
company's profit.
The horizontal line indicates
sales and the vertical line
indicates expenses.
Fixed expenses such
as salaries and
depreciation amounts
to approximately
three million yen per month.
The variations in
the expenses
for material
processing is this.
The point where the two
lines meet is the turning point
from a deficit. In other
words this factory
must have 7.5 million yen
in sales to earn profits.
What a bind.
What are you doing?
Is this a quiz?
Be quiet and sit down!
And so...?
Mr. Omori, what is
the monthly sales?
Nowhere near 7.5 million yen.
This factory goes into
further deficit every month.
It's not possible to increase
sales in such a short time.
Let's look at a different
idea. Let's try reducing the
fixed expenses.
Thus sales will be
5 million yen and no deficit.
So...
Reduce salary expense.
It means the
reduction of personnel.
Wait one minute!
You said let's all
think of a strategy.
Yet you've already fired
one of us. That's not fair.
Be responsible for
what you've said.
We're not fools.
Then show me
another strategy!
Come on...
Manager, give it to her...
Isn't there another
reason for the deficit?
If there is, show it to me.
The efficiency of the
non-professionals is poor.
Let's do our best tomorrow.
Let's make a pledge in
front of the factory chief...
How about that?
Idealism in not logical.
Our efficiency level is
poor because we can't
play baseball.
Leave that on
the side for now.
Why! It's important.
The fate of the team hasn't
been clearly explained.
How many people do
you need for baseball?
Nine.
If there are 8 people, it'll
inevitably be dissolved.
Is someone being laid off?
Based on the data the
earnings per employee
is too low. That's due to
the fact that we employ
unnecessary people.
Let's verify the necessity
of each employee.
Seitoro Mikumi
Your title is Quality
Control Manager.
Only I can determine
the quality of of the mackerel.
It's nothing to be proud of.
You're qualified. Is there
anyone else
with that qualification?
You're essential to the
factory. It can't be helped.
It can't be helped.
Genyo Omori
Accounting Manager.
Fire me and you
can take over.
Is there anyone capable
of bookkeeping?
No, they're all
awful at math.
Then, it can't be helped.
You must remain.
Mochizuki Shijimi
You're the Assistant
Factory Chief.
What are your
job specifications?
I'm your subordinate.
I have no need
for a subordinate...
Oh, my...I guess
I'm going to be fired.
Why are you
Assistant Factory Chief?
The past factory
chief decided it.
It's the main
office's request.
Your company
made that decision.
Shijimi's father is
the head fisherman.
You're the daughter
of an influential man.
Your company likes
that kind of human affairs.
What are your merits
as Assistant Factory Chief?
There aren't many...
What about the
demerits for your dismissal?
Terrible! Her father
won't bring the fish.
He favors our
factory during droughts.
She's the only
woman at the factory.
The factory will
lose sex appeal.
In Tokyo, that statement
would be the cause for a sexual
harassment suit.
What is it?
I have business to take
care of. May I go home?
The meeting
hasn't finished.
What is it?
I'm going to see my wife.
His wife is in the
hospital, for many years.
I go to see her everyday.
I'm sorry, but I'm leaving.
Which is more important?
My wife.
Please stay to the end.
I want to talk to you.
Marketing...
I do sales and buying.
Your sales record?
The main office determines
export destinations.
Other than that, the
town's grocers.
Don't you make sales
calls on other stores?
Should I?
Sales is just a title.
That's not true!
Mr. Tsuruki can do sales.
However...Mr. Shioya has
been doing it all this time.
Reorganization begins
with the breaking of tradition
and customs.
Firing him might be difficult.
Why?
His wife's hospitalization
expenses are high.
Private matters are
none of my business.
His wife is ill. We have
to sympathize.
We'll relieve Mr. Tsurugi's
position to Mr. Shioya.
I can do that.
You traitor.
Firing Tsurugi
will be difficult.
Tell her how
important I am.
Tsurugi must organize
the obon festival.
Only I can do it.
Just cancel the festival.
We can't do that! The
town looks toward to it.
If we cancel it,
a riot will occur!
As everything has
been settled,I'm leaving.
Only I can service
the binding machine.
It won't work unless I kick it.
Anyone will do.
Mysteriously, it
has to be Nobu.
If the mark is even
1 mm off, it won't work.
When I kicked it, it moved.
That was a coincidence.
Don't meddle, you dunce!
Just get it serviced.
The manufacturer went
bankrupt 10 years ago.
Buy a new one.
If we had the
money, we would.
Any complaints? I'm the
most necessary person.
You're still here?
Don't cry...
I'm leaving.
Why are you working here?
He's from Thailand
to do research study.
Thailand.
It was the main
office's request.
Are you here because
of the new factory
in Thailand?
You'll be going home soon.
I won't let you leave.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Ishii Takeshi
Operation Control.
What do you do?
I take care of the
part-time old ladies.
Is that all?
Yes.
Is that necessary
to the factory?
I keep them company
during breaks.
He's the only one
that does that.
They like me, too.
They like me the best.
Ms. Takahashi
said I'm cute.
She gives me
rice crackers...
If Takeshi is fired, there
won't be any part-timers.
Maruyama Saburo, you
manage the warehouse.
What do you do?
I stand in front of
the warehouse.
All day long?
That's my job.
Why do you have
to stand there?
Dogs go in sometimes.
The lock is broken.
Buy a new one! It's not as
expensive as a machine!
A key is more than
adequate.
Please don't fire him.
Why?
He's memorized the
whole radio exercises.
You memorize it!
He's been with us
for 30 years.
So?
Haven't you heard of
the seniority system?
What a warm phrase.
That's an obsolete word.
I judge by performance.
That's a cold word.
This is for the sake of
the company's profits.
Sentimentality and
business are separate.
Please...Mr. Maruyama
has 3 little children.
Who can't operate
a machine...
isn't the child of an
influential man...doesn't have
an ill wife...isn't particularly
loved by the part-time
old ladies...and doesn't fall
under the seniority system!
You're an Operations
Manager, too.
What do you do?
I turn an the main
power switch.
Anyone can do that. You
don't have to kick it, right?
There's no need
for 2 people.
I guess.
Do you have any
qualifications?
None.
The factory doesn't
need you.
You shouldn't fire him.
And why not!
The situation with
his mother...
That's irrelevant!
He works and pays
off her debts.
That's enough...
I compromised with the
others but the debts
are his mother's problem!
Why does the company
have to support a woman
who gives money to men!
All right! I quit.
Mr. Hayakawa, you should
settle your disorderly
personal life before
working at a company.
How dare you say that.
The company will not
be responsible for
people with personal
problems.
I don't care what
you say about work,
but I will not forgive you
for insulting a colleague.
Apologize.
Apologize for hitting me.
You're the one who
has to apologize.
We're not machine parts,
we're human beings.
You're not human. You're
lower than a mackerel.
Are you doing that
until morning?
I can't go home. The
factory chief lives there.
I'm going home.
I think you should
apologize.
It's not good to hit
a woman.
Don't lecture me.
That's right.
Naoto, take care of your mother.
She's all you've got.
Butt out.
Was that the first time
you hit a woman?
Let's put that to rest.
I've never been
hit by a man.
If I were, I may fall in love with him.
To be continued
ASANO Atsuko
TAMAKI Koji
SUZUKI Anju
NISHIMURA Masahiko
MURATA Takahito
KONDO Yoshimasa
INOHARA Yasuhiko
HOSOKAWA Shigeki
HORI Masaki
ONO Masahiko
TAKASHIMA Reiko
ASAKA Mayumi
FUJIMORI Shunji
ISHIDA Junichi
Written by:
KIMITSUKA Ryoichi
Theme Song: "Den'en"
Artist: TAMAKI Koji
English subtitles by Nippon Golden Network