What is it? Explain!
Our international telephone circuit project was called off!
What?
We got a call from the Ministry of Posts
and Telecommunications this morning!
We'll have to start all over
again for the authorization!
What does that
have to do with me?
Your manager was called into
an emergency director's meeting.
You met with Hirabayashi Junzaburo
yesterday, right?
So what about it!
That's the problem!
You'll be relieved of your position temporarily.
Please wait...
It's for one month.
When things settle down,
you may return.
I will apologize to Mr. Hirabayashi.
Please allow me to apologize!
There's no need.
It's already
been decided.
Am I being transferred?
To our affiliate company--
A food processing factory.
Where is that
factory located?
l'm looking for a factory.
They went bankrupt
quite a while ago.
Are you all right?
You all seem to be relaxed
and laid back, but
People with that attitude
will be fired in 2 minutes.
Remember that.
Henceforth, at this factory...
Wait one moment!
We have work to do.
It's an important matter.
Let's put some spirit into it!
Is this the important
matter?
Would you like to
play with us?
Let's play baseball.
Section Chief Kubota
will not return
to the main office.
Manager Nagamine said
she'll commit suicide
with that factory.
I see...
What's the matter?
Is it all right for you
to come back?
l can't to stand still.
If I pause, I lose.
Did something happen
over there?
I like it...very much.
What kind of factory is it?
Well...it's like the club room
of a school's physical
education department.
It's filthy and smelly.
Everyone's goofing off.
If I stay there for 3 days,
my brain will rot.
Is it that bad?
Do you know what the
employees do?
They play baseball!
Play baseball?
It's a lineup of fools!
It's a factory that
manufactures
human scum.
Good morning.
May I help you?
I can't stay there forever.
I have work to do here.
There's the Australia ranch
buyout project, too...
Mr. Sakakibara, I want
to see the data.
That project has been
postponed indefinitely.
Why?
You should be well aware
of the circumstances.
When is a good time
to visit Kanto Foods?
Ms. Nogawa, what about the
contract with Daiya Foods
I asked you to process?
Show me the contract.
I made a decision
to cancel it.
Don't do things of
your own accord!
Upon examination of the
contract terms,
we won't make a
big enough profit.
We'll get a contract with
someone else.
Ms. Kubota, we're in the
middle of a meeting...
Is there something else?
Where are my floppy disks?
I'm sorry, I assumed
whatever you left behind
could be disposed of.
Leave this here. I'll be
back in one month.
Mr. Sakakibara, I want
you to send the daily
transaction data to
my computer.
I'll be reviewing them.
Don't misunderstand. I'm
still the Section Chief here!
Throw it away.
What is it?
Why do I have to
manufacture 200 yen
canned good,
when I was producing
annual transactions\of 2 billion yen?
Calm down.
I can't stand to be run over
by that woman.
It's only for a month, and
yet she's acting superior.
Should you be wasting
your time here?
That factory is in
financial trouble.
We may be able to obtain
30 tons of Angus beef
from Brisbane.
The Kansai office...?
They're waiting for our call.
Let's examine the route...
Who's in charge
in Brisbane?
Mr. Tanaka.
She came back
so suddenly.
I told you to look
out for her!
Chief, please
apologize for us.
Why do I have to
apologize?
There's nothing to
apologize for.
The factory can operate
even while we play.
You're right.
Don't you have
something to do?
You get paid for
working, right?
Please approve this.
What is this?
The budget for the
bon dance festival.
Bon dance festival?
We sponsor the annual
event in August.
I'd like to increase the number
of participating shops.
The budget's sort of high.
Is that okay?
We're not friends.
What does she mean?
Speak honorifically to her.
Honorifically...
Scrubbing brush...
We use it to wash
the machines.
Why do you need my
approval for a brush?
It's 100 yen a piece. If I buy
50, they sell it for 99 yen.
I'll be saving 50 yen. I
wanted your opinion
as to whether we
should buy in bulk.
Just buy as many
as you want!
Omuri-san!
Show me the financial
statements.
Financial statements?
Don't make me say it
more than once.
Why?
I want to know about
the factory!
You'll be here only
for one month.
You're wasting your time.
Nothing's wrong
with knowing.
I understand this
factory is dying.
This factory's not dying.
It's dead.
Show it to me.
Just give me the floppy
disk. I have a computer.
Isn't it on a floppy disk?
No one knows
how to use it.
We lost the instructions.
Word processors
are difficult to use.
It's called a computer.
What is it?
You want to know
about the factory?
Please come this way.
Please...
Let me explain. There are
8 different types of cans.
Recently, pocket
cans are popular.
They're manufactured for
single people and
have become the biggest
hit in the canning industry.
Our factory manufactures
sardines and saury.
However, we've been
manufacturing these boiled
mackerels
through the years.
It's seen quite frequently in
Southeast Asia.
Do you want to know more?
You do, right?
I'm not interested.
You want to know.
I hate mackerel!
Your face...
Have you been bitten
by it? It hurts.
I had food poisoning!
It's bringing
back memories...
Factory Chief!
Please listen to
my new product idea.
I have a lot of ideas.
Only if your idea is to
pack the employees of this
factory into a can, and
send them to Southeast Asia.
Factory Chief, would
you like some, too?
We have rice.
We have more than
enough canned food.
I'm eating out.
There aren't any
restaurants around here.
There's a
drive-in restaurant.
Then, I'll go there.
It's 2 kilometers away.
Excuse me...There's
supposed to be
a drive-in restaurant
around here.
Drive-in...Ah!
It's beyond that inn.
Factory Chief!
Leave me alone. I'll walk.
That's not it.
Your belongings
have arrived at the
company housing.
We're here.
Is this the
company housing?
Yes.
Why?
Please come in.
Please use these.
The factory chief is here.
I'm in the wave room.
Be careful. Sometimes the
boards come loose.
Please come this way.
What is this!
Come in.
Who opened my
personal belongings?
Did you open them?
You don't have
to thank me.
Don't touch other
people's things!
You've committed a crime!
He did it out of kindness.
If you're living
here, we're all family.
You've got to be kidding.
I can't live here.
It's a beautiful view.
When you open the window,
you'll know tomorrow's
weather forecast.
I'm not here to do
weather forecasting.
I'll look for an apartment!
Take me to a realtor.
There's no such thing here.
What about a hotel?
We have no tourists.
You have nothing?
Yes, there's nothing here.
If I have to sleep here...
I'll sleep with the crabs
on the seashore!
She's a beauty, but she
throws a straight ball.
I know it's a small place,
but let's try to get along.
Why do I have to
get along with you?
I live here, too.
Why!
It's my home.
Isn't it, Dad!
Yes it is, Seitaro!
What are you doing?
I tried mixing mackerel,
miso and tomato.
It's very complex.
New ideas must
have impact.
Want to try some?
Is the factory chief
staying at your place?
Our place has a contract
for company housing.
I think I need more...
Doesn't it have impact?
It's delicious.
Typhoon 13 is huge,
possessing a lot of power.
At 12:00 p.m., near
the southwest area
of the Izu peninsula...
Typhoon season
is early this year.
Turn off the TV
and come here.
But there's a
typhoon nearby --
If it lands...
I don't care! Turn it off!
Those who underestimate
the typhoon, will pay for it.
Within the past year, there
have been numerous
missed payments
on bank notes.
Look at the bank liabilities...
This factory has
a deficit of nearly
a million yen annually.
I know, I've been doing
the books for 5 years.
How did this happen?
A drop in canned
goods consumption and
the deficiency in our
raw fish inventory.
Have you developed
a plan?
The lack of desire
for canned goods
is a product of the
change of times.
The deficiency in fish is
an environmental problem.
I want a a specific plan.
The change of time and
environmental problems
are uncontrollable...
Get real!
Don't get mad.
I'll only be here for one
month, so it doesn't matter.
To be honest, the
former factory chief
is a failure as a proprietor.
This factory is better
off closing down.
Wait! I'm still talking!
The typhoon is very near!
You're going to
play baseball, right?
If it rains, we can't practice!
Typhoon 13 possesses
enormous power...
As a result, the Kanto region
is experiencing severe rain...
I'll be here only until I find
a more suitable place.
Gen, from the local fishing
group said to give this
to you for dinner tonight.
I'm eating out!
There's nothing.
Leave me alone.
I'll find a place.
Be careful. There's a
typhoon coming...
There is a place...
Why?
Isn't this a convenience
store? You're supposed
to operate 24 Hours!
It's awful over there!
Help us!
Which way...?
Hey Dad! They need
help at the Harbor.
Seitoro. The factory chief
hasn't returned.
Hello.
This is Tokyo Chuo Taxi.
I'd like to request a taxi.
What is your address?
Chiba prefecture,
Kujukurihama...
Please stop joking.
Hideaki. Please come
for me. I can't get a taxi.
Can you hear me?
Hideaki! Please answer...
What else do you know?
I've told you everything.
You're so shocked,
you're speechless.
Your girlfriend is
a sacrificial offering.
I'm not shocked.
Companies do that.
The fault is in those
who get involved.
If I pause...
I lose.
It's the factory chief.
Factory Chief,
are you all right?
Factory Chief!
If I pause, I lose...
Chief! Chief! Chief!
What happened?
Did she die? I'm not
holding a funeral for her!
Don't kill her off!
Shall we take
her clothes off?
Do it!
Won't we be in trouble?
Warm her in a bath!
Did you find the
factory chief!
She's alive.
If I pause...
I lose...
She's been saying the
same thing over and over,
If I pause, I lose...
Dad is heating
the bath right now.
We've had fishing
boat disasters,
but never a
disaster on land.
It's suicidal, going out to
the seashore during a typhoon.
If she got engulfed by
the waves she'd be lost.
We had one like that,
last year. He went fishing...
He was from Tokyo.
The next day he washed up
on the other side of Neboseki.
I went to see him...
You like those
kinds of things...
I was excited. After
all, it's boring here.
If you die at a time
like this, does workmen's
compensation cover?
I don't think it does.
But if you were on your
way home from work,
isn't it all right?
I wonder how much
they'll pay if you die?
Do you want to try?
Leave!
You have no right
to make fun of me!
I graduated from
Keio University
and I'm the Foods Division
section chief at Godai Bussan.
I've had business dealings
with Australia and the U.S.
I've sealed annual
contracts of 20 billion yen...
I'm different from
you people, who
make dinky canned goods!
Don't take me for a fool!
I'm not like you! If you
came to laugh at me,
then leave!
I don't know what you're
angry at, but we didn't
come here to laugh at you.
We're worried about you.
Isn't it natural to come
to the rescue of your
fellow townsperson?
Let's go home.
Have you eaten yet?
During typhoons and field
trips, riceballs are the best!
You're all inconsiderate!
Have some. It's not pretty
but it's good.
What are you doing?
Remember this! I'm not
a member of this town.
Who does she think she is!
Gen, let's go home.
Hello.
It's me.
Hideaki....
I called you earlier.
What? The phone didn't ring.
What is it?
I found out...
The real reason
you were transferred.
I have a meeting to attend.
I only have 5 minutes,
They're making plans
to close down that factory.
Close down?
They're building a
new factory in Thailand.
Costs are lower and profits
higher with overseas factories.
It's the same as your
Australia ranch project.
But there's a reason why
they can't simply close it down.
If they close it down,
it'll upset the fishermen.
They're afraid of retaliation
by the local people.
They intend to convince
the local people that it was
closed due to financial
trouble and dismiss you
to appease them.
Why? That factory was in
trouble before I got there.
They knew that,
and sent you.
In one month, they'll make you
take responsibility and fire you.
The factory
will be shut down.
Everything's already
been planned.
Was it Nagamine's plan?
No, the manager's.
It's rumored that he'll
be promoted to the
auditor's office of
the Board of Directors.
Thank you for finding out.
Are you going to help me?
Don't misunderstand.
l was just an informant.
My five minutes are up.
I'm leaving.
If you were in my
shoes, you would've
done the same.
Of course. I don't want
your problem to
to undermine my
advancement opportunity.
I'm glad you understand.
The announcement of
the new factory will be in
one month. Is everything okay?
Ninth floor.
The elevator is going down.
You've planned this
from the beginning.
In one month, you're going
to force the responsibility
of the factory shut down
on me, right?
Eighth floor.
It's full.
The elevator is going down.
I know you're building
a factory in Thailand.
I'm the person in charge
of that project.
Hurry and close down
that distressed factory.
You have no right
to order me around.
Why don't you quit and
find another job?
I'll accept your resignation.
Or will you rebuild
that factory?
Sixth floor.
Sorry to burden you for
the sake of my advancement.
Are you going
to be our coach?
I won't allow you to play
baseball anymore.
You're going to work.
I'm going to work
you to the ground!
I'll create my own destiny.
To be continued
ASANO Atsuko
TAMAKI Koji
SUZUKI Anju
NISHIMURA Masahiko
MURATA Takahito
KONDO Yoshimasa
INOHARA Yasuhiko
HOSOKAWA Shigeki
HORI Masaki
ONO Masahiko
TAKASHIMA Reiko
FUJIMORI Shunji
ISHIDA Junichi
Written by:
KIMITSUKA Ryoichi
Theme Song: "Den'en"
Artist: TAMAKI Koji
English subtitles by Nippon Golden Network