It's the middle of
the night there, right?
Is this an emergency?
Please face
toward your right.
Fifty tons of Iowa beef.
What about the quality?
How much per kilo?
Please hold your breath.
It sounds like a great offer.
Don't inform the company
yet. I'll call you back.
If you sleep, I'll fire you!
Yamamoto? It's unusual for
you to be at the office
so early in the morning.
So you can
be useful.
Mr. Minamoto from
Chicago just called me
There's a surplus of beef
that was supposed
to be shipped to Canada.
Right. It's 2,000 yen
per kilo. We'll buy it.
I want you to inform
Mr. Shimizu immediately.
It'll all depend on his
client Kanto Foods.
Ouch!
When Minamoto's fax
regarding the
beef's quality is received
tell Mr. Shimizu to take it.
I'll talk to the president
of Kanto Foods.
What? The physical...?
I'm undergoing it right now!
lt's a waste of time, though.
Please go to your
next examination.
Make reservations for a
cargo shipment tonight,
Chicago to Narita.
I want you to negotiate a
favorable freight charge.
This is Kubota
President, how are things?
Forty-five! My, my...
By the way, your supermarket
is running a food fair, right?
We were able to obtain 50 tons of Iowa beef.
Yes, it's 2100 yen per kilo.
I will guarantee the quality.
No, nothing in particular.
Is it a deal?
Thank you very much.
What a fast decision.
That's very promising.
Yes, definitely next week.
Goodbye.
Yamamoto?
The deal is sealed.
There are actually fools who
purchase merchandise sight unseen.
It's a rush.
Wait a minute!
Don't tell the manager yet,
I'll tell him personally.
I closed the deal...
All by myself.
Any complaints? Goodbye.
Please stop your calls.
It's prohibited.
I'm done.
We're not done yet.
You're wasting your time.
There's nothing wrong.
There's a fatty substance
on your liver.
You should change
your diet.
Reduce your meats and
eat more fish products.
I hate fish. I had food
poisoning from mackerel.
Furthermore,
your stress level...
What is stress?
Don't you have
any complaints?
My personal life is fine,
and my work is perfect.
I have no complaints.
Hello, this is Kubota...
Is it going to be the
President's Award again?
What is?
I understand you sealed a
100 million yen deal,
while undergoing
a physical.
You heard already?
It only took a few seconds
to reach the 11th floor.
Rumors have no legs.
I hope the news reached
the president.
I'm envious.
You're doing well.
Nothing's qood about it!
We're doing poorly, so
I have to work extra hard.
Our company services
international telephone circuits.
No matter how
hard I work,
there're  so many
complicated obstacles
like regulations
and authorizations.
Griping is recognized as
lack of competency.
I'm not griping,
I'm bragging.
We're on the verge of
winning over the head of
the Ministry of Posts and
Telecommunications
Within this month, we'll get
the authorization,
thanks to my
great performance.
Oolala! Bravo!
Once we get the authorization,
we're going to mass market
to all the companies.
We have to repay our debt
to the government agency.
Be careful of wiretap
microphones.
They are in the ceiling.
Please be good to
Iwasa of the
Telecommunications Department.
What about tonight...?
I won't be too late.
I'll be waiting at
the apartment.
Sixth Floor...
I'll be waiting while I drink.
Don't fall asleep.
We have something to do.
Welcome back.
How was the physical?
Don't talk to me about
anything else but work.
I'm sorry.
What about our contract
with Kanto Foods?
It's a done deal
The client was elated.
I want you to arrange
for a dinner meeting.
How is your schedule?
I can't attend everything.
Use your discretion.
It doesn't have to be
too expensive.
This is the consignment schedule
and freight budget.
I've already discussed this with
Mr. Minamata in Chicago.
Don't discuss things
without me.
I'll keep an eye out
for the merchandise.
Please take care of it
with Mr. Yamamoto.
I understand.
Don't you dare
make a mistake.
It's a deal that I closed.
You had 5 phone calls.
Get me a cup of coffee.
Right away.
Where's the material
for the meeting?
What about the point at
issue from the last meeting?
Is it easier
to understand?
It's been reduced
to one page.
This should've been done
from the beginning.
I hope today's
presentation goes well.
You're too naive.
That's why you can't
make promising deals.
It's not "I hope it goes well".
I know it will.
Section Chief Kubota will,
make another proposal.
As I've explained over and
over, this is a new market
development plan
for imported beef.
In other words,
we don't buy beef
from ranches overseas.
We'll build our own
ranch overseas and
become self-producing.
If you look at the
materials provided
based on the development
of this strategy
you'll understand that
imported beef
will become even more
economical to purchase.
The prospective ranch to be
purchased is 20,000 acres,
located in the suburb
of Australia's Gold Coast.
If successful, 100 tons
of beef will be exclusively
secured every week.
There's an image that
imported beef is not good.
Will that affect sales?
That was 10 years ago.
Current consumers
aren't concerned with
domestic or imported,
as long as they can eat
an abundance of
cheap meat.
Breeding will be 100
percent, Japanese style.
We'll guarantee the taste.
This way, Sir.
Thank you.
I'm Hirabayashi.
I'm Nagamine, Manager of
the Food Department.
I'm Kubota of
the 3rd Section.
I'm in charge of
beef importation.
A female section chief?
That's very promising.
I didn't call you here for
entertainment purposes.
This is a study session.
I understand thoroughly.
Please have a drink.
No, thank you.
We have a beautiful
snapper tonight.
We'll have that.
Is that all right?
I'm sorry. I don't eat fish.
You hate it?
I've had food poisoning
from mackerel.
This is a special occasion.
I can't eat it.
Please prepare meat
for this young lady.
Thank you.
We'll serve ourselves.
I don't have time,
so I'll get to the point.
A friend of mine from
the Ministry of
Agriculture and Forestry
informed me...
You intend to buy out
a ranch in Australia.
Yes. Well...we're still
formulating the plan.
Is it a consideration?
Yes, it is.
It's my idea.
Terminate it. I promise to
return the favor next time.
Okay. Everything's set.
Please listen
to our proposal.
Stop it. Let's drink
until dinner.
I'd like an explanation...
Don't misunderstand.
I'm not commanding you.
Please understand...I just
asked you to terminate it...
That's all I have to say.
I don't understand.
Ms. Kubota..!
We haven't violated the
law and there aren't
any regulations.
We're appeasing the needs
of the consumers by
providing them with
cheap, abundant, imported
beef at a very low cost...
Yes...Mr. Hirabayashi is
currently in a meeting...
Let me be frank then.
The ranch in my hometown
is worried. The cheap beef
which you import,
has created a low demand
for domestic beef.
Please don'tl torment them.
I pity the people
of my hometown.
That's the way it is.
I understand
We will re-evaluate...
Pity is illogical. I want
hard data that proves
their financial distress.
Politics cannot
be run by logic.
Our job is to save
pitiful people.
Our work has
no compassion.
Compassion is the
protest of weak people.
We don't have to
tend to them.
That's enough, Ms. Kubota.
I don't mind. However,
you can't ignore your fellow
Japanese citizen,
who is suffering.
Domestic tunnel vision is
adequate for you, but
we look at Japanese
economy on an
international level.
Historically speaking,
there are times when
the needs of the mass
outweigh the
needs of the few...
Will you please turn that off!
Mr. Hirabayashi has an
emergency phone call.
This is important
to me too!
It's irritating.
Please turn it off.
I'll call you back.
Ms Kubota, right?
Do you hate telephones?
You hate telephones. I see.
What were your intentions?
It would have been favorable
for him to be happy.
I was in a cold sweat.
He agreed,
after we explained.
You're too simple-minded.
Politicians live
purely on honor.
It's because of politicians
like him that prevent
the consumers from
purchasing cheap,
fine quality items.
That's not the point.
You couldn't say it,
so I said it for you.
Stop acting so tough!
Good work.
Baseball results
won't help your job.
Change the channel!
What's amusing about
an adult swinging a bat?
Aren't you interested
in the sudden drop
of the New York
Stock Exchange?
What's bothering you?
I'm excited. My great success
will be exhibited tomorrow.
Your protect's
materializing already?
Cheers!
No way.
I'm not so naive
as to celebrate
someone else's victory.
I cornered a politician.
He'll soon admit that I was right
and there was no
reason to refute.
I'm taking a shower.
Open a bottle of wine.
I don't have much time.
I'm going to work, first thing.
Do you understand?
If you pause, you lose.
What is it?
You're right.
There's no reason to refute.
I'm exhausted.
Griping is considered as
a lack of competency.
I don't care,
if it's in front of you
You never know when
I'll be your enemy.
Good morning!
Mr. Iwasa!
Something terrible...!
Good morning!
The project is being
materialized!
Don't be a fool.
Nothing's been decided upon.
The emergency meeting
started at 8 am.
Really?
They're voting
on your project.
This early in the morning?
The Manager's in the
Director's office too.
It's definite.
Even that slowpoke
is in early.
What in the world
did you do?
What is it? Explain!
Our international telephone circuit project was called off!
What?
We got a call from the Ministry of Posts
and Telecommunications this morning!
We'll have to start all over
again for the authorization!
What does that
have to do with me?
Your manager was called into
an emergency directors' meeting.
You met with Hirabayashi Junzaburo
yesterday, right?
So what about it!
That's the problem!
What's going on?
It's turned into an
extremely messy situation.
Tell me.
Hirabayashi Junzaburo
got angry at your attitude.
And...?
You owe me one.
I understand.
Tell me.
Hirabayashi is an
agricultural representative
but until the last election,
he was a member
of the Telecommunications
Review  Board.
He has power with the
Ministry of Posts and
Telecommunications.
He placed a lot of pressure
in retaliation against you.
It doesn't concern the
Telecommunications Department.
It's the same company
He retaliated.
We have a 2 billion yen
debt for this project.
if we don't get the
authorization,
it's the end.
It wasn't smart to
anger Hirabayashi.
Mr. Hirabayashi is in a
meeting. Please leave
I apologize for my
subordinate's rudeness.
I don't know how
to apologize.
Please forgive us.
This is our company's
proposal, in formal apology.
First, we will double last
year's political contribution
to your party. Second,
our company will sponsor
your financial seminars
5 time in the next year.
Women are no good.
They're emotional animals.
I'll allow the authorization of
your international telephone
circuit. I intend to
keep my relationship
with your company.
I will severely
caution my subordinate.
If my daughter spoke to
an older man like that
I would spank her in the
rear and kick her out.
That's what l would do.
That's the end.
Please move forward with the
international telephone
circuit project.
Thank you very much.
Mr. Nagamine...
Regarding Ms. Kubota...
Is this all right?
I believe that's appropriate.
Do you agree?
If the Director agrees...
Let's go with this.
In this regarding
Section Chief Kubota
of the Foods Division?
We've decided to
terminate her.
Are you dissatisfied with
a sacrifice for your sake?
It can't be helped.
Please pardon my intrusion.
We'll leave.
Sit down.
Is this regarding
yesterday's incident?
I represented the
company and apologized.
Won't you listen to me?
You'll be removed
from your position,
for a period of time.
Please wait...
I the recognize the
fault on my part...
It's for one month.
When things settle down,
you can return.
But Manager...!
My department needs me...!
Don't worry.
I'll find a replacement.
I will apologize to
Mr. Hirabayashi.
Please allow me
to apologize!
There's no need.
The decision is made.
Thank you.
You may leave.
Director...
Please listen,
one more time.
I cannot leave
my department
for one month.
I have many projects
that are in
process right now.
Please look at this!
I promise to
make it a success.
Please look at this, too.
This is how much
I've improved on the
company's profits since
my employment.
A lot of projects
have been successful and...
It's all written here...!
My performance had climbed
higher than any other manager
of the same rank.
The food department
needs me!
I've already devised a
reform plan for the
organization, when I
become manager!
I want to centralize
all 4 departments...!
Open your eyes!
The first few hours this
morning were critical
to the existence
of the company!
Even my position!
I am the interim section
chief for the Third Section,
I will be taking over all
the current work-in-process
projects and any other
current matters.
When I return, I'll worki
ten times harder.
I'm not throwing away my
life because of this.
If you pause you lose.
That's right.
That's what I've decided.
My work is my life.
Is it a transfer?
It's our affiliate
food product factory.
The head of the factory
retired and we have
an opening. You'll work
there for one month.
Where is that
factory located?
We'll momentarily
be arriving at
Kujukunhama Kominato.
I'm looking for a factory.
Factory?
It's here somewhere.
They went bankrupt
a long time ago.
That's impossible.
It used to be down
that small lane.
You're wasting
your time.
I'm not buying
any insurance.
My name is Kubota Nagisa
Leave your pamphlet
and I'll look at it later.
Ms. Kubota...? Are you
from Godai Bussan?
Yes.
She's our new
factory chief.
Over there...
Do I look like an
insurance salesperson?
Only insurance sales people
are dressed like you
in the countryside.
I'll take note of that.
Where are the
other employees?
They're around...
Somewhere...
She's our new factory chief.
You're an employee?
I guess.
She's the assistant chief,
Mochizuki Shijimi.
Apparently, that's what I am.
I'm not thrilled.
I just do miscellaneous chores.
You were goofing off
during working hours?
The weather was nice.
It's a wonderful feeling,
reading on the seashore.
Aren't you supposed
to be working!
Am I being reprimanded?
The binding machine
is causing problems.
Don't tell us every little
problem! Nobu's there!
He won't wake up!
He was out playing
all night in Tokyo.
Kick it. Kick it,
and it'll work.
I'll try it.
Please take our factory chief
on a a tour of the factory...
Yes, I will.
What are you producing?
Canned mackerel.
Mackerel?
It's a fish.
I know that!
Why don't you go ahead?
Who do you think
you're speaking to?
Watch your behavior.
We're already her servants.
I'm pleased to meet you.
My name is Ishii Takeshi.
Is he an employee too?
Yes.
You're all very unique.
Yes. They're all good people.
I'm being sarcastic.
Please go in.
Please come this way.
This is the canning process.
I'll start from
the beginning.
I will explain the
work process.
First, they cut up
the mackerel.
Are you all right?
Fish...
I hate them.
Are you all right?
Don't shake me!
What's the matter?
The new factory chief...
Is she here?
Why are you hugging her?
You're mistaken!
She got ill.
Really? Are you all right?
Are you all right?
You hate fish.
You came to a
a terrible place.
We only deal with fish here.
If you take fish out of
this town, there's nothing.
What shall we do?
Don't get friendly with me.
Gather all the employees.
This is your podium.
Please use it.
I'm a transferee from
the main office.
My name is Kubota Nagisa.
It'll only be for one month,
but it's been determined
that I'll be working here.
You all seem to be relaxed
and laid back, but...
People with that attitude
will be fired in 2 minutes.
Remember that.
Henceforth, at this factory...
Wait one moment!
I haven't finished!
Get back here!
We have work to do.
It's an important matter.
Let's put some spirit into it!
The game is just
around the corner!
Let's get a win!
Is this the important matter?
Would you like to play, too?
Let's play baseball.
It'll cost you 50,000 or
60,000 yen to Tokyo.
I don't care. Just hurry.
I want to get out of here.
Section Chief Kubota
will never be able to
return to the main office.
Manager Nagamine said
she'll commit suicide
with that factory.
I see...
ASANO Atsuko
TAMAKI Koji
SUZUKI Anju
NISHIMURA Masahiko
MURATA Takahito
KONDO Yoshimasa
INOHARA Yasuhiko
HOSOKAWA Shigeki
HORI Masaki
ONO Masahiko
TAKASHIMA Reiko
FUJIMORI Shunji
ISHIDA Junichi
Written by:
KIMITSUKA Ryoichi
Theme Song: "Den'en"
Artist: TAMAKI Koji
English subtitles by Nippon Golden Network