SAGAN: Imagine that we are travelers
from the stars...
...bound for the sun.
We would discover it surrounded by
four giant, cloudy, gas worlds:
Blue Neptune and its
frozen moon, Triton.
And then farther in, Uranus
and its dark rings...
...made perhaps of organic matter.
Saturn, the jewel
of the solar system...
...set within concentric rings...
...composed of a billion icy moons.
And finally, flanked by massive
satellites...
...the largest planet, Jupiter.
Its multicolored clouds...
...studded with flashes of lightning.
Still farther in...
...closer to the sun...
...there are no more
giant planets...
...only a host of lesser worlds...
...made of rock and metal...
...some with a thin envelope of air.
They huddle about the sun...
...with almost no internal heat of
their own...
...tiny places with solid surfaces...
...one of which is a blue
and pretty world...
...called Earth.
Half-covered with clouds...
...it is the home planet
of travelers...
...who have just learned to sail
the sea of space...
...to investigate close-up...
...Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus and
Neptune...
...its brothers and sisters
in the family of the sun.
Human voyages of exploration
to the outer solar system...
...are controlled, so far, from a
single place on the planet Earth...
...the Jet Propulsion Laboratory...
...of the National Aeronautics and
Space Administration...
...in Pasadena, California.
Here on Sunday, July 8th, 1979...
...the Voyager 2 spacecraft...
...began its close passage
by Jupiter and its moons.
General science systems...
JPL MAN:
...are you ready with status check?
Yes, I am.
SAGAN:
The spacecraft had been instructed...
...how to explore
the Jupiter system...
...by a sequence of commands
radioed earlier...
...to its onboard computers.
Power, 450 watts.
Power is go at this time.
DSE systems.
LACP mode is far and counter.
We are at take 21 0.
Direction last recorded was reversed,
and the track is track one.
Here we check how faithful
an emissary Voyager is.
Does it understand the commands?
How is its health, its temperature...
...its brains...
...its heart?
Yes, detailed science is coming up...
"A" systems...
...completed the status check...
...and the spacecraft is go.
Roger. Thank you.
SAGAN: The modern ships that sail to
the planets are unmanned.
They are beautifully constructed...
...semi-intelligent robots.
Voyager's eyes are
two television cameras...
...designed to take many thousands
of pictures in the solar system.
Along with other instruments, they are
mounted on a scan platform...
...which points at passing planets.
Voyager's brains are three integrated
computers set amidships.
It communicates with Earth
through a radio antenna...
...mounted like a sail.
Voyager bears a message
for any alien civilization...
...it may one day encounter
in interstellar space.
Its louvers open and shut to help
control the onboard temperature.
But Voyager cruises
so far from the sun...
...that it cannot depend
on solar power.
Instead, it has a small
nuclear power plant...
...quarantined from the rest
of the ship.
Many things can go wrong
in such pioneering missions.
So people are a little uneasy...
...at Voyager mission control.
Jupiter is surrounded by a shell of
invisible but extremely dangerous...
...high-energy charged particles.
If Voyager flies too close...
...its delicate electronics
will be fried.
A collision with a small boulder
in the rings of Jupiter...
...could send the spacecraft tumbling
wildly out of control...
...its antenna unable to find
the Earth, its data lost forever.
Voyager 1 and Voyager 2...
...were launched a month apart
in late summer of 1977.
After many alarms and close calls...
...they successfully arrived months
apart at the Jupiter system...
...where they worked brilliantly...
...providing the first close-up views
of mighty Jupiter...
...and its four large
and mysterious moons:
Io, the innermost of the four...
...Europa...
...and moving away from Jupiter...
...Ganymede...
...and the outermost big moon...
...Callisto.
In a mission that costs
a penny a world...
...for every human
on the planet Earth.
Voyager's passage by Jupiter...
...accelerated it towards
the planet Saturn.
Saturn's gravity will
propel it on to Uranus...
...and in this game of cosmic
billiards, after Uranus...
...it will plunge on past Neptune,
leaving the solar system...
...and becoming
an interstellar spacecraft...
...destined to wander forever...
...the great ocean between the stars.
And if Voyager should,
sometime in its distant future...
...encounter beings from
some other civilization in space...
...it bears a message.
A phonograph record.
Golden, delicate...
...with instruction for use.
And on this record are a sampling of
pictures, sounds, greetings...
...and an hour and a half
of exquisite music...
...the Earth's greatest hits.
A gift across the cosmic ocean...
...from one island of civilization
to another.
The record bears in English...
...an additional handwritten
greeting that says:
"To the makers of music,
all worlds, all times."
These voyages of exploration
and discovery...
...are the latest in a long series
which have characterized...
...and distinguished
the human species.
In the 1 5th and 16th centuries...
...you could travel from Spain
to the Azores in a few days.
The same time it takes now
to cross that little channel...
...from the Earth to the moon.
It took, then, a few months
to traverse the Atlantic Ocean...
...and reach what was called
the "New World"...
...the Americas.
Today it takes a few months
to cross the inner solar system...
...and reach Mars and Venus,
truly and literally...
...new worlds awaiting us.
In the 1 7th and 18th centuries...
...you could travel from Holland
to China, say, in a year or two...
...the same time
it takes now for Voyager...
...to travel from the Earth
to Jupiter.
And in comparison to the resources
of the society...
...it cost more then to send
sailing ships to the Far East...
...than it does now
to send spaceships to the planets.
The passion to explore...
...is at the heart of being human.
This impulse to go,
to see, to know...
...has found expression
in every culture.
Africa was circumnavigated
by Phoenician sailors...
...in the employ
of an Egyptian pharaoh...
...in the 7th century B.C.
The islands of the Pacific
were settled...
...by skilled and heroic navigators
from Indonesia.
Great fleets of ocean-going junks...
...left the ports
of Ming Dynasty China...
...to explore India and Africa.
A century later,
three ships left Spain...
...under the command
of an Italian navigator...
...to discover the Americas.
And then a Portuguese
expedition succeeded...
...in sailing all the way
around this blue globe.
These voyagers of many cultures...
...were the first planetary explorers.
They have bound the Earth up
into one world.
In our exploration
of other worlds...
...we follow in their footsteps.
Our present spaceships
are the harbingers...
...the vanguard of future human
expeditions to the planets.
We have traveled this way before...
...and there is much to be learned...
...by studying those great voyages of
a few centuries ago.
In the 1 7th century...
...the citizens of the new Dutch
Republic...
...pursued a course of vigorous
planetary exploration.
Holland was then
a revolutionary society.
It had just declared its
independence from the powerful...
...but stagnant Spanish empire...
...and with a newfound
self-confidence...
...Holland embraced, more fully than
any other nation of its time...
...the spirit of the European
Enlightenment.
It was a rational, orderly
and creative society.
But because Spanish ports and vessels
were closed to the Dutch...
...the economic survival
of the tiny republic...
...depended on its ability to
construct, man and operate...
...a great fleet of commercial
sailing vessels.
The Dutch East India Company...
...was a combined governmental
and commercial enterprise...
...which sent shipping
to the far corners of the world...
...to acquire rare commodities and
resell them at a profit in Europe.
Such voyages were the life's blood
of the republic.
Navigational charts and maps
were classified as state secrets.
Ships sometimes left
with sealed sailing orders...
...the crews embarking
for an unknown destination...
...more than a year away
on the far side of the planet.
These expeditions were not only
commercial exploitations...
...although there was certainly
plenty of that.
Beside the usual appeals
of ambition, greed...
...national pride
and the thirst for adventure...
...the Dutch were also motivated
by a powerful scientific curiosity...
...and a fascination with
all things new.
New lands, new peoples...
...new plants and animals.
This building,
then the Amsterdam town hall...
...still attests
to the hardy self-assurance...
...of its 1 7th-century architects.
Its lavish crystal adornments
still reflect...
...the glittering pride they felt
in their accomplishments...
...and their prosperity.
It took shiploads of marble
to build this place.
Constantin Huygens, a poet
and diplomat of the time...
...said that this town hall
dispelled what he called...
..."the Gothic squint and squalor."
The Middle Ages had ended,
the Enlightenment had begun.
Up there, do you see...
...is Atlas supporting the heavens
on his shoulders.
And beneath...
...is Justice with a golden sword...
...and golden scales flanked...
...by Death and Punishment.
And who is it that Justice
is trampling underfoot?
Why, it's Avarice and Envy...
...the gods of the merchants.
The Dutch knew that the unrestrained
pursuit of profit...
...posed serious threats
to the soul of the nation.
A less allegorical symbol...
...is down here, on the floor.
It is a great inlaid map...
...stretching from West Africa
to the Pacific Ocean.
The whole world was then
Holland's arena.
In a typical year, many sailing
vessels...
...set out halfway around the world
for the Far East...
...on voyages of exploration
and discovery, of trade...
...journeys taking years
to accomplish.
Down the west coast of Africa, through
what they called the Ethiopian sea...
...skirting the southern coast
of Africa...
...through the Straits
of Madagascar...
...and on past the southern tip
of India...
...to the Spice Islands
and present-day Indonesia.
Another set of voyages went south
then east, to New Holland...
...later renamed Australia.
And still other journeys ventured
through the Straits of Malacca...
...to the Empire of China.
But Holland was a small country
forced to live by its wits.
There was a strong pacifist element
in its foreign policy.
Never before or since
has Holland boasted such a galaxy...
...of scientists, mathematicians,
philosophers and artists.
This was the time of the great
painters, Rembrandt...
...and Vermeer.
Because Holland was tolerant
of unorthodox opinions...
...it was a refuge
for intellectuals...
...fleeing the thought control and
censorship of other parts of Europe...
...much as the United States benefited
enormously in the 1 930s...
...from the exodus of intellectuals...
...from Nazi-dominated Europe.
And so it was that
17th-century Holland...
...was the home of the great
Jewish philosopher Spinoza...
...who Einstein admired so much...
...of Ren? Descartes,
a pivotal figure...
...in the history of philosophy
and of mathematics...
...and the home of a political
scientist named John Locke...
...who was to have a powerful...
...and profound influence...
...on a group of philosophically
inclined revolutionaries...
...named Paine, Hamilton, Adams...
...Franklin and Jefferson.
The Dutch University of Leyden...
...offered a professorship to an
Italian scientist named Galileo...
...who had been forced
by the Catholic Church...
...under threat of torture...
...to recant the heretical position...
...that the Earth went around the sun
and not vice versa.
Galileo had close ties
with Holland.
His first astronomical telescope
was based...
...on a spyglass
of Dutch manufacture.
And with it, he discovered
the craters of the moon...
...the phases of Venus and the
four large moons of Jupiter.
Becoming an exploratory power...
...made Holland a vital intellectual
and cultural center as well.
The improvement of sailing technology
spurred technology in general.
A key problem in navigation was
the determination of longitude.
Latitude could be determined
easily...
...the farther south, the more
southern constellations you could see.
But longitude required precise
timekeeping.
An accurate shipboard clock...
...would continue to keep time
in your home port.
The rising and setting of stars
would give you the local time...
...and the difference
between the two...
...would tell you how far
east or west you had gone.
Technological advance
required the freest...
...possible pursuit of knowledge.
So Holland became the leading
publisher and bookseller in Europe...
...translating works written
in other languages...
...and printing books
that had been censored elsewhere.
Adventures into exotic lands...
...and encounters
with strange societies...
...shook complacency.
They challenged
the prevailing wisdom...
...and showed that ideas accepted
for thousands of years...
...might be fundamentally in error.
In a time when kings and emperors
ruled much of the planet...
...the Dutch Republic was governed,
more than any other world power...
...by the people.
They enjoyed a certain
material well-being.
But the interiors of their houses...
...celebrated by a generation
of Dutch painters...
...suggest restraint and discretion.
The officers of these ships
of exploration and trade...
...would return from their long
voyages...
...share in the goods
they had acquired...
...and discuss the wonders
they had encountered.
Holland prospered
in its freedom of thought.
In Italy, Galileo
had announced other worlds.
Giordano Bruno had speculated
on intelligent life elsewhere.
For this they were
made to suffer brutally.
But in Holland, the astronomer
Christiaan Huygens...
...who strongly supported both ideas,
was showered with honors.
Christiaan was the son
of Constantin Huygens.
The elder Huygens
distinguished himself...
...as a master diplomat of the age,
a man of letters...
...a close friend and translator
of the English poet, John Donne.
Constantin was also an accomplished
composer and musician.
It was Constantin who had discovered
a young painter...
...named Rembrandt van Rijn...
...in several of whose works
he subsequently appears.
He opened the doors of his house...
...to artists, musicians, writers...
...statesmen and scientists.
A feast of goods and ideas...
...from all over the world
awaited them.
The philosopher Descartes,
who visited him here...
...said of Constantin Huygens...
..."I could not believe
that a single mind...
...could occupy itself
with so many things...
...and acquit itself so well
in all of them."
He even excelled
at the art of parenthood.
He was a tender and loving father.
His son, Christiaan, flourished
in this rich environment...
...demonstrating extraordinary talents
for languages, drawing...
...law, science, engineering
mathematics and music.
"The world is my country," he said...
..."science my religion."
Light was the motif of the age...
...the symbolic enlightenment of
freedom of thought and religion...
...the light that suffused
the paintings of the time...
...and light as an object
of scientific study.
The microscope was invented in Holland
at this time...
...and became
a drawing-room curiosity.
Its inventor was a friend
of Christiaan Huygens...
...a man named Anton Leeuwenhoek.
The first microscopes
were developed from...
...magnifying glasses
used by drapers...
...to examine the quality of cloth.
Leeuwenhoek and Huygens...
...are the grandfathers of much of
modern medicine.
Because, to his amazement...
...Leeuwenhoek discovered a
universe...
...in a drop of water:
The microbes, which he described
as "animalcules"...
...and thought "cute."
Leeuwenhoek and Huygens...
...were among the first people to see
human sperm cells...
...a hitherto hidden microcosm
of the human life cycle.
Leeuwenhoek had discovered
the microbial world.
Huygens had argued
from his telescopic observations...
...that Mars was another world...
...and probably, an inhabited one.
What a waste of a planet,
he thought...
...if Mars were barren.
So the Viking search
for microbes on Mars...
...can be traced directly back
to Huygens and Leeuwenhoek...
...in 1 7th-century Holland.
The telescope and the microscope
developed here...
...represent an extension
of human vision...
...to the realms of the very small...
...and the very large.
Our observations of atoms
and galaxies...
...were launched
in this time and place.
From the bending of light
through a lens...
...Huygens advanced the idea...
...that light was a kind of wave.
He ground and polished lenses...
...for the successively larger
telescopes he constructed...
...although it did take him
a time to figure out...
...how to use them properly.
Huygens was the first person
to see a surface feature...
...on the planet Mars.
He was the first person
to speculate...
...that Venus is completely
covered with clouds.
He was the first person to understand
the nature of the rings of Saturn.
"Saturn is surrounded," he wrote...
..."by a thin, flat ring...
...which nowhere touches
the body of the planet."
His discoveries with the telescope...
...who by themselves
have ensured his place...
...in the history
of human accomplishment.
Huygens was the discoverer of Titan...
...the largest moon of Saturn.
The immense size and changing clouds
of Jupiter entranced him.
Astronomers, as well as navigators...
...need accurate clocks to time
the movement of the heavens.
Huygens was the inventor
of many precision timepieces...
...including the pendulum clock.
To illustrate the sun-centered
universe of Copernicus...
...he built computers that reproduced
the clockwork of the heavens...
...from Mercury to Saturn.
The machines he designed, he signed...
..."Christiaan Huygens, inventor."
He was delighted that
the Copernican system...
...was widely accepted
in everyday life in Holland...
...and acknowledged by astronomers,
except those, he wrote...
...who "were a bit slow-witted or
under the superstitions...
...imposed by merely human authority.
Across the sea of space...
...the stars...
...are other suns."
A point which Huygens appreciated
perfectly well.
He reasoned that if
our planetary system...
...involved the sun
and planets going around it...
...that those other suns should
likewise have a retinue...
...of planets going around them...
...and also that many of the other
planets were inhabited.
He set forth these conclusions...
...in a remarkable book...
...bearing the triumphant title...
...The Celestial Worlds Discovered.
The subtitle is...
..."Conjectures Concerning...
...the Inhabitants, Plants
and Productions...
...of the Worlds in the Planets."
He wrote this book sometime shortly
before his death...
...in the year 1 690, in this study.
By and large...
...he imagined that the environments
of the other planets...
...and also the inhabitants
...were pretty much like those
of 17th-century Europe.
I wonder if he imagined...
...traveling to those other worlds
which he had been...
...the first to examine close-up...
...through the telescope.
Perhaps he dreamt that voyages
of discovery to the planets...
...would one day be like the
voyages of geographical discovery...
...in his time and place.
He did imagine of
extraterrestrial beings...
..."that their whole bodies,
and every part of them...
...may be quite distinct
and different from ours.
'Its a very ridiculous opinion,"
he says...
..."that it is impossible
a rational soul...
...should dwell in any other shape
than ours."
You could be smart,
Huygens was saying...
...even if you looked funny.
But he then went on to argue...
...that they didn't look
all that funny...
...that extraterrestrial beings
must have...
...hands and feet and stand upright...
...and have writing and geometry.
Even that the four
moons of Jupiter...
...the Galilean satellites,
were there in order to provide...
...a navigational aid,
a convenience...
...for the sailors
in the Jovian oceans.
Well, maybe.
(WOOD CREAKS)
That bit of speculation
is probably wrong, but...
...think of a citizen
of the 1 7th century...
...with the courage and insight...
...to imagine other landscapes
and other intelligences.
Might there really be mariners...
...on a million other worlds?
In his book, Huygens wrote:
"What a wonderful and amazing scheme
have we here...
...of the magnificent vastness
of the universe.
So many suns. So many earths.
And every one of them
stocked with so many animals.
Adorned with so many seas.
How must our wonder and admiration
be increased...
...when we consider the prodigious
distance and multitude...
...of the stars?"
The Dutch called their ships
"flying boats"...
...and the Voyager spacecraft
are their descendants...
...true flying boats...
...bound for the stars,
and on the way...
...exploring some of those worlds
which Christiaan Huygens...
...a man from Earth...
...knew and loved so well.
Travelers' tales:
A main commodity...
...returned by those sailing ship
voyages of centuries ago...
...were stories.
Stories of alien lands
and exotic creatures.
They evoked a sense of wonder
and stimulated further exploration.
Those tales of strange worlds...
...enabled some Europeans
to see themselves anew.
There had been accounts
of headless people, foot people...
...cyclops people.
Now the Dutch brought back
fantastic stories...
...of giant hunters...
...dodoes...
...rhinos...
...leopards...
...and other creatures.
Modern voyagers
also return travelers' tales:
Tales of a world shattered
like a crystal sphere.
A place where the ground is covered...
...with what looks like
a network of giant cobwebs.
A world with an underground ocean.
Tiny moons shaped like potatoes.
A yellow and red pockmarked land...
...with lakes of molten sulfur...
...and volcanic eruptions
300 kilometers high.
And a place called Jupiter...
...so large that a thousand Earths
would fit inside.
There are no mountains, valleys,
volcanoes or rivers there.
Just a vast ocean of gas and clouds.
Everything we see on Jupiter
is floating in the sky.
But there's much that is fascinating
about Jupiter.
As the solar system condensed
out of interstellar gas and dust...
...Jupiter acquired most of the matter
not ejected into interstellar space...
...and which didn't fall inwards
to form the sun.
Jupiter is made mostly of hydrogen
and helium, just like the sun...
...and had Jupiter been a few dozen
times more massive...
...the matter in it...
...might have undergone thermonuclear
reactions in the interior...
...and Jupiter would have begun
to shine by its own light.
Jupiter is a star that failed.
Had it become a star...
...we would be living
in a double-star system...
...with two suns in our sky...
...and the nights
would come more rarely.
Deep below the clouds of Jupiter, the
weights of the layers of atmosphere...
...produce pressures
which are much greater...
...than any that are found
anywhere on the Earth.
The clouds are this layer here.
The deep interior
is this high-pressure place.
The pressure is so large...
...that electrons are squeezed off
hydrogen atoms, producing...
...liquid metallic hydrogen.
But at the very core of Jupiter,
there may be a lump...
...of rock and iron...
...a giant Earth-like world
under astonishing pressures...
...hidden forever at the center
of the largest planet.
Just before Voyager...
...encountered Jupiter, you could see
that giant planet at night...
...shining in the sky as our ancestors
have for the last million years.
And on my way to study
the Voyager data...
...arriving at the
Jet Propulsion Laboratory...
...I thought that Jupiter
would never be the same again.
Never again just a point of light
in the night sky...
...but forever after, a place
to be explored and known.
To see the first close-up images
of a world never before known...
...is a great joy in the life
of a planetary scientist.
In the early morning hours of
July 9th, 1979, on the real-time...
...television monitors at the Jet
Propulsion Laboratory...
...we began to learn
about a world called Europa.
These are the modern explorers.
Men and women trained...
...in astronomy, physics,
geology or engineering.
Many devoting five to eight years
to this single mission.
JPL MAN: Cassen's model for Europa
says if you start with a liquid...
...you can put in enough energy
to keep it liquid.
But Cassen said in order for there
to be enough heating going on...
...you had to start the heating
before Europa basically cooled off.
But what about relief
from the cracks?
...and Europa there's a twin,
a pair there...
You can't look at a world
so different from ours...
...without wondering
how both were made.
Just rotate it out a little bit.
Voyager presented us with six new
worlds in the Jupiter system alone.
The more you learn about other worlds,
the better you understand our own.
We speculate, criticize, argue,
calculate, reflect and wonder.
We return again to the astonishing
data, and slowly...
...we begin to understand.
The Dutch sailing ships brought back
rare and valuable commodities...
...from the new worlds they visited.
Our Voyager spaceships...
...return rare and valuable
information...
...to computerized wharves on this
shore of the sea of space.
Here the data are stored,
enhanced, processed and treasured.
Maps of alien lands will be generated
from this information.
In this electric warehouse
are tens of thousands of images...
...of previously unknown worlds.
How does a picture from
the outer solar system get to us?
Sunlight shines on Europa,
and is reflected back to space...
...where some strikes the phosphors...
...of the Voyager television cameras,
generating an image.
The image is radioed back
across the immense distance...
...of half a billion kilometers...
...to a radio telescope on Earth.
One in Australia, say.
The telescope then passes
the information...
...via communications satellite
in Earth orbit...
...to Southern California.
There, it's transmitted
by a set of microwave relay towers...
...to a computer
at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory...
...and there it is processed.
The picture is like
a newspaper wire photo...
...made of a million individual dots
of differing shades of gray...
...so fine and close together
that at a distance...
...the constituent dots
are invisible.
We see only
their cumulative effect.
The information specifies
how bright or dark...
...each dot is to be.
After processing, the dots
are stored on a magnetic disk...
...something like a phonograph record.
By this day, there were already 1 1,000
pictures from Voyager 2 in our...
...electronic library.
Finally, the end product
of this remarkable set...
...of links and relays...
...is a hard copy which comes
out of this machine showing...
...in this case,
the wonders of Europa...
...which were recorded for the first
time in human history, today.
It is absolutely astonishing.
Voyager 1 got very good pictures
of the other three big moons...
...Galilean satellites of Jupiter,
but not of Europa.
It was left to Voyager 2 today...
...to get the first
close-up pictures of Europa...
...where we see things that are only
a few kilometers across.
At first glance, it looks like
nothing so much as...
...the canal network of Mars that
Lowell imagined existed on that planet.
We see an amazing, intricate network
of crisscrossing...
...straight and curved lines.
Are these straight lines ridges?
Are they troughs?
Is it connected with plate tectonics
on the Earth?
How does it illuminate the other
satellites of the Jovian system?
At this moment,
the vaunted technology...
...has produced something
astonishing.
But it remains for...
...the limitations and cleverness
of another device...
...the human brain, to figure it out.
Fortunately, we have plenty
of pictures to help us.
What about Gene's idea of geysers
down the troughs?
Geysers down the troughs?
LARR Y SODERBLOM:
You need a mechanism to drive it.
SAGAN:
Larry Soderblom, Voyager imaging team.
LARR Y: An idea was proposed a while
ago that we might have a sort of...
...champagne-bottle model.
And that's...
You seal the crust and have liquid
underneath that solid crust.
Do you have then a condition which
is an explosive effervescence?
SAGAN:
Lonnie Lane, deputy project scientist.
You have enough resolution
in some of these pictures that...
...you don't see anything
spread laterally.
Do we have the high-resolution piece?
-It was right here.
-There it is.
We'll pick out the relief,
and if we're going to see...
...the things we recognize...
SAGAN: Weeks after the pictures
from Europa were received...
...we were still debating
what was in them.
It's as if we almost got to the...
Look at the mesas here.
We almost got the resolution
needed to see the craters.
The craters which would last
indefinitely on a crust this thin.
Apart from the r?seaus...
...there's a set of very fine
small dots, markings...
...mostly in the mottled terrain.
Like those guys. Do you think
those are...
...sites of outgassing, calderas,
fumaroles, solfataras?
I don't know, but I'll tell you
one thing I just found...
Look right here.
It disappeared.
See the central peak?
See the little hole?
I think it's an impact crater.
Look at the central peak.
SAGAN:
There are almost no impact craters.
Wait, we just found one.
Almost none.
Therefore, finding one which is
alleged to be the exception...
...maybe it's not the exception,
but something else.
Perhaps, but you asked about those
little holes that we can't make out.
The big craters go away by some
rheological deformation...
...and the little ones stay
but are out of our resolution.
That's because they're one-tenth
the depth of the rigid crust.
Well, maybe.
SAGAN: Computer processing of
the pictures has revealed...
...a few features on Europa
which seem to be impact craters.
But something...
...has wiped out the big craters.
Computer processing
also played a major role...
...in an amazing Voyager discovery
made on the moon next to Europa...
...a world called lo.
Even from Earth we could tell
that lo had a strange color.
We knew that somehow sulfur
had been removed from its surface...
...and ejected into a great
doughnut of gas orbiting Jupiter.
Then Voyager 1 sailed close to lo.
There were a few places on lo which
looked like the mouths of volcanoes...
...but it was hard to be sure.
Then, Linda Morabito, a member
of the Voyager navigation team...
...used a computer
to enhance the edge of lo...
...in order to bring out
the stars behind.
Four days after the Voyager 1
encounter with Jupiter...
...I was looking at an
optical navigation frame.
In enhancing this particular quadrant,
what became very evident to me...
...was an anomalous crescent...
...in the upper left-hand corner,
just off the limb of lo.
SAGAN:
What was it?
The plume was in exactly
the position...
...of one of the suspected volcanoes.
We realized then that
what we were observing...
...was a volcanic plume and,
in fact, a volcanic eruption.
SAGAN: Voyager had discovered the
first active volcano beyond the Earth.
We then found that lo
has many volcanoes.
There are at least nine
intermittently active plumes...
...and hundreds, maybe thousands,
of extinct ones.
The plumes can eject sulfur
and other atoms off lo altogether...
...and account for the sulfur clouds
surrounding Jupiter.
Rivers of molten sulfur flow down
the sides of the volcanic mountains...
...and are the probable source
of Io's distinctive colors.
The volcanoes may be tapping some vast
underground ocean of liquid sulfur...
...beneath a surface
that is only a few thousand years old.
So far, in our voyages
to the outer solar system...
...we humans have stayed home...
...and sent robots and computers
to explore in our stead.
Someday, perhaps, we'll go ourselves.
But suppose...
...like those Dutch sea captains
of the 1 7th century...
...the computers aboard Voyager
could keep a ship's log.
That log, a combination of the events
of Voyagers 1 and 2...
...might read something like this:
Day 1: After much concern
about provisions and instruments...
...we successfully lift off from
Cape Canaveral on our long journey...
...to the planets and the stars.
Day 13: We have taken the first
photograph of the Earth and moon...
...as worlds together in space.
A pretty pair.
Day 1 70: A problem
in the deployment of the boom...
...that supports
the science scan platform.
If the problem is not solved...
...we will be unable to take
most of our pictures.
Day 207: Boom problem solved, but
failure of main radio transmitter.
If the backup transmitter
also fails...
...no one on Earth
will ever hear from us again.
Day 21 5:
We cross the orbit of Mars...
...and enter the main asteroid belt.
Day 570: We can now make out
finer detail on Jupiter...
...than the largest telescopes
on Earth have ever obtained.
Day 640:
The cloud patterns are distinctive
and gorgeous.
No painter trapped on Earth...
...ever imagined a world
so strange and lovely.
The white clouds are ammonia
crystals, high and cold.
We do not know the nature
of the red-brown clouds.
Maybe phosphorous or sulfur
as a stain.
Perhaps organic molecules of the sort
that led, four billion years ago...
...back on Earth,
to the origin of life.
And what is the great red spot?
(COMPUTER HUMS)
It is an immense swirling column
of gas...
...reaching high above adjacent
clouds.
So large that it could hold
half a dozen Earths.
Its motion hypnotizes us.
Some think that the red spot
is a great spinning storm...
...a million years old.
Day 650: Encounter.
A day of wonders.
The ship maneuvers
so we can take pictures...
...of the multi-ringed basin
on Callisto.
Images of the astonishing
lined surface of Ganymede.
A close passage by Europa.
And, a view of volcanic lo.
We successfully negotiate
the treacherous radiation belts...
...and accomplish
the ring plane crossing.
Looking back, we marvel
at the rings...
...and see the sun emerge
from behind the giant planet.
We are outward bound on our mission
to explore the outer solar system.
Ten thousand years from now...
...Voyager will plunge onward
to the stars.
We have made the ships
that sail the sea of space.
We travel past Jupiter...
...three quarters of a billion
kilometers from the sun...
...Saturn, one and a half billion,
Uranus, three billion...
...and Neptune, four and a half
billion kilometers away.
In our ship of the mind...
...we retrace the itinerary
of the two Voyager spacecraft...
...on their journeys to Saturn
and beyond.
Saturn was first glimpsed
through the telescope by Galileo.
Its rings first understood by Huygens.
But only now do we begin to penetrate
its deeper mysteries.
Saturn is the second largest planet
in the solar system.
Like Jupiter, it is cloud-covered,
and rotates once every 10 hours.
It has a weaker magnetic field,
a weaker radiation belt...
...and a grand, magnificent...
...exquisite system of rings.
The rings are composed of billions
of tiny moons...
...each circling Saturn
in its own orbit.
The biggest gap in the rings
is called the Cassini Division...
...after the colleague of Huygens
who first discovered it.
There are many other gaps...
...each produced by the periodic
gravitational tugs...
...of one of the larger outer moons.
From just beneath the ring plane...
...we see a sky full of moons.
Within the rings,
the individual moons become visible.
They are orbiting chunks
of snow and ice...
...each perhaps a meter across.
In young parts of the ring system,
there hasn't been enough time...
...for collisions to round the edges
of these fragments...
...the snowballs of Saturn.
Far from the rings,
bathed in its red light...
...we encounter Saturn's immense
cloud-covered moon...
...Titan.
It has an atmosphere
denser than that of Mars...
...and a thick layer of red clouds...
...which are probably composed
of complex organic molecules...
...produced by solar ultraviolet light
and other energy sources...
...from the methane-rich air.
No ship from Earth
has ever penetrated those clouds...
...and viewed, close-up,
the surface of this tantalizing world.
It seems likely that the ground
is covered, encrusted...
...with organic molecules
raining from the sky.
There may be volcanoes
and valleys of ice...
...and, just perhaps...
...hiding in the warm places,
some very different kind of life.
Near an ice cliff of Titan...
...through a rare break
in the clouds of organic molecules...
...we can see, looming and lovely,
the ringed planet, Saturn.
It is a view that will still be
appreciated centuries from now...
...by our descendants,
who will know it well.
As well as we have come to know...
...Hudson's Bay and the Barents Sea...
...Indonesia, and Australia
and New York.
They will look back to when Titan was
first seen by Voyager spaceships...
...on their epic journeys
past the giant planets...
...out of the solar system...
...to the great dark
between the stars.
Since Cosmos was first shown...
...Voyager spacecraft have explored
the systems of the planets...
...Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune...
...and have now passed the outermost
planets on their way to the stars.
We inserted the flavor of those
encounters in our captain's log.
But with image processing...
...we've been able to reconstruct
astonishing movies...
...of some of these worlds.
Here, for example, is Jupiter,
with its great red spot.
And volcanic lo, spinning before us.
Icy Enceladus, a tiny moon of Saturn,
on much of which, somehow...
...the craters have melted.
And Miranda, of Uranus.
Austere, blue Neptune.
Or consider Titan,
the giant moon of Saturn.
We've taken the nitrogen and methane
in its atmosphere...
...irradiated it in the lab with
electrons of the sort that are...
...beamed at Titan from
Saturn's magnetic field...
...and we made this stuff...
...which matches, almost perfectly, the
observed properties of the Titan haze.
What is it?
It's a mixture of
complex organic molecules.
You drop some into water and,
among other things, you make...
...amino acids,
the building blocks of proteins.
So the starting materials of life...
...are raining from the skies
of Titan, like manna from heaven.
I can't wait
until the Cassini mission...
...sends an entry probe
through the organic haze of Titan...
...to its enigmatic surface.
The Voyager spacecraft rush on
past the planets and to the stars...
...still returning data.
As it left the planetary part
of the solar system...
...Voyager 1 turned back...
...to take one last portrait
of the planets of the solar system.
...and one of those pictures
was of the Earth.
A tiny blue dot, set in a sunbeam.
Here it is.
That's where we live. That's home.
We humans are one species,
and this is our world.
It is our responsibility
to cherish it.
Of all the worlds in our solar system,
the only one, so far as we know...
...graced by life.