Hey, I'm Guy Fieri.
And you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun!
I'm on my way to Flavortown.
This is "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
This trip...
I'm going to have to start
stretching it out.
...we're hitting spots
mixing global flavor...
We're in the awesome zone.
...with American favorites.
My expectations
were high.
You beat my expectations.
Like an Indian pizza mash-up
at Salt Lake.
Dude, we have just robbed
the Indian spice counter.
And a comfort cafe...
I could spend weeks trying
to get my way through this menu.
...serving up Scandinavian
specialties.
This would be a dish
I would come to enjoy
a couple times a month.
Plus, uber-creative Chinese...
Whoa!
I didn't see that coming!
...loaded with crazy
New Orleans attitude.
Like a multi-cultural Mardi Gras
for your mouth.
I have been to some
funky places.
This might be the capitol.
That's all right here,
right now on "Triple D."
♪♪
So I'm here in New Orleans
in an area known as Bywater,
about 10 minutes
from the French Quarter.
And listen, if you watched
"Triple D" long enough,
you know I love Chinese food.
I mean, I'll eat it anywhere,
any time, any place.
So when I get here,
and I find out there's a joint
that's doing some real-deal
Chinese, but with some true
N'Orleans attitude --
you know I got to check it out.
This is Red's Chinese.
♪♪
Beef and broccoli.
This is one of my favorite
places in New Orleans.
The large Hawaiian
fried rice.
A little outside the ordinary.
FIERI: The kind of joint
where owner, Amy Mosberger
liked to hang out
when she worked
in other people's restaurants.
I have been to some funky,
funky places.
This might be the capitol.
It was actually abandoned for
a few years when we moved in.
We just kind
of transformed it
into this weird pirate ship
restaurant.
FIERI:
With chef Maxwell Darling firing
up a funkified menu to match.
Kung Pao pastrami in the window.
[Bell dings]
WOMAN: It's the most unusual
Chinese food you've ever had.
It's unreal.
Chinese food with a Southern
twist and a sense of humor.
For example,
the General's chicken,
we do, like, a nice
Southern-style
bone-in fried chicken
and then we dip it
in a sweet tangy, spicy,
kind of,
General Tzo's inspired sauce.
Enjoy.
Alright, so let's make
the General's chicken.
DARLING: We're going to start
with the egg.
Chug that.
[Laughs]
And then we're going to add
some Louisiana hot sauce.
Score the chicken, dip the
chicken into the egg wash.
With the hot sauce.
And then we're just going to go
into some standard AP flour.
-Alright, so we fry that off.
-Par cook it.
Okay.
What's our next step?
Alright, we're going
to make the slurry.
It's going to thicken up
the chicken sauce.
I've got soy sauce,
mushroom powder.
Mushroom powder?
Yeah, it's dried
shiitake mushrooms.
-Nothing wrong with that.
-Corn starch.
I need somebody to keep
stirring this...
Okay, I got you, captain.
...while we're building
the rest of this sauce.
Hi, welcome to One Pot.
I'm Guy.
Now I'm starting in the wok,
I'm going to add soy oil.
How many BTUs?
Probably around 120,000.
There you go!
Grated ginger.
Then we get the water out of it.
-Show off.
-Minced garlic.
How long did it take you
to get the technique down?
Still working on it.
Yeah, you really look
like a beginner.
Can you make some of the --
hey, hey!
Hey!
White sugar.
That thing is screaming hot
right now.
We're making a caramel
with this sugar.
Caramel of ginger and garlic,
thank you very much.
Then it's going
to start popping.
That's when you've kind of got
to turn it down a little bit.
That'll be fun.
Then we're going to deglaze
with shaoxing cooking wine.
White vinegar.
So there's our sweet
and our sour.
And then a little bit
of spice.
Arbol chiles.
Oh, you bring it then?
And then we're going to
thicken it up with this slurry
that we made.
-I like it.
Take the chicken,
then fry it again for service.
Absolutely.
Out of the fryer,
straight into the sauce.
Whoa-ho!
Absolutely.
I've had a lot
of general's sauce.
I've never seen it
with that kind of texture
and funk going on there.
So now we're going to garnish
with the house-made chili oil,
tons of szechuan peppercorns,
star anise, coarse-ground
Korean chili flakes,
fried peanuts, oranges,
cilantro on top.
Wow!
There you go.
That's the money bite,
right there.
♪♪
[Mumbling]
Sounds good.
I'll be there.
[Laughter]
This is out there, bro.
I mean, this is big flavor,
super-crispy, it's tangy,
it's sweet,
it's got depth of flavor,
and you don't know
where to stop.
At least I don't.
I got sticky
from here to here.
It's real deal.
Thank you.
I mean, legit, bro.
That sauce is just sweet,
viscous, lingers
afterwards a little bit.
It's so good.
What's your favorite thing,
Michael?
-Chicken.
-The chicken is the bomb, huh?
But it doesn't look like
you're sharing
any of the chicken, buddy.
It looks like you got
chicken all to yourself.
-I do.
-The General's chicken.
You did a great job, man.
The flavors are killer.
So if you're going to come
to a funky Chinese joint
in New Orleans, you should
invite three funky brothers.
First, from Motley Cue,
the barbecue team,
the one and only
Onion, the one
and only Panini Pete,
and then from my favorite
New Orleans band
Cowboy Mouth, Fred.
So, tell me
about Red's Chinese.
This is like a multi-cultural
Mardis Gras for your mouth.
I love it.
Here's the deal. I'm going to
have to start stretching it out.
We're hanging out, having
New Orleans-style, funkified,
real-deal Chinese food.
When we come back,
we're going to make.
Cheeseburger f--
Ah-da!
Sorry.
I'll tell you in a bit.
There you go.
Get after that.
That's how you do it.
And where are you from?
From a small town
outside of Madison, Wisconsin,
called Flavortown.
Sun Prairie.
[Laughter]
Sun Prairie, Wisconsin.
I was going.
You had me.
♪♪
Welcome back.
"Triple D" hanging out
in N'Orleans.
We're at a funky joint
called Red's Chinese.
Chef Max has rocked out.
WOMAN: It's an experience
that sort of gets you
out of your lane
in New Orleans.
Alright, guys, coming in.
This city is very traditionalist
with their dishes.
Red's has had the courage
to fusion
New Orleans cuisine
with a different cuisine.
FIERI: Which means local flavors
served Chinese-style...
Crawfish rangoon
through the window.
FIERI: ...and Eastern takes
on Western classics.
DARLING:
Cheeseburger fried rice up!
That's exactly what it is --
cheeseburger fried rice.
Pretty much has everything
that a cheeseburger has in it.
It's almost like a dirty rice.
It's fantastic.
This is where things are going
to get weird, folks.
This is when the New Orleans
attitude steps in.
We're going to make
the cheeseburger fried rice.
But it's going to taste
like fried rice?
It's going to taste
like a cheeseburger.
In fried rice.
When you mess with
the fried rice,
you're messing
with my emotions.
So we're going start by making
the awesome sauce,
that's this sauce that goes on
top of the cheeseburger.
Awesome sauce.
Yeah.
We've got pickle chips made
into a relish, three egg yolks.
Now I'm going to add minced
garlic, mushroom powder.
You love
that mushroom powder.
Drizzling a little bit
of soy oil.
So we just made
pickle-relish-garlic aoili.
Absolutely.
Alright.
We're in the awesome zone.
Now I'm going to fold
in the ketchup.
So, a really fantastic
scratch-made thousand island.
Alright, now we're going to make
the cheeseburger fried rice.
We're going to sautee
some onions.
Bacon.
Copious amounts.
Now I got ground beef.
Add a little bacon fat in there.
This is where we're going
to fry the rice.
Doesn't get any better
than this.
White sugar, a bit of mushroom
powder, lettuce.
Whoa!
I didn't see that coming.
Roma tomatoes.
Nacho cheese sauce.
Awesome sauce.
Yellow mustard.
Sesame seeds, pickle chips.
How do you eat it?
I use a spoon.
You're breaking the rules!
What rules are there?
Exactly.
I love fried rice.
Hawaii Five-0.
You picked it up!
Exactly what I said!
Bro, one minute I get a bite
and it's all cheeseburger
and I'm like,
"Okay, ground up cheeseburger."
The next bite I get is, like,
all fried rice.
You picked the iconic aspects
of both dishes
and made them really sing.
I can see why
it's such a big hit.
Spot on!
It tastes like exactly
what its supposed to taste like.
And that ends up
being delicious.
The dill pickle on the top
just makes it authentic.
Is it fried rice
and a cheeseburger together?
It's got everything
but french fries.
Everything but french fries.
So it passes?
Oh, I'd say so.
Pork buns in the window.
It's just a great place
that is never a bad choice.
FIERI: It's awesome.
I love the place.
And you got an open bar,
you got karaoke at night.
This place
must get rocking.
It gets weird.
Come on down,
bring the whole family.
♪♪
FIERI:
Up next, a decades-old spot
in Salt Lake City...
This is what "Triple D"
is all about.
...continuing a delicious
Scandinavian legacy.
That's Norway right there,
buddy.
♪♪
So the other day I was thinking
to myself,
"You know, on 'Triple
D' we've hit a lot
of Italian places,
Mexican joints,
we've been to a bunch
of Chinese places,
Greek family restaurants,
you name it.
But you know what we haven't
done a lot of?
Scandinavian places."
So I roll in to Salt
Lake City, Utah,
and I hear about a place
that's doing American cuisine
with kind of, like,
a Scandinavian twist.
And it's got a great story
and tons of character --
I had to check it out.
This is Finn's cafe.
GURHOLT:
One salmon benedict, table 4.
The food is delicious.
Unique flavor
you can only get here.
One sourdough pancake.
It goes back a legacy
of 50 years.
FIERI: Started by the original
Finn Gurholt,
a Norwegian immigrant who opened
a Salt Lake cafe in 1952,
and became a local
restaurant legend.
FIERI: He was a character.
If there was a camera,
he was in front of it.
Now, Finn Jr.'s at the helm.
Two minutes
on the schnitzel.
He switched locations,
but is still carrying
on his pop's legacy
with this breakfast-lunch joint
he runs with his wife, Nikki.
That's real,
real good stuff.
I'd classify myself
as an American cafe
with Scandinavian flair.
Do you speak Norweigian?
[Speaking Norwegian]
Yatak.
That's all I have
is "Yatak."
One wienerschnitzel.
WOMAN: The wienerschnitzel
is very good.
This is the place to come
and get it.
What are we going to make,
chef?
We're going to do my brown sauce
for the Wienerschnitzel.
I buy an inside round
and I trim it all off.
You make the meat
for different dishes,
and then you reserve the jus
to make for your schnitzel.
Exactly.
I start with chopped celery,
carrots, sweet garlic.
Some garlic.
Onions, tomatoes.
Interesting.
Mirepoix plus plus.
Black pepper, salt,
and pickling spices.
You get the roast in,
and more of the seasonings.
In the oven, how long?
An hour and a half.
And then we'll take the jus
from this,
and that's
for the schnitzel.
And then I add coffee, burgundy
or red wine, ketchup, and water.
Nice.
See that little move?
Then I get it back in the oven
and juice it down.
Draining that, and...
Tighten up with our roux
for the schnitzel sauce.
What's next?
We're seasoning the flour
for wienerschnitzel with salt,
crack pepper, and garlic.
You love
that garlic powder.
I do.
This is a schnitzel,
and it's done
by my father's butcher.
He takes all of his trimmings
and then runs it
through a tenderizer.
I love it.
Dip it in the egg.
And I only dredge it
on one side.
Really? I've never seen just
the one-side dredge.
Yeah, no. I don't want
that much flour on it.
I'm not making
chicken fried steak.
So that goes down.
Yeah.
Flip it over, that's it --
simple, simple.
Then I got some potatoes,
asparagus that I've grilled up,
my schnitzel, brown sauce it,
garnish it with a lemon.
And some capers to boot.
Yeah.
It's a very simple dish, but it
eats so delicate and so tender.
You're getting all
of that rich flavor.
Just the attention to detail
you take in the schnitzel.
The perfectly
cooked asparagus,
beautiful pan-finished
finger length potatoes,
and the piece de resistance,
really, is this gravy.
Try it with some lemon
and caper.
As soon as you add
that little bit of acid
and the little brightness
of one of those capers.
This would be a dish
I would come to enjoy
a couple times a month.
Fantastic.
Wienerschnitzel.
Wienerschnitzel
has got great flavor.
It's super-light.
It's not heavy.
-It's perfect every time.
-Capers please.
It's the little nuances
that make all the difference.
Everything's fresh.
I do all my own baking.
Wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
It's tradition.
My dad was a konditor.
A konditor?
Pastry chef.
Konditery is a bakery
in Scandinavia.
I make wheat, rye, sour, French,
and julekake.
You can compare the julekake
to fruit cake.
Julekake is traditional
what times?
Christmas.
But they eat it all year long
because it's so marvelous.
It's a marvelous
julekake.
That's right.
[Laughs]
What are we going
to make with it.
I'm making julekake
French toast.
How do we do it.
Unbleached flour, sugar,
fresh yeast.
Let me see
the block of that.
Boy, that's a monster.
Butter --
this is a very rich dough.
Is baking
your zen time?
I love baking.
What do we got?
This is cardamom.
Okay.
Lot of cardamom
in Norwegian food?
A lot.
Really?
They love it because when they
went to the Mediterranean,
the Vikings,
they brought back spices.
Salt, eggs, and whole milk.
It mixes for 12 minutes.
Once it's incorporated, we add
the black raisins and citron.
Do you know citron?
It's a candied melon.
It's weird.
You got to put that in there?
I do traditional.
Alright, so once this
is done mixing, what happens?
I divide it, proof it...
Holy moly!
GURHOLT: ...bust 'em down,
sheet 'em through.
I love the way
this is going.
This is 100% egg wash.
This will proof again.
Right.
Then to the oven.
375, 400.
35, to 40 minutes.
Julekake loaf.
You can taste the cardamom
coming through.
You get a little sweetness
coming due from the raisins.
It's a rich bread cake.
We put together the eggs,
heavy cream, and some cinnamon.
Whisk that together,
then we'll dredge this.
Wow. I like it.
Hit it with some strawberries,
some butter and syrup.
Make it look cute.
Delicious, lot of flavor
without a lot of sweet.
You get a little bit
of that melon.
For as heavy and dense as it was
when it came out of the oven,
it really softens up
and becomes light and pillowy --
sponginess that you want.
Taste it with the lingam berry
and see what you think.
That's Norway right there,
buddy.
Julekake French toast.
I really like getting
all the different textures.
It's kind of more
like a fruity taste.
Pour that syrup all over it,
and it just feels good.
The legacy just gets better
and better and better.
This is what "Triple D"
is all about.
Straightforward, mom and pop,
done with your on personality,
flair, and style.
Love the homage
to the old country.
I could spend weeks trying to
get my way through this menu.
Thanks for having me.
Thank you.
Come down for the food,
meet the man.
You're going
to have a blast.
FIERI: Coming up, we're staying
in Salt Lake...
Starving.
...to check out a joint
all about Indian...
People are going to be
in a hurry for the curry.
...piled on the pie.
What do you think?
I think I'll have
another piece.
♪♪
So I'm here in Salt Lake City,
Utah.
And check this one out.
I'm looking for a joint
where a dude is making pizza,
but he's flavoring it
with Indian spices.
I can definitely smell it
in the air.
Oh, let me ask these guys.
'Scuse me, sir.
Is there a restaurant
around here where a gentleman
is putting Indian food
on top of pizzas?
[Speaking native language]
Okay, good.
This must be the place.
This is Curry Pizza.
Plate zero.
I don't think there's any
other place like this.
Garlic cheese naan sticks.
Indian has always been one
of my favorite types of food.
And who doesn't love pizza?
And I can't believe that
no one's ever thought
of blending the two before.
FIERI: At least not here
in Salt Lake City,
until 5th-generation
restaurant owner
Bhinda Singh came up
with the concept.
I bought a pizza place
down in southern Utah.
Then after that, I was like,
"Oh, you got Indian restaurant,
then now you got pizza,
now why don't we merge them?"
All the flavors
just melt together.
Alright, chef. So what are we
going to make today?
We're going to make
a Bhinda special.
The who-what?
Bhinda?
Yeah, that's me.
How do you spell your name?
B-H-I-N-D-A.
Bhinda.
But like "panda".
Bhinda panda.
The Bhinda special has
the tikka masala sauce.
-It's got the marinated chicken.
-I love it.
So are we making naan --
Non-pesto, yeah.
Let's see it.
We'll start with milk,
homemade yogurt, baking powder,
salt, sugar, water,
put our flour into it.
-How long is this going to mix?
-Five, to seven minutes.
-With the oil at the end?
-Yeah.
So this is not just some crazy
Indian deep dish right now.
This is going to get cut
into how many pieces?
SINGH: 14.
This machine makes perfect
dough balls.
What are we making now?
We're going to make
a garam masala for sauces.
Pomegranate seeds,
bay leaf, mace...
The outside of the nutmeg.
...cinnamon sticks,
brown flax seed,
white flax seed.
You got the rainbow
of the flax seed.
Yeah. Nutmeg, green cardamom,
and black cardamom.
Any Greek?
Dude, we have just robbed
the Indian spice counter.
Cumin seed, cloves.
Black pepper, coriander.
Fennel seed.
That's a lot of flavor.
You grind it once,
and then twice?
Yeah. No we're going to make
the honey crepe baste.
Great.
Wish Garam masala
with Ginger.
-Roasted and ground?
-Yeah.
Oregano, basil, red pepper
flakes, paprika, olive oil,
then we will rest it
for a week.
So we made
the garam masala...
Yeah.
...then we made
the paste --
all the more to make to
to make the on sauce.
One sauce.
We still got a couple
more steps to go.
You're killing me,
Smalls.
Whole tomatoes, cumin seeds,
roasted garlic, ginger,
paprika, add water,
cook about four hours.
What's the next step?
The onion gravy.
Oil, cumin seeds, roasted garlic
ginger, salt, onions,
water, paprika powder, turmeric,
let it cook for 7 hours.
Onion gravy?
Onion gravy.
Goes in the sauce?
Goes in the sauce.
The paste we made earlier, we're
going to put in there with it.
Add honey in there, as well.
Let it cook.
This is the honey curry?
It is honey curry.
I like it.
Next up, we're going
to make the chicken tikka.
So chicken breasts.
Homemade yogurt,
lemon juice, coloring.
Got to make it red.
Chili powder, paprika, salt,
garlic, and ginger.
Roasted garlic and ginger.
What are you thinking
back there?
Little bit of oil.
So we are going to let it
sit for 10 hours at least.
Okay.
I roast at about 500 degrees
for 25 to 30 minutes.
And now we make
the pizza?
Exactly.
I'm starving.
We take the dough ball --
a little bit of oil.
Cooks a little bit.
Oh, puts a little heat
on it.
We take the curry sauce.
Fresh-grated mozzarella.
Chicken on, roasted fresh
garlic, fresh Ginger.
It's flavor city
right here.
Didn't see that coming.
I still need green onions.
The 80s said that
I'd impeach the folks.
Basil, cilantro, jalapenos,
garlic salt, fenugreek
In the oven.
Look how excited is.
Two, three minutes.
It looks like you went and stole
everything off of the pizza line
and put it on one pizza.
That's why I call it
the Bhinda special.
What do you think?
I think I'll have
another piece.
It's actually going to wreck
pizza for me for a while.
You've brought such depth
and such flavor
and such creativity
and new textures,
like the cauliflower.
You get a touch of the oregano
and the basil in that sauce,
a little bit of the Italian,
and then you come heavy
with everything from
the fenugreek to the cardamom.
The naan is nice, I mean,
it's thin,
neopolitan-style crust.
So you get that nice cracker
crunch that you want out of it,
but it's still tender.
My expectations were high.
You beat my expectations.
Thank you.
Bhinda special.
These are good friends of mine
from a company called Camp Chef,
and they know
a lot about cooking.
So I think they would be
the perfect ones
to ask what they think
of the pizza.
It's spicy, but there's, like,
a really good flavor.
I really like the crust.
I would say my favorite pizza
I've ever had.
-Seriously?
-I love Indian food.
It's the marriage
of the two.
-Yes!
-Margarita.
When they do American pizzas,
they do their own.
And then they do
create your own.
You guys are brothers,
I take it?
-Twins.
-No.
Curry Pizza catered
for our school,
and these kids go like,
"Man, this is great
cheese pizza.
Where's it from?"
WOMAN:
They have the mozzarella cheese,
the paneer cheese,
which has got a firm texture,
but it's creamy.
Next one
we're making is...
Glaze paneer.
Walk me through it.
The honey curry sauce
we made earlier.
In the same dough
that we made.
Yup,
those are all our cheese.
Paneer.
-Do you make it here?
Yes.
They make the yogurt
at home
know they make
the paneer at home.
On the ends.
Tomatoes, red feta cheese.
Don't forget-a the feta.
We're going
to cook this now.
That's arugula.
The balsamic vinaigrette.
I want this monster piece.
♪♪
I love paneer.
It has such great texture.
It has more like a barbecue
sauce flavor to it
when you mix it
with the balsamic.
I mean, it's not
just those eggs.
The cheese pizza --
wah-wah.
This is a cheese pizza!
That's the real deal.
Congrats, man.
Thank you.
-The glazed paneer.
-The cheeses all come together.
-Awesome flavors.
-It's fantastic.
Yeah,
you've had a few slices.
-Maybe?
-I can see it.
Maybe I have,
and don't judge me.
MAN: Thai peanut.
GIRL: I love Indian food.
Like, that's my all-time
favorite.
And I love pizza,
and so it's like, awesome.
Oh, I'm sorry
who stole the show.
[Laughter]
Chicken with the sausage.
People are going to be
in a hurry for the curry.
Trademark that.
-Thank you.
So that wraps this edition of
"Diners, Drive-ins, and Dives."
It you want to get some
of the of the recipes
from today's show,
go do foodnetwork.com.
I'll be looking for you
next week
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and dives."
What are your kid's names?
Kids are Minder
and Dopinder.
So my phone is bo-pinder.
Hold on.
My mom is Clovinder.
I'm out, that's it.
You're not --
Now you're messing it me.