Hey, I'm Guy Fieri,
and you know what I need?
I need you riding shotgun! I'm
on my way to Flavortown!
This is "Diners,
Drive-ins & Dives."
This trip...
Ah, hot!
We're living large...
Which is bigger,
the pancake or my head?
And going supersized.
Just look at
the cascading joy.
We've got piled-up
Cincinnati chili...
Just went from
ridiculous to crazy.
Michigan burgers
stacked to the max...
I don't know where
to post up on this thing.
Big-time breakfast
near Chicago...
Just the food alone
is three pounds.
And a bomb Baltimore
beef joint...
Is there anything wrong
with this picture?
Where I'm making my boy Duff
a skyscraper sandwich.
Look at the bite
out of it!
That's all right here
right now on "Triple D."
On "Triple D," when we hit
a historic place like Baltimore,
well, we've got to use
the inside track
of a buddy who lives here,
so regardless of the weather
or how busy this dude is,
we're at Charm City Cakes
to talk to the cake bad boy,
Duff Goldman, and find out one
of this favorite joints.
Call the cops.
Is this where the magic happens?
How you doing?
Nice to see you.
Good to see you.
So you open up the bakery.
You've been doing
this thing here.
But you really come
from a culinary background,
not just a background
of making incredible cakes.
I've been a cook
for almost 20 years.
I come to Baltimore,
I want to try some
iconic Baltimore food.
Locals know,
got to get pit beef.
So where's the best
place to get it?
I think probably Chaps.
Chaps.
Let's get some pit beef.
All right, let's do it.
Oh, sweet.
Isn't that nice?
Come on, let me drive.
Seriously.
Seriously, can I?
No.
Ah, come on.
I didn't get to make any cake.
But when we get there,
I'll be sure to make Duff
a Fieri-style
mile-high masterpiece.
This is the famous Chaps.
This is Chaps.
Look at that.
You come to Baltimore,
this is what you better see.
And if you don't,
it's not pit beef.
The charcoal, the pit beef,
you're not going to
get it nowhere else.
One medium-rare beef
on a roll.
It is so tender.
Just falls right apart.
I'm going to need
three pit beef.
FIERI:
Done the way you want...
Medium-well
and a medium-rare.
Then sliced thin...
Oh, look at that.
And piled high.
Best pit beef I ever had.
It started 21 years ago
when Bob and Donna Creager
got married.
As a wedding gift, my father
gave me this little shack.
For lawn tools,
or what was the reason?
Well, no, he said since
my husband loved to cook,
we should put a pit beef stand
outside of his nightclub.
Fry and a rare.
We started just a grill
and exhaust system
and a register.
FIERI:
And learned real quick...
Two beef on a roll.
Thank you.
Bringing in so many fans,
they had to add on
a dining room.
Is this the best
pit beef in Baltimore?
Yes, it is.
Now, this is...
It's a bottom round.
You put about six of these
on to start the day.
MAN: And you can smell it
from as early
as probably 6:00
in the morning.
Put this straight on the grill,
just like it is.
400, 500 hundred
degrees usually.
Baker boy, what do you think?
That's about right.
That'll melt the gold.
Where'd your bling go?
Can you get part medium-rare
and part well-done?
Here? You can get
whatever you want.
A medium and a medium-rare.
They're both rare? Good.
Yes, sir.
I like rare
more than anything.
Pulling it rare, cut it.
FIERI: Look at that!
Now, in about 15 minutes,
you're ready to start
working then.
What're we going to make first?
We'll make a beef sandwich.
You can do it.
Come on, now. Keep pushing it.
It got to the point where
it's really on the rare side.
I mean, we're almost
tartare right there.
So that goes
back on the grill.
And then we'll bring
another piece out.
So this is like
tag-team meat slicing.
Exactly.
Hey, look at that over there.
Oh, what?
Check that out.
Ah.
Now, what do you like
to put on these?
little horseradish
on there.
You know, I like
the little char to it,
but I've got to say,
the medley of the --
the white onion,
the really nice,
bright horseradish,
a little bit of salt and pepper,
a great roll,
not too much bread.
I hate when you get
too much bread
and it starts to become...
Nah, it's all
about the meat.
Right.
Welcome to Baltimore.
It's spicy, it's moist.
The meat is so tender.
I give it way past a 10.
FIERI:
And there's way more than beef.
If you want a variety,
the ham, the turkey.
I like it.
And then of course sausage,
too.
Oh, yeah. What do you got there,
meat wizard?
Corned beef.
Yep, they're even pit-grilling
the corned beef
for killer Reubens
and combos any way you want,
and I'm going to be going for
large and extra-large.
I think we should have it
every single way
you can possibly make it.
My favorite is the bulldog.
A couple slices of cheese,
and we put the sausage on,
put the beef on.
Get up underneath it like this.
Bring your shoulders
to protect yourself
when you're at the counter.
You come into my town
and teach me how to bulldog?
I didn't think the pit beef
could get any better.
It's got a little
sausage kicker. Mm.
This one's got pit beef,
ham, and corned beef.
Is there anything wrong
with this picture?
Actually, no, there's not.
When the bread won't
even wrap around...
That is so much flavor,
sweetness of the ham,
that briny, pickle-y spice
on the corned beef,
and then just a nice smoky
flavor from the pit beef.
This is like sandwich
engineering right here.
Good mouth feel.
It is, good mouth feel.
You so want a bite of this,
don't you?
Mm.
This is great, man.
Well, I like everything
they got in here.
I need a breaded chicken
barbecue for Colin.
They've got the best smoky
flavor in the whole town.
You make these
great combos.
Now, can I custom-build
my own combo?
Oh, absolutely.
For my boy Duff?
Sure.
Yeah?
We'll start with the beef.
Some jalapeños down,
the horseradish.
Okay, now put
the ham up there.
Cut the burger in half.
Nacho cheese sauce.
Sausage.
Pickles.
Little chopped beef, turkey.
Where are you, Duffinator?
My brother, just look
at the cascading joy.
There you go.
There's a champion.
Let's cut this in half.
No, no, no. Don't cut it.
No?
Don't. If you cut it,
it's going to explode.
Look at the bite
out of that!
Make sure you don't
lose anything.
Get over here.
Oh, he goes for a double bite.
What cheese?
You got something --
Is there anything right here?
No, you look fine.
Coming up, a funky diner
in Springfield, Illinois...
Whoa!
Putting out
pizza-sized pancakes...
That'll make you proud.
And a regional favorite that's
way more than a plateful.
There's no reason
you should leave here hungry
with something like this.
No, sirree.
FIERI: So now I'm going to
take you to a joint
that was an airplane hangar
in World War II.
Then it become a town hall,
then, of course,
it evolved into a restaurant.
Did I mention it's
a Quonset hut?
Eating good food
in a Quonset hut.
Well, works for me.
Quonset huts were the big
silver buildings
the Army put up all over the
country in the '40s and '50s.
Half a century later,
in Springfield, Illinois,
this one's still standing
as Charlie Parker's diner.
Robin, small pancake.
Did you buy the building?
Yes.
Girls, order.
My husband and I
had come in here
when it was
a restaurant previously.
He said, "You know, I think
we can do better than this."
Hash brown.
And I said, "You know,
I think you're right."
And my Reuben basket
and small cake.
FIERI: So when the restaurant
became available,
Brenda Shirley
and her husband made an offer.
You have what experience
in the restaurant business?
None.
Just a dream.
Do you love to cook?
I love to cook.
And they made it work.
Hot sauce or anything, boys?
Cranking out big plates,
like the Reuben sandwich,
homemade stuffed pork chops,
overstuffed omelettes,
and a local specialty
you can only find around here
that a friend of mine told me
I've just got to try.
T-ray, Thomas Ray,
one of my fraternity brothers,
and he said,
"You know what?
On 'Diners,
Drive-ins & Dives,'
you've got to try the..."
Horseshoe.
Two pieces of toast,
a piece of ham on it,
and the ham is cut
in a horseshoe shape,
and then a cheese sauce.
Then french fries
were put on top
as the nails in the horseshoe.
Wow.
Hamburger shoe.
Cheese sauce.
FIERI: Some other folks
will tell your
the first shoe was actually
made with hamburgers.
There you go, girls.
But these days,
they'll make 'em
with just about anything.
I prefer the sausage gravy.
The breakfast shoe, they all get
two pieces of toast.
The scramble.
Now he's going to add the eggs.
Bacon.
Look at that.
There's no reason
you should leave here hungry
with something like this.
No, sirree.
Half cheese,
half gravy.
Oh, it's delicious.
And the American fries.
You've got one breakfast shoe.
Do you have a scale?
Just the food alone
is three pounds.
I'm not going to have to eat
anything the rest of the day.
FIERI: It's not just the shoes
that are big here.
Get a load of the pancakes.
That's a big pancake.
16-inch pancake.
16-inch?
Did you know what
you were getting into?
I didn't.
That'll make you proud!
And how many
ounces of batter
do we put down
for the mondo cake?
About 18 ounces.
Which is bigger,
the pancake or my head?
And way too much.
FIERI: But in this big hut
of big plates...
You can eat that, can't you?
Oh, yeah.
The king of the hill
is still the shoe.
Probably eat half of it.
I cut it up and hope
for the best.
I could eat 'em for breakfast,
lunch, and supper.
I've got to make a special
shoe for a buddy.
Okay.
Let's make one of
those big pancakes,
ham steak, burger patty.
How exactly will
we be moving this?
Slide it under quick
so it don't stick.
There you are.
Hoh!
Very nice.
That's a biggun'.
The ham, the patty.
Do you want eggs on this?
How 'bout three scrambled?
Three scrambled?
Very nice!
What do we serve this on,
a trash can lid?
We've got a pizza tray.
Wow, that's hot.
Sausage and bacon temple.
Oh, yeah.
I mean, you know...
You've got to fit
the pallet there, yeah.
Right in the middle.
There we go.
Because this side is more of
the lunch-y side of it.
Right.
Just hit that
with some of that.
Oh. Hot!
We've got to get all
three potatoes on there.
He is so going to
thank me.
I don't like to shake off
any of the excess oil.
Throw that on there.
I think it looks beautiful.
You think we should
just go for it?
Go for it.
This is the whole
horseshoe sandwich.
Happy horseshoing.
Yes.
That should at least
cover you till lunch.
I'll still be
eating it at lunch.
It's been two hours.
How are ya?
Come on,
loosen that shirt up.
Get in there, son.
Up next, a Cincinnati spot
where chili is king.
I could eat that six
or seven times a week.
And they're definitely not shy
with their servings.
Then all you have to do
is invite
15 of your best friends
over to come eat it.
Texas has its brisket.
California has tacos.
Memphis has barbecue.
New England has chowder.
What does Cincinnati have?
That's right,
Cincinnati-style chili.
Now, Cincinnatians
go through more than
two million pounds
of chili a year,
topped with over
850,000 pounds of cheese.
Now, there's been
a big debate --
who made it first
and who makes it best?
Well, everybody
has their opinion,
but a lot of you wrote in
and sent me to a place
that I've never even heard of --
Blue Ash Chili,
15 miles north of Cincinnati,
and my question now is,
am I going to have it two-way,
four-way, five-way,
or at this joint, six-way?
Got a six-way.
'Cause stacking chili
on spaghetti...
Two-way chili coming up.
Is something folks
grow up with here.
u nywhere
in Cincinnati and say,
il
Is something folks
grow uI'm getting onions,
I'm getting beans,
I'm getting cheese.
Correct.
And here at Blue Ash...
Bowl of chili.
The chili hasn't
changed at all.
Not since this joint
first opened...
Chili to go.
Back in '69.
The original Greek owners,
it's their recipe,
and it's been in their family
for a long time.
And when restaurant vets
Nick Insco...
Cheese Coney.
And his wife Charlene
bought the place...
Hi, there.
They bought the chili recipe
right along with it.
It's a unique flavor.
It's terrific.
When I see something like this,
I know that you're
either feeding the troops
or we are going to make
a mess of chili.
Absolutely,
but we're going to start off
with about a hundred pounds
of ground beef.
A hundred pounds?
Yep.
Fresh ground,
never frozen?
Correct.
Fill it up with water.
We'll just stir it
to a slurry.
Now we add salt,
garlic powder.
How long is this going to cook?
Two hours.
You've never seen
a hundred pounds of meat boil.
That's On Golden Meat Pond.
It is.
Its got to be around
250 degrees, at least.
So now what goes in?
Now we put in the onions,
tomato paste...
That'll put some
nice color in this.
And then chili spice mix.
Paprika, tomato powder,
cumin, black pepper,
cinnamon, salt.
Correct.
But you won't tell me
the portions.
Got that right.
Or the last two ingredients.
All we do is just stir it up.
How long does this go?
That's going to go for
about an hour and a half.
Now we're going to go ahead
and open up the lid
and put in the slurry mix.
Now, the slurry mix is water
and cracker meal,
and that's going to help
tighten the chili up.
Correct.
Right now, we'll go ahead
and set up
for another 45 minutes
and allow it
to steep overnight.
It stays above 140 degrees,
so it's safe,
and it just sits here
and melds all the flavors.
Correct.
I hear that there's
a lot of turf wars
here in Cincinnati,
and where do you think
you stand in this?
I think we have
the best chili in town.
And Blue Ash takes it
even further.
Six-way.
Six-way, we top it off
with our beer-battered
jalapeño bottle caps.
So these are your pickled
jalapeño peppers.
Correct.
Build me a six-way, brother.
Start off with your spaghetti,
chili.
All right,
so now it's a two-way.
Now it's a two-way.
Onions, kidney beans.
We're going to go ahead
and top it off with cheese.
Whoa, whoa!
Beer-battered
jalapeño bottle caps.
It just went from
ridiculous to crazy.
Look at that bite
right there. Mm.
The chili has
a unique spice to it.
The onions
are nice and fresh.
And the pasta really works,
cooked al dente,
which I think is critical.
Having the beans in there,
there's a texture
that you expect
to see in chili,
but the beans are
a little bit more whole.
Right.
Then you put
a ridiculous amount
of cheese on it.
That's a great way to do chili.
Mm.
I could eat that six
or seven times a week.
Got a six-way to table 30.
The spaghetti and the chili
is a great mixture.
The jalapeños really
adds a kick to it.
Tons of cheese.
What else can you
possibly do with chili?
We do a chili Philly as well.
He's trying to hurt me.
Now selling Philly chili.
Regular Philly cheesesteak,
they load it up with chili.
FIERI: And homemade roast beef.
Top round. Now, how are we
going to season it up?
Start off with cracked
black pepper,
the oregano,
dehydrated onions, kosher salt,
thyme, crushed red pepper,
and we've got the rosemary.
Mix it thoroughly.
Do you dry rub this in there?
We go ahead and pour olive oil
over the top round
and we do it on both sides.
Rub it up.
Then we'll go ahead and take
our spice mixture here,
going to generously put it
on both sides.
Wrapped up, and how long
will this marinate?
This'll marinate overnight.
Let it sit for a little bit,
then roast at what?
We roast it at 275
for about 4, 4 1/2 hours,
depending on the size
and the weight.
Let it rest.
Cut it half and throw it
in the slicers.
We're going for
a thin slice of meat.
Look at how thin that is.
We're about to medium there.
How are we going to heat it up?
Fresh baked bun
with some butter on it,
little weight on it,
get a nice crisp on there.
Throw down our roast beef.
Little salt and pepper.
Going to season that meat off,
saute the green peppers,
red peppers,
and some onions.
Sauteed mushrooms that are
sauteed with butter and whiskey.
There you go. So it's a typical
Philly cheesesteak.
Yep. We're going to lay
our provolone cheese over it.
Wow, you're really
building that up.
Put the steam lid over there.
Little steam helps
melt the cheese.
Absolutely.
Then all you have to do
is invite 15 of your
best friends over
to come eat it.
That's right.
Take our bun off
the grill there.
Got that, you're making
that look easy.
Now the chili.
Now we're going to ladle
the chili over.
This is wrong.
That's our chili Philly.
How much does it weigh?
Three pounds?
A good couple pounds.
Ah. The Philly
on its own, tasty.
Nice toasted bun,
fresh veggies in there.
The chili,
it was ridiculous.
You're showing Cincinnati chili
can go on just about anything.
A chili Philly with fries.
I'm a big cheesesteak fan,
and if you add
chili to the top of it...
Icing on the cake.
Philadelphia meets
Cincinnati.
The Bengals
play the Eagles.
Looks like the Bengals
are winning, though.
They're just smothering
the competition.
We've got chili
cheese fry.
It's outstanding.
This is my cousin,
Gene Bob.
This guy can eat.
Take his word for it.
Six-way chili.
It's the best.
We just make it
with love every day.
You guys to continue to keep
knocking out the chili.
Thank you.
Good job, buddy.
Thanks.
FIERI: Coming up, a crazy spot
in Ann Arbor, Michigan...
Dave, Dave, Dave!
Where folks are
eating burgers 10...
10 patties?
Or even 20 at a time.
Just keep my hands and feet
inside the ride at all times.
So when I'm cruising the quad
at the University of Michigan
in my Mac '67 Camaro,
a question comes to mind --
where should I eat?
Now, if you ask anybody
in the student body
where to go for the bomb burger,
they're going to say
Crazy Jim's Blimpy Burger,
where piling down patties
has become
a collegiate competition.
Regular buns, regular buns.
What you having, girlfriend?
I need two doubles.
It's the burger you can get.
Mm.
It just tastes better
than anything else.
Who's next?
You love the Blimpy,
don't ya?
What do you want?
I want a bacon,
lettuce, and tomato.
A B.L. what?
FIERI: At this joint,
you may know what you want.
No, like, I want
hamburger with bacon,
lettuce, and tomato.
No, no!
FIERI: But you better know
how to say it.
You want a double
with bacon on it, okay?
Yes, that's what I want.
There you go.
That's what you want.
And you've got to
order in order.
What you having, sir?
Sides, then size.
How many patties
did you say you wanted?
Then grilled toppings
and bun...
And you have nothing
grilled on yours, sir?
No.
Why not?
Before you even think
about choosing your cheese.
American.
What I want to know is,
do you want a bun?
That's real important to me.
God, I'm nervous for you.
I know!
I'm about ready to have
a nervous breakdown,
and I've only made two patties.
[ Chanting]
Yeah!
FIERI: Divvy Askew's been
doing this forever.
I just love this job.
I'm going to cook meat,
I got you.
I got you, baby.
How long you been doing this?
Uh, I was 14 when
I started working here.
Alongside Rich Magner...
What do you want
on your burger?
Who was a college kid
at the time.
And I worked part-time
off and on for four years.
When Rich came back
and bought the place
more than two decades later,
he changed almost nothing...
Yes.
From ordering etiquette...
Anything thrown extra on it?
No, ma'am, thank you.
FIERI:
It's not the military.
"Yes, sir. No, ma'am."
To the burgers themselves.
Single or double?
From singles
to a stack of five,
or any size you want.
Can I get 10
on a kaiser?
You go, baby!
With almost 30 toppings,
cheeses,
and buns to chose from...
What are you having
on this?
The possibilities
will fry your brain.
I got a quad on onion
with bacon.
Triple with bacon,
banana pepper.
Double on onion,
Swiss cheese,
banana peppers,
pickles, and ketchup.
Anything grilled extra
while I'm cooking it?
No, thank you.
Good. I don't want to
do it, anyway.
FIERI: And don't be fooled
by the floor show.
Lean back. Hey!
These are
the real-deal burgers.
Outstanding.
Absolutely awesome.
And the real foundation,
you believe, of this meat
is it's fresh ground
by you everyday?
Yeah.
Now we're going to make them
into the 10 balls per pound,
which is 1.6 ounces a ball.
That's right,
it's 8 ounces for 5,
which is
16 ounces for 10.
'Cause we go through easily
500 pounds of meat.
500 pounds.
That's two tons a month.
Some are quints,
some are doubles.
Okay, what kind of burger
would you like?
Let me get a double
with hot peppers,
onions on pumpernickel.
I need a triple bacon,
sesame bun.
She has no idea what's coming.
Can I get a quint,
onions, peppers, bacon,
salami, and mushrooms.
Yes. If I forget it,
you just eat it.
Look at that.
Mayonnaise, mustard, ketchup,
lettuce, pickle,
onion, and relish.
Here you go.
Baby burger,
mommy burger,
with the little one, huh?ar
Mm. That meat
is so tender.
Wow, that's tasty, with
the cheddar and the peppers.
The beauty
is layering it.
You get all your flavors
mingling just the right way.
I don't know where to
post up on this thing.
Look at
the festival of funk.
So much salami,
call my mommy.
[ Laughs ]
That's one of our biggest
expenses, is the napkins.
Delicious and messy.
Next.
FIERI: And you better
be ready to pack 'em away.
Triple with bacon, egg,
cheese, grilled onions.
Let's see,
there's the single,
the double, the triple,
the quad, and the quint.
But why stop at five?
10 patties?
Mushroom, onion,
Swiss cheese.
I'll just keep my hands and feet
inside the ride at all times.
Turns out, there's a whole
competition thing going on.
Dave, Dave, Dave, Dave!
And we don't promote this.
No, no no no.
The record stands
at a little over four pounds.
FIERI: And no one's
breaking that today,
but records are still at risk.
There's a double snack bite
with a pull-away cheese.
Dave Williams is going for
a personal best of 20.
How you feeling right now?
Hungry.
Oh, you're hungry?
Get the forehead.
Get the pit crew in here.
Some girls showed up
right here.
Her 21st birthday,
looks like she looks over 21.
And Lauren Lobert
is serious.
I'm a hockey player and I'm a --
I'm an eater.
What's the most you've done?
Um, 10 in 7 minutes,
and some french fries
and dessert.
FIERI: But today,
for her 21st birthday,
Lauren Lobert's
going for 21 burgers.
I'm doing three sevens.
Three sevens?
Yeah, seven, 14, 21.
Are you really going to
be able to do 21?
Oh, for sure.
I think I'm in love.
That is one juicy-looking
burger, though.
Delicious.
Dave, Dave, Dave!
Round of applause.
20 patties.
He got his 20,
but she's still chasing 21.
I see the end is near.
You got it. Do it.
Lauren, Lauren,
Lauren, Lauren, Lauren!
Okay, that's it.
Am I catching some
eye water over here?
I'm crying
because I'm so happy.
Don't leave me hanging.
So was that another
righteous road trip or what?
But don't you worry.
We've got plenty more joints
to find all over this country.
I'll be looking
for you next week
on "Diners,
Drive-ins & Dives."
She's an athlete.
We have
hockey practice tonight.
You have hockey
practice tonight?
I'm just going to tell my coach
I have the flu or something.
The flu.
[ Laughs ]