Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
All aboard.
We're putting it in gear
and hitting the highway...
- I can feel the magic.
-It's so exciting.
...heading back East
for a culinary road trip.
16 tickets
to Flavortown.
In New York City...
You got to check this out.
...Neapolitan pizza
straight out of Italy...
That's a different level, baby.
...and legit barbecue
in the middle of the Bronx?
In the world of dives,
my friend,
this is Culinary Dive 101.
Then, an all-American diner
in Philly...
You're teasing me.
...and real-deal Italian
in Baltimore.
If I was taught
how to make those at home,
I never would've left home.
Plus, in Rhode Island...
We're watching.
...a family joint dishing it out
for decades...
Off the hook.
...and a burger joint
gone bananas.
And bananas is good.
That's really nice.
So buckle up and dig in...
I could have
6 to 12 pounds of that.
...'cause this is gonna be
a righteous feast in the East.
I can't get it in my mouth
fast enough.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
So, I'm here in New York City
on 50th Street,
right between
8th and 9th Avenue.
I mean, this place is busy.
I'm here to check out
a real-deal pizza joint.
Now, when I say "real-deal,"
I'm talking from Naples.
I'm talking the owner
of this place --
I mean, he's the president
of the Association
of Neapolitan Pizza Makers!
This...
Fieri, you're late.
...is Iron Chef
Geoffrey Zakarian,
and this is Don Antonio.
I've never had pizza like this
ever in my entire life.
This pizza is as authentic
as it comes.
Margherita's ready.
I came from Italy.
I can say that this
is one of the best pizza
that I eat in my life.
So, when New Yorkers and
Italians swear it's the best,
you know renowned pizza master
Roberto Caporuscio
is doing it right.
Kind of helps that he was born
and raised on a dairy farm
in the heart
of Italy's pizza country,
right between
Rome and Naples.
I was cheese maker
before.
You were
a cheese maker?
Yes.
In 2012, he partnered up
with his mentor,
his don, Antonio Starita,
to school Americans
on true Neapolitan pizza.
Chef Roberto, Iron Chef
Geoffrey Zakarian, okay?
You guys know
each other?
Yeah, he was,
before, here.
Yeah, he's been
here before.
Break it down for me
from the beginning --
What makes
true Neapolitan pizza?
The most important start
for the dough.
Hit it.
Okay, water.
This is
so exciting.
I can feel
the magic.
So exciting.
Keep notes on this,
by the way.
I am.
Salt.
And we start
with a flour,
So, you're just gonna add the
flour to the water and the salt
in your own vision
and touch-by-feel?
Yes.
You don't have to worry
about ripping this recipe off.
This is fresh yeast.
Okay,
this is fresh yeast.
Okay, so, really, you're just
looking at this...
When we started over 20 years
ago, there was no machine.
Just put that
anywhere.
You're gonna clean that.
After that, we need to
let it rest for one hour.
Then we start making
the dough balls.
So, you're
tucking it in.
Look at that.
Looks so easy.
Pinching it off.
Wow.
Can you do it both hands?
I used to be able
to do both hands.
That's nice.
We let it rise
for at least --
between 24 and 36 hours
before using.
What is the next key step
in making true Neapolitan pizza?
The stretching part.
The stretching part?
Yes.
The method in
which you stretch it?
Yes.
Table?
Table, very, very --
no, no, no, no.
No throw?
Very delicate
because it's very soft.
Okay.
Don Antonio tell you,
you touch your dough
like how you
touch your wife.
If you touch
very tough...
Hang on a second.
I'm gonna make a note
of that one. Okay.
That gentle?
Yes.
It's always
the same size, Robert?
Yes,
all the same size.
'Cause I just went
It's done.
And the last component, the most
key, important piece is...?
The oven.
It comes from Naples,
a wood-fire oven -- That's all.
It's volcanic stone.
Its mouth is very small.
This dome is very low.
Cook the pizza
in one minute and a half.
And it's a good thing
it only takes a minute
because Don Antonio's
has -- Count 'em! --
60 pizzas on the menu,
including the Pizza del Papa
with butternut squash
and zucchini,
custom made
for Pope John Paul II.
And then there's this savory pie
that's literally going nuts.
This, right here, is amazing.
This is pistachio and sausage.
So, these are pistachio we
make here in-house.
Pistachio with
Parmigiano-Reggiano and oil.
It's like a pesto
without garlic.
Yes.
Oh, man,
that looks good.
The sausage, we cook here
with Chianti wine.
Fresh basil...
and extra virgin oil,
of course, on top.
And fresh mozzarella.
And it go inside the oven.
Whoa!
That was scary.
You almost took that one
to the teeth, homey.
He's already ready
to turn it.
Yeah,
I check the bottom.
It's almost done.
I need to just...
That is so fast.
A little brûlée
on top.
Done.
Please.
Go ahead, 'cause it's gonna be
9,000 degrees, Geoffrey.
Yeah, go ahead
and burn your mouth right off.
I don't care.
The fresh mozzarella.
And the dough.
Look at how thin
that is.
My favorite part
of wood-fired pizza
is the little char
that you get on the bottom.
It really just adds
such depth of flavor.
That action going on
with this dough is outstanding.
What do you think?
It's light.
I mean, it's just -- You can eat
a whole pizza and feel great.
Yeah.
Life-changing pizza.
Fluffy, but it's still crisp.
It's got great texture to it.
It's great.
Great wasn't good enough
for these dudes,
so they took that crust
to the next level.
All right, guys.
Montanara Starita.
Thank you.
It's a fried pizza,
which is amazing.
Let's see it.
He's giving it the claw.
We make a hole because
then it will be -- puff up.
How long are we gonna be
in the fryer?
35 seconds.
What temperature?
We at 350 on that?
400.
These are
the sauces now.
This, we cook with little bit
of extra virgin oil and garlic.
San Marzano tomatoes?
San Marzano.
The plum tomatoes?
Yes, the plum tomatoes.
Little basil, Parmesan.
Smoke mozzarella
comes from Italy.
Here.
Go ahead. I got it.
I got it. I got it.
Whoa!
Wow!
That is smoke.
Smoke and salt.
Mmm.
Mmm!
And now...
That's it?
...inside the oven.
How long?
For another 30 seconds.
Be careful with that thing.
He's gonna kill you.
Oh, God.
Please.
Okay.
I just want to smear this
all over me.
I can't get it
in my mouth fast enough.
And no grease.
Unh-unh.
Zero grease.
That's
a different level, baby.
Who's got
the extra two pieces?
The smoked flavor,
the crust --
I mean, you do not
leave this crust.
I'm gonna finish
all of this up.
This experience
is overwhelming.
I mean, this has been
outstanding.
Thank you very much.
Chef.
Thank you
very much.
Don't leave me hanging.
Nice job.
You got to check this out,
and while you're in town,
stop by Geoffrey's place!
He's always available.
Did you
just throw that? Rock on.
Up next...
- Bada-bing?
-Yeah.
On a street corner
in the Bronx...
Low and slow, baby.
...true-blue barbecue...
That would challenge any good
Texas brisket right there.
...in one of the most unlikely
places ever on "Triple D."
It's a funky joint.
Great barbecue
out of a auto shop.
On "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives,"
we'll go anywhere in any weather
to find you the joints
that you want to know about,
like this place, MoGridder's,
stuck in the parking lot
of an auto repair show
in the Bronx, New York.
Gloria!
Inside a 35-foot trailer,
they're serving up
some barbecue so good
you'll think you're in Texas
or maybe Memphis...
Here's some
pig candy, baby.
...not...
The Bronx.
And check out
the Bronx brisket.
The brisket, it just falls apart
in your mouth.
Ribs, pulled pork, and chicken
slow-cooked in a massive smoker
and pulling in the crowds.
Barbecue's the best
over here.
In even the lousiest weather,
it's just that good.
Two racks of ribs.
Two racks?
Two racks.
Two separate containers.
Pulled up at the light
and looked to my right
and saw the truck and said,
"What?"
Had my first order of ribs,
and I've been hooked since.
It's only in the Bronx
where you can watch your truck
get a front windshield
and get some mean barbecue ribs
out here.
Getting a tune-up
and some ribs.
And you can order that
on the menu?
On the menu.
Today's special is ribs, oil,
and a filter special for $34.95.
Anything I should try?
We're doing a three-meat combo
to go home.
Oh, no. I said,
anything else I should try
when I bring
my car here?
Oh, when you bring
your car here?
Get a windshield.
I've done that many times.
Do you have any background
in the restaurant business?
Nah.
The guy behind all of this
is auto shop owner
Fred Donnelly.
What's next?
A few years back, he took up
barbecuing as a hobby.
Grab my ribs.
He started bringing in
samples for the customers
and ended up
with a trailer out front
and a dining room where
he used to have service bays.
MoGridder's.
MoGridder's
was a childhood nickname
my cousin used to call me.
What is a MoGridder?
We don't know.
How did he come up
with it?
- You could be a MoGridder.
-I'm a MoGridder.
You could be a MoGridder.
Hey, MoGridder,
what's happenin'?
Ribs are happenin'.
In the East Coast, I don't
hear so much about ribs.
In the South,
I hear all about St. Louis
or spare ribs.
And then on the West Coast,
it's all about baby backs.
Why'd you pick up
on the St. Louis?
I think it has a little more
meat than the baby back.
You think?
I think it has tons more meat.
Okay, we rub 'em down
in a dry rub,
MoGridder's seasoning.
It's got salt, pepper,
garlic, paprika,
and a few things
he's keeping to himself.
He dry-rubs the brisket, too.
We're gonna use garlic
first.
Then we're gonna put
some black pepper.
Do you not notice that
a windshield just went through?
No.
We do about 40 to 50 windshields
here a day.
So a windshield coming through
here in the middle of lunch
is not really
that big of a deal.
It's not a problem.
You won't taste it.
All right.
So these are rubbed down.
Gonna have
a nice bark.
These'll go on 225 degrees,
about 10 hours.
- Bada-bing?
-Yeah.
Never get tired
of that smell.
Nope. That's beautiful.
Okay.
Whoa.
Are you there? Fred?
Auntie Em?
Here you go, Guy.
There's some brisket.
Look at that.
Oh, boy.
Always load
the bottom first.
Otherwise, it'll tip,
and we'll have a mess.
Okay.
But we don't want 'em
touching
because we got to let smoke
go up between 'em.
And put that one
on the other side.
That one on the other side.
Pork butts?
Yeah. Here you go.
Okay. Pork butt.
Fat up?
Fat up.
We've got our brisket on.
We've got our pork on.
We've got our ribs on.
Let's throw some chicken on.
All in together,
but each item will smoke
for a different length of time.
Now, where are you getting
your wood from?
Don't say trees.
We get it
from the suburbs of Jersey.
They have
a lot of cherrywood.
They had a lot of apple orchards
out there.
I tell you, my team,
Motley Que,
I think they're gonna think
I'm a traitor.
I'm out here barbecuing
with this cat
on a corner in the Bronx.
This is odd.
Oh.
Now, the test.
Shouldn't come off the bone.
People say, "Fall off the bone."
Well, it falls off
in a spot.
You should be able to tell
where you just took a bite.
Nice bark,
nice crust up top.
Low and slow, baby.
That's great.
What do we pull next?
We'll pull the brisket off.
Check those out.
Man, that's great-looking bark
on there.
Look at that,
all nice and black.
That's not burned.
That's flavor.
If you cut it
with the grain,
then it's gonna be stringy
and chewy.
So you got to cut it
against the grain.
Right.
Oh. Look at that smoke ring
on that.
Nice and tender,
and the rub, the dry rub...
That would, uh...
That would challenge any good
Texas brisket right there.
- That's good stuff.
-Thank you.
So's the pork butt...
It just slips right out.
...which makes a mean
pulled pork sandwich,
and the chicken,
rubbed with salt, pepper,
and olive oil before smoking.
It comes
with a barbecue sauce glaze,
same with the ribs,
but they're killer
all by themselves.
You can get that
on the corner of...
Hunts Point and Randall.
Hunts Point and Randall
in the Bronx.
Which makes it
one popular intersection.
What are you gettin', Joey?
What are we havin'?
Two rib platters.
Two rib platters?
We do between
150 and 200 lunches.
This place rules.
Everything is good here.
The pulled pork, the ribs,
everything is delicious.
The sodas are
in the cooler on the side.
Don't go taking any more
like this guy Gene did.
- Okay.
Can you eat all that?
You gonna be able to finish
all the ribs?
And I think I could eat
a little bit more.
- Oh, you think you could?
-It's that good.
- Really?
-Yeah.
No commercial background
in doing this,
no restaurant experience.
You're knocking it out, man.
Good stuff.
Thank you.
I mean,
it's a funky joint.
I mean, we're eating great
barbecue out of an auto shop
and cooking it all
out of a monster rig.
I mean, in the world of dives,
my friend,
this is Culinary Dive 101.
Ultimate dive.
Coming up...
Look at that.
We're filling up
in Philly...
Who's the cook,
King Kong?
...at a spot
rocking the retro...
That's funkadelic, man.
...with a menu filled
with classic diner favorites.
Get it away from me
or I'm gonna eat it all.
In a world of 24/7,
when the sun's coming up,
well, that means
the end of a late night
or the beginning
of an early morning.
Either way,
you're gonna need some grub.
And the folks here at
The Dining Car in Philadelphia,
well, they got you covered.
Turkey --
whole wheat, mayo.
Thank you.
- Veil Parmesan?
-Mm-hmm.
I often have this
in the morning.
Creamed chipped beef.
It's good.
- You're gonna like everything.
-That's delicious.
Let me show you this
all-world chicken Caesar.
- Come on with me.
-First thing I think of is,
"What am I gonna get
at the diner?"
That's a tough call
'cause at this joint,
they've got it all...
They're always delicious.
They're always different.
...at any hour...
- Here you go.
-Thank you.
...with local favorites
like chicken croquette...
It's very good.
...and pot roast, Reubens,
cinnamon French toast,
even homemade bagels...
We have a night out,
and we always stop here
for breakfast.
Wow.
You girls roll hard
in Philly.
Oh, this is what time I normally
roll in for breakfast.
We had a long night
last night.
- Did you?
-We did.
If a customer wants to eat,
day or night,
he knows he can come
to The Dining Car.
Joe Morozin's been running
restaurants for years.
There you are, ladies.
He bought the original
Dining Car in 1961
and almost 20 years later,
replaced it with a bigger one
right next door,
now run by his three kids,
including daughter Nancy.
A lot of the customers came in,
like, 6:00 in the morning
'cause they wanted to be
the last one to eat
in the old diner
and then the first one to eat
in the new diner.
So, have you
been here before?
Oh, my God.
We come every Sunday.
Every Sunday?
Yeah.
We made it today.
- Today's not Sunday.
-I know.
Two times.
Every day?
Every day on weekdays.
Five days a week?
Five days.
Now, how long have you
been here?
32 years.
Long enough for Chef Larry Thum
to know exactly what folks
around here are looking for,
like this classic from the '40s.
- What is that?
-Chipped beef.
- Is it chipped beef?
-Yes.
My dad talked about it
when I was a kid,
about having it
in the military,
having it in the Navy,
but this is gonna be
a first.
What are we gonna do?
We're gonna put in some oil,
and then we're gonna put in
the flour, in the hot oil.
This is like a hot paste.
We're gonna pour the hot milk
into the roux,
and that usually thickens it
almost immediately.
All right.
So that's done.
So, what was this?
This was the eye of the round?
That was actually
a top round.
Okay.
So now we thin-slice this.
That's got a little kick.
I cut it in squares,
little cubes.
Now, remember,
we're gonna frizzle it up.
You're gonna what it
it up?
We're gonna frizzle it.
- Is that a cooking term?
-Yeah.
- Frizzling?
-Frizzled beef.
So this is just gonna put
a little crisp on it?
Yep.
Now, we're frizzlin'.
Chef McFrizzle.
And people
order this a lot?
70, 80 gallons a week.
You make 20 of those
in a week?
Sometimes, toward the weekend,
we'll make a bigger batch.
You have that smooth blandness
of the sauce,
and then you have the meat
that gives it the kick.
You know, the old standby
is always white toast.
Look at that.
Mm.
Oh, the toast makes it.
I used to hear people
complain about that.
It's gotten a bad rap,
but not when it's made right.
Not when it's made here.
Get it away from me
or I'm gonna eat it all.
All right.
Mm. Delicious.
Around here,
it's still a favorite.
And so's this local flavor.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's that?
That is scrapple.
Is it meat?
It's meat.
Actually, it's deep-fried
pork scraps in cornmeal.
The locals love
to talk you into trying it.
You're gonna be surprised.
I was born and raised
on it.
That's funkadelic, man.
Today is your birthday?
Yes.
How about a piece
of scrapple a la mode?
And it isn't just the scrapple.
At this joint, they're totally
on top of all the local flavors.
It's exactly what I used to have
when I was little.
Chicken croquettes,
we call 'em in Philadelphia.
Croquettes?
It's a very old
traditional diner item.
People years ago,
they would take their scraps
from their chicken,
roll it up, bread it,
and fry it up
and get an extra meal
out of it.
So it's making, like, a little
chicken-and-dough dumpling.
We just use cracker meal.
We use a milk egg wash,
and we use breadcrumbs.
So, now, what do we do?
Go fry these?
Gonna fry 'em up.
These go down, but they
got to be made in cones.
The traditional diner one
that's around here
is usually made in a cone.
You place 'em
on a bed of mashed potatoes.
Milk, chicken stock,
and parsley.
Right.
Hot, I bet.
It looks like
a volcano.
Bro, that is rich and big.
The sauce
brings it home.
- It's a filling Philly meal.
-Yes.
It's, you know,
one of those comfort foods.
Who's the cook,
King Kong?
But comfort food
at this joint
is more than just the basics.
Crepes Florentine.
It's one of their
specialties here.
This is one of the first menus
that we've ever come across
that we've seen crepes,
or crepes.
How do you say it?
Crepes,
but we don't make crepes.
We make crepes in Philadelphia.
What do people think?
I mean, you're in a diner.
It started off slow,
but then it started to catch on
a little bit at a time.
Let's get our crepe on.
So six eggs
and six extra yolks.
Right.
- Some milk.
-3 cups of flour.
Exactly 3 cups of flour.
Exactly 3 cups.
See that eagle eye?
Good eye, good eye.
So on the crepes,
this is called Supreme Sauce?
That's correct.
Okay, so chicken stock
going into some blond roux.
So that's gonna tighten up
and make, like, a chicken gravy.
That's right.
Sauté up
a little bit of mushrooms.
Now, this is not
traditional diner fare.
One of philosophies
is that when people come in,
we have a little bit
for everybody.
Cold crepe batter,
hot pans.
Clarified butter.
Little bit
of clarified butter.
Clarified butter.
I'd rather have
a little extra butter in 'em,
and you're gonna put in
two ladles full of crepe batter.
With that much butter,
I'm a little gnarly
about flippin'.
I mean, I didn't...
You bring it up and over.
Yeah, no.
Okay.
Want an apron?
- Ready?
-Looking good.
Wonderful!
Almost a nice-looking
omelet there.
This is crazy crepe.
It's crazy crepe!
Now what?
Sliced ham.
This ham,
what does this taste like?
Try a piece.
It's baked, smoked.
- Mm.
-Virginia baked ham.
I could have
6 to 12 pounds of that.
Natural, pure cheddar cheese.
Fresh-cooked spinach.
And we're just gonna
roll 'em up.
This is how
we roll sushi, too.
But then we'll just give 'em
a little bit of that --
You're just teasing me
with that.
That's all.
Mm.
That's really nice.
The kicker
is that Supreme Sauce.
Mmm.
We try to take crepes and make
comfort food out of 'em.
Welcome
to comfort crepe.
And the real comfort
for folks around here
is knowing they can count on
this joint 24/7.
Oh, the food's always been good,
and you can always
count on it being good.
This diner here
is gonna take care of you.
And they know me,
and it makes it nice.
You know,
you feel comfortable here.
Oh, I'm here all the time.
Get whatever you want
whenever you need it.
Right.
- Hanging in there.
-Yeah, not bad.
No. Not bad.
So, what are you gonna do now,
go to sleep?
Oh, my god. Yes.
Up next on this full hour
of East Coast cruising...
A little...
In Narragansett, Rhode Island...
You know what
you're doin', man.
...a place so crazy
about their burgers...
Whee!
...they just keep
the combos comin'.
That could be served on, like,
a grilled flip-flop.
Every other year,
the family and I vaca
here in Rhode Island, down at
the beaches with the in-laws.
Now, about 5 years ago,
we rented a house
here in Narragansett
about two blocks that way.
Now, I must have passed by
this place a half a dozen times
early in the morning,
and finally,
I'm gonna do
what I tell you guys to do --
That's slow down
and take a look around.
It's time I check out
Crazy Burger.
Fire Burger.
The Homemade Burger -- Awesome.
Moo-moo medium.
A new sensation
for your taste buds.
Chicken Marsala Burger.
My favorite is
the Goofy Gorgonzola.
Goofy Gorgonzola Burger.
Mushroom Burger.
Whassupy Burger,
coming up.
The owner has
a creative flair.
Chika-pow!
You think?
Whee!
But this is serious stuff
to owner Michael Maxon.
31 different burgers.
31 -- All these
different kinds of meats,
different kinds of breads,
funky sauces.
What's your first burger
we're gonna make?
The Whassupy Burger.
We have your 5 pounds
of Grade A beef.
We're gonna make
a little rub for it.
Roasted garlic, sesame oil,
Worcester-shis-shish-shire
sauce,
horseradish,
barbecue sauce,
and ground roasted fennel,
crushed red pepper, celery salt,
coarse ground pepper.
All right,
we're gonna grind this up.
Uhhhhh...
You made your own noise.
Just in case
it wasn't working.
Then we'll add it to the beef,
mix this all up.
You're really trying
to convince me
that you do that
with that spatula?
Thank you.
No, I do it.
Okay, this guy gets
a foot in there, I bet.
Okay, we're gonna
portion them out.
Seven ounces, cover them up,
hold them in the cooler,
and then
they're ready to go.
Next, we're gonna make
the wasabi mayo.
Correct. Add a few
little chipotle flakes...
to that.
A little...
Can I get
the Crazy Burger dictionary?
We're gonna
come out with that one.
This is prepared wasabi,
stir-fry sauce.
There's rice vinegar.
Mix this all up.
Wa-da-la-da-
la-da-la-da-la.
We've got the burgers done,
we got the sauce done,
let's go cook the burger.
All right.
We are going to
charbroil it.
Put a little dimple
in the top
to keep it
from getting to, um...
- Too...
- You know what I'm saying.
We got a nice
whole wheat bread.
Brush it with butter.
Slap it down here.
For this burger,
we make fresh onion rings.
These are red onions
marinated with buttermilk,
flour, salt and pepper,
and then breadcrumbs.
Okay, so, we fry these up.
So, now what do we do?
Flip this one more time.
Melt some Brie cheese.
Ooh, I like it.
Throw a little water
for steam.
Ooh, wa-wa!
Bep-bop, kshew!
All right,
I think we got the melty Brie.
We'll just place it
lovingly on the bun.
You want me to get
those onion rings?
Could you please?
There we go.
All right.
Those will go
right over the top.
A little ba-da-choom.
A little ba-da-choom?
And there we go,
the sauce on the side.
Now, this is the wasabi sauce
that we made.
Correct.
The whole-grain bun's
really nice
'cause you need something
that's got some strength.
Really good burger.
Nice Asian flavor.
Oh, and then the Brie.
Totally works.
Look at that.
Good flavor.
Oh, yeah.
Now I'm just gonna get
a little dip on the wasabi mayo.
That's really nice. Nothing
I would change on that burger.
Nice.
The Whassupy Burger.
Phenomenal.
Mmm. Wow.
It's just great.
It's got a really nice
wasabi kick to it.
The onions, the cheese --
It's amazing.
It's unlike anything
I've ever had.
But don't let
the name fool you...
'Cause it's not
just burgers.
The food is
absolute excellent.
What's so good about it?
You just know you're getting
fresh ingredients.
Making the food ourselves...
Bringing out the flavor
in things.
Like these...
Pacific Rim rolls.
...filled with
fresh roasted chicken
and a ginger-cilantro slaw,
hand-rolled and deep-fried.
Ah! I'd like to order
9,000 for a wedding.
And their fish burger...
The Luna-Sea Burger,
delicious.
Talk to me, Goose.
The Luna-Sea begins
with salmon.
Check for bones.
Take the skin off
in one fell swoop.
We're gonna cut it up
into grinder-size pieces.
You chop it up,
now you're gonna grind it.
Grinding makes a much better
mouthfeel at the end product.
Really?
So, we bring it back,
and then we're gonna mix it
with the pistachio pesto.
This part, we have basil,
roasted pistachios...
Roasted garlic.
Parmesan cheese, a little
orange juice, hot sauce...
So just some
regular, ol' hot sauce.
And we've got
a little salt and pepper,
which we're going to
throw in the pesto.
Put a little in the salmon.
While we're pulsing,
we're going to loosen this up
with a little olive oil.
So, we want a little bit
of texture in that?
We want some crunch.
I want to try this.
All right, try the pesto.
Mmm!
That could be served on, like,
a grilled flip-flop.
You have to mix it
with the salmon.
Throw some breadcrumbs
in here...
To bind it.
So now, we have this
all mixed up.
This is mixed up,
the burger.
I mean, this is mixed up.
So now
you portion them up.
And when we press down,
we don't care
if they're perfectly round.
Okay, now
we go to the oven.
We're gonna pop them
at 500 degrees.
Hot and fast.
Just barely cook them.
And then hit right to
the walk-in and cool them down.
Ba-choom!
I wrap it in some phyllo dough,
and we're gonna
griselle iatta casa bonay.
You just
made those words up.
Yes.
So we're gonna take
a couple sheets of phyllo dough.
We're gonna fold them
not quite in half.
Fold it
not quite in half again.
And no basting it
with any butter?
We use garlic oil.
Get that burger
in the middle,
and then wrap around it
nice and tighty-whitey.
Place it on a tray to cook it
for the second time.
500 again,
another 7 minutes.
Dough gets brown. Pull it out.
Cool it off quickly.
How do we heat it
for service?
Put a little butter
on the griddle.
This side down.
Put a little brown
on that side.
Little flippy-flip.
Just so
it's cooked through.
There we go.
We're gonna turn it over,
cut it in half, make it
look pretty on the plate.
Voilà.
That gets the orange
chili mayonnaise.
The flavor profile is huge.
The pistachio,
the crunch,
and the texture, and the bite
that gives you -- Great.
You know what
you're doing, man.
Thanks, sir.
Appreciate it.
You really know
what you're doing.
Luna-Sea Burger?
Delicately seasoned,
and with the sauce, it's great.
Good texture.
It's crunchy, and it's, like,
light. It's very good.
Four, five, six,
seven burgers.
This place is great.
Freaky Fajita Burger.
Everything's different.
You could do breakfast, lunch,
dinner, dessert,
and really anything
in between.
Nice job. I give this a
whap, whap, whap, whap, whap!
Aww, that's better than
a pah-bah-niki-nah
that you gave it before.
Coming up...
In Providence,
Rhode Island...
What a neat place.
...a 24/7 local landmark...
It'll be interesting.
like everything here is.
...serving their own spin
for over 60 years.
Yeah. Coming. Every day.
See you every time.
I so dig doing "Triple D"
on the East Coast.
One of the main reasons is
all the history.
Here I am, Providence,
Rhode Island,
at a family-owned restaurant
that's been open
for more than 62 years.
Now, a lot of businesses
have come and gone in this area,
but not this joint.
They're still serving great food
at reasonable prices
to college students
because that's what
Louis Family Restaurant
is all about.
Meatloaf dinner!
Everyone knows about this.
It's kind of, like, a tradition.
Coming here is like family.
It's like having breakfast
or dinner in your home.
A number one over hard.
It's cheap. It's huge.
Good food?
Great food.
Thanks to John Gianfrancesco...
Western with cheese up.
And his brother, Albert...
Good.
Louis is Louis,
the way it's always been.
And Louis was your dad?
Yeah, he was a cook
in the Army.
And when he got out,
he opened this joint.
53 years later,
the boys took over...
Turkey dinner up!
...serving
scratch-made favorites...
The same as the first time
I walked in the door.
...and old standards
done John's way.
Barbecue-chicken ravioli!
Johnny always
gives us surprises. It's fun.
I've never had
a barbecue-chicken ravioli.
Today you will.
We need to make
a barbecue sauce.
Tomato sauce
and onions.
Honey, vinegar,
orange juice.
Garlic, the paprika,
red chili flake.
Coriander, sage.
The oregano.
Pepper, salt.
Rosemary, parsley,
and then caramel coloring
that makes it dark brown.
That's it.
Whoo!
16 items,
16 tickets to Flavortown.
All aboard!
Can't believe I just said
the "all aboard" part.
Okay, so,
the sauce is done.
We're gonna put it
on the chicken.
So we make sure that the sauce
gets on the flesh.
And we want to make sure
that they're gonna taste it.
Now we're gonna
go to the oven with this?
Yes.
How long?
Two hours.
What temperature?
About 300.
Maybe we'll
raise it up later.
If we're feeling wild.
The chicken ready?
Yeah. A little warm.
Let it cool down
and then shred it?
We're gonna
cut it in little chunks.
Chicken in the bowl.
Ricotta cheese.
Frozen spinach.
Parsley, prosciutto
that we made.
Oh! A whole bunch
of cheddar and jack.
Some Parmesan.
Just easier if I say it for you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
White onions
and some mozzarella.
And then
we're gonna put six eggs.
What are we gonna mix all this
in there, Johnny?
It seems like, uh...
Tell us what we've got,
Johnny.
A bowl.
It's a little small.
Yeah. Whoo!
Wow. That's
a good-size bowl.
Okay, so, the eggs go in.
You whisk those up.
Whisk which?
Or just use a spoon?
We're gonna
use our hand.
We kind of have to
work it a bit.
Whose recipe is this?
Father had
a cheese ravioli
without the chicken
and the prosciutto.
Now we grab the dough...
That we made,
put flour everywhere.
You start it out
on the highest number first.
You got to do it a couple times
the big way.
Dial it down to --
Whoa, you're gonna go that fast?
Living on the edge.
I can play that.
Wow.
All right,
now it's your turn.
You want me to do
the doling out of the...
Yes.
Okay, I just know that we can't
have it on the edges.
Looking good.
And how many
come with an order?
12.
That's one order.
Get after it, Rocky.
So, now these are done?
Yes.
Now that is
a stuffed ravioli.
Boil them in a little saltwater
till they float.
There you go.
They're ready.
That's your 12.
And top them
with some marinara?
Hey, that's only 10.
Ah, make sure
I had enough dough.
You only gave me 10!
Look at that.
Mmm!
Oh, my gosh.
Look at the huge pieces
of chicken that are in there.
That right there is as good
as any ravioli you will find.
Off the hook.
The spinach, the cheese,
stuffed full.
That's just awesome.
Made the barbecue sauce,
barbecued the chicken,
made the marinara
and handmade the ravioli.
Mmm!
Uh-huh. Yeah. Coming. Every day.
See you every time.
They're really good.
It's one of my favorites.
It tastes like he knows
what he's doing.
Spinach pie,
going out!
Everything's meant
to please the customer.
I like how you can get
a turkey dinner at 11:00.
Or if you need lasagna
at 5:00 in the morning.
Hash up!
Corned beef hash from scratch.
Grilled pumpkin muffin.
You just know it's golden.
Totally delicious.
Totally.
Blueberry pancakes.
Pumpkin pancakes.
There's just so many options.
I got the granola pancakes.
Yep, with homemade granola.
These are so good.
Granola pancakes?
It'll be interesting.
Like everything here is.
Some old-fashioned oats,
some wheat germ.
Oh, you're getting healthy
on this.
Now some bran.
It's gonna make a nice strudel-y
kind of thing when it's done.
Strudel-y?
Yeah.
Sesame seed.
I'm gonna
put this in the oven
about a half-hour
at 250, 300.
It smells toasty,
doesn't it?
It does smell toasty.
I'm gonna
add some fruit.
Blueberries
and cranberries?
Yeah. Just another
10 minutes in the oven.
Just for granola.
Smells good.
We're gonna add some cinnamon,
honey, and some maple syrup.
Raisins, too.
You're gonna
stir it into this?
Yes.
A little more honey.
Yeah.
Do you like my drizzling
technique?
Yes.
That's it.
Now we're gonna make
Louis' pancake batter
from his Army cookbook.
Eggs and sugar.
Instead of lard,
we're gonna use corn oil.
Milk.
I didn't bring
my Gallagher shield.
Now we're gonna add some spice.
Nutmeg --
That's how little, actually.
Turmeric.
Turmeric
in pancake batter.
Vanilla, with
a little touch of rum in it.
Vanilla with rum?
Louis liked rum.
And now, our dry ingredients,
Flour and cake flour
and baking powder.
Instead of sifting,
we're rubbing.
He's rubbing.
We're watching.
And this goes in there.
Gonna whisk?
Go ahead.
There you go. Don't let me
get ahead of it or anything.
Just dump it right in.
Then we're gonna dump
the granola right in this?
Yes, probably slowly.
How about I dump it all in,
and then you try to whisk it?
That's it.
We're ready to go.
Put it on the grill.
How many pancakes
come with an order?
Three pancakes
with an order.
That's a lot of pancake.
Aren't you hungry?
I think that's it.
Your order's
already ready.
I'm intrigued
with these granola pancakes.
Good pancake.
Oh, good.
It's got texture.
You get some of the oat
in there.
You get some of
the fresh fruit,
some of the raisin,
some of the hot pancake
on your flip-flop.
It's not super sweet.
A really good pancake.
It's so moist
and so much flavor in it.
Can you eat
all those pancakes?
Oh, yeah.
Big portions
of really delicious food.
Poached passion
Florentine up!
Whatever he's doing back there,
he's got it down.
Loaf of Johnny bread!
It's cheap,
and it's so good.
I love you guys
sticking to it,
Keeping the business open,
having it available
to the college students.
Congratulations.
What a neat place, man.
Up next...
Ah!
...on Baltimore, Maryland...
Winner, winner,
rice-ball dinner.
...an old-school
Italian market...
Is this
one of the best?
This is the best.
...keeping tradition alive
in the kitchen.
This is how
its supposed to be done.
Yeah.
This is
what your mom said?
That's right.
With a name like Guy Fieri,
you know I love Italian food.
If you find yourself
in Baltimore,
and you're looking
for some good Italian.
Check out this, DiPasquale's,
making their own pasta,
doing their own mozzarella,
casing their own sausage,
and doing it old-school
in the back of a market.
Is that gonna be
for here or to go?
Can I have
a honey-glazed ham?
It started wh,
"You make me a sandwich,"
There you go.
Then add more tables
and more tables.
And that led into this.
A full-menu...
Do you want that
heated or cold?
...of home-made Italian.
I'm having the lasagna.
The spices, the sauce --
absolutely delicious.
The arancini, I've never had it
like this before.
It's always good.
- The kind of cooking...
- That's good.
...Joe DiPasquale and his wife,
Sabrina, grew up with.
I use what my mother
and my parents have taught me,
what my husband and I learned,
and put it all together.
- The food is amazing.
- Very authentic.
More like old-school.
When I walked in,
I could smell it --
from the fresh mozzarella
to the sausage.
This is all home made.
So, you make your pasta noodles
for every lasagna?
Mm-hmm.
Oh!
Now, why do you
make the moat?
Well, because
I'm gonna scramble the egg.
Why not scramble them
ahead of time?
I like doing it this way.
This is how
it's supposed to be done?
This is
what your mom said?
That's right.
Pound of flour, five eggs,
a little salt,
and a lot of love.
Yes.
Then, actually, just
a little drizzle of olive oil.
Just about a teaspoon?
Yeah.
You want to get it
to where
it just stars to form together
and then grab it out.
That's right.
You're gonna let it rest
for about, what --
20 minutes, 30 minutes?
About 20 minutes.
You cover yours with, like,
a little damp towel?
Yes, I do.
So it doesn't dry out.
This will be enough
to make our lasagna.
Yes.
We're gonna quarter this.
We knead them down
a little bit.
Well, then let me play.
Okay. Not too wide.
Because it won't fit
in the machine.
Yeah, that's good.
Take it...
Let it
draw through itself.
And it's a nice,
thick pasta sheet.
Now fold it into itself.
Back to the press.
Change the notch,
press again.
Seven times just to get us
to this stage.
These'll just get a chance
to kind of hang out a bit
until we're all done,
and then we'll use
a little salted, boiled water.
And a little bit of olive oil.
Give them about 2 minutes.
I'm just gonna grease the pan
a little bit
with some butter,
a little bit of marinara.
Marinara that we made.
Look at the color
on that. Mmm!
Go over to
our pasta sheets.
Look at that!
Lay it down in here.
Right, and you overlap it
because that helps it
stay together when you come out
with the spatula.
That's right. A little bit
of sauce. Parmigiano first.
This adds a little bit
of saltiness to it.
Then I go
for the ground beef.
Now fresh ground
that we do,
a little garlic,
a little salt and pepper.
Parsley, a little bit
of the Mozzarella.
Nice and melt down.
And that'll melt
and spread a little bit.
It will spread out.
And then we're gonna go
for the Ricotta cheese.
- Nice and light.
-Mm-hmm.
How many layers of this,
three?
Three should work.
So we go back down
with the noodles, sauce,
Parmesan, ground beef,
Mozzarella, Ricotta,
and then again.
-And again.
- We bake open on the top layer.
-Yes.
for about 45 minutes.
Fantastic.
A-ha, look at that.
See those layers
in there?
Oh. Mmm.
That's delicious, exactly
how it's supposed to be done.
Nothing's pouring out.
You can taste the meat.
The Ricotta stands out.
That's up there with any
of the best lasagnas there are.
- Great job.
-Thank you.
I can't get enough
of the filling, a lot of flavor.
This is where
I get authentic lasagna.
I've never had a lasagna
like this, out of this world.
All that they serve here is done
in a traditional setting.
You can come here and do
your grocery shopping, also.
Not only can they shop,
they get a bite.
They get an espresso,
a glass of wine.
They do everything wonderfully.
I love their sandwiches.
Homemade Italian subs
are just excellent.
This one stacked
with Prosciutto,
capicola, and soppressata,
and they've got
their own sausage...
You can definitely tell
that this is authentic,
sweet Italian sausage.
...handmade from scratch.
It really mixes well
with the fresh Mozzarella.
Yep, they're doing that
fresh, too.
How many pounds of Mozzarella
do you guys make a week?
200 pounds.
Because they're using it
on just about everything
from lasagna to sandwiches
and for the bocconcini,
the little ones,
in caprese salad.
It's not a recipe.
It's a technique.
You have to make
a lot of batches in order to...
To really
get it straight.
Starting off
with the curds.
Small batch of curds,
submerged.
No salt or anything
in this, right?
No.
- It's regular hot water.
-Yes.
You want them all
to kind of soften up
and start
to break down.
Yeah,
so I can work it.
Look at that.
Make sure
all the lumps are out.
Okay. Didn't I see this
in "Gladiator"?
The sacred
Mozzarella oar.
We want to eventually get it
to a ball.
Kind of like
I'm working pizza dough.
Now we want to go
into the salt water.
Yeah, this solution gives it
its salty outside
but a sweetness inside.
-Right.
It also helps
in the preservation of it.
Yes.
Cover them, and they sit in here
for about 40 minutes.
And then
we eat them.
Mozzarella is so fresh.
When you pull it up,
cheese just keeps coming.
You can taste
all the fresh flavors.
So this is the Mozzarella
that we made.
You need
to taste it.
Mmm, nice, little salty
exterior, firm on the inside.
Mmm,
it melts in your mouth.
Definitely a little richer,
more flavorful.
You can't find this
in any restaurant.
This is the real-deal Italian.
Everything you'd expect.
Lasagna.
I come here
to get some nice pastas,
salads,
and things like that.
Definitely some of the best food
I've ever had.
I feel like
I'm at...
- In Italy.
-Yeah, Italy.
We're down at Sicily
for this one.
The arancini -- it's delicious,
and it's all melted together.
Amazing in the center.
Are we gonna fry these
or bake them?
We are gonna fry them.
Ha.
- My favorite word.
-"Fry."
- No, ha.
- Let's begin this.
-This is actually beef stock.
Half gallon,
and we make that here?
Yes, we do.
Gonna wait for that to boil.
We're using
the arborio rice,
which is a nice, big,
thick, short-grain rice.
Mm-hmm.
Great to work with
when you're making
some kind of rice ball.
It's easy to mold.
Going to give this
a quick stir.
Just let
this simmer.
When are we gonna add in
our ingredients?
I'm gonna add in
a little bit of sea salt.
Okay.
A little white pepper.
Some white pepper,
a teaspoon of butter.
- All right.
-When it's halfway cooked...
We throw in
the saffron.
- Look at that.
-It's beautiful.
The saffron
can't last that long.
- That's right.
-Let it bloom and then boom.
So we let that finish cooking,
and then what's gonna happen?
Let it cool down
for about 20 minutes.
Now are we doing this
traditional style?
Yes.
- I'm learning it the right way?
-Yes.
Grab some rice there.
- Make a little ball.
-Little?
Now we're going to press down
on it,
make, like,
a little well in there.
- My well of friendship there.
-Sure.
We're gonna grab a little bit
of this ground-meat mixture
that we made earlier.
Beef and pork
with marinara and veggies.
- A little Mozzarella.
-Mm-hmm.
Now we kind of bring the top
over, so we've got to get --
So that gets buried
in the center.
Then you're gonna dip it
in your little flour and water.
- Then into the bread crumbs.
-That's right.
- Just putting a crust on them?
-Yes.
- 350-degree oil?
Okay, and then we'll serve
them with a little bit
of this warm marinara...
- Marinara sauce.
-...or tomato sauce.
Just 'til they're nice
and golden-brown.
- Which one you like?
-I think that one's perfect.
Okay.
The melted Mozzarella.
It's beautiful.
Pour a little sauce
over it.
Mmm.
If I was taught
how to make those at home,
I never
would have left home.
The rice has got a nice,
little firm center to it
but a nice creaminess
on the outside.
Mmm.
That is
just fantastic.
I love the peas
in there, too.
Mm-hmm.
That's about it
right there.
Winner winner,
rice-ball dinner.
First thing that hits me is the
crispiness of the outer crust.
The meat and the rice and the
Mozzarella all blend together.
It's really good.
One meat lasagna.
The best home-cooked
Italian meal you'll ever have.
On a scale of one to 10,
I'd give it a 12.
In the world
of Baltimore Italians,
is this one of the best?
-This is the best.
I would recommend it
to everybody. It has an
authentic Italian feel.
Look at
the portions.
They give you the portions
on how big you are.
Is that what you do,
you scale in?
- And then they serve you...
-Right, yeah.
I don't come back here
just for the Mozzarella
and the pasta and the sausage
and the whole thing,
just to hang out
with these cats.
So that's it for this edition of
"Triple D," but don't you worry.
There's plenty more to enjoy.
It's all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
- I'm hungry.
-I'm starving.
I know
it doesn't look like that.
I have
my Barney shirt on.