Hey. I'm Guy Fieri.
And we're rolling out,
looking for
America's greatest diners,
drive-ins and dives.
This trip,
a full hour
of classic burger joints...
This is kind of
like a burger emporium.
...from Cali to Jersey...
Cheers.
...Minnesota to Oklahoma.
This is off the hook.
We've got lights-out
local landmarks...
Been doing it that way
for 50 years.
50 years.
...piling 'em up.
I don't know where to post up
on this thing.
...inside out...
Oh, that looks killer.
...and even with a skirt.
That is the craziest thing
I've ever seen.
Plus, peanut butter
near Purdue...
That much?
...and a Boston mac attack.
Where has that been
all my life?
So get ready
to go old-school...
That's what a burger's
supposed to be.
...A-plus real deal.
That's all America, baby.
That's all right here,
right now
on "Diners, Drive-ins
and Dives."
It's not often
that you find yourself cruising
a residential area looking
for a place to eat.
But the locals
here in Glenview, Illinois,
say, "This is the spot."
Right behind Grandma's house
is this joint.
And they say,
"The burgers are the bomb."
- So great.
-Oh, that looks killer.
There's a lot of fun
in the bun.
Part of growing up in
the northern suburbs of Chicago
is that you come to Hackney's.
- You sure do.
-That okay?
After 80 years,
for folks around here,
it's just that simple.
Number-one-selling item
on the menu here is the burger.
Is the Hackney Burger.
That's right.
- Just the straight-up burger.
-The straight-up burger.
An 8-ounce oblong
they've been getting
from the same butcher
for 30 years.
I order the Hackney Burger
every time...
- Every single time?
-...because it's so good.
There's
the inside-out burger
stuffed with cheddar and bacon.
It's a mess.
It's so juicy.
And the blue cheese
burger, with the cheese
mixed into the meat
before it's grilled.
The patty melt,
the brick of onion rings
and a huge menu of all kinds
of home-cooked favorites
and home-baked desserts.
Pretty much, you can't go wrong
with the menu.
But when folks think,
"Hackney's,"
the first thing
they're thinking is the burger.
It's the best burger.
It is.
And has been since
Prohibition back in the '20s,
when Bebe Hackney
started serving burgers
at the illegal beer joint
she was running
on her back porch.
They gave the food away
in the early days.
- Kind of like peanuts at a bar.
-Exactly.
You come
and drink the beer
and then we'll give you
the burger for free.
- Exactly.
-Wow.
I wish that was still
the program.
Okay.
So it's not free anymore.
But it really is a heck
of a burger.
And this is kind of
like a burger emporium.
Um, this is like
a burger emporium.
Stuffed, you can get 'em
done with blue cheese.
You get 'em
the original way.
And check out the original way
they're still making
the inside-out burger.
I mean, this is, like,
the technique here.
This is the technique
that we use
to make
the inside-out burger.
What is this,
just a regular old lid
off of one
of the mayonnaise containers?
This is our very
high-tech gadget.
Yes.
I can see that.
And, uh, we take approximately
half of the burger.
And we shape it out.
And you got to pack it
in there a little bit.
Next thing that we do is we put
in the cheddar cheese.
Try to keep it a little bit
towards the middle
in order to, uh,
let the edges
of the burger meet.
Otherwise, when you do cook it,
it falls apart.
It starts coming
out the sides.
Okay.
-Last, the, uh, chopped bacon.
Now, how many
of these burgers will you make?
- 50, maybe.
-50.
Yeah.
You could count 51 today.
Okay, 51, good.
- That's our inside out, right?
-That's our inside out.
- That one's ready to go.
-Okay.
No mayonnaise,
mustard, nothing.
That's right.
Just lettuce and tomato.
Oh, man.
That looks great.
Little crunch in the bacon.
- Good meat.
-Tons of flavor.
Oh, that is great.
Soft and cheesy on the inside.
Tastes bacony.
Or maybe you'd rather go
with the blue cheese.
We have a lot of blue cheese.
We -- we take our --
our, uh, Hackney Burger,
8 ounces.
We throw about another ounce
of cheese inside.
Mix it up.
-And mix it all together?
- Exactly.
-Let's do it.
Take about an ounce.
And then it
just all melts inside.
And then
what else goes in this?
No, uh, it's just a Hackney
Burger and blue cheese.
That's it. The Hackney Burger
with blue cheese.
That's right.
Once it's mixed,
it's slapped on the grill
and even more blue cheese
is melted on the top.
Mmm.
All the blue cheese.
That is rich.
Don't get emotional
about it.
Wow.
Why not?
They even bake their own buns.
The bread's off-the-hook.
Smell.
And the special dark rye,
they've been serving
on the signature Hackney Burger
forever.
It's a tradition.
Because you to go to Hackney's
and you get the Hackney Burger.
And to go with it,
a huge brick of onion rings.
So this is burgers plus, now.
-This is burgers plus.
Tell me that's not
six extra days at the gym.
Their fried onion
rings are fantastic.
The onion ring loaf
starts here.
That's right.
Okay. Now,
who made this recipe up?
It was on a Friday fish fry
back in the early '50s.
And on a certain
Friday night,
they ran out
of, uh, lake perch.
And a customer
had ordered it.
And Carmen, who was a cook here,
said, "In the meantime,
I'm gonna fix up something
you're never gonna forget."
So she came.
She breaded up some onion.
And she fried it up
in a basket.
And then that was the birth
of the onion rings.
It looks like you've
done it before.
Yeah.
No.
Grandma made us
pass this test.
You know, we had to make sure
we could dump it good.
- Hey, hey, hey.
-Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
You're not taking it
anywhere.
Oh, man.
Just like decades ago.
And that's the whole idea
with everything here.
So many places
change after a while.
And this one
has stayed true
to their
original concept.
It's our joint.
It's about the food.
It's about being here.
It's about the people.
It's just...it's nice.
Feels good.
Oh, yeah.
Tastes good, too.
This is awesome.
That's all America, baby.
This is great.
Next up, in Somerville,
Massachusetts...
You can do it, man.
Work out harder.
...a righteous burger spot
capping things off with comfort.
Putting mac and cheese
on it's pretty gangster.
Plus, the bomb burgers
in Hackensack...
I could have
18 or 75 of these.
...at a Jersey diner straight
out of Central Casting.
Don't make a wrong move
in this joint.
You know, I think one
of the big misunderstandings
about "Diners,
Drive-ins and Dives"
is that I eat at burger joints,
like, all the time,
which is not really the case.
So when I do eat
at a burger joint,
it's got to be a place that's,
you know, outside the box.
So here I am outside of Boston
in Somerville, Mass,
to check out
the Boston Burger Company.
We got another Killer Bee.
It's a great representation
of Boston.
Three monsters up.
He has the best burgers
in town.
I wouldn't eat a burger
anywhere else in Boston.
Homemade, fresh.
You don't feel like you're
eating something out of a box.
Handmade and grilled up
daily by owner, Paul Malvone...
Table two, hot mess.
...who mailed in a job
at the post office
to get back
to his restaurant roots.
I was cooking for a
little while, and I liked it.
And when I got out of it and
got into the postal service,
I missed it.
So, I decided
to come back to it.
Order's up!
And he came back in a big way,
creating 28 different kinds
of gourmet burgers.
Got the Killer Bee first.
It's so good.
It's got, like,
bacon and onion rings
and cheese and the sweet,
delectable barbecue sauce.
It's so good.
-Got the Pilgrim burger.
Turkey burger, stuffing,
cranberry mayo.
It's basically Thanksgiving
dinner in your mouth.
But he's got this one burger...
The Mac Attack.
...that's the dictionary
definition of comfort food.
Mac and cheese in a burger,
two best things.
You'd totally recommend it
to anybody that's a burger fan?
- Highly recommend.
-It's wicked awesome.
I'm gonna make
some mac and cheese.
the cheese sauce.
Take our chopped onions,
the butter.
We're gonna let that
sweat up.
I'm gonna throw the flour
right in.
Okay, so we've got
the roux built,
cooked out the flour,
got the onions in there.
Now we're gonna go
with some milk?
We're gonna go
with some milk.
Cheeses.
American.
Throw some cheddar.
Cheddar, wicked cheddar.
We definitely got
the accent going.
We'll work on that.
We're gonna throw some
shredded cheddar jack cheese.
So stir it up,
get it done.
Boil some water, make some
pasta, and there we go?
Absolutely.
All right.
Cheese sauce is made.
Gonna throw
a little hot sauce.
We're gonna mix this up.
Good-looking mac.
New ingredient I'm adding
to my mac and cheese
flavor profiles, hot sauce.
Where's that been
all my life? Andale.
All right, I'm gonna throw
some Parmesan,
a little Pecorino Romano.
How you doing
with that right there?
And we're gonna throw
in some salt and pepper.
We're just gonna mix this
right up.
It's like a workout.
You're a champion.
You can do it, man.
Work out harder.
Now you dump it in the pan,
let it set up overnight?
Absolutely.
And why are we
letting it set up?
If it's too hot,
it's gonna fall apart.
Too hot,
it'll fall apart?
Fall apart when
it gets on the grill.
We're gonna grill
the mac and cheese?
We're gonna throw
a burger right down.
Okay.
Nice 80/20.
Never frozen?
-Never frozen.
We make every one of these
by hand every day.
Throw on some bacon.
The bacon's cooked to order
each time?
Yes, sir.
This way, it comes out nice.
Gonna be nice and pliable.
Bun's on.
We toast all our buns.
- And the buns are local?
-The buns are local.
Throw that right
on the grill,
put some
cheddar jack cheese on.
I'm gonna get, like,
one of those road construction
signs on my heart.
Look at this.
I've seen ridiculous
in the burger world.
This might have to be
a contender.
Mac Attack.
Look at that goodness
from the flattop.
Mm.
I'm telling you what, pretty
rockin' mac and cheese, bro.
Mm.
Really good meat
in the burger.
It's got good tooth to it,
good chew,
good texture, good fat.
The bun does a great part,
where it just kind of absorbs
into all these flavors.
If you're gonna go
for a big burger,
putting mac and cheese on it
is pretty gangster.
Go big or go home.
Or come here
and go home big.
Table four, Mac Attack.
All right,
hope we're hungry.
I've had
a lot of mac and cheese,
but this takes the prize.
Best I've ever had.
It's gooey and cheesy
and stringy.
There is just something
about cute girls
eating big burgers, huh?
I'm gonna make a calendar.
Watch the burgers.
You make the chips.
You make the slaw.
You make your sausage.
You do all your mayos.
You're pretty much
a scratch-made burger joint.
Pretty much.
Try hard.
- I'm impressed.
-Thank you.
Give me a hug.
There you go.
See?
Now he's in it to win it.
Well, it's lunch time.
So we're headed to Hackensack,
to a diner
that's a burger joint.
And I mean, a burger joint.
- Who's next?
-Six burgers.
Best burgers I've ever
had in my life.
Would you like onions
on it?
You don't get this
anywhere else.
Delicious.
Every time you come by,
you just got to stop in.
It's never frozen.
And it's always fresh beef.
Totally fresh.
Oh, and they cook it
right in front of you.
It doesn't sit
under a heat lamp.
Three double cheese
for you.
And here at the White Manna,
the question isn't do
you want a burger...
Good? Mmm.
...it's how many?
Can I get
three cheeseburgers?
Can I get six burgers?
Now, are you supposed
to eat 'em dainty like that?
Or do you usually just do
a little pile shove.
No. I just try
to eat it dainty.
They've been cranking
out these tiny sliders here
for more than 60 years.
Ronny Cohen and his brother
bought the joint in '86
after moving here from Israel.
I got two cheese with onions.
One cheese without.
And kept almost everything
just the way it was.
I'm the only one
that stays the same, you know?
Culinary epicenter.
If you be out of this town
for 30 years,
you won't recognize
anything but White Manna.
But you'd recognize
this joint.
I'll take the small box.
You hold this.
Okay.
That's good.
We get chopped meat
delivered every morning.
That's some good-looking
chopped meat.
Show me this little thing
you did.
Uh, okay.
I do, uh, slow motion.
- Okay.
-I grab a piece.
And then I...
That's it.
And now, how many of these
will you make in a day?
Well, we roll
about 800 to 1,000.
And then, uh, sometimes
you got some more...
- A week?
-A day.
Are you next?
Go ahead.
Cheese.
-Now what do we do?
Okay.
This is a single.
And this is a double.
-Two of 'em stacked up.
Sliced onions,
we slice every day.
That's thin.
Oh, right into the patty.
Right into the patty.
- The cheese.
-Cheese.
The bun on top.
So when the onions are cooking,
the moisture
that's coming
out of those and then
the moisture that's coming
out of the meat steams the bun.
And the cheese melts
all in the same little package.
Exactly.
And I take one, and...
Okay. So, you pick it up
with the top off it.
Oh, oh.
- Oh, look at this.
-It's correct.
Just press it in
and push it out.
Press it.
Don't make a wrong move
in this joint.
Cheers.
Fresh made
in front of you.
Not frozen.
Honestly, I could have
18 or 75 of these.
How many will you have
in a day?
Two doubles,
two singles.
I normally get between four
and six.
10 to 12 burgers each.
So we made an order
today of 111 burgers.
It's -- it's a big hit
in the area.
Everybody knows about the place.
Everyone comes here.
This is kind of like
the all-American style of food.
I mean, was this something
you were thinking about?
In the beginning,
I looked at is
as a business,
to be honest with you.
And I...
-It wasn't a life.
It was just a business.
But the more I was getting
into it,
and got to love it.
It's like a family.
And it's fun.
It's fun to work here.
Oh, thank you.
Coming up,
in Sacramento, California...
Dude,
you are full throttle.
...a funky little dive...
This really works.
...not messing around when it
comes to their cheeseburgers.
That is money.
You know, there's a lot
of great food here
in Sacramento, California,
between the Sierras
and San Francisco.
But probably a place
you wouldn't expect to find
would be a burger joint
where they put as much cheese
on their burger as they do meat.
You're gonna love it.
Oh, oh.
A 1/3-pound burger
and a 1/3-third pound of cheese.
It's called
a five-napkin burger --
messy, juicy and tasty.
It's the squeeze with cheese,
an off-the-hook burger
covered in cheddar.
Best burger in Sacramento.
That is the craziest thing
I've ever seen.
Well, you see, the cheese
just hangs down here.
It's very crisp and just cheesy.
Kind of wakes up the taste buds
before you bite
in the big, juicy burger.
What time do you open?
10:00.
And they're already
lining up...
I drive across town
for this.
...at this tiny 12-stool dive
called the Squeeze Inn.
It's hard to find a seat
in this place.
So when you find one,
you got to sit down
and enjoy it.
I think that's why they must
call it the Squeeze Inn.
You're all set.
Have a good day.
Owner Travis Hausauer bought
this place six years ago.
And he's keeping a 30-year
tradition alive and kicking.
That one got a little big
on me there.
But we're gonna, you know,
it's just gonna right there.
We'll fold it up.
That is
a good-looking burger.
See, I like flattop burgers.
-Yeah.
I enjoy 'em.
'Cause you get that little --
you get that little
caramelized crisp there.
It's almost, uh...
- It's all good flavor.
-It's the fat.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, there's a little crunch.
We're gonna throw
some cheese on here.
Just grab a handful.
When it comes out,
I don't know, it's about
1/4 pound or what.
But we lay that on there.
Did they --
did they ask for extra?
- No, that's normal.
-That's as much cheese
as it is burger.
-Yeah. Pretty much.
Then comes
the totally out-of-bounds way
they finish 'em off.
A handful of ice.
All that's gonna do
is generate steam.
And we'll take
the bun like this.
Throw it on top.
We'll throw a little
more ice on there.
And then you're gonna
put the lid on.
This does not make --
I mean, it makes sense.
Who did --
who invented this?
I think the previous owner
got it going.
Pretty unique and original.
- It's pretty unique.
-People love it.
This is
what's so cool about it.
It cooks the cheese.
You add the steam factor.
Steams the bun.
Keeps the burger juicy.
There's components
of cooking going on here
that I don't think anybody
would have designed it and said,
"This is how this is
gonna work."
But this really works.
-It does.
I mean,
this really works.
- And then pull the hood off.
-Wow.
So that's it right there.
See how the cheese
is all melted down on there?
Now that bun, see that?
Now, where --
where does all the cheese
go with it?
-It's all got to go with it.
Oh, man.
To fry cheese like that.
Yep.
See.
It's bubbling up there.
A lot of times,
if you do it right, you can get
it to the counter in time.
The cheese
is still bubbling.
That is money.
Look at that.
Absolutely wonderful.
How much of that
do you get through?
Surprisingly,
almost the whole thing.
- No.
-Yeah.
The standard squeeze
comes done up right.
Mayonnaise, mustard,
long-sliced dill pickles,
couple tomatoes.
The long-sliced
dill pickle,
that's also part of the...
-It is.
And it's
a refrigerator pickle.
So it's not one
of those real heavy, vinegary.
It's more of a crisp
pickle taste that...
- Really?
-...really jumps out at you.
Oh, it's great.
You got all your options, too.
Bacon burger.
Mushroom burger.
We could add jalapeños,
avocado.
I can help whoever's
next to order.
And when the Squeeze Inn
gets rocking...
That's an order for 10
right there at 11:30.
...so does Travis.
Well, there's four
ready to roll.
That's crazy.
So then we're just gonna
come in and slice it.
Watch your toes, man.
It's hot stuff.
Wrong day
to wear flip-flops.
Who cooks with you?
I'll do all
the cooking by myself.
Up to 10 hours a day, non-stop.
Dude,
you are full throttle.
And don't think this is easy.
You got to really cut.
Push hard.
There you go.
You got to get force on that.
- Dear God!
-Okay.
- The burger.
-Where?
- Burger?
-There. Yep.
There, you go.
It's hard to figure out
where you land it.
I can't even
find the burger in it.
I guess it's okay
to make a mess here.
If you don't make a mess,
you're not doing it right.
You're not doing it
right?
Doesn't have
the right flavor.
I think I got to
loosen 'em up first.
Ah-hah.
That's the key.
Coming over hot.
-Perfect.
You're there, man.
I might as well
just go home.
- Yeah.
-You're dialed in.
You might as well
go home.
And even if you master
the melting of the cheese,
you still got to master
the eating of the cheese.
Got to grab it just like that.
Known at the Squeeze Inn
as the skirt.
Now, you took
your skirt off.
I take part of it off.
Eat it.
You got to fold it in.
Then you got to rip the side
a little bit.
Now, do you eat the --
the part
that you're tearing off?
-Yeah. Of course.
Hold the burger with one
hand and never let it go.
And you eat your fries
with the other hand.
It can be a bit messy.
I just go like that.
Make a berthing spot.
There you go.
Yeah.
It tastes great.
That thing is money.
Fast-food chains
across America
want their burger
to look like that.
- Yeah.
-But it's about the --
it's about the real deal, man.
-It is, yeah.
Not bad for a total
newcomer to the restaurant biz.
Actually, I worked
at a school for years.
I never, uh, never even thought
about a restaurant.
But when an old Army buddy
told him the Squeeze Inn
was up for sale,
he decided to take a chance.
Do you miss school?
-Not at all.
Within months,
he mastered the squeeze
with cheese and the rest
of the menu, too,
like tacos made
from rib-eye roast.
Hey, that's a pretty
premium cut of meat.
- Yeah, it is.
-And smothered in cheese.
Yay.
That's a good taco, man.
And steak teriyaki
with a killer homemade sauce.
It's wonderful.
And Travis is turning this
into a family affair now, too.
- All right, the double.
-That's my daughter, Morgan.
My future daughter-in-law,
Katie.
- Now, this is your son?
-That's my son, Brandon.
Are you gonna take over
the empire some day?
Yeah.
Some day.
The empire thing's no joke.
And you keep winning
best dive restaurant?
Yeah. We have
for four years in a row now.
- "Best dive restaurant."
-Yeah.
For the food and the
experience of chowing down
in what might as well
be a phone booth,
well, a phone booth
with a patio.
Have y'all been here before?
-Yeah.
And hundreds
of fanatic regulars.
- Squeeze burger.
-A double.
Look at the pipes.
Of course you can eat
the double, man.
- That's right.
-The squeeze with cheese.
Look at that.
'Cause for tons of folks
around Sacramento,
the Squeeze Inn is a habit
no one wants to break.
- Awesome.
-You guys have this attitude
about sticking
to what's real,
sticking what you already did,
sticking with what worked...
If it works,
you don't want to change it.
You promise my doctor
won't see this, right?
We have that
confidentiality thing.
TV host and some dude
that's on...
Yeah, Russ.
Don't worry, man.
Up next,
on this full hour
of knock-out burger joints...
How many patties you think
we've done so far?
...in Cloquet, Minnesota...
Healthy with that, huh?
...a timeless joint hitting
the griddle for generations.
When you think about
the all-American drive-in,
that's the kind of burger
they're talking about.
And in Oklahoma City...
Let's go cook these.
...a stand-out spot sticking
to the tried-and-true.
No frills,
straight-up quality.
I know why
this place is packed.
"Triple D" in history.
I think it's one of the things
I love about this show.
It's finding the joints
that have been doing it
old-school for generations.
So here we are, about 20 miles
south of Duluth, Minnesota,
off Interstate 35
in a lumber town called Cloquet.
Now, check it out.
These folks have been rocking
over 11 1/2 billion
burger patties
since they opened in 1960.
And here's the kicker --
They're only open six months
out of the year.
You wrote in about it.
We're here.
This is Gordy's Hi-Hat.
- Bacon cheeseburger up.
-You wrote the e-mail.
- Why'd you want me to come here?
-'Cause it's off the hook.
Mushroom and Swiss.
- Did you write in to me?
-A couple times.
And you like it
'cause it's old-school.
They're still doing it
the old-fashioned way,
making the patties
by hand.
- Two hamburgers.
-Look at that.
The burger is always
so juicy and good.
Hand patty
every day.
1,500 of 'em.
That's about a ton a week.
Been that way
since Gordy Lundquist...
- Can I help you?
-...and his wife, Marilyn...
Order up.
...opened the place
50 years ago.
Bacon deluxe.
And when son Dan took over...
Hi.
What can I get you?
...he knew better
than to mess with tradition.
Double cheese
with the works.
What the number-one-selling item
on the menu?
Double cheeseburgers with
Marilyn on the grill, my mom.
Now we're gonna make
a double cheeseburger.
- With all these patties?
-Put all those patties on.
I heard that you run
this better than anybody.
I do.
I dump all the onions.
Onions are just sitting here
all the time, going?
All the time.
Then, we have our pepper
and salt mixed together.
- Healthy with that, huh?
-Then I start flipping 'em.
As soon as they go on,
you're already starting
to flip 'em, and...
I flip 'em right away.
- How many times you flip 'em?
-Just a couple times.
Then we'll put a bun on
and get 'em as they want 'em,
if they don't want mustard
or whatever else.
- What about those onions?
-Put some onions on.
Like your cheese melted?
-Please.
We always melt the cheese.
Couple pickles.
So it get all built
right on there.
It's all built on there.
And then I just
put it on the bun.
The bun tops are toasted.
Then we put it
into the container.
And this is
the number-one seller?
- Number-one best-seller.
-Mmm.
There's something about when
you cook a burger on a flattop.
Builds a little crust.
Then, when you melt
American cheese on it,
it gets a creaminess about it.
Look at all that juice.
When you think about
the all-American drive-in,
that's the kind of burger
they're talking about.
Everything's fresh.
You make it yourselves.
Been doing it that way
for 50 years.
- 50 years.
-Pretty awesome.
- Awesome.
-Cheeseburger.
Oh, man.
These cheeseburgers are great.
Beef is incredible.
Everything's fresh.
Double cheese.
The burgers
are just really good.
427.
You ever eaten here twice
in a day?
Oh, yeah.
But in the Minnesota winter,
you can't eat here at all.
It's closed six months
out of the year.
I know.
You guys should put
a moose out front.
Tell people the park's
closed for the season.
It's huge when they open.
And after six months
of waiting...
Cheeseburger and an order
of onion rings, please.
...Gordy's customers
know what they want.
Fish sandwich, the mushroom
and Swiss and the onion rings.
Need a ring, please.
The onion rings is the best
I've ever had.
We just
serve 'em with catsup.
- With what?
-Catsup.
I think
that means ketchup.
Is this how you do it
right here in the...
- Perfect.
-Oh.
Those are great.
-That's some awesome.
The food is wonderful.
It's a very classic diner.
Proud to have capped
a classic menu...
Burger's up.
Burger, fries
and a shake every time.
Blackberry and a raspberry.
Let me just help you out
with that.
- Roast beef sandwich up.
-The food's great.
It's a family tradition.
-Chili and a blackberry.
- Thank you.
-It's comfort food.
It warms you up
from the inside out.
Your Coneys are up.
Just great, down-home cooking.
They do it old-fashioned way.
-You have a nice evening.
We walk in.
They know us by name.
And you're welcomed,
no matter what.
Dan, your fish
and chips are up.
There's a lot of places
in northern Minnesota,
but not like Gordy's.
Really?
I mean, this is an institution.
- Gordy's is the best.
-Thank you.
This is kind of therapeutic,
you know, Gordy.
Oh, yeah.
It's good for you.
It's a happy time, right,
when we don't see any red
on the outside?
Perfect.
Yep.
So how many patties
you think we've done so far?
About 40, 50.
We're not even one-tenth
of the way done.
No. No.
We're not even close.
Awesome.
I'm glad we could spend
this time together.
Here we are, northwest area
of Oklahoma City.
Locals around here
call this Ten Pen --
10th at Pennsylvania Avenue.
Now, like just about every
neighborhood, there's the gem.
And here at Ten Pen, the gem --
it's a righteous burger
at a joint called Nic's Grill.
- There's one.
-Love the burgers.
It's great.
-Best burger I've ever had.
- There you go.
-Burger that makes you happy.
It's always served
with a smile around here.
- Nic, the owner...
-Here's your burger, Bubba.
- He's just a great guy.
-Your name's not even Nic.
Justin Nicholas.
-Yes.
They called me Nic
as a kid.
Milo, yours for here.
-Never did restaurants before.
Never.
Till 12 years ago...
Some mustard
and mayonnaise.
...when he bought a house
that came with two apartments
and -- oh, yeah --
an abandoned diner.
You're a landlord,
a homeowner
and a restaurateur
all within 50 feet.
- About like that.
-About like that.
Good thing, too, 'cause
he's here all the time.
I do breakfast
all by myself.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
You get here at 6:00 a.m.
to do breakfast?
Yeah. I start
breakfast about 7:00.
The best breakfast in town.
No doubt.
He's got everything in here.
Look.
There's some love right there.
-There we go.
Javon comes in at 10:30.
All right.
And he helps me
through lunch 'cause
it's takes two of us at lunch.
-Oh, yeah.
'Cause Nic's turned
this 15-seat joint
into a local legend.
Really well-known
throughout the city.
There you go.
And at lunchtime,
folks pile in
for another local legend.
- Mmm.
-Onion burger.
The onion burger's
the best thing ever.
There's quite a few places
in Oklahoma
that serves 'em.
-Two burgers.
But Nic's famous
for the way he does 'em.
- No one else even comes close.
-What are we doing?
This patty next
and my burgers.
It's about a half a pound,
somewhere around there.
75/25 burgers.
You just roll 'em up
and patty it.
I try not
to pack 'em too tight.
No, 'cause you push all the fat
out of 'em when you cook 'em.
- Absolutely.
-And that's it.
Let's go cook these.
-All right.
First, I usually put some onions
and get them sautéing.
- Little butter.
-Lot of butter.
Get 'em grilling
down good.
And put our burgers on.
You threw the ball
of fun on there.
And then
just smash it on there.
I like that you get
the buns are kind of
getting cooked on there
and soaking up a little juice
while they do.
This griddle's pretty hot.
The hotter the grill gets,
the grease gets to flying.
And that's what glazes
the buns over.
Puts a little extra.
You see the way his eyes
sparkle a little bit
when he starts talking
about that.
It scares me.
The onions just sit there
and do their magic.
If you cook 'em too fast,
they skin up, lose the juice
and all that.
-That's a mess of onions.
And what can I get
with these as a side?
French fries
or mashed potatoes.
Well,
let's do some fries.
That's Javon's department,
one spud at a time.
He cuts 'em up to order.
7,500 pounds a day.
Cook 'em all
in peanut oil.
Peanut oil takes a little
more heat and not burning.
Put the cheese
on the burger
at the same time
that I drop the fries.
And then it gives
the cheese time to melt.
You see, it's starting
to glaze up.
All right.
Let's get this baby off.
Bring the fries up.
Let 'em drain off
a little bit.
- Is that a normal setup?
-That's a normal setup.
Dude, that's huge.
Look at that monstrosity.
Served with more fries
than I'm gonna be able to eat.
Mmm.
That's great, man.
Look at all that juice
running off that.
Can't beat that.
That's what a burger's
supposed to be.
Onions are killer.
No frills,
straight-up quality.
I know why
this place is packed.
It almost melts in your mouth.
Like, it's so fresh.
The juiciness.
And it's a handful.
It just runs all over the place.
It's great.
Only burger joint I've ever
seen get served with a fork.
I eat mine with my hands.
I don't need a fork
like the rest of them do.
Oh.
Gets a little saucy here
at the counter.
- Everybody loves the place.
-Thanks, buddy.
Sort of self-taught
whatever I --
I guess I do my restaurant.
May sound crazy,
but hey.
Right, wrong or in between,
that's what I do.
- Welcome to Nic's.
-What you having?
He passes the test
with all of us.
Everything here's good.
I've had all the specials.
There you go.
And you could set
your calendar by him.
- Tuesday special.
-Nice, big, thick pork chop.
There you go.
Here's your meatloaf.
Meatloaf on Fridays.
- And it is fantastic.
-Mmm.
That is comfort food
101 right there.
There's your chicken, Bubba.
Fried chicken, burgers.
All right.
I'd serve one thing here.
Burgers.
Potatoes and chicken, too.
-All right.
You only go back to places
that you really like the food.
In dinerese, he said,
"This is off the hook."
Here you go, Bubba.
It's the best place
to come in town.
I see why everybody
lines up here.
Ten Pen's lucky to have you.
You sure are the gem
of the neighborhood.
-Well, thank you.
Thanks, bud.
Coming up,
in West Lafayette, Indiana...
That's a good burger.
...a place keeping tradition
alive and well...
When did Ben Franklin
invent this one?
...while sneaking in
some untraditional toppings.
I want to go home.
I want my mom.
I'm here in West Lafayette,
Indiana.
You know, the home
of Purdue University?
And two things come to mind.
One, how did the Boilermakers
really get their name?
And two, what in the world
would they be serving
at a place called
the Triple XXX Drive-In?
Triple XXX.
This is ready to go 'cause
I don't see flour, right?
Okay.
One answer is burgers,
burgers and burgers.
Is it a good hamburger?
Look at that bite.
The burgers are excellent.
As for Purdue...
Without Triple XXX, Purdue
would be incomplete.
The Boilermakers' nickname
may have come from the fame
of their engineering instruction
in the 1800s.
As for the fame
of their athletes,
it's a local obsession.
Check out the wall
at the Triple XXX,
where they've even got burgers
named for former players.
Like the Bernie Flowers
with a Hunk of Onion
or the Drew Brees
Breakfast Special.
I would choose Triple XXX
over fast food any time.
Because for more than 75 years,
the Triple XXX has been way more
than the average burger joint.
This is a tradition that,
like, everybody knows it.
They know that the building
is orange and black.
It's, like, an icon.
And owners Greg
and Carrie Ehresman
are committed
to keeping it that way.
We don't call 'em hamburgers.
They're steak burgers.
- Chopped steak.
-Steak burgers.
Never hamburgers.
- They're called chopped steaks.
-Chopped steaks.
- Chopped steaks.
Since 1929.
All cut and ground
fresh right here.
And not just any steak, either.
Top-choice sirloin butt.
I mean, look
at the marbling on that.
You could cut that
into steak just by itself.
- That, we have done.
-I imagine you have.
And it cooked quite well.
I've seen enough
cut, cut, cut.
I want to see
grind, grind, grind.
All right.
Here we go.
It looks like
we are making
a ton
of multicolored spaghetti.
Wow.
That is a nice --
that's a nice mix
between, uh,
between
fat-to-meat ratio.
It's a real nice blend.
Nice red, deep, rich color.
I mean, look at that.
He turns it all into patties
the same way it's been done
for more than a half a century.
When did Ben Franklin
invent this one?
This is the Hollymatic.
The Hollymatic
Super '54.
What year
was this thing made?
1954.
No.
Yes, way.
1954.
I didn't say "No way."
So if I don't say "No way"...
-I can't say "way"?
- ...You can't say "Yes way."
-Yes way.
'Cause it makes you
sound like...
- Let's reshoot that.
-...it's warm up here.
Okay.
So, no way.
- Yeah.
-No.
That's -- that's...
-Oh, I missed it.
I missed my cue.
That's where you say,
"Yes way."
It sounds
as old as it looks.
Sounds like it's just right
on the edge of breaking.
It does, doesn't it?
But it gets the job done.
You take 'em three
at a time.
I feel like,
uh, Lucille Ball.
Pull it.
There's your
third one there.
Now you're back in rhythm.
-There you go.
It's like meat poker chips.
Yeah.
I'm all in.
And so's Greg,
who can't remember a time
when he wasn't hanging out
at the Triple XXX.
As a customer growing up...
Dad always sat in the
corner at number 27.
And then I kind of
went down the line.
...with his wife here
when they were dating.
Finally, his parents
buying the place.
Him working with them,
then taking over
with Carrie 8 years ago.
How are they doing running
this place since you left?
- I haven't left.
-You haven't really left.
I know you come in
and grind the meat.
Best thing they have
is their double cheeseburger.
The secret to their burgers
is something
totally out of bounds.
- More flour.
-More flour.
-Drag a little up.
Okay.
Drag a little up.
Right.
Put her down there.
Whale on it.
-Okay.
Put her on the grill.
Beautiful.
- That's it?
-That's it.
On the grill.
-On the grill like that.
- Yeah.
-Huh.
Just a touch of oil.
You're doing good.
You need a rubdown,
we'll call the people in.
- Okay. There we go.
-That's good.
See, I love that.
I got to try that.
This is
the coming-of-age burger.
As a kid, I always head up
the counter with Dad.
He would have this big,
fat double cheeseburger.
- Okay.
-And I always thought, "Man,
whatever I get big enough,
that's when I get that..."
-Whenever I'm a big guy.
Whatever I'm a big guy,
I'm there.
That's what I got to get.
Barney, one day, decides,
who was the cook
at the time,
decides that I'm ready
for the double cheese.
- Time.
-It's time.
So he makes it for me
and brings it out himself.
And just looks at me
with a big grin on his face.
And he said,
"There you go."
And here we are.
-And that was it.
That was it.
Double cheese.
Cheers.
-You got it, brother.
All right.
Oh. Oh.
That's a good burger.
Now, Barney himself
wasn't a double cheese guy.
So if you order the Barney
burger, you're getting this one.
Barney loved to have
a thick white onion cut raw.
But you can't do that to...
- Most people can't handle that.
-I understand that.
- So we go with grilled onion.
Or you could have
a burger with your breakfast.
Want to put gravy
on the potatoes
of the Drew Brees
just like that.
Lay it on there.
That goes back in.
And there's your
Drew Brees special.
And check out
the Dwayne Purvis Burger.
Peanut butter.
Get a big slab of that.
And you just take it
and just lay it on there.
- That much?
-Nice.
Well, you got to have a taste.
We got to put tomatoes.
Got to put
some pickles on it.
Put a little bit
of lettuce
and some onion,
fresh-cut white onion.
- Have you eaten this?
-It's a love --
You either love it
or don't like it.
And I'm -- I'm a...
He loves it.
- And there you have it.
-I don't care for it.
I envy you
for the first bite.
That's awesome.
That is --
that's gonna be great.
-Go ahead.
No. No.
This is yours.
I absolutely don't enjoy that
at all.
I want to go home.
I want my mom.
Okay.
Not exactly my thing.
But you can't argue
that whatever they're doing here
is definitely working.
If you don't go here
as a Purdue student,
then you're doing
something wrong.
Where did the name
Triple XXX come from?
That's a long story.
Brand of root beer.
Oldest brand of root beer
in the United States.
In the '20s, there were
100 Triple XXX franchises
around the country.
That ended years ago,
but this place kept the name
and the root beer.
Has that sarsaparilla...
-It's not as sweet.
Yeah. It's got more --
more bite in it.
At the Triple XXX,
there's no breaking
from tradition.
- Exact same machine.
-With everything.
The pork, the burgers,
even your basic breakfast.
The group over there
was all breakfast and pancakes.
You're all omelets.
If you're gonna be anywhere
near Purdue, Triple XXX
is by far the best food
you can find.
The best time is when that rail
is from here to here.
And it's jammed up.
Tickets are stacking on the end.
People are walking
in the door.
That's the best.
It is -- it's a riot.
It's a lot of fun.
-No way.
- It is a heck of a lot of fun.
-Oh, yeah.
Just 'cause
when I say "No way,"
what would you say?
"Way."
I got like
three no-ways on you.
Finally.
Up next, in Ann Arbor, Michigan.
Baby burger, Mommy burger,
go to the hospital burger.
...a crazy campus hot spot...
Dave, Dave, Dave, Dave.
...where powering down patties
has become
a collegiate competition.
Okay.
That's it.
So when I'm cruising the quad
at the University of Michigan
in my Mac '67 Camaro,
a question comes to mind.
Where should I eat?
Now, if you ask anybody
in the student body where to go,
for the bomb burger,
they're gonna say,
"Krazy Jim's Blimpy Burger."
Regular buns, regular bun.
What you having, girlfriend?
I need two doubles.
It's the best burger
you can get. Mmm.
This tastes better
than anything else.
Who's next?
- You love the Blimpy, don't ya?
-What do you want?
I want a bacon,
lettuce and tomato.
B L what?
At this joint, you may
know what you want...
No, like, I want a hamburger
with bacon, lettuce and tomato.
No. No.
But you better know
how to say it.
You want a double
with bacon on it, okay.
Yeah.
That's what I want.
There you go.
That's what you want.
And you've got
to order in order.
What are you having, sir?
Sides, then size...
How many patties
did you say you wanted?
...then grilled toppings
and bun...
You have nothing grilled
on yours, sir?
- No.
-Why not?
...before you even think
about choosing your cheese.
American.
What I want to know
is do you want a bun?
That's real important to me.
- God, I'm nervous for ya.
-I know.
I'm about ready
to have a nervous breakdown.
We've only made two patties.
Yeah!
Davee Askew's
been doing this forever.
I just love this job.
I'm gonna cook for you.
I've gotcha.
I got you, baby.
How long
you been doing this?
Uh, I was 14
when I started working here.
Alongside Rich Magner...
What do you want
on your burger?
...who was a college kid
at the time.
And I worked, uh, part-time
off and on for four years.
When Rich came back
and bought the place
more than two decades later,
he changed almost nothing.
Yes.
From ordering etiquette...
- Anything grilled?
-No, ma'am.
- Thank you.
-It's not the military.
Yes or no, ma'am?
...to the burgers themselves.
From singles
to a stack of five...
- Okay. I'm the queen.
-...or any size you want.
Could I get, uh,
10 on a kaiser.
There you go, baby.
With almost 30 toppings,
cheeses and buns
to choose from...
-What are you having on this?
...the possibilities
will fry your brain.
Get a quad on onion with bacon.
Triple with bacon,
banana pepper.
Double on onion, Swiss cheese,
banana peppers,
pickles and ketchup.
- Anything grilled?
-Uh, no, thank you.
Good.
I don't want to do it anyway.
And don't be fooled
by the floor show.
Lean back.
Hey.
These are
the real-deal burgers.
Outstanding.
Absolutely awesome.
And the real foundation
you believe of this meat
is fresh-ground
by you every day?
Yeah.
And we're gonna double grind.
- Okay.
-Never been frozen.
Now we're gonna make 'em
into the 10 balls per pound,
which is
1.6 ounces a ball.
That's right.
8 ounces for 5,
which is
16 ounces for 10.
We go through easily
500 pounds a week.
500 pounds.
That's 2 tons a month.
Some are quints.
Some are doubles.
-Okay.
What kind of burger
would you like?
Let me get a double with,
uh, hot peppers,
onions on pumpernickel.
I need a triple bacon
sesame bun.
She has no idea
what's coming.
Can I get a quint, onions,
peppers, bacon, salami
and mushroom?
-Yes.
If I forget it,
you just eat it.
Uh.
-Look at that.
Mayonnaise, mustard, ketchup,
lettuce, pickle, onion
and relish.
There you go.
Baby burger, mommy burger,
go to the hospital burger.
Think I'm gonna start
with the little one,
huh.
Mmm.
That meat is so tender.
Wow.
That's tasty with
the cheddar, the peppers.
The beauty
is layering it.
You get all your flavors
mingling just the right way.
I don't know where to post up
on this thing.
Look at the festival
of funk.
So much salami.
Call my mommy.
That's one of our biggest
expenses, is the napkins.
And for some folks,
even these burgers
are better with something
fried on the side.
You have to get a fries
to go with your burger
just to top it off.
They've got
deep-fried mushrooms...
Delicious.
...cauliflower,
broccoli and zucchini.
The zucchini is one
of my favorites.
And the onion rings...
These are the best onion
rings in the world.
...they take three days to make.
Ah, beauty, beauty, beauty.
The first two
just to dry 'em out
so the batter will stick
the way it should.
First day,
the onion comes in.
And it gets the skin taken off,
the ends cut off.
And it gets thrown in a tub
and refrigerated for a day.
Second day, gets sliced.
Go back in the bins.
From the third day...
-Dipped into the batter.
And then, uh,
thrown in the breading.
And taken out on the line
and served that day.
So I guess the sweating
of the onion idea
is when you cook it,
the moisture would want
to expel out of the onion,
which would blow
the batter off.
- Exactly.
-Man, I cannot believe
how that batter
holds on to those rings.
I'm having, like,
a crunch fest.
These onion rings,
really,
are up there
in onion rings.
- Thank you.
-I mean, you guys
should be proud of those.
But as good as the rings are,
the big show
is still the burgers.
- Delicious and messy.
-Next.
And you'd better be ready
to pack 'em away.
Triple with bacon,
egg, cheese, grilled onions.
Let's see. There's
the single, the double,
the triple, the quad
and the quint.
So why stop at five?
10 patties?
Yep. Mushrooms, onions,
Swiss cheese.
I'll just keep my hands
and feet
inside the ride
at all times.
Turns out there's a whole
competition thing going on.
Dave, Dave, Dave, Dave.
- And we don't promote this.
-No, no, no, no.
The record stands
at a little over 4 pounds.
And no one's breaking
that today.
But records are still a risk.
There's a double snack bite
with a pullaway cheese.
Dave Williams is going
for a personal best of 20.
How are you feeling right now?
-I'm hungry.
Hungry.
Oh, you're hungry.
Get the forehead.
-Need a pit crew in here.
Some girl showed up
right here on her 21st birthday.
Looks like she wants
to go for 21.
And Lauren Lobert is serious.
I'm a hockey player.
I'm an eater.
What's the most
you've done?
Um, 10 in 7 minutes
and some french fries
and dessert.
But today for her 21st birthday,
Lauren Lobert's going
for 21 burgers.
I'm doing three sevens.
- Three sevens.
-Yeah.
7, 14, 21.
Are you really gonna
be able to do 21?
Oh, for sure.
I think I'm in love.
That is one juicy-looking
burger, though.
Delicious.
Dave, Dave, Dave, Dave.
Round of applause.
That is 20 patties.
He got his 20.
But she's still chasing 21.
I see the end is near.
-Yeah.
- You got it.
-Do it.
Lauren, Lauren, Lauren,
Lauren, Lauren,
Lauren, Lauren, Lauren.
Okay.
That's it.
Am I catching some eye water
over here?
Ow.
- I'm crying 'cause I'm so happy.
Don't leave me hanging.
So that's it for this episode.
But don't worry.
There's plenty
more joints to find.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins
and Dives."
My girl, Rachael Ray,
she gave you props
about your burgers?
-Yes.
I got a hug on the --
on the show.
You hugged?
Really?
Don't think you're getting
that from me.