Hey, everybody.
I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
[ Laughing ]
...we're piling on the pork...
I like me a tender hog foot.
-Yes.
...and some hearty homecooking.
I'd eat that every day.
Check out these monster
chops in San Antonio...
Holy moly!
...pig's head tacos
in New Orleans...
They're gonna flock-o
for this taco.
...plus, Southern bird meets
Far East flavor...
"A rad place to jam
and killer chicken."
...alongside knuckles
that pack a punch.
Dude, that's righteous.
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives."
♪♪
So, I'm here in New Orleans
on Broad Street,
just a few blocks
away from Canal
that'll take you right down
to the Quarter.
Listen, I love coming
to this city.
You got great people, amazing
food, all kinds of characters,
you got the party,
you got the history,
and listen, I'm here
to check out a joint
that's got all that
under one roof.
This is Marjie's Grill.
Charred pig tail
in the window.
I love this restaurant.
Fresh cracklings
for you guys.
Nothing like it in town.
Southeast Asian Southern
barbecue is what we call it.
FIERI: And it's what you get
when Marcus Jacobs
and Caitlin Carney
travel through Southeast Asia
and bring new culinary tricks
to Big Easy cooking.
Louisiana, Mississippi,
Gulf Coast ingredients
seasoned with Thai, Vietnamese,
and Lao flavors.
Well, you guys are just
gigantic copycats.
This is crazy.
It's new. I think he invented
a whole new genre of food.
FIERI: And apparently,
a whole new language.
Honey butter yardbird.
Da whoda wini henay?
-Honey.
-Butter.
-Yardbird.
-Honey butter yardbird.
My favorite chicken
in New Orleans.
Ah, man. It's the smoke --
the grill in the back.
It's got this amazing chili
and herb sauce with garlic.
You can't beat it.
This is the chicken spice.
This is what we use
to rub our honey
butter yardbird.
Let's see it.
First, we go
salt, black pepper,
paprika, white pepper
right there...
-Okay.
-...garlic powder, onion powder.
-Japones?
-It's like a Japanese chili.
Add dried
Vietnamese chilies.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Did I miss this?
The slogan, man.
Marjie's --
"A rad place to jam."
That's the best line ever.
Now we're gonna butcher
the chicken -- spatchcock.
But you did it down the breast
and not down the back.
Correct.
This way,
it gets a lot of that
smoke flavor in the breast...
-Okay.
-...from the grill outside.
-This is the setup.
-Yeah.
So, we're just gonna put it
right on here
over our burning oak logs --
about two hours or so.
Love it.
Only in New Orleans.
All right, next up...
-A chili garlic sauce
to serve alongside it.
-I dig it.
We add some shallots.
So, these get pounded up.
-Next...
-The garlic, chilies,
raw Louisiana cane sugar,
lime juice, and fish sauce.
All that together.
I'll have that on any...
bath mat.
So, we got our chicken
all glazed up here with honey,
butter, and some more
of that chicken spice.
Okay. And this is one of
the staples of the house.
Definitely.
This is my favorite thing
that we ever cook here.
Some of that
chili garlic sauce.
And it gets finished
with a little French sea salt.
♪♪
I'll tell you what --
that's good eatin'.
I got a sweet glaze
and smoke taking me
into great Southern chicken,
and all of a sudden,
I come into fish sauce
and chilies.
Yeah.
And, I mean, I think
that it bridges
the Louisiana influence
and the Southeast
Asian influence.
I don't know how much
it bridges it,
as much as it creates
its own new superhighway.
This garlic sauce
should be bottled.
This chicken -- you get
the heat, you get the sweet,
you get the vinegar, you get
the spice, you get the salt.
You're setting people up to be
disappointed next time
they have to eat
just regular smoked chicken.
Dude, that's righteous.
It should say, "A rad place
to jam and killer chicken."
SERVER: Your honey
buttered yardbird.
The chicken is unbelievable.
MAN: The chili sauce --
you dip it
and you just keep coming back.
You know, you can spend
about three hours in here.
I ain't lying --
I did it before.
MAN #2: I come to Marjie's
because it feels
like you're at a dinner party
every night.
-Where did the name come from?
-My mother.
She passed away
when I was younger,
and we just wanted
to honor her.
-What a cool way to do it.
-Yeah.
We got Som Tam
with a knuckle chicken quarter.
MAN #2: I always tell people,
you just got to come,
you got to sit down, and eat --
it's gonna be amazing.
I've tried things that I would
have never tried
at any other restaurant.
Crispy pork knuckles.
There's fish sauce
on the knuckles and fresh herbs
that you wouldn't normally
find with Southern cuisine.
All right, brother.
Tell me all about it.
JACOBS: We're gonna take
these split pig feet,
boil them off,
and get rid
of some of that funk.
-Get rid of the funk.
-A little salt.
While that's going, we're gonna
make ourselves a nice,
flavorful, crawfish-boil-style
braise to cook the feet in.
We got three gallons of water...
-Got it.
...our soy sauce,
fish sauce...
Copious amounts of garlic.
...cut lemons, dried chilies,
Japones, of course.
-Okay.
-And some satsumas.
That's what
I was gonna put in.
Yeah.
That's Louisiana citrus.
Some onions, and...
-Crawfish boil.
-Crawfish boil seasoning, yes.
-Got it.
We're gonna simmer it
for, like, 20, 30 minutes,
strain this out,
and then cook them
in the flavored boil
for about two
and a half, three hours.
-I like me a tender hog foot.
-Yes.
Yeah, you don't want them
al dente.
And then, we'll drop
in the fryer.
Crisp up
the skin on them,
hit them with a little
black pepper.
Fresh cracked.
This is a mix of fish sauce
and lime juice.
This is cane syrup.
Scallion, right here.
Fresh chilies, torn mint,
torn basil,
and a little cilantro.
Oh, you should smell it.
As soon as those herbs hit those
hot knuckles, they just...
As I'm cruising down the street,
I'm telling you,
I'm not expecting
these flavors inside of here.
So, knuckles go right on
and we get all of
our goodies in there --
some of the herbs,
some of the chilies.
♪♪
Mmm!
I've had the Southern
delicacies of pigs feet --
pickled pigs feet typically
is how you get them,
but this right here
is probably one of
the best representations
I've ever seen.
-Thank you.
Put a completely different
spin on them
with those herbs
and that fish sauce.
It's tender, it's crispy,
unique, over-the-top flavor.
It's using
a part of the animal
that doesn't get
as widely recognized,
but I'll tell you what --
you know what you're doing.
Mmm!
I got to go.
Yeah.
See ya.
SERVER:
I have your crispy pig knuckles.
They're so amazing.
You just have to really get
in there with your hands,
take them apart,
get sticky.
The fresh herbs are real
aromatic on your palette.
You know, the fish sauce,
the chilies, the lime juice --
they're perfect.
Caramel-encrusted yardbird,
right up.
Every time I come here, I have
a good meal and a good time.
Name says old school, the style
and energy says fun,
the creativity
in the kitchen says respect.
You're given a culinary passport
right on Broad Street.
-Thanks, man.
-Crushed it, homes.
I'll be back.
-Cool.
You're gonna love
this place.
FIERI: Up next...
Let's see.
What's it have, Mase?
...another funky spot
in New Orleans...
Wow, that's dyno.
...going big and a little crazy
with the pig.
This is
everybody's taco.
♪♪
FIERI:
Hey, I'm here in New Orleans.
Is this Turkey and the Wolf?
Oh, great.
Can I come in?
Well, what time
do you guys open?
Peace?
What time -- Oh, 11:00.
I'm with "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives."
You sure I can't come in?
♪♪
Oh, thanks!
Wow, it's cold out there.
This is Turkey and the Wolf.
♪♪
HEREFORD: Cabbage salad.
The food here is crazy
and off the wall
but familiar
and always delicious.
Lamb neck roti.
They're doing things
that nobody else is doing.
FIERI: And a feat pulled off
by this joker --
Mason Hereford, whose reputation
for inventive grub
has made it
all the way to NorCal.
I was shooting
"Guys Grocery Games"
and one of our great team
members, Tara, said,
"Listen, I hear you're
going to New Orleans.
You got to go shoot this place
called Turkey and the Wolf."
Tara seems awesome.
Tara.
What kind of food?
Well, I mean, we're a sandwich
shop based on fun...
Right.
...and trying to make big
flavors, make people happy.
There's weird,
quirky things on the menu,
but it's all executed perfectly.
Two headcheese tacos.
The hog's head tacos
are crunchy and spicy
and they have that fatty
hog's head cheese.
What are
we gonna make first?
The hog's head cheese
that's gonna go on
our hog's head cheese
tacos.
All right, so we've got
this beautiful hog head.
We're gonna go in
with some water, celery,
onions, carrots...
-Got it.
...onion powder,
granulated garlic,
white pepper,
black pepper, chili powder...
-Okay.
-...Korean chili flakes,
paprika,
mustard powder...
Copious amounts
of garlic.
...hot sauce,
and a little bay leaf.
First, get it rolling and then
drop it down to a simmer.
10 to 12 hours and
it should be falling apart
and ready
to pick the meat.
So, we've been standing here
for 10 to 12 hours.
Boy, are my legs tired.
-Yeah, and my stove is tired.
Boy, we almost ran
out of propane.
Yeah...
and things to talk about.
Exactly.
[ Whistles ]
So, the way you know it's done
is when the ears
are totally broken down
and you can pull
the back jaw out.
Right. Okay. Got it.
That's usually my d--
uh, when I pull the jaw out.
-We've got the meat.
We also have reduced down
all that liquid.
We chopped up
some mirepoix.
Some sherry vinegar.
Korean chili flake.
Some Creole mustard.
Kosher salt.
Fresh, ground black pepper.
-That's the key.
Hot sauce.
Last but not least,
we have this reduction.
Let's see.
What's it have, Mase?
We're gonna start by
throwing some tortillas
on the flat top.
Ours, we make in-house.
This is gonna be an American
cheese slice right here.
Good man.
Melt the cheese by steaming it
with a little water.
What are these little
strips of deliciousness
that I'm eating?
"Strippies" --
it's our tortillas.
Slice 'em up.
We fry 'em.
Yep.
We make a little, sort of,
taco spice of sorts.
-Delicious.
-And we season them up.
Little bit of our hog's head.
Sour cream.
We actually put a little
buttermilk in there --
make it extra tangy.
Hot sauce.
Hit it with what we call
"shrettuce,"
which is shredded lettuce.
We find ourselves
pretty clever here.
You guys are laughing at your
own jokes a lot.
-Constantly.
-Yeah.
"Strippies" on top.
Fresh jalapeño.
Just coming off
the flat top,
we got a little
surface-of-the-sun hot.
♪♪
You took the funky elements
of a fast-food taco --
"shrettuce,"
the American cheese,
and the crunchy topping --
legitimized it,
making
the critical ingredients
refined and delicious.
You take the handmade tortilla
and the super-unctuous,
mega-flavor headcheese --
give it some nice hot sauce
and a little tangy crema.
It's the best of both worlds
coming together.
This is
everybody's taco.
They're gonna flock-o
for this taco.
That's all we hope for.
♪♪
SERVER #2: Hog's head tacos.
The hog's head cheese
is really rich,
but there's something
about the American cheese
and the hot sauce
mixing together.
-So good.
-We got lamb coming up.
I love eating here.
It's just a fun scene.
WOMAN: Whenever you order
at the counter,
they give you a unique animal,
and that's how they find you.
So you'd be like, "Oh,
this one goes to the dead bat."
Go ahead and take these two
collard-green melts
over to
the dragon table.
Collard-green melt.
WOMAN #2: This is a melty, hot,
spicy sandwich
that is reminiscent of,
like, Jewish-style Philly deli.
It's, like, a triple-decker,
collard-green sandwich
with some Reuben vibes.
First thing we're gonna do
is make the collard greens
for it.
Getting after it.
We're gonna start with
a good spoonful of butter.
Minced garlic.
Rice wine vinegar.
Red wine vinegar.
A little Korean chili flake.
That's his go-to.
Creole seasoning.
Black pepper.
Sugar.
Kosher salt.
A little water to the pot.
And add
the collard greens.
While these are cooking,
we're gonna make
the Russian dressing.
Got it.
So, we're gonna start
with mayonnaise.
Chopped-up,
pickled cherry peppers.
Smoked paprika.
Ketchup.
Let me guess --
Korean chili flake.
Yeah.
Black pepper.
Kosher salt.
Finished off
with hot sauce.
Now we make the sandwich.
We have three pieces
of rye bread.
-Three pieces.
Middle slice is
the soaker slice.
It soaks up all the juices
from the collard greens.
Two of the slices
get Swiss.
We're gonna add the collard
greens to our sandwich now.
We're gonna finish it
with our Russian dressing
and our coleslaw.
Soaker slice.
-Okay.
Here we go.
And that's our collard-green
melt sandwich.
So, everything you want
in a Reuben, but vegetarian.
Exactly.
Yeah.
That cherry-pepper
Russian dressing is gangster.
The slaw
is a great foil.
Of course,
I love a Reuben,
but if you're going to put
something in the center,
you got to put something in
there that's got some texture,
got some body,
got some life.
-Yeah.
-It's got to have some identity,
and the collard greens are
the perfect wingman for this.
Wow, that's dyno.
Mmm!
-I'll take it.
-All right, Chef.
Nice job.
Watch out for this guy.
We have
the collard-green melt.
MAN #3: That's a perfect
combination
of, like, spice and savory
and just fills your mouth
with robust flavor.
And then, you have that slice
in the middle
that gets all the good
collard-green juice in there.
It's great.
-Bologna sandwich!
I can't understand
how his brain works
and how everything comes
together and tastes so good.
Watch out for the turkey
and the wolf.
Which one
are you gonna be?
Hope I'm not the turkey.
[ Laughing ]
FIERI: Coming up -- prime time
Puerto Rican in San Antonio.
That's a different level
right there, sister.
Putting an island twist
on nachos.
I don't even know
where to start.
And taking pork chops
into new territory.
I've been to a lot
of restaurants.
I've never seen that cut.
I've never seen
that presentation.
My dance team in the hallway
are the best, by the way.
These guys
are priceless.
♪♪
So, I'm here in the southeast
side of San Antonio, Texas,
and I got to tell ya,
I have talked more people out
of getting into the restaurant
business than you can imagine,
especially if they don't have
a ton of experience,
but listen to this story.
This girl comes from Puerto Rico
and gets her degree in Medical
Imaging in New Mexico,
and then she goes
and teaches school,
and all of a sudden,
on a whim, she says,
"I'm gonna open up
a Puerto Rican restaurant."
You know what I say?
No way.
But she did,
and she's killing it.
This is Luna Rosa.
Guavate, table 1.
MAN #4: Every time I bring folks
over here,
all I get is rave reviews.
Two more minutes
on that seafood mix.
This is like Puerto Rico
in South Texas.
You don't get stuff
like this anywhere else.
FIERI: And you don't hear
stories like Iris Ornelas'
most places either.
So, how did the restaurant
start?
You stopped teaching?
After 25 years,
I stopped teach--
You taught for 25 years?!
Now I'm doing what I wanted
to do when I grew up.
The whole time,
you wanted to be a chef?
This is
what I wanted to do.
So now she's doing it --
firing up traditional
Puerto Rican recipes alongside
her own creative spins.
MAN #5: The Caribbean nachos.
This is
my favorite thing to get
'cause it's not like
your typical nachos.
FIERI: That's right -- no simple
chips and cheese here.
This is plantains loaded
with culinary plus.
The first thing we're gonna
make is the base
for every Puerto Rican food --
the sofrito.
The base -- it has recao.
-Recao.
Most people call it
culantro.
Very similar to cilantro.
Some oil.
Blend it.
Put the onions in there.
-That's a lot of garlic.
-Garlic.
That's the foundation
of everything.
All right.
Now we're going to make
the brew for the beans.
-The what?
-We call it the brew.
-I like it.
-First, add some olive oil.
Bacon.
And then, garlic.
-Some of the sofrito.
-Sofrito.
The onions.
Green bell peppers.
Add some salt.
-Okay.
Annatto -- or achiote --
powder to give it some color
and some good flavor.
And then, what is this?
That is pumpkin.
I've made a lot of beans.
I've never put
pumpkin in it.
Puerto Rican beans --
most people add pumpkin,
and it's just
not any pumpkin.
It's Puerto Rican --
-It's not just any pumpkin.
Puerto Rican pumpkin.
Oh, of course,
it's Puerto Rican pumpkin.
Puerto Rican pumpkin.
That's all I carve
at Halloween.
Add some tomato sauce.
Top it with water so that
it can boil for a little bit.
Dry pinto beans.
-Right.
-Salt.
More sofrito.
-Green bell pepper.
-And the onion.
-How long is this gonna go?
-For about an hour.
-And then what happens?
We're gonna add that brew
to our cooked beans.
And that's just the beans,
just as a side dish?
-Just -- yes.
-A lot of work.
Now we're making
the pork roast.
We call it pernil --
very traditional
in Puerto Rico.
We have salt, garlic,
pepper, oregano, oil.
Rub the pork.
-Wow.
They're gonna go in the oven
for about six hours.
What's our next step?
A Hatch red chili
for our nachos.
-Hatch?
-Hatch -- yes.
And that's
not Puerto Rican,
but my husband is
from New Mexico,
so I had to have
something here for him.
So, give me the rundown.
This is
the Hatch chili puree.
Salt, garlic, and oregano.
And a little bit of water.
And then, it's going to boil
until it thickens.
And on top of these nachos,
we're gonna use plantains?
-Yes -- fried.
-I like it.
Now we're gonna build them --
the Caribbean nachos.
-Okay.
-Add the beans.
Chili sauce.
Pork.
Cheese.
In the oven
for about five minutes.
To let the cheese melt,
and then bring it out
and garnish it?
Yes.
Luna Rosa sauce.
The recao.
And there are your
Caribbean nachos.
I don't even know
where to start.
Mmm!
The pork is super tender.
Plantains are crunchy.
For anybody that hasn't had
a plantain,
this would be
a great way to experience it.
Some of the best beans
I've had.
Now, that's a different level
right there, sister.
Great flavors
and a big portion.
I can see
why people are happy.
Definitely the nachos
is my go-to.
The pork is really, really good.
Oh, the best, the best.
Ropa Vieja, table 2.
What makes the place
so special?
They treat you like family.
Everybody's family here.
FIERI: He's not kidding.
Iris' husband, Manuel,
and two sons, Amadeus and Omar,
are in on the action as well.
WOMAN #3:
They invested their time,
efforts traveling back
to Puerto Rico
to get the recipes from home.
FIERI:
Like this beast of a meal.
When it came in, I saw the size.
I was just completely amazed.
Holy moly.
I don't think I've ever seen
a chop like that.
It looks like a cross
between a Halloween mask
and some meat dreadlocks.
That's dangerous.
FIERI: ...when we come back.
♪♪
FIERI: At Luna Rosa
in San Antonio, Texas,
former teacher Iris Ornelas
is schooling the locals
on authentic
Puerto Rican cooking.
Cuban with sweets.
I always kept telling
my husband,
"I want to own a restaurant.
I want to cook."
So, you always had
the restaurant in your head.
Yes, yes.
So, she left her 25-year
teaching career and went for it.
So, I went home,
told my husband, and --
"Hey, guess what, honey?
We're in the
restaurant business."
Yes. "We're opening
a restaurant."
And they're going big
with this dish.
The Chuleta Kan-Kan.
WOMAN #3: This is like
the Flintstone
brontosaurus-type pork chop.
MAN #6: Once you mix it with
the white rice and the beans,
it's like
a perfect, perfect plate.
We are going to make
Chuleta Kan-Kan.
-Okay.
-It's the big pork chop.
Holy moly.
I don't think I've ever seen
a chop like that.
Yeah.
They're very unique.
You've got the pork chop.
This is the back.
Now you come down the side.
Here's your ribs.
-That's a rib.
Wow.
This thing is just riddled
with flavor.
The only challenge to this
is how to cook this all together
and not have these loins
become dry by the time
these sides
and rib areas become tender.
So, that's why
we brine them.
Add salt.
-Just a tiny bit of salt.
-Yes.
-So, these are brined overnight.
Next, we are going
to season them.
Salt and oregano.
Garlic salt.
Sofrito.
And then oil.
-Okay.
And why
are we making two?
Well, I guess one for you
and one for me.
Sounds good to me.
Okay, so now, we are going
to add the annatto,
especially
around the edge
because we want the annatto
to make the skin very crispy.
The annatto seed is ground up
to make the achiote powder
to give a nice,
beautiful, red hue to this.
Then, we're gonna bake them
for 15 minutes at 350.
For 15 minutes --
that's it?
Because then, after that,
we fry them to order.
Let's see it, sister.
IRIS: We're gonna eat this
pork chop with white rice.
Garnish it
with some recao.
The beans
with the pumpkin.
Sweet plantains.
Garnish it
with chimichurri.
And you're ready to go.
When are the other guys
gonna show up?
The ones that are gonna
share this with you?
-Yeah.
-I don't know.
-The rest of the football team.
-You need to call them.
♪♪
Well, I'll tell you this
right off the bat --
that's dangerous.
Chimichurri's dynamite.
The presentation, of course,
is amazing.
The meat on the bone
surrounded by the fat...
Mmm.
When you can get a bite
of the pork chop
and the...chicharrón
all together,
that's prime time.
Mmm!
But I don't even know why
you go to all that effort
to serve that pork
when the rice
and beans are money.
This just wrecks rice and beans
for every other culture.
Mmm!
I'd eat that every day.
I've been to a lot
of restaurants.
I've never seen that cut.
I've never seen
that presentation.
It's fantastic.
-All right!
MAN #4: It's crunchy, yet
the inside is full of flavor.
How they do it, I have no idea.
Mofongo seafood mix!
MAN #7: You know what you're
getting here
is delivered with love
from Puerto Rico,
and it's very evident.
For a Medical Imaging
graduate, mother...
A teacher.
...teacher turned restaurant
owner and chef,
you definitely,
definitely did that right.
Thank you.
So, was this a great road trip
or what?
But don't you worry.
I got plenty more joints to find
all over this country.
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners,
Drive-Ins & Dives"!
Okay.
-I'm gonna wash my hands.
So, first we're gonna
cook off the funk...
-Mm-hmm.
-Oh, I got it, Cap -- I got it!
You just go!
-Thanks. Appreciate ya!
Right. So, boil it
and then add the spaghetti
with the eggs and the cupcake.
Got it!