I'm Guy Fieri,
and we're rolling out
looking for America's greatest
diners, drive-ins, and dives.
This trip...
Wow!
It's a first-course feast.
This is like
an eclectic funk menu.
On this full hour of
amazing appetizers.
I'm gonna have to go back for
another round of hot yoga.
We've got tasty Denver tots.
That's the most tot-alistic.
Smoked Kansas poppers.
Brother, that's wicked.
And in Oklahoma,
how about some
good, old Rocky Mountain
oysters?
You got to be right in my face
with this, don't you?
Then we're wrapping cheese in
Atlanta.
I've never seen it done
this way.
Stuffing grape leaves
in Maryland.
Do you put magic in there, too?
Eating escargot in Miami.
That's pretty well done, huh?
And in Queens, atomic fireballs?
These things are banging, dude.
Plus, all kinds of wings.
Oh, oh, oh!
Made with some
unexpected things.
Probably gonna get kicked out of
the national wing-eating club.
So, get ready to share...
I can get in trouble with these.
As we start this
appetizer-palooza.
Are you guys excited at home?
That's all right here,
right now,
on "Triple D."
♪
I'm here in
the Highlands neighborhood,
about a mile from downtown
Denver, Colorado,
and about a mile away
from Citizen Pictures,
the folks that happen to produce
"Diners, Drive-Ins, and Dives,"
but don't let those details
confuse you.
I'm here to check out
a joint that I hear
has the most real-deal,
off-the-hook,
outrageous bar food
you can find.
This is Highland Tavern.
Stupid Burger
in the window.
Much more upscale than what
you would consider a local bar.
Not a Philly.
MAN: The attention to having
higher-end ingredients
in a dive-bar feel.
FIERI: Just when owners
Brian Sommatino and Andy Stutz
had in mind
when they bought this old joint.
The building we're in is
an old Coors Brewing building?
Yeah, built in 1901
by Coors.
It's been a bar pretty much
from 1901 till now,
minus prohibition.
So, they kept the suds flowing
and hired fine-dining chef
Jeremy McMinn
to build up the menu.
Every dish has a little
something added to it
that just makes you
remember it.
Like a pork shank
braised in ancho chili,
spare ribs
glazed with Dr Pepper,
and house-made pastrami
he's dropping
on this killer sandwich.
McMINN:
Bombshell up.
It is just marvelous.
And if you're looking for
something at the table to share,
they're rocking out
their version
of a bar food
favorite...
Tavern Tots.
...the homemade tater tot.
By far, the best things
I've ever found
in my entire life.
Do I need
to freeze-dry them?
to dehydrate them?
What exactly --
Eventually I just gave up
and we made up our own thing.
All right.
Well, let's see how you do it.
We're gonna cook
the potatoes.
Cold water.
We're gonna bring these up
to just barely a simmer.
Okay.
And then even
the heat out on it,
and just let them sit.
It usually takes about 40
minutes until they're al dente.
Al dente -- No, okay.
Yeah, that's probably
a pretty good description.
So, do you have a timer
on this?
No.
Awesome.
So, there's a variable
here.
Yeah.
All right.
So, we got our partially
cooked potato
that's just cooked enough
that it'll still make shreds.
Yeah.
So, hash brown-ish.
Hash brown-ish, yeah.
There you go.
Ooh!
It's like a snow blower.
So, if you're
a breakfast house,
you would die to have
hash coming out like that.
A little bit of grit
to it,
so it's not completely finished,
and this is the foundation.
That's it.
I love it.
Now what's the process?
Then we got to mix in
our dry ingredients.
Salt?
Salt.
Granulated garlic.
Granulated onion.
Cayenne pepper.
Nice.
The key is there's a lot
of nooks and crannies
to all that --
All those different pieces
of potato,
so the more evenly
you can distribute this...
Okay.
We're gonna add tamari
to our eggs.
Really?
Yeah.
So, that little bit of egg's
gonna help bind it.
Yeah.
I'm excited.
Are you guys excited
at home?
Now, we got to form these,
freeze them,
form them, set them up.
Form them
and drop them.
Like it's hot?
They will be hot
once we've dropped them.
Okay. What size tot
do you make?
It's about an ounce
and a quarter.
Okay.
Cook them on 350?
375.
Till they're GBD.
That's golden brown
and delicious.
I pick it up.
A little salt on these.
There it is.
Small order of tots.
This is the moment.
[ Angelic vocalizing ]
Good separation.
Looking good so far.
That's what you're looking for
in a tot.
Out of all the house-made tots
I've had...
mine included...
that's the most
tot-alistic.
[ Laughs ]
This is ridiculous.
Way to hammer that out.
Thanks.
In the world
of "Triple D,"
that's probably one of the best,
if not the best rendition
of a homemade tot.
Thanks.
Nice job.
And great seasoning.
[ Laughs ]
Watch out
for this guy.
I like to think of them
as, like, tots redefined.
WOMAN: This will ruin tots
for everywhere else
because they are really
just the best.
WOMAN:
Good people, really good food.
Just a wonderful place to be.
It's almost like
having a party at home.
Everybody knows everybody.
Everybody knows the bartenders.
FIERI:
In fact, the place is so local,
owners Brian and Andy
plucked Jeremy from a barstool.
He was a regular.
He lived about a block away.
Came here after work
to have his beer to go home,
and I asked him to be the chef
and he said yes.
That was like
hitting the lottery.
Yes.
Okay, so, this has been pretty
much a ridiculous visit.
We have declassified
the tots.
And now we will venture
into --
'Cause there's nothing
that this guy won't touch.
What are we doing now?
We're gonna make
our pork rinds.
Pork rinds
in the window.
Crazy.
Yeah.
Okay.
Give me the rundown.
Got some raw pigskins.
Now, these are pigskins
from the --
Belly skin.
Belly skin, primarily,
is what you want to use in this?
This is where the bacon
has been taken out,
just to give you
some reference,
and you are now
going to...
We're gonna drop this
in some boiling water.
Drop it.
Drop it
like it's skin.
We're gonGreat. That's a little
i"Silence of the Lamb"-y for me.
So, you got to cook this
through.
Got four hours
at a full-on boil.
Salted?
No salt.
All right.
Wow.
That is funky, man.
Now you'll cut them into chunks,
pieces, strips?
Little strips.
Okay.
So, this little
munchkin dehydrator
is gonna do
all the work.
It's gonna do
How long
are these gonna go?
Set it and forget it
for about 26 1/2 hours.
Not 27?
Not 27.
Not 25.
Not 26.
26.
26 and a...
Half.
When you dehydrate it
and take all that moisture out,
that's what gives them
the chance to really puff up?
Yeah.
All right.
Load 'em up,
shut 'em down.
26 1/2 hours,
and here we go.
That's it.
Genius.
Okay.
They're ready
to come out.
Dehydrated pig skin.
Really?
Yeah.
Like, hard plastic.
So, now we're gonna go
to the fryer.
Let's go.
Whoa!
It's amazing every single time
you do it, too --
doesn't get old.
That is --
I'm telling you,
I have seen some cool things
on "Triple D."
That might be
in the top 10 coolest.
Bring over
those mouth killers.
Wow. Hot!
Okay. Next.
We're gonna make
the chili lime-salt mix.
We got our lime salt.
Korean chili flake.
Chili powder.
A little mix.
Season 'em.
That's ridiculous.
There you go.
Look at that.
That's a lot of work,
buddy.
[ Crunching loudly ]
Dude, you kill this.
Thanks.
This is how they were
to be appreciated.
Fresh, crispy, light,
not dense.
The flavor jets
just turned on.
They're trying
to shut down
that flavor fire
I got in my mouth.
You want another one?
Maybe a little Tebow.
Hang on a second.
That is ridiculous.
I don't say this often,
but that's the best chicharrone
I've ever had.
Thanks.
I appreciate it.
I'm really taken back,
man.
MAN:
I love the pork rinds.
I think they should be
prescribed to me by my doctor.
Magic in the mouth.
These are great.
Pretty ridiculous.
Yes.
Just keep talking. I'm gonna
just keep eating these.
One of the best "Triple D"
experiences I've had.
And I've seen a lot.
Okay?
There we go.
Thanks, man.
Up next in Miami...
Legit, legit.
...a funky little strip mall
tavern...
I don't know that I've
seen this.
...getting fits with
the fixings.
Hands down, the first time we've
ever seen escargot on a menu.
I'm here in Miami where,
20 years ago,
a flight attendant
and a carpenter
took a chance to open
a restaurant.
Now, it didn't look like much.
It's here in a strip mall,
but they had a plan.
All right, guys.
People would call it
a sports bar.
You're having the escargot?
And you're serving escargot?
Yep.
It's fabulous.
Mussels Provençal,
blackened mahi mahi.
It's got a nice kick to it.
Chicken Francaise.
The seared tuna.
It's incredible.
10 wings, Buffalo style.
Even the bar food's
over the top.
Gourmet wings.
It's like chicken piccata
on a stick.
What you don't expect,
you'll get here.
I do this food because I worked
in a French restaurant.
You got guys in chef coats.
Dude, you're legit.
Chris Hirsh started working in
the restaurant biz at 14.
Rock and roll.
Got out at 26
to go into construction.
You're supposed to be
ordering a cake.
Then his wife, Cass,
won a kind of lottery
the state of Florida runs to
hand out some liquor licenses.
CASS: So I said, "Look, you can
build bars, you're a chef."
Had either of you managed or
owned a restaurant before this?
No.
But they weren't gonna do it
the standard way, anyway.
Pickup.
Chris introduced different
things to these people,
and they just learned to love
his cuisine.
What does Chris do?
I don't know,
but it's melt in your mouth
delicious.
Everything is fresh.
Home cooked, from scratch.
WOMAN: Peppercorn dressing.
FIERI: Makes it himself?
He should bottle it, oh, yeah.
Homemade croutons
from leftover bread.
Wow, those are good croutons.
And look at all the different
sauces being held.
That tartar sauce is legit.
That scampi butter with
shallots, garlic.
I put my juices in, which is
white wine and lemon juice.
Mm, it's tasty already.
And they use it all over
the place.
Pick up, one mussel.
From mussels Provençal
to oysters with jalapeños,
lemon juice, and a little
provolone, to escargot.
Yeah, this is exactly the
process I thought I'd be finding
when I pulled up to Scully's.
A lot of people pass us by,
don't know what
they're gonna miss.
I looked at the menu, I said,
"Oh, they have escargot."
You find that at every bar
joint, right?
WOMAN: They serve it to you just
like you would get it
in a French restaurant.
Hands down, first time we've
ever seen escargot on a menu.
But it goes over well?
Fantastic.
People love it?
They love it.
Quit talking, let's get into it.
Let's do it, then.
Let's do it.
The pan's hot, already.
6 mushrooms.
Okay, is this new math,
'cause you got 7.
There you go. Put a little oil
in it first
just to get it started.
We take Belgian escargot,
got a little seasoning with
salt and white pepper.
And then as we made earlier,
our garlic butter.
So, everybody comes to
temperature together.
We're gonna take out
our mushrooms.
Take our escargot.
And this is a big seller
on the menu?
Big time.
You come and have that,
a couple appetizers,
make it a meal.
Oh.
We're gonna take a little
provolone cheese.
Look at that.
That's pretty well done up.
Mm, nothing like a little snail
and cheese.
I've had so many escargot
that are so chewy.
That was so delicate,
it was like --
It was like buttah.
Oh, man.
What you getting after,
a little escargot?
Mm. It's good?
Excellent.
It's rich, very well-cooked,
very tender.
Mm. It's so good.
I asked for extra garlic,
and you get it.
I didn't see where it said
Le Sports Bar and Le Pub.
[ Laughter ]
Blackened dolphin.
Gourmet food in a dark bar.
Blue Burger, no fries.
Even their bar food classics...
Chili cheeseburger.
...are done the Scully's way.
10 wings.
I mean, I've had wings
many ways to Sunday.
I have never fried them,
and then grilled them.
But that's exactly what they're
doing here.
And what are you having,
the Oriental Wings?
The Garlic and Buffalo.
Scampi Wings and sauce.
All with sauce done Chris's way.
10 wings, Buffalo style.
Buffalo wings are hot sauce
and butter,
and that's it,
but I'm ready to watch.
We're gonna take a gallon of
hot sauce,
half gallon of Worcestershire.
Fresh chopped garlic.
Whipped butter.
Yeah, roasted wings.
They're all fresh wings.
Like a pterodactyl.
We par-fry 'em.
Put a crunch on 'em.
Yeah.
So you fry 'em,
then you toss 'em,
then you grill 'em,
and then you eat 'em.
I love the handle.
That's a good wing.
It has that smoky under flavor.
Delicious.
I have never tasted any wings
like this.
Or this.
Scampi wings.
Scampi wings, take our smashed
and crushed garlic,
chopped garlic.
No oil in the pan?
Not yet.
I don't know that
I've seen this.
Or the sauté with the finger.
Gonna add a little bit of oil.
Caramelize that.
Now we can start to add
our butter.
So, you let that slowly
melt down.
How are our wings looking?
What do you think?
Crispy?
Just grill it up,
give it a little flavor.
Sauce is ready?
Let's do it, let's do it.
Wow, you can smell 'em.
Parmesan cheese.
And that's it.
Probably gonna get kicked out of
the national wing-eating club.
Sacrilege.
Mm, I would have just done it
with regular garlic,
but the kicker was
the caramelized garlic.
Some legit food, brother.
Legit, legit.
It's delicious.
Got a card special,
Bleu Burger.
I've had everything on the menu.
You're never gonna be
disappointed.
The thing that makes this place
work is Chris and Cass,
they're great.
This is awesome.
People just love it,
and they keep coming.
FIERI: The joint that's got two
pool tables,
people would call it
a sports bar,
and you're serving escargot.
Yep.
Fantastic, dude.
Coming up in Queens, New York.
What up?
Mac and cheese gone atomic.
All right, this is now --
And an offer that's
hard to refuse.
Never seen that coming, baby.
So, I'm right over the bridge
from Manhattan
in Astoria, Queens.
You remember Astoria --
wan area with a lot of history
and a lot of character,
this is it.
And speaking of characters, wait
till you check out this joint.
I hear it's off the hook.
This is Queens Comfort.
Captain Crunch chicken fingers,
table 11.
It's just mind blowing.
The Egg Mc'Ruffin.
I love it.
This is great.
I mean, it brings you
back to your childhood.
A little bit of nostalgia.
It makes you feel
like you're a kid again.
MAN: All the pictures
on the wall made you feel like
you were at your aunt's house --
your aunt that could cook
really good.
Brisket mac and cheese,
table six.
The food here is unmatched.
Donnie makes it work
fantastically.
This is Donnie D'Alessio.
Double "D."
Nice to meet you.
[ Laughs ]
What up?
FIERI:
A cat from Queens who traded
in his low-budget film career
to open up this joint in 2011.
And he's had a "Triple D"
drive-by on his mind ever since.
This is
my dream come true.
Seriously?
Yeah.
Are you married, Donnie?
Um...
[ Laughs ]
Okay, I'm not married yet.
I've been in a relationship
for five years
and I just recently bought
a ring,
but I haven't proposed yet.
Very nice.
Probably 'cause he's had
his hands full
coming up with the out-of-bounds
dishes
that keeps this place packed.
This is like
an eclectic-funk menu.
Enchiladas and burgers
and comfort food.
D'ALESSIO:
Chicken and waffles.
Anything you can imagine.
FIERI:
Or Donnie can imagine.
Atomic Fire Balls.
FIERI: Plus, he's making
the kind of unique food
that only a kid could dream up.
I got the Atomic Fire Balls.
It's like homemade mac
and cheese scooped into a ball.
They're atomic, but they're
really, really, really good.
So, now we're making
the Atomic Fire Balls.
Okay.
All kinds of cheese.
We got the Béchamel, here.
This is milk and cream.
When are
you gonna get engaged?
Oh,
a couple years from now.
Man, I wouldn't wait around
on that one. Okay, we good?
Garlic powder.
Okay.
Onion powder.      Onion powder.
Cayenne.
Salt.
Black pepper.
Tabasco.
Texas Pete.
Wow, this is spicy.
Sriracha.
Shredded yellow cheddar.
White cheddar.
Yeah.
Shredded fontina cheese.
All right,
so we're gonna whisk this...
Okay.
So, that's that.
We're gonna add heavy cream
and the egg yolks.
Gonna whisk that in.
Elbow macaroni.
Pour it into a hotel pan
and let it set.
That looks
like it's gonna be a mess.
Try this.
Mmm! That is spicy, though.
Whoo!
Parchment.
Let it set up.
So, now we're gonna make
the egg wash. Eggs, here.
Tabasco.
Texas Pete.
Sriracha.
That's ready to go.
All right, so, now we have
our flour, panko.
Now we're gonna make
the balls.
Scoop the macaroni.
Form it.
Now you go into the flour,
into the egg wash...
Yeah. Into the panko,
which we also have --
And the panko
is seasoned with...?
Cayenne.
You deep fry it.
So,
they're out of the fryer.
You get five per order.
This is the garnish.
Oh, geez.
All right,
this is now obscene.
Mmm! Aw!
I'm gonna have to go back
for another round of hot yoga.
[ Laughs ]
That's crazy.
Typically, when you have mac
and cheese balls, they're dry.
But the fact that you had
that Béchamel so thick,
you fried them quickly,
you made them small enough
so the heat could get
all the way through
without cooking
all the cheese out.
These things
are bangin', dude.
Well done.
Pow!
Fire Balls ready.
It's like my mom's mac and
cheese but with a kick to it.
Clear your sinuses right up.
It's just a great thing to have
in the neighborhood.
Being on this show
has been a dream come true.
It would also be
a dream come true if...
Jill Sirota,
will you marry me?
Yes, of course!
[ Laughs ]
Engaged today on "Triple D."
Never seen that coming,
baby!
Up next on this full hour of
amazing appetizers...
I'm telling you.
Thank you.
Good eats.
In Paola, Kansas...
A lot of work for
a chicken wing, man.
...a barbecue joint even smoking
the starters.
I've had smoked mozzarella,
but smoked cream cheese?
And in Vinita, Oklahoma...
Ah!
...a down home café...
Look at that right there.
...taking the bull by the
opposite end of the horns.
Huh?
Moo, moo, buckaroo.
about 40 miles south of
Kansas City.
Now, a lot of folks think of
this as cattle country,
but you might change your mind
after you try some of
the tasty pork at
the BBQ Shack.
Order up!
From whole hogs
to racks of ribs.
Fantastic.
It's go big...
Look at that!
...or go home at this joint.
Just get into it?
Yeah.
And you can eat the whole thing?
Come back in an hour.
Order up!
It was a big gamble that paid
off big for Rick Schoenberger.
Got the barbecue blood flowing.
You barbecue, right.
Who left a corporate job to turn
his hobby into his business.
Now, he's firing up
the monster smoker...
Figure out what you need and get
the next step bigger.
...cranking out burnt ends,
homemade sausage,
and even loading the smoker
with chicken wings.
That's a mess of wings.
They're good.
They're the best chicken wings
around.
Most people just take 'em,
fry 'em, sauce 'em,
but you're gonna season 'em,
smoke 'em,
and then fry 'em to order.
Then we deep fry them to order.
We'll just take some of this
rub, dump it right on.
And a little of this?
Now, this is the secret kicker?
Throw some of them peppers
in there, too.
Dried chipotles, 'cause these
are dried, smoked jalapeños.
Put a nice little kick on it.
How long do these go on the
smoker for?
Probably a couple hours.
Really? A lot of work for
a chicken wing, man.
t iteytake --
Oh, maybe a minute.ours.
Looks like they're ready.
All that seasoning still
stays on?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's cooked into 'em out
there on the smoker.
You get that smoke
right off the bat.
Yeah.
Wow, this is good.
Good stuff, brother,
I'm telling you.
Thank you.
Good eats.
I think it's the best place
in Paola to eat.
Just real friendly, just that
kind of atmosphere.
FIERI: And the kind of place
where the smoker's
always smoking with everything
from whole hog to ribs...
Fantastic.
...to brisket...
It's real tender.
...and now jalapeño poppers --
the way they were done
before the chain restaurants got
a hold of 'em.
Where do all the peppers
come from?
These particular ones
I grew in my garden.
We actually just core the seeds,
the insides of the jalapeño.
Okay, so you take the top off.
Yeah, core the jalapeños
with the chili twister.
Now, tell me about this
cream cheese thing.
Okay. Take just your standard
cream cheese
and just squeeze a little bit
into each one of them peppers.
That enough?
Yeah, that's probably good.
We'll take it a step further.
I use a water chestnut
marinated overnight
in a little brown sugar
and some soy sauce.
I have seen some funny things to
stuff a pepper with,
but this might be the top of it,
a water chestnut.
And then some more cheese?
All right, now we're ready
for the baking.
Try to get your beginning and
end to meet in the same spot?
That'd be a good thing.
And then go right through
the center.
And now we're gonna sprinkle
the dry rub --
the universal dry rub?
Just a little bit, kind of use
it like paprika
to give a little
nice appearance.
Just dust it, add some color.
Yeah.
Now these go in the barbecue.
Yep, right on the smoker.
Look at those.
Those are like mondo popper.
I've had smoked brie,
I've had smoked mozzarella,
but smoked cream cheese?
Those are fresh peppers.
Brother, that's wicked hot.
It is.
Great flavor.
Like everything
Rick's rolling out.
Just really good, really good.
He really is the real deal.
The rub, the smoke,
all done low and slow.
And it's the same every time,
wonderful.
I've had everything.
You've run the menu?
I eat here a lot.
Out goes the old theory of
cooking them
cools them down, huh?
That's right.
Seasoned peppers are hot. Wow!
Welcome to Vinita, Oklahoma,
about an hour northeast of Tulsa
in cattle country.
Now, we're heading to a place
called Clantons,
a family-owned joint
for over 80 years.
Famous for their
chicken-fried steak,
and another
cattle country delicacy
you just got to check out.
Ever had calf fries?
I've not had any calf fries
anywhere else in a restaurant
like these.
Cat fries?
Calf.
Some places know 'em as
Rocky Mountain oysters.
Others don't know 'em at all.
They come from the underside
of the calf.
Mm.
They say -- when you're a
first-time customer,
they send out a free order.
They're a classic here, along
with chicken-fried steak.
And they do use
the good seasonings.
And chicken and dressing.
It's just like my mom
would have made.
Country favorites --
and a local favorite.
In the same family
for four generations,
starting with a guy named
Sweet Tater.
WOMAN: My great-grandfather.
'Cause he was
a sweet potato farmer.
Wasn't making a living at it.
So, he said he was gonna
open up his own restaurant.
And 80 years later,
Dennis Patrick
and his wife, Melissa --
she's a Clanton --
are keeping it rolling.
Chicken-fried chicken ready?
They took over
almost ten years ago
when Melissa's
parents retired.
MELISSA: We were both pretty
busy in the corporate world,
and our kids were getting into
high-school age,
junior high age, and we said,
"We're coming back."
Nice.
Iced tea, got it.
Real friendly people,
great food.
It's just a nice, homey place.
FIERI: A homey place where their
home cooking knows
homemade calf fries.
DENNIS: The governor and his
wife come in here.
She loves 'em.
FIERI: "You have the best
calf fries in Oklahoma"?
That is the first lady of
Oklahoma telling you that.
Here we have Oklahoma's finest
calf fries.
FIERI: Where does one
harvest these?
From the underside of a calf,
actually.
Agh!
Yeah, the batter's gonna matter.
Chicken base,
ground mustard,
a little salt and pepper
in here.
Just pour that in there.
The whole thing?
Yes, sir.
It's chunky.
Well, it's buttermilk.
With a cornmeal,
cayenne flour dredge.
Cayenne, kill it, kill it.
Now we just dump 'em
in the deep fryer.
See, they didn't even scream.
[ Laughs ]
You got to be right in my face
with this, don't you?
Not bad.
Not really good.
Got any hot sauce?
Digging it with the blue cheese.
Chicken-fried calf fries,
Buffalo wing style.
Hot.
That was good.
I don't know that I like
the big ones yet.
Look at that right there.
Huh?
Moo moo, buckaroo.
Calf fries, you need ketchup
with those fries?
Do they ever do, like,
calf fries ceviche
or calf fries
on the half shell?
[ Laughter ]
How did you like the calf fries?
We were anxious to see how you
liked them.
They were very unique.
I like smaller ones better.
I did -- a couple that I had
were very big.
Were very, like --
the whole family was there.
[ Laughter ]
We pride ourselves on carrying
over the tradition
that started actually
80 years ago.
FIERI: And not just
the calf fries --
they're keeping everything
classic.
Two iced teas.
With down home favorites like
fried catfish,
homemade apple pie,
and Clanton's legendary
chicken and dressing.
How you doing?
And for the folks
in this small town,
Clanton's has been kind of
an extension of
their own dining room
as far back as they remember.
Appreciate y'all
coming in.
Everybody kind of gets together,
and they know one another.
It's nice.
It's like sitting at
mama's table.
Is it, really?
Yes.
Every day, every dish,
for everyone of 80 years.
Like you'd get at home.
Just a real savory taste.
A few more minutes.
I've ate here ever since
I've been 6, 7 years old,
that's where I've always come.
Thank you.
Have a good day.
Your order of calf fries are
coming out right now.
Oh, super.
How many you have?
You got to evolve.
People are always changing,
except they'll say,
"Hey, that's great.
Let's try that on the menu.
Let's put something fancy
on that, but I'm gonna eat
my chicken-fried steak."
You get emotional about this?
I do.
I love this place.
Coming up in Atlanta, Georgia...
Gosh, that's good.
...we're bellying up the bar...
appetizer menu you
Gwouldn't expect..
Jerk chili?
Yeah.
You know, finding great bar food
is way more than just a menu --
it's a whole experience,
like here in Atlanta at
this joint, The Highlander.
It's a dive bar in a strip mall.
Now, they're heavy on tattoos,
but serious about
scratch cooking.
Cheers!
Everybody here is
really twisted.
Who's got the chili
and fritters?
The food here is so much better
than it needs to be.
MAN: Look at the menu --
oxtail soup.
You see that on every
drive through.
It's awesome bar food.
It's very fresh.
Wow, you got it going on with
this, man.
Excellent.
It's a neighborhood place.
FIERI: Has been since '92...
You want a cider, right?
when Jeff Merback and some
buddies took a chance
and opened up in a strip mall.
Anrear   16 years later.
That's your brand, right? mall.
Like being the place
that's still open
at the end of a long night.
More Jaegers, absolutely.
We knew our clientele was gonna
be bartenders, waiters,
waitresses, cooks, and I
couldn't throw out
Ibrahim Garba Jahumpa.
Oh, so let's just
go with Ice.
Ice, yeah.
French dip, there you go.
When he became our kitchen
manager, he brought
his personality
to our special board.
Every day, something's
different.
They have a lot of things here
that a lot of places
in Atlanta don't have.
This week, our specialty is
oxtail soup and curried goat.
I'd walk right by here and
think, "Mm, curried goat."
And for a starter, there's a cup
of this with a twist.
Jerk chili?
Yeah.
It's the best bowl of chili
in town.
What makes it jerk?
There's a jerk marinade that we
add to it.
I mean, just because you're
cooking it with me
doesn't make it jerk, right?
No, no, no, ground beef.
80/20?
Yeah, and spicy Italian sausage.
So, this cooks to nice
and brown.
Onions, yellow, red.
Yellow peppers, red pepper,
green pepper.
I like the colors.
Now we add the kidney beans,
black beans,
and the peeled tomato.
No garlic, though?
The garlic is coming
in a second.
All right, just making sure.
This looks like about the entire
spice counter.
So, that is the veggie base.
Chicken stock.
The habaneros?
Habaneros.
Roasted garlic.
Oh, I like that call.
Your jerk seasoning?
Can I taste it?
Not too spicy.
Spiced rum, tomato paste.
We just gonna mix everything
that's in here.
Now, he's happy now,
you know.
Everybody move back.
That's nice.
Have that in a holster, maybe
wear it on a --
[ Laughter ]
Put that in my bag.
This goes in our cauldron of
beans and peppers.
Want me to scrape?
Sure.
I mean, if we're gonna be
same team.
Brown sugar, black pepper,
thyme, onion powder, mustard.
Dry mustard, garlic powder,
bay leaf.
Right, color.
Cilantro.
Okay, red chili flake,
celery seed.
The allspice.
So, there's your Jamaican.
A little white pepper.
White pepper, cumin,
chili powder.
Round it out with the cayenne.
Wow. So, now how long we
gonna let that simmer for?
A couple hours.
Big chunks of meat,
still see all the colors.
Gosh, that's good.
That's got a little heat to it.
Great spice, great color,
great textures.
That's good chili.
Dude, is the chili legit?
Outstanding.
It's meaty,
lots of nice spice.
Crazy dependable food.
There's some chips,
ready to roll.
The fish specials
are always amazing.
There's a wonderful caprese
salad that I really dig.
Marinated lime chicken, it's got
really refreshing lime marinade.
Mussels, the corn fritters.
Those are huge.
They're like golf ball size.
FIERI: Served up with
The Highlander's
roasted red pepper remoulade.
I like the remoulade sauce
'cause I'm from Louisiana.
Mm, I like it, man.
I got to make myself a note
on that remoulade.
It's spicy and delicious.
FIERI:
And seriously in demand.
Potato skins are up.
Like everything here.
Turkey sandwich with a salad.
FIERI: 'Cause a lot of folks'll
tell you that this is
their first choice for
eating out and hanging out.
Who's dry?
This food is nothing
if you don't have the atmosphere
going with it.
Jaeger?
All night, coming right up.
From mohawks just down
to yuppies.
It is the epitome of where
you're allowed to be yourself.
Everybody's welcome here.
It's a twisted Cheers.
Ally's on it.
People would come here to drink,
anyway,
and you get a great menu of
food on top of it.
FIERI: Even the bar basics.
Nachos coming out.
With that Jamaican jerk chili.
Tonight, I'm eating the loaded
potato skins.
Mini burgers they're calling
sliders.
Chicken quesadilla,
I love them.
Spicy buffalo or Jamaican
jerk chicken wings.
MAN: Bar food,
you don't expect much,
but here, they give you it made
from scratch.
FIERI: Even the bar staple
mozzarella stick.
Here, it's wrapped in pasta.
They're much better than normal
mozzarella sticks.
It just adds a little
something extra to it.
I'm gonna make an egg wash, egg
yolk, a little bit of water.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, just yolks?
I've never seen it done
this way.
I've never seen it done this way
until I came here.
Until you came here.
This is the breading.
We're going to add Italian
seasoning to it.
Sheeted egg pasta, brush it with
a little bit of the egg wash.
Just like that.
That's it, just one rollover.
Yeah. Yeah, now we're gonna
dip it in the --
Wash again.
And then the bread crumb.
I like this.
Now we're gonna fry 'em?
So, does the pasta get crunchy
on the outside?
Yes.
Oh.
What are we gonna serve
with these?
The marinara sauce.
Marinara sauce.
Scratch made with roasted
garlic, onions,
peppers, red wine, herbs,
and spices.
Wow, those look good!
Wow.
I'm impressed.
That's great, man.
The sheet around it makes it
hold together,
gives it a nice texture --
that's tasty, man.
Those are bananas.
These are delicious.
MAN:
Everyone loves this food.
He is as good for this place
as any of us.
Atlanta has better bar food
than any city deserves,
and The Highlander is one of
the best in town.
You come here, and it's just
comfort -- comfort food.
FIERI: Whatever the hour.
Roll in, hang out,
have a blast.
You got food coming.
It's supposed to be a bar,
but it's not bar food.
Southern comfort food,
all the way.
You still like each other?
Oh, yeah.
Anybody got a Highlander tattoo?
Not one I can show you.
[ Laughter ]
Up next...
Opa!
In Dundalk, Maryland...
You are the quintessential
diner dude.
Real deal Greek.
That is killer.
Just like Yia Yia made it.
Your Yia Yia should be very,
very impressed with that.
And in Belmar, New Jersey...
Mm!
Mm, mm, mm!
...a bar food classic...
These are rockin'.
...getting a Mexican makeover.
Got to come try these wings.
You know, I think we've figured
it out by now.
Some of the greatest diners
we've seen on "Triple D"
are owned by Greek families.
I mean, it's the passion
for food, the strong family,
and fueled by tradition.
And this one's no different.
Here we are in Dundalk,
Maryland,
right outside of Baltimore --
this is the Boulevard Dinner.
Spinach Pie up.
Brown gravy on that.
It's like a landmark here.
This is the go-to joint.
Oh, yeah.
Sour beef and dumplings.
FIERI: Perfected over years by
owner Marc Tsakiris's granddad.
Your grandfather has
a diner back in the day.
It was called the --
House of Neptune.
Seafood diner?
Crab house.
Some of the old school
menu items
that he did there, you guys
still do here.
Yes.
Boiled crab cakes in the window.
So, it was an easy choice
when the pre-med student
got a shot at running
his own diner --
Spinach pie up!
On, get this,
the same family lot.
♪
This is just part of
your family make up.
Part of my family
make up, yes.
What's the favorite thing
on the menu?
Yia Yia's grape leaves.
It's a rice and a beef mixture.
They're great.
And that makes 'em very special.
Yia Yia is grandma?
Yes.
It's my grandmother,
and these are a family recipe
that comes from Greece.
They're actually called --
[ Speaks Greek ] -- we just call
them stuffed grape leaves here.
So, we're gonna start with our
ground pork and beef,
fresh scallions, fresh dill --
[ Whistles ]
Copious amounts of that, huh?
Yes. Chopped white onion,
and then we're gonna add
some garlic powder,
salt, and a little
black pepper.
We're gonna have some rice.
Sands of the hour glass.
And we're gonna mix it up.
Mm, I smell that dill,
it's awesome.
Okay, right now we're gonna make
our tomato puree sauce.
We're gonna start with some
butter, melt that in there.
We're gonna add olive oil.
We're gonna add some
tomato puree.
Cook it all the way down,
and this all goes in with
Yia Yia's
grape leaf mixture.
Yes, sir, we're gonna
dump that in.
Smell the magic in there.
Did you put magic in there, too?
I didn't even hear it.
So, now we've got this mixed up,
now what up?
Roll 'em up.
Grape leaf.
Take this stem
off the back here.
Get a little portion on,
and we roll the back first,
then the side.
Then all the way.
You got it.
Yours is a jumbo,
but you're a natural.
When you were a kid, and you'd
go to your Yia Yia's house,
you'd make these?
She would.
Now everybody in my family
gets me to make 'em for 'em.
So, you're the one --
I am the dolmade man.
Now, this into here?
Yes, but first we're gonna
line the bottom of the pan
with some grape leaves, also.
An old Greek trick, I guess,
so that we don't burn the bottom
portion of the grape leaves.
So, you can just stack 'em
on top of each other?
We're gonna stack 'em neatly.
It's gonna go this way.
So, they're in.
Now, we're gonna add
some olive oil first, and we're
gonna add lemon juice.
And usually, we use
a full bottle just because
this is where all
the flavor comes from.
It gets saturated into the grape
leaf, and that's what you want.
And a little bit of water.
And we're gonna cover this.
Where's the lid?
Just went into robot.
So, we've put the pie pan down,
and we put this to
weigh it down.
That keeps pressure
on the whole mix?
Keeps the pressure on so
everything doesn't
blow up in there, and then
we're gonna put our lid.
Keeping all the steam inside.
That's it.
Wow, that fits snug.
Oh, yes.
I use it as a shield.
[ Laughter ]
Simmer probably for about
an hour.
They're done.
We usually put five out.
We also have a sauce
with it, too.
We're gonna put our chicken
stock down.
We're gonna let that go roux
to that, and raw eggs.
And a little lemon.
And that's gonna be the sauce?
That's gonna be the sauce
we're gonna put on top
when we present it.
Awesome.
Cracked pepper,
and we're set.
That's all she wrote.
Dude, that is killer.
The grape leaf just really wraps
around it nice and tight.
I think people look at it
and go, "Ooh, grape leaf,
I don't know if I want to eat
a grape leaf."
That's the thing, yeah.
It's tender.
You got the lemon juice eggnog
sauce that you put on there.
You got the texture of
the beef, the rice.
All the flavors locked
right inside.
Right.
I'd get in trouble with these.
[ Laughs ]
Outstanding.
Your Yia Yia should be very,
very impressed with that.
I could seriously --
I'll have those to go.
Great.
Nice job.
MAN: The feeling has to be nice
and moist.
Not soggy.
Exactly.
I've had grape leaves elsewhere,
but these are the best.
This is real deal food.
Oh, real deal.
Chicken souvlaki.
WOMAN: The menu has pretty much
got everything you want.
FIERI: This is not a menu.
This is a book.
It's a book.
Dude, it's enormous.
It's a shield.
It's a hat.
It's wings.
[ Laughs ]
I absolutely love it.
Cool place. Yeah, I see why
the tradition's going well.
You're rocking it out.
You are definitely a character.
You are the quintessential
diner dude.
Diner dude!
On "Triple D," when I say
New Jersey,
I know what you're thinking --
you're thinking diner capital.
Along with those great diners,
they got some funky
little joints
like the one
I'm here to visit today.
45 minutes south of New York
City in Belmar, New Jersey,
this is
10th Avenue Burrito Company.
Smothered burrito.
Smothered in chipotle cream
sauce, absolutely phenomenal.
Chicken tortilla soup.
It is the best.
This, to me, is like food
that we find in California.
Firing a corn soup.
'Cause that's where Jersey boy
Brian Katz fell in love
with this kind of Mexican food.
Firing pork mole.
And learned to cook, too.
Went for a job one day, and I've
been in the kitchen ever since.
And after decades
in the biz...
Tequila lime shrimp.
...he brought his own take
on Mexican home to Jersey.
Amazing.
You can't get any Mexican like
this around here.
I just like to let people
experiment with new
and different flavors.
FIERI: Like a Mexican spin
on chicken wings.
Adobo wings.
I've never made Adobo.
And that gets tossed on
the wings?
That gets tossed on the wings.
The Adobo sauce is outrageous.
Adobo wings.
I love 'em.
We're gonna make Adobo sauce.
Adobo being the red
tomato sauce,
some vinegar that reconstitutes
the chipotles.
Absolutely.
Which is a smoked jalapeño.
Got 'em right here.
Put the strainer in the pot,
and then we're gonna add
everything in the strainer.
Okay.
Whole heads of garlic.
Onions in there.
Wow, this is cool.
Cinnamon sticks, a little
sweetness with the heat,
thyme, the oregano.
Like a cup, just about.
Throw some bay leaves.
Peel and seal it.
Oh!
This, crystallized, hard,
Mexican sugar. Awesome.
Add just a few cloves,
oranges, water,
straight-up white vinegar.
And this is pineapple and orange
that I just let steep in
cold water for a few days.
Let that cook down for about
3 1/2 hours.
All right,
so this is simmered.
Strain out all the solids
from the Adobo.
Look at 'em, how they soak up
all that juice.
A little tomato puree.
Let it boil out, go ahead
and give this a --
Whoo! How much longer are
we gonna let this simmer?
For about another
15 or 20 minutes.
I don't feel any more
chunks, boss.
I think we're good to go, then.
Check this out.
That is awesome.
Aw, you're gonna
put that on wings.
Season them with a little
kosher salt,
a little cracked black pepper,
and toss 'em in the sauce.
Nice, thickened up a little.
And you don't just serve 'em
like that, put 'em on the grill?
No, we actually put 'em on
the grill,
just a little more flavor,
put 'em right back in this bowl.
Awesome, and we're gonna
come over here and plate 'em,
a little
avocado ranch dressing.
Here we go.
Mm, gosh, dude.
Mm, these are rocking.
The sauce is out of bounds.
Right heat, right spice.
Mm, mm, mm!
Dude, you are truly
a rock star on this.
Nice job.
Thanks, man.
Got to come try these wings.
Adobo wings.
Fantastic.
MAN:
Caramelized on the outside,
when it's grilled,
puts it over the top.
Pork mole platter.
Fresh food, unique food.
Amazing.
Adobo mac and cheese, please.
You're knocking this food out.
It's a great job.
Thanks, man.
I appreciate it, man.
It's really a pleasure.
Thank you.
So, that's it for
this road trip, but don't worry,
we got plenty more joints to
find all over this country!
I'll be looking for you
next time
on "Diners, Drive-ins,
and Dives."
[ Applause ]
Amazing.
Did you see the tear?
Actually, I got a little tear.
He gave you the ring, and you
started to cry, I'm, like, "Ah!"