(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
DRIVER: There's 100,000
streets in this city.
You don't need
to know the route.
You give me
a time and a place,
I give you
a five-minute window.
Anything happens in that
five minutes and I'm yours.
No matter what.
Anything happens a minute
either side of that
and you're on your own.
Do you understand?
Good.
And you won't be able to reach
me on this phone again.
Hey, there you are!
She's down there.
Plain Jane Boring,
just like you asked for,
but I dropped in 300
horses on the inside,
she is going to fly.
You look
like a zombie, kid.
You getting any sleep?
Can I offer you some Benzedrine,
Dexedrine, caffeine, nicotine?
Oh, you don't smoke.
That's right.
Better off.
There she is!
Chevy Impala, the most popular
car in the Stale of California.
No one will be
looking at you.
(SIREN WAILING)
(RADIO ANNOUNCER CALLING
BASKETBALL GAME)
(GUNSHOT)
(ALARM SOUNDING)
(BEEPS)
(STATIC)
POLICE OFFICER 12
...Robert Victor 3.
POLICE DISPATCH: License 5-1-4.
Robert Victor 3...
(DISPATCH CONTINUES)
(TURNS UP VOLUME)
POLICE DISPATCH: Code 30 Ringer
located at 421 South Alameda.
Reports of shots fired
at Code 30.
Come on.
Where the fuck is he?
(SIREN WAILING)
POLICE DISPATCH:
Unit 5, what's your 20?
POLICE OFFICER 1: We are approximately
two minutes from that location.
Come on, man.
Where the hell are you?
Come on!
Come on! Get in!
Get in! Get in!
Whew! Whew!
Come on, man.
Go, go, go, go, go!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
POLICE DISPATCH:
AH units be advised.
Possible vehicle
in question.
Late model
silver Impala.
POLICE OFFICER 1: 1-Adam-3,
South Bay at Seventh, clear.
Roger, 1-Adam-3.
Requesting
air unit support.
(DISPATCH CONTINUES)
POLICE OFFICER 2: Unit 5 to Dispatch,
heading eastbound on Sixth.
POLICE DISPATCH:
Copy that, Unit 5.
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
POLICE DISPATCH:
Base to Air 3.
Any sign of
that silver Impala?
AIR 3: Air 3 to Base.
Negative.
Got a visual heading west
on Seventh Street bridge.
(ENGINE REVVING)
Copy, Air 3. All units,
be advised...
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Base, Air 3 here, We've
lost visual on suspect,
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
Base to Air 3.
Possible gang shooting in progress.
Proceed immediately to Washington and La Brea.
(SIRENS WAILING)
Roger, Dispatch.
Pm out.
(RADIO STATIC)
POLICE DISPATCH: AH westbound
units, be advised.
Suspect last seen near
Seventh Street and Sanfa Fe.
(RADIO ANNOUNCER CONTINUES
CALLING GAME)
(TURNS UP VOLUME)
POLICE OFFICER 3: Dispatch,
this is 1-Adam-6.
Possible suspect vehicle
sighted at stoplight.
Stand by.
Roger, Unit 6.
(ACCELERATING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(RADIO ANNOUNCER CALLS
END OF BASKETBALL GAME)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(CROWD CLAMORING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
(NIGHTCALL PLAYING)
♪ I'm giving you
a night call
♪ To tell you
how I feel
♪ I want to drive you
through the night
♪ Down the hills
♪ I'm gonna
tell you something
♪ You don't want to hear
♪ I'm gonna show you
where it's dark
♪ But have no fear
♪ There's something inside you
♪ It's hard to explain
♪ The're talking
about you, boy
♪ But you're still the same
♪ There 's something inside you
♪ It's hard to explain
♪ They're talking
about you, boy
♪ But you're stiff the same
♪ There 's something inside you
♪ It's hard to explain
♪ The're talking
about you, boy
♪ But you're still the same
What floor?
Fourth. Thanks.
Hey, kid,
you know what?
Director wants to see a roll over.
Are you okay
with that?
Remember, if you don't feel
good, just abort the shot.
There's no shame
in that, all right?
I mean, you're...
You're doubling for the star.
You're not like a day
player or anything.
And I got you
500 more, huh.
Of course,
we split that.
You okay?
Ready to go?
All right.
Counting on you!
PRODUCTION MANAGER: Excuse me, pal.
I just need a minute here.
Before I put you on camera, I
need you to sign this contract.
It just basically releases
liability to the company
in case you die, get maimed,
or seriously injured.
ASSISTANT DIRECTOR:
And action!
(CAR SPEEDING)
ASSISTANT DIRECTORS: All right,
that's a cut!
Oh, kid!
That was fantastic!
Just fantastic.
Okay. How you doing?
You all right?
You were good. You were good.
Thai was perfect.
IRENE: You're a monkey.
BENICIO: No,you're the monkey.
(SOFTLY) You're the monkey.
You're the monkey.
No, you're the monkey.
Hey, tell me one thing.
BENICIO: I love you.
I love you.
(CAR ENGINE HISSING)
Ah!
Where should I put this?
In the kitchen.
Thank you.
Just be a second.
Scary.
(BENICIO LAUGHS)
Hey, you want
a tooth pick?
IRENE: You want
a glass of water?
Okay.
(POURING WATER)
Thanks.
So, you just
moved to LA?
No, I've been here
for a while.
You're just new here?
Mmm-hmmm.
That's Benicio's father.
Where is he?
He's in prison.
Oh.
What do you do?
I drive.
Like a limo driver?
No, like, for movies.
Oh.
You mean, all the car
chases and stuff?
Yeah.
Is that dangerous?
It's only part-time.
Mostly I work
at a garage.
Where?
Reseda Boulevard.
I gotta go.
Okay.
Thanks for the water.
Say bye.
BENICIO: Bye.
(SIGHS)
WAITER: Mr. Rose,
your food, sir.
ROSE: Okay.
Chicken chow mein
and some Peking duck.
Okay. Where are
the chopsticks?
WAITER: Oh, you Know.
The guy just...
(WAITER MUMBLING) Go get them.
Go get them.
I don't want that.
I don't want that. You eat it.
Chopsticks
and a fortune cookie.
Put out the fucking cigarette.
I'm eating.
Sorry.
What's the matter
with you?
Rm just...
What happened to all the
ashtrays in this town?
(CHUCKLING)
You run a perfectly
good business.
I don't know why you
want 10 change now.
You know how much my
business made last year?
Thirty grand.
I can build a car
in six months
and in six seconds, these
jerks write it off as a stunt
that won't even make
it into the movie.
Mmm-hmm.
See, all I need is
a hard used stock car.
That's all.
And I figure we start off with small
town circuit and we work our way up.
And once we get to the show,
we're talking millions.
WAITER: I have the chopsticks, sir.
Yeah.
Where's the cookies?
WAITER: Uh... You know, I...
Forget it. Forget it.
So, you still haven't
given me a number.
All right.
$430,000.
(EXCLAIMS)
Mr. Rose, I wouldn't
come to you with this
unless I was
absolutely sure about it.
How can you be sure,
Shannon?
What do you got that the big
professional race teams don't?
I got the driver.
You just told me they had
half a dozen drivers.
Not like this one.
This kid is special.
I've been working
with him for a while.
I've never seen
anything like it.
If I had the money,
I'd back him myself.
Yeah, but you don't
have the money.
Mr. Rose, you put this
kid behind the wheel,
there's nothing
he can't do.
There's money here.
You can't lose.
Fuck you eating chink food
in my fucking restaurant?
What's a Jew doing
running a pizzeria?
You remember Shannon.
Take a fucking hike.
I want to talk to my partner.
I'm just fucking
with you.
How you doing, Shannon?
How's the fucking leg?
I paid my debt.
I'll think about it.
Okay?
But I want to
meet the kid first.
That's all I ask.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Come on, I want you
to meet somebody.
And whatever you do like about
the car, don't say anything.
I want to drive the price
down a little bit.
Kid, I want you to
meet Mr, Bernie Rose.
Nice to meet you.
My hands are
a little dirty.
So are mine.
(CHUCKLES)
Good driving
out there.
Thanks.
SHANNON: He's a good kid.
So, what do you think?
Do we get the 400?
I'll give you 300
for 70%.
Done.
Right. Good.
(LAUGHING)
You won't be sorry.
I'm Shannon.
Hi. Irene.
Irene. How can
I help you?
It just broke down.
Just broke down. Just like that.
IRENE: Mmm-hmm.
You want me to take a look at it?
IRENE: Yes, please.
All right. Uh...
We got
all our bays full.
Hey, pal,
just drop it down here.
We'll push it in,
all right?
We want to push her
into number three.
The car, not you.
on, good. (LAUGHS)
Hi.
You two know
each other?
Don't.
Oh. Look at that.
We're neighbors.
Neighbors? Very good.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, we'll try to
be neighborly too.
You blinked.
What?
Can I call a cab
from here?
Yeah. Sure.
What am I
talking about?
You and the kid
are neighbors, right?
He can take you home.
Oh, no.
I'd feel bad.
No, no.
Don't even think
twice about it.
He'd be happy to do it.
He's a good guy.
You know, he walked into my shop
here about five or six years ago.
Right out of the blue.
Asking for a job.
So I put him to the test
to see what he could do.
The kid's amazing.
Yeah.
So, I hire him
on the spot,
Boom. (SNAPS FINGERS)
At about half the wages I normally pay.
(LAUGHS)
He didn't
blink an eye.
Hey, kid, come over here
for a second, will you?
And I have been exploiting
him ever since.
(LAUGHING)
(SHUSHING)
Don't tell him.
Looks like we have a bigger
problem than I thought.
And we're going to have to keep
the car here for a few days.
So I offered your services to
take Benicio and Irene home.
Thar be okay?
Yeah, sure.
Yeah.
I don't have wheels
on my car.
(LAUGHING) Okay.
It's one thing you
should know about me.
Well, put the tires on.
You got five minutes?
Yeah.
Hey, do you want to
see something?
Yeah.
Okay.
(A REAL HERO PLAYING)
♪ Back against
the wall and odds
♪ With me strength
of a will and a cause
♪ Your pursuits are
called outstanding
♪ You're emotionally complex
♪ Against the grain
of dystopic claims
♪ On the thoughts
your actions entertained
♪ And you have proved to be
♪ A real human being
♪ And a real hero
♪ Real human being
♪ A pilot on a cold,
cold morn'
♪ One-hundred fifty-five
people on board
♪ All safe and all rescued
♪ From the slowly
sinking ship
♪ Water warmer than
his head so cool
♪ In that tight bind
knew what to do
♪ And you have
proved to be
♪ A real human being
♪ Real human being
That was good.
He had a good time.
Me, too.
Sorry if I put you on the
spot showing up like that.
It's okay.
I'm not doing anything
this weekend.
If you want a ride
or something.
(BENICIO LAUGHING)
SHANNON: Don't worry about her bumps
and bruises, that's just fiberglass.
That's easily
replaceable.
Put a coat of paint on there,
some sponsor decals.
Look at the tread on the
tire's still good, huh?
We're in business.
We paid 300 fucking grand
for this piece of shit?
ROSE: I paid for it.
Out of my own pocket.
This is just the shell.
It's the inside that
counts, not the outside.
Right, Shannon?
SHANNON: You are correct, sir.
Fuck that shit.
I pay 300 for something,
I want everybody
to fucking see it.
ROSE: Of course
you do.
Now, this.
That is one motherfucking fine-ass
pussy mobile, motherfucker.
Damn!
Shannon, sell
him the car.
He wouldn't be able to find
pussy in a whorehouse.
SHANNON: You know what?
This car will even make you good-looking.
NINO: I'm already
good-looking, pal.
How's it going?
When's our first race?
Uh, pretty soon.
You gonna
be ready?
I hope so.
(LAUGHING) "l nope so."
Hey, no false modesty.
I got a lot of money in this.
Did Shannon ever
tell you how we met?
No.
I used to
produce movies.
In the '80s.
Kind of like action films.
Sexy stuff.
One critic called
them European.
I thought
they were shit.
Anyway, he arranged all the cars for me.
Did all the stunts.
I liked him.
I liked having him around.
Even though he overcharged
the shit out of me.
His next business venture,
he got involved with
some of Nine's friends.
They didn't go for
the overcharging bit.
They broke his pelvis.
He's never had
a lot of luck.
The reason
I'm telling you this
is that he has a lot
invested in you.
And so do I.
So anything you need,
you call me.
We're a team now.
(LAUGHS)
I'm excited.
Nino, let's get the
fuck out of here.
(TV PLAYING)
Is he a bad guy?
Yeah.
How can you tell?
Because he's
a shark.
There's no
good sharks?
No. I mean, just look at him.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Does he look like
a good guy to you?
Hi.
How are you?
Good. How are you?
Good.
This is Cindy.
Hi.
(PHONE RINGING)
That was my
husbands lawyer.
He's coming home
in a week.
(UNDER YOUR SPELL PLAYING
IN ANOTHER APARTMENT)
♪ I don't eat
♪ I don't sleep
♪ I do nothing
but think of you
♪ I don't eat
♪ I don't sleep
♪ I do nothing
but think of you
♪ You keep me
under your spell
We're here celebrating, but it's
a shameful thing what I did.
And I have a lot of making up
to do to everyone.
But second chances
are rare.
Right?
And that's worth
celebrating. Right?
So I want to make a toast
to that lady right there.
Thanks for staying.
I love you, Renie.
Salud.
♪ I don't sleep
♪ I do nothing
but think of you
♪ I don't eat
♪ I don't sleep
♪ I do nothing
but think of you
♪ You keep me
under your spell
(VOCALIZING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hey.
Hi.
Sorry about
the noise.
I was going to
call the cops.
I wish you would.
STANDARD: Oi!
You're getting heavier.
STANDARD: Hey.
IRENE: Hey.
(COUPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
STANDARD: Hey.
How you doing?
Hi. This guy's been telling
me a lot about you.
Says you been coming
around, helping out a lot.
Yeah? Helping our?
Is that right?
Mmm-hmm.
Oh.
That's very nice.
That's nice of you. Thank you.
You're welcome.
You drive
for the movies?
Yeah.
I can take that.
No, no, no. I got it.
Let Mommy talk
to her friend.
Come on.
Have a good night.
You're Shannon's
buddy, right?
We met last year.
You drove me and my brother
back from Palm Springs.
(MUMBLES)
We hired another wheelman.
I spent six
months in jail.
My brother, he got
himself Killed.
I got this sweet
job coming up.
How about this?
You shut your mouth.
Or I'll kick your teeth down your
throat and I'll shut it for you.
Nice seeing
you again.
STANDARD: Come on,
it's okay.
Come here.
Don't be scared.
Don't tell
Mommy, okay?
Okay? it's a secret
between the boys.
Oh, fuck me.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(TV PLAYING)
Who were they?
(LAUGHS) What the fuck
are you going to do?
You're gonna go
beat them up for me?
Huh, stunt guy?
Why the fuck do you want
to know who they are?
Huh?
(SIGHS)
There are some guys that
want me to do a job for them
and I'm not
going to do it.
That's who they are.
What's the job?
They want me to rob a
pawnshop in the Valley.
Why?
'Cause I owe them some protection
money from when I was inside.
It's 2,000 bucks.
But as soon as I got out,
oh, it's 5,000 bucks.
Oh, no, actually, it's $10,000.
$20,000.
Tomorrow I don't know what
the fuck it's going to be.
What are you
going to do?
That's a really
good question.
They said they were going to come
after Benicio and Irene next.
You okay?
You want something
to drink?
What is ii
you got there?
Can I see?
One of those men
gave you that?
Mmm-hmm.
They told me not to lose it.
You want me to keep
that for you?
Okay.
(SIGHS)
How's Benicie?
Good.
You just saying that?
No.
What do you mean?
I saw that Standard
was in an accident.
Yeah.
What happened?
He got beat up.
Mmm-hmm.
Why?
Just drunk kids.
You should come over.
You should come and see him.
You want to...
You want to hear a story?
Do you want to hear how
Mommy and me met? Yeah.
Yeah? Okay.
(IRENE CHUCKLING)
STANDARD: We were at a party.
And she was 19 years old.
IRENE: Seventeen.
You weren't 17.
I was.
Wow. So it was illegal?
IRENE: Yeah.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
(LAUGHING) All right. So I illegally
walked over to a 17-year-old girl.
And I walk up and
I say, "Hello, Miss.
"What is your name?"
And she didn't say anything.
And then I said.,.
"Well, my name is
Standard Gabriel."
Then what did you say?
I said...
"Where is the deluxe
version?" (LAUGHS)
(STANDARD LAUGHS)
STANDARD: She's
good, man.
Sharp.
Oh, man.
It killed me.
(LAUGHS)
And then a year later,
you popped out, man.
It was the best day
of my life.
(STARTS ENGINE)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
DRIVER: If drive for you,
you get your money.
You tell me where we start,
where we're going,
where we're going
afterwards.
I give you five minutes
when we get there.
Anything happens in that
five minutes, and I'm yours.
No matter what.
Anything a minute on either side
of that and you're on your own.
I don't sit in while
you're running it down.
I don't carry a gun.
I drive.
You look like you're
hard to work with.
Not if we understand
each other.
What's to understand?
I can't do
this thing alone.
COOK: You got Blanche.
Come on, man.
COOK: (LAUGHING) She's
beautiful. Look at her.
What the fuck you rolling
your eyes at for?
You know what, get
the fuck out of here.
Get up!
Standard, take her with you and
go get her a fucking coke!
Okay, here's the deal.
This much for Blanche,
this much for that asshole,
minus what he owes me,
and this much for you.
You still interested?
Good. Anything else?
When you get your money,
his debt's paid.
He's out for good.
And you never
go near his family again.
You understand?
STANDARD: I'm here
with my family.
And my new friend.
And...
Toast to the future.
To our future.
Hey.
I'll see you
in five minutes.
I'll see you in four.
(WATCH TICKING)
(GUNSHOT)
(BLANCHE GASPS)
BLANCHE: Oh, my...
(GUNSHOTS CONTINUE)
Shit!
Oh, my God!
(CAR HONKING)
(EXCLAIMING)
(HONKING)
(TV NEWS IN BACKGROUND)
How much did Cook say
we were going to get?
Forty grand.
Stay here.
(DIALING PHONE)
(CHATTER ON POLICE RADIO)
POLICEWOMAN: When was the last
time you saw your husband?
Can you answer
the question?
Ma'am.
(PHONE RINGING)
BENICIO ON PHONE: Hello?
Benicio?
Is that you?
Yeah.
Hey.
Hi.
Is your mother there?
Uh... She's sitting down
talking to the police.
Okay, just tell her I'm going
to call her back, okay?
Okay, bye.
In related news, an attempted
robbery turned tragic today
when the owner of a local pawnshop
opened fire on an intruder.
The armed robber was
pronounced dead at the scene.
He has been identified as Standard
Gabriel of Echo Park, Los Angeles.
Other details are unclear,
but the owner of the pawnshop
told reporters that
Gabriel acted alone
and that no money
had been stolen.
In other news, four high school
athletes were arrested...
If he saw you
take the money
and he saw you
get in the car,
then why didn't
he say anything?
I have no idea.
Did you have any idea
there'd be a second car?
I already told
you everything.
(MUFFLED SOBBING)
Now, you just got a little
boy's father killed.
And you almost
got us killed.
And now you're
lying to me.
So, how about this?
From now on, every word out
of your mouth is the truth.
(CRYING)
Or I'm going to hurt you.
Do you understand?
Now what did
Cook tell you?
He said there'd be
another car to hold us up,
but he didn't say anything
about all this money.
He didn't say anything
about anyone getting killed.
You were going
to rip us off?
What's his real name?
He says it's Chris,
but I just call him Cook.
You're going to take me
to him right now.
(BLANCHE WHIMPERS)
Do you understand?
Yes.
(PHONE VIBRATING)
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(GRUNTS)
(THUD)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(CONTINUES RINGING)
Easy. Easy.
What did you do
with the cash?
'Cause I could keep it
safe for you...
Will you just stop it?
This guy Cook, does
he have a real name?
Chris.
Maybe.
I'll ask Bernie.
See if he knows him.
Jesus, I can't...
I can't stop thinking about what
we could do with all that dough.
Will you just stop?
All right.
A lot of guys mess around
with married women,
but you're the only one
I know who robs a joint
just to pay back
the husband.
Crazy.
Don't worry about it.
I'll take care of it.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Where's Cook?
He's in the
dressing room.
Where's that?
It's over there.
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
Whose money do I have?
Don't worry.
They're going to come get it.
No! No!
Call them.
Somebody call Nino!
Do you remember this?
(COOK COUGHING)
(PHONE RINGING)
MAN: Hello.
Nino?
No, sorry, pal.
Why don't you call back later?
We're closed.
I could, but I think Nino would
be upset that you made him wait.
Can I ask what
this is about?
I have something of his.
And that would be?
A million dollars.
Please hold.
NINO: You got something
that fucking belongs to me?
It seems that way.
And you're calling me?
Why?
You expect me to buy my
own shit back from you?
I'm not selling it.
I'm going to give you
a time and a place
and you're going
to come and get it.
Do you understand?
And what do you
get out of it?
Just that.
Out of it.
And your partners
are happy with that?
I don't have any partners.
You discuss this
with anybody else?
No, just you.
You're not very good
at this, are you?
(DRIVER HANGS UP)
Go check out who
this fucking guy is.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(IRENE EXHALING)
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
Can't talk.
I have to go.
Can I just walk
with you for a...
Yeah.
I have to tell you
something.
Standard was into some...
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
...guys in prison
for a lot of money.
And they were going to hurt you
and Benicio if he didn't pay it.
He asked me for my help.
Everything went wrong.
I'm sorry.
I still got the money.
You can have it
if you wanted to.
You can take Benicio...
I just thought you could get
out of here if you wanted.
I could come with you.
I could look out for you.
(ELEVATOR DOOR OPENS)
Sorry. Wrong floor.
(GRUNTING)
They came to my
apartment, Shannon.
How'd they know
where I live?
I told you. I was
going to call Bernie.
I just warned him to know that...
That it wasn't about...
That you're not interested
in the money.
That you just did
it for the girl.
(GASPS)
I just... Why did you have to
fucking tell them about Irene?
Calm down!
You told them
about Irene!
Calm down, kid.
Just calm down.
I should fucking
kill you!
You told them
about Irene.
I just wanted him
to know
that as soon as you returned the
money, that was the end of it.
That's all.
I didn't know...
How was I supposed
to know?
to know that? Okay?
Look, let me just
talk to Bernie. Okay.
Why you got to fuck
everything up, Shannon?
How was I supposed to know
everything led to Nino?
They're gonna come
looking for me.
And they're going
to come for you.
Do you understand?
You got to get out of here.
And you got to get out now.
Listen to me.
Oh, God.
Listen to me, Shannon.
Listen.
You get out of here and you
never fucking come back.
You never come back.
What are you
going to do?
I already gave you
my advice.
You should have taken the
money and left the guy alone.
It's not that
simple, Bernie.
No, of course not. Now that
it's bounced up in your face.
COOK: Nino,
I owe you this guy.
Just give me a little time
and I'll get rid of him.
Shut the fuck up,
you fucking monkey.
The money belongs to some
half-assed wise guy out of Philly.
Now, I'm ripped off,
he was stashing a million
bucks in a pawnshop.
He was going to invest
it here in LA.
He was going to set
up a rival operation.
So you stole from the
East Coast mob?
No. I stole from
some jumped-up punk
who was trying to step
on our action.
Yeah? Then why didn't
you come to me
before you set up
this dummy robbery?
Before you hire
this piece of shit.
This is something
off to the side, Bernie.
I didn't want to
involve you in this.
Well, I'm involved now!
I'm going to tell
you something.
Anybody...
Anybody finds out
you stole from the family,
we're both dead.
What fucking family?
The family who still
calls me a fucking kike!
To my face!
Yeah, I'm 59
years old, Bernie.
They still pinch my cheek
like I'm some fucking kid.
Family.
The money always
flows up, Izzy.
You know that.
(NINO SIGHS)
That's why this driver's
gotta go, Bernie.
He's gotta go.
And your pal, Shannon.
These are the only two guys who
can tie me to this robbery.
(COOK SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
Now it's your turn
to clean up after me.
All these
priceless cars.
One would think you'd
have better locks.
Why?
Door's always
open to you.
Going somewhere?
Uh..- (LAUGHS)
Thinking about ii.
I'm looking
for your driver.
You break in here,
I figure it's bad news.
No, Shannon.
it's bad luck.
2,000 heists a year
in this city,
he has to pick
the wrong one.
He tried to put it right.
Well, he picked the wrong
guy for that, too.
My partner is a belligerent asshole
with his back against the wall.
Right now, so am I.
If I don't set this straight,
I'm in big trouble.
Any idea where
he might be?
Mexico.
Or maybe it was Belize.
Really?
I was getting excited
about this whole thing.
My name on a car!
I mean, look
how beautiful.
I wanted to see
my name on this thing.
I think we would have made
a go at this business.
(GASPS)
Don't worry.
That's it.
It's done.
There's no pain.
It's over. It's over.
(GASPING)
(SIGHING)
(OH, MY LOVE PLAYING)
♪ Oh, my love
♪ Look and see
♪ The sun rising
from the river
♪ Nature's miracle once more
♪ Will light the world
♪ But this light
♪ Is not for those men
♪ Still lost in
♪ An old black shadow
♪ Won't you help me to believe
♪ That they will see
♪ A day
♪ A brighter day
♪ When all the shadows
♪ Will fade away
♪ That day I'll cry
♪ That I believe
♪ Oh, my love
♪ High above us
♪ The sun now
♪ Embraces nature
♪ And from nature
we should learn
♪ That all can start again
♪ As the stars must fade away
♪ To give a bright new day
What the fuck was that?
(DOOR CLOSES)
Let's get out of here.
Yeah.
(PANTING)
ROSE: Hello?
DRIVER: You know the story about
the scorpion and the frog?
Your friend Nino didn't
make it across the river.
I think this has gone
on long enough.
You see any reason
for it to continue?
What do you
say we meet?
Why?
Well, you, me, and your girlfriend
are the only players left.
How's that for a reason?
When?
Tomorrow.
There's a place
on Sherman Way,
it's a restaurant
called The Great Wall.
Do you know it?
DRIVER: Can I talk to you?
I won't keep you long.
I have to go somewhere and I
don't think I can come back.
But I just want you to know.
Getting to be around
you and Benicio
was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
Did you bring
the money?
Here's what
I'm prepared to offer.
You give me the money,
the girl is safe.
Forever. Nobody
knows about her.
She's off the map.
I can't offer
you the same.
So, this is what
I would suggest.
We conclude our deal.
We'll shake hands.
You start the
rest of your life.
Any dreams you have,
or plans,
or hopes for your future...
I think you're going to
have to put that on hold.
For the rest of your life you're going
to be looking over your shoulder.
I'm just telling you this
because I want you
to know the truth.
But the girl is safe.
Where's the money now?
It's in the car.
Come on.
(YELLS)
(GRUNTS)
(A REAL HERO PLAYING)
♪ A pilot on a cold, cold morn'
♪ One-hundred fifty-five
people on board
♪ All safe and all rescued
♪ From the slowly
sinking ship
♪ Water warmer
than his head so cool
♪ In that tight bind
knew what to do
♪ And you have
proved to be
♪ A real human being
♪ And a real hero
♪ Real human being