A beginning
is a very delicate time.
Know then, that it is
the year 10,191.
The known universe is ruled by the
Padishah Emperor Shaddam the Fourth,
my father.
In this time, the most
precious substance in the universe...
is the spice, melange.
The spice extends life.
The spice
expands consciousness.
The spice is vital
to space travel.
The Spacing Guild
and its navigators,
who the spice has mutated
over 4,000 years,
use the orange spice gas,
which gives them
the ability to fold space.
That is, travel to any part
of the universe...
without moving.
Oh, yes.
I forgot to tell you.
The spice exists on only one planet
in the entire universe.
A desolate, dry planet
with vast deserts.
Hidden away within the rocks of these
deserts are a people known as the Fremen,
who have long
held a prophecy...
that a man would come,
a messiah,
who would lead them
to true freedom.
The planet is Arrakis,
also known as Dune.
[Wind Howling]
A secret report
within the Guild.
Four planets have come
to our attention...
regarding a plot which could
jeopardize spice production.
Planet Arrakis,
source of the spice.
Planet Caladan,
home of House Atreides.
Planet Giedi Prime,
home of House Harkonnen.
Planet Kaitain, home of the Emperor
of the known universe.
Send a third-stage
guild navigator to Kaitain...
to demand details
from the Emperor.
The spice must flow.
[Voices, Indistinct]
- Father,
- Irulan, you must leave.
A third-stage guild navigator...
will be here within minutes.
We felt his presence.
I shall want telepathy
during his visit...
and a report
when we're finished.
I am your Truthsayer,
my lord.
He's here, my lord.
The Bene Gesserit witch
must leave.
Leave us.
Yes, my lord.
We are alone.
[Breathing]
- We have just folded space from lx.
- Yes?
How was your journey?
Many machines on lx.
New machines.
Oh? Yes.
Better than those on Richese.
You are transparent.
I see many things.
I see plans within plans.
I see two great houses,
House Atreides,
House Harkonnen, feuding.
- I see you behind it.
- Yes.
You must share with us.
The Atreides House
is building a secret army...
using a technique unknown to us.
A technique involving sound.
The duke is becoming
more popular in the Landsraad.
He could threaten me.
I have ordered House Atreides
to occupy Arrakis to mine the spice,
thus replacing their enemies,
the Harkonnens.
House Atreides will not refuse because of the
tremendous power they think they will gain.
Then, at an appointed time,
Baron Harkonnen
will return to Arrakis...
and launch a sneak attack
on House Atreides.
I have promised the baron five legions
of my Sardaukar terror troops.
So the Harkonnens
will rid you of House Atreides.
Yes!
[Navigator]
One small point.
Here it comes.
We ourselves perceive
a slight problem...
within House Atreides.
Paul. Paul Atreides.
You mean, of course,
Duke Leto Atreides, his father.
I mean Paul Atreides.
We want him killed.
I did not say this.
I am not here.
I understand.
[Inner Voice] Why would they
want the duke's son killed?
We must have a look
at Paul Atreides, on Caladan.
[Princess Irulan] The powerful Bene
Gesserit sisterhood for 90 generations...
has been manipulating
bloodlines...
to produce the Kwisatz Haderach,
a super being.
On Caladan, Jessica,
a member of the sisterhood...
and the bound concubine
of Duke Leto Atreides,
had been ordered
to bear only daughters.
Because of her love
for the duke...
she disobeyed
and gave birth to a son--
Paul-- Paul Atreides.
Here we are now, Caladan.
And 19 light-years beyond,
beyond Bene Tleilax.
[Man] The training planet
of the Mentats, the human computers.
Know a Mentat
by his red-stained lips.
[Inner Voice]
There. Arrakis.
[Woman]
Spice mining.
Carryalls lower
the harvester to the sand...
and lift it off to safety
when a worm attacks.
Worms attack
all rhythmic vibrations.
Weather. See storms.
No precipitation.
[Paul]
Never one drop of rain on Arrakis.
And the Harkonnens are near.
There. Giedi Prime
and the Baron Harkonnen.
The enemy.
[Man] The Baron Harkonnen has
sworn to destroy House Atreides...
and steal the ducal signet ring
for himself.
I know, Thufir.
I'm sitting with my back to the door.
I heard you, Dr. Yueh,
and Gurney
coming down the hall.
Those sounds
could be imitated!
I'd know the difference.
[Inner Voice]
Yes, perhaps you would at that.
My father sent you to test me.
Music, then?
No music.
I'm packing this for the crossing.
- Shield practice.
- Gurney, we had practice this morning.
I'm not in the mood.
Not in the mood!
- Mood's a thing for cattle and love play, not fighting!
- I'm sorry, Gurney.
Not sorry enough.
[Inner Voice] What's wrong
with Gurney? He's not faking this.
Now, guard yourself for true!
Is this what you seek?
Good. The slow blade
penetrates the shield.
But, uh, look down.
[Gurney]
We'd have joined each other in death.
You did seem finally
to get the mood.
Would you really
have drawn my blood?
If you'd have fought
one whit below your abilities,
I'd have given you a good scar
to remind you.
Things have been
so serious here lately.
Soon we leave for Arrakis.
Arrakis is real.
The Harkonnens are real.
Dr. Yueh, do you have any information
on the worms of Arrakis?
I have obtained a filmbook
of a small specimen.
- Only 125 meters long.
- [Laughing]
-Only?
-There have been documented sightings...
of worms as large as 450 meters
in the deep desert.
That's far from where
we'll be in Arrakeen.
The desert belt and the south
polar region are marked forbidden.
[Paul]
How do the Fremen survive there?
We don't know much
about the Fremen.
They live in the deep desert,
some in the cities.
They have blue within blue eyes.
Oh, the eyes. Yes.
The saturation of the blood
by the spice, melange.
Could the spice affect us
in other ways?
[Thufir]
Many dangers exist on Arrakis.
For one, the Harkonnens
would not have given up...
their CHOAM Company contract
so easily.
The Harkonnens
are our enemies, yes.
But behind them, I suspect,
is the Emperor.
You'll make
a formidable duke.
Now remember, the first step
in avoiding a trap...
is knowing
of its existence.
I know. But if it is a trap,
then why are we going?
We have our new army.
Dr. Yueh,
put the weirding module on him.
Well.
Clear and lock the room!
[Guard]
Detachment, stand down.
Activate a fighter.
[Mechanical Whirring]
[Clanging]
Make the range two meters.
[Mechanical Noises Continue]
[Humming]
Precise control.
[Heavy Footfalls]
Duncan!
Paul. I was just on my way
to say good-bye to you.
I have to go on ahead.
I won't be seeing you for a while.
I wish you were
coming with us. Why?
Something for your father.
He wants to talk to you.
I'll see you on Arrakis.
May the hand of God
be with you.
be with us all, Duncan.
- Father.
- Thank you for joining me, Paul.
Thufir Hawat has served House Atreides
three generations.
He swears you are the finest student
he has ever taught.
Yueh, Gurney and Duncan
say the same.
- Makes me feel very proud.
- I want you to be proud of me.
I'll miss the sea.
But a person needs
new experiences.
They jar something
deep inside,
allowing him to grow.
Without change,
something sleeps inside us...
and seldom awakens.
The sleeper must awaken.
Arrakis.
Dune-- Desert planet--
[Inner Voice]
I will kill you.
The second moon.
Tell me of your home world, Usul.
[Inner Voice]
I know she has come to test him.
No man has ever been tested
with the box.
Tonight, I may lose my son.
Jessica, you were told to bear
only daughters to the Atreides.
Jessica!
It meant so much to him.
You thought only of a duke's desire
for a son?
Desires don't come into this.
An Atreides daughter
could have been wed...
to a Harkonnen heir
and sealed the breach.
We may lose
both bloodlines now.
I vowed never
to regret my decision.
I'll pay for all my own mistakes.
And your son will pay with you.
Arrakis... Dune...
Desert planet.
Moving. Moving.
[Thunderclap]
[Reverend Mother]
We'll salvage what we can.
But I can tell you,
dear God--
For the father, nothing.
[Inner Voice]
For the father, nothing?
Did you really think you could bear
the Kwisatz Haderach?
The universe's super being?
How dare you?
My greatest student.
And my greatest disappointment.
He's awake.
He's listening to us.
Good. Ready yourself,
young Paul Atreides.
I want to see you in your mother's
chambers in one quarter of an hour.
Paul, this is very important.
[Inner Voice]
Kwisatz Haderach. The super being.
For the father, nothing.
Vas.
[Thunderclap]
This is the Reverend Mother
Gaius Helen Mohiam.
She's going to observe you.
- Please.
- Jessica,
you know it must be done.
Your Reverence.
[Inner Voice]
What does she fear?
What about my father?
Paul.
Listen to the Reverend Mother
and do what she tells you.
[Deep Voice]
Now you...
come here!
[Inner Voice]
She's using the Voice.
No.
[Inner Voice]
Some strength there.
Surprising.
Come here!
Do you see this?
Put your right hand
in the box.
What's in the box?
Pain. Stop!
Put your hand in the box.
I hold at your neck
the gom jabbar.
This one kills only animals.
Are you suggesting
a duke's son is an animal?
Let us say I suggest
you may be human.
Your awareness may be powerful enough
to control your instincts.
Your instinct will be
to remove your hand from the box.
If you do so, you die.
You will feel...
an itching.
There.
Now the itching becomes...
burning.
Heat upon heat.
- Upon heat!
- It burns.
Silence! Silence!
[Inner Voice] I must not fear.
Fear is the mind killer.
Fear is the little death
that brings total obliteration.
I will face my fear.
I will permit it to pass
over me and through me.
- I must not fear.
- You feel the flesh crisping?
...is the little death
that brings total obliteration.
Flesh... dropping off.
Fear is the little... death!
I must not fear.
Fear is the little death.
I'm--
- The pain!
- No!
Enough.
Kull wahad. No woman child
ever withstood that much.
Take your hand out of the box
and look at it,
young human.
Do it!
Pain by nerve induction.
A human can resist any pain.
Our test is crisis
and observation.
I see the truth of it.
[Inner Voice]
Could he be the one? Maybe.
But will he be
ours to control?
Tell me of your home world, Usul.
Do you know
of the Water of Life?
The bile from the newborn worms
of Arrakis?
- I have heard of it.
- It is very dangerous.
The Bene Gesserit sisterhood
use it to see within.
There is a place
terrifying to us,
to women.
It is said
a man will come,
the Kwisatz Haderach.
He will go
where we cannot.
Many men have tried.
They tried and failed?
They tried and died.
Jessica.
[Inner Voice]
My son lives.
I sense your teachings in him.
Ignore the regular order
of training.
His safety requires the Voice.
I've heard enough of my safety.
What about my father?
I heard your talking.
You speak as if he were dead.
Well, he's not.
And he won't die.
Tell me he won't die.
- What can be done has been done.
- Mother, tell me.
[Messenger]
Message for Mentat Piter De Vries.
The Baron is impatient
for Leto's reply.
It is by will alone
I set my mind in motion.
It is by the juice of Sapho
that thoughts acquire speed,
the lips acquire stains,
the stains become a warning.
It is by will alone
I set my mind in motion.
It is by the juice of Sapho
that thoughts acquire speed,
the lips acquire stains,
the stains become a warning.
It is by will alone
I set my mind in motion.
My lord.
Piter.
The Atreides will be leaving
Caladan soon, Baron,
and I have here your answer
from Duke Leto.
What does Leto say, Piter?
He wishes to inform you that "vendetta,"
as he puts it, using the ancient tongue,
the art of Kanly,
is still alive.
He does not wish to meet
or speak with you.
I've made my peace gesture.
The forms of Kanly
have been obeyed!
Bring in Feyd and Rabban.
As you instructed me,
I have enlightened your nephews
concerning my plan--
My plan!
The plan...
to crush the Atreides.
Feyd.
Rabban.
Go quietly.
No other great house
of the Landsraad...
must ever know of the Emperor's aid
to the Baron.
The entire Landsraad
would turn against the Baron...
and the Emperor.
Put the pick in there, Pete,
and turn it 'round real neat.
Ahhh.
[Laughing]
You are so beautiful, my Baron.
Your skin, love to me.
Your diseases,
lovingly cared for...
for all eternity.
[Baron]
I will have Arrakis back for myself.
He who controls the spice
controls the universe!
And what Piter
did not tell you...
is we have control
of someone who is very close,
very close to Duke Leto.
This person, this traitor,
will be worth more to us
than ten legions of Sardaukar!
And who is this traitor?
[Laughing]
I won't tell you who the traitor is...
or when we'll attack.
However, the duke will die
before these eyes,
and he'll know,
he'll know that it is I,
Baron Vladimir Harkonnen,
who encompasses his doom!
[Laughing]
Ha, ha! Ha, ha!
[Inner Voice] This is what I'll
do to the duke and his family.
Oh, I'll miss Caladan so much.
[Inner Voice]
Caladan.
Soon they will begin
to fold space.
[Inner Voice] Far off
in the control rooms of spice gas...
traveling... without moving.
[Reverend Mother Ramallo]
And now, the prophecy.
One will come.
The voice from the outer world,
bringing the holy war,
the jihad, which will
cleanse the universe...
and bring us
out of darkness.
[Princess Irulan Narrating] House Atreides
took control of Arrakis 63 standard days...
into the year 10,191.
It was known that the Harkonnens,
the former rulers of Arrakis,
would leave
many suicide troops behind.
Atreides patrols were doubled.
Duncan.
What have you discovered
about the Fremen, Duncan?
Tell me. Why haven't
we heard from you?
My lord, I suspect so much.
I think they
are the allies we seek.
They are strong, fierce.
They do not give their loyalty
easily or quickly.
As you know, the Imperium has never been
able to take a census of the Fremen.
Everyone thinks that there are but few
wandering here and there in the desert.
My lord,
I suspect an incredible secret
has been kept on this planet,
that the Fremen exist
in vast numbers--
vast--
and it is they
who control Arrakis.
[Indistinct Chattering]
[Military Announcer] Each trooper
will be charged with responsibility...
for preserving water.
Our existence
as an operating army...
depends on these following
water-saving procedures.
Remember, water is life.
Why is the shield not yet up?
Sir, we found and removed
another sabotage device.
I think it'll
go up now, sir.
[Military Announcer] ...armed forces
prospects for rehabilitation are good.
We're finding
these sabotage devices too easily.
[Military Announcer]
House shield activating.
Duke Leto is now here. Spice mining
inspection to start immediately.
So you are Dr. Kynes,
the Judge of the change.
- And the Imperial Ecologist, sire.
- Our intelligence informs us...
that there's still
a strong Harkonnen presence.
The process of removal continues.
This is my son, Paul.
- Are you a Fremen?
- I've been on Arrakis...
in the service of the Emperor
long enough for my eyes to change.
[lnner Voice]
In the service of the Emperor.
We are in your hands, Doctor.
Your gift of the stillsuits
is much appreciated.
Will you give us an explanation
of their workings?
Well, this is a stillsuit
of Fremen manufacture,
the most efficient type
on Arrakis.
- Basically--
- [Growling]
It's all right, Gurney.
Yes, sire.
Basically,
it's a high efficiency
filter and heat exchange system.
Perspiration passes through
the first layer,
and is gathered
in the second,
where salt is separated.
Breathing and walking
provide the pumping action.
The reclaimed water
circulates to catch pockets...
from which you can drink
through this tube...
at your neck.
Urine and feces are processed
in the thigh pads.
Should you be
in the open desert,
remember to breathe in
through your mouth...
and out through
this nose tube.
With a Fremen suit
in good working condition,
Iife can be sustained
for weeks,
even in the deep desert, sire.
My thanks.
With your permission.
- You've worn a stillsuit before.
- No.
Your suit is fitted
desert fashion.
- Who told you how to do that?
- No one.
It seemed the proper way.
That it is.
[Inner Voice] He shall know
your ways as if born to them.
We're wasting time, sire.
[Indistinct Grunting]
Battle language?
Translate it.
[Grunting Continues]
Very faint.
Harkonnen!
[Air Controller]
Airspeed: zero five.
Ambient temperature:
300 degrees kelvin.
Airspeed: three zero.
...75%%% efficiency.
That's where I told your sandmaster
to concentrate the harvesting today.
Southeast, over the shield wall.
[Air Traffic Controller]
Ambient temperature: 350 degrees kelvin.
Airspeed: one three zero.
Caution: You've now cleared
protective shield wall...
and entered open desert.
Will we see a worm?
Where there's spice and spice mining,
there are always worms.
- Always.
Why do they come?
To protect their territory.
Vibrations attract them.
[Inner Voice]
He must be a Fremen,
or in with them.
He's studying us.
He's hiding something
about the spice.
Is there a relationship
between the worms and the spice?
As I said,
they defend the spice sand.
As to their relationship
with the spice,
who knows?
[Inner Voice]
My message. It's here.
There are more enemy bodies coming in
for your inspection, Doctor Yueh.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, I'm fine.
Thank you, Thufir.
- Dust cloud ahead, sire.
- That's it. Spice mining.
No other cloud quite like it.
Wormsign. Is it wormsign?
[Doctor Kynes]
Yes. Worm. Big one.
You've got sharp eyes.
May I?
Calling Harvester Pad Nine.
Wormsign.
[Man On Radio]
Who calls Pad Nine?
Don't mention the duke.
This is an uncoded channel.
Unlisted flight northeast of you.
Wormsign on intercept course.
Estimated contact: 15 minutes.
[Man On Radio] Have sighting
confirmed. Stand by for fix.
Contact in 16 minutes minus.
Very precise estimate.
Who's on that unlisted flight?
- What happens now?
- The carryall will come and lift off the spice harvester.
Try to get in close
over the harvester.
You'll find this interesting, sire.
They'll work until the very last minute.
Spotter control,
there's no sign of the carryall.
It isn't answering.
The worm is eight minutes away, sire.
[Spice Miner] Spotter control,
give me a report by the numbers.
- [Miner Number One] Report One.
- [Miner] No contact.
- [Miner Number One] Report Two.
- [Miner] Negative.
- [Miner Number One] Report Three.
- [Miner] Negative, sir.
- [Miner Number One] Report Four.
- [Miner] No contact.
I think they've got
our carryall.
Damn it.
Harkonnens.
We are coming down to take you off the
harvester. All spotters are ordered to comply.
- Ordered by whom?
- Duke Leto Atreides.
- Yes. Yes, sire.
- How many men do you have?
Full crew, 26 men.
But, sire, we can't
leave all this spice.
Damn the spice!
Get out of there!
Two men in each of the spoilers!
You, over here! Run! Run!
I can't see him yet,
but he's very close.
Damn sloppy.
Really damn sloppy.
Come on, boys, come on!
We're going to be heavy, sire.
[Inner Voice]
Spice.
Pure, unrefined spice.
[Doctor]
Here it is! We've got to go!
Bless the maker and his water.
Bless the coming and going of him.
- May his passing cleanse the world.
- What's that you're saying?
Nothing.
[Growling]
[Worm's Growling Continues]
Gods, what a monster!
Someone is going to pay for this,
I promise.
[Inner Voice] He's more concerned
over his men than the spice.
I must admit,
against all better judgment,
I like this duke.
Milady, the local people,
the maids and servants,
await your inspection.
Hawat has cleared them.
Excuse me, milady.
The Harkonnens may have
tampered with them medically.
When you said Harkonnens,
I didn't know you had
so much reason to hate them.
My wife--
[Sighing]
But of course, you didn't know my wife.
The Hark--
Forgive me.
[Inner Voice]
They must have killed her.
Please excuse me
if I can't talk about it.
[Inner Voice]
He's holding something back.
Yet--
There's the Imperial Conditioning.
Assurance of trust.
[Inner Voice]
The Bene Gesserit mother. The legend.
Where is your son?
I must warn you,
you are in great danger.
[Beeping]
Safe.
[Inner Voice]
Spice.
What is it doing to me?
Second moon.
[Leto]
The sleeper must awaken.
[Paul]
Am I the one?
[Buzzing]
A hunter seeker.
Can't get me if I don't move.
It's too dark in here
for it to see clearly.
I've got to try to grab it.
Suspensor field will make it
slippery on the bottom.
I must grip it tightly.
Who is operating that thing?
It has to be someone
in the palace.
I could shout for help, but it would
kill whoever opened the door.
[Inner Voice]
Hold still.
- [Panting]
- It would have killed me.
I was its target.
It went to the motion.
Who are you?
I am the Shadout Mapes,
the housekeeper.
I must cleanse
the way between us.
You saved my life,
and we Fremen pay our debts.
[Inner Voice]
A Fremen.
It is known to us that you've
a traitor in your midst.
Who it is, we cannot say.
But we are certain of it.
A traitor.
- [Alarm Blaring]
- [Shouting] Let's go, guys!
[Shouting Continues]
Set up a sonar probe immediately.
Over here!
Harkonnen.
[Inner Voice] They have tried
to take the life of my son.
Sector six through 80,
progress reports, sire.
Take it, Thufir.
Sector six, 80, copy the sixth,
the sum of the eighth,
the quadrant over the ninth, plus 80, four
circles, weave the 80 and call the fourth.
Copy.
[Machine Cranking]
Eight, Thufir Hawat,
Mentat, Master of Assassins.
The, uh, the palace
is now secure.
The city of Arrakeen
is under martial law.
We have troops here,
headquartered underground,
on subfloors six through ten.
The rest of the troops
are stationed in Arrakeen,
and we have some
on the airfield.
Our new army
is still in training,
but everything,
everything is shielded,
and with this shielding,
we are impenetrable.
Sleep well, my son.
[Straining]
Father... drugged.
[Inner Voice]
Jessica, what is wrong?
Forgive me,
my beloved concubine.
I should have married you.
Why hold a dream to ascend to a throne
through a political marriage?
I should have married you.
[Gasping, Groaning]
[Gasping, Groaning Continue]
What happened?
[Grunts]
Yueh!
[Inner Voice] He sabotaged the
house generators. We are wide open!
[Man On Loudspeaker]
House shield deactivating.
I've destroyed the new army's
weirding modules.
I've brought
House Atreides down.
- Why?
- I wish to kill a man.
Not you, my dear Duke.
You were already dead.
But you'll get close
to the baron before you die.
You'll be tied and drugged,
but you can still attack.
You can still attack!
When you see the baron,
you'll have
a new poison gas tooth.
He'll want you close
so he can gloat over you.
One bite on this tooth,
and a strong exhale--
- Refuse.
- No, you mustn't!
Because, in return, I'll save
the lives of your Paul and Jessica.
For Paul.
Oh!
When you see the baron,
remember the tooth.
The tooth. The tooth!
- [Alarm Blaring]
- The shield is down! The shield is down!
Open the doors!
Signals!
- Get that shield up!
- The shield! The shield!
[Thufir]
The weirding modules. Destroyed!
Long live Duke Leto!
[Troops Shouting]
The drug was timed.
Dr. Yueh has been
very valuable to us.
What a pity
you must remain gagged.
We can't let ourselves be swayed
by your witch's voice now, can we?
[Inner Voice]
Leto, where are you?
How simple to subdue us.
[Crying]
[Explosions In The Distance]
Good-bye, Jessica.
And good-bye
to your sweet son.
I want to spit once on your head.
Just some spittle in your face.
What a luxury.
We were ordered
to kill them, so kill them.
[Gasping, Groaning]
[Inner Voice]
I wish this was Paul.
I knew Yueh's wife.
I was the one who broke
his Imperial Conditioning.
I've thought of many pleasures
with you.
It is perhaps better that you die
in the innards of a worm.
[Groans]
What are your orders, Piter?
Take them to the desert
as the traitor suggested.
The worms will destroy the evidence.
Their bodies must never be found.
They're down on this floor somewhere.
Down there.
Duncan!
Yaaah!
Yaaaah!
You wish now to join your wife?
Is that it, traitor?
She lives?
You wish to join her?
Join her.
[Gasping, Choking]
You think you've defeated me?
You think I don't know what
I gained... for my wife?
[Gasping, Coughing]
Take him away.
[Jessica's lnner Voice]
Yueh's sign.
He's left us stillsuits.
[Laughs]
[Using The Voice]
Don't touch my mother!
[Inner Voice]
He's trying the Voice.
The Reverend Mother
said it could save him.
Did you hear a noise
from the little one?
Huh? I didn't hear anything.
[Grunts]
- The little one.
- [Laughs]
[Using The Voice]
Remove her gag.
[Inner Voice]
Excellent.
[Voice Echoing]
Remove her gag.
[Panting]
[Using The Voice]
There's no need to fight over me.
[Voice Echoing]
There's no need to fight--
[Groaning]
[Inner Voice]
A poisoned blade.
[Using The Voice]
First... cut my son's bonds.
That's it.
[Grunts]
Oh, my God!
[Inner Voice]
It's under control.
Duke Leto Atreides.
Where is the ducal signet ring?
I must have his ring.
[Mutters]
The ring!
He was brought to us
as is, my lord Baron.
[Panting]
You killed the doctor
too soon, you fool!
[Inner Voice]
The doctor, Yueh. What did he say?
Paul and Jessica safe.
Yes! The tooth!
He's coming around, Baron.
Where's your ring?
Huh? You do not answer?
[Inner Voice]
Wait. Wait.
You must come closer.
The water...
of my life...
for Paul.
He's crying. He's crying!
What does that mean, Piter?
Come closer, Baron.
[Bites Tooth]
- [Yells]
- [Dish Shatters]
[Inner Voice]
Jessica! Paul!
Leto! Leto, he's dead!
[Crying]
Oh, he's dead!
I know.
Am I alive?
- I'm alive?
- Yes.
You're alive, my Baron.
[Laughing]
I'm alive, eh?
I'm alive!
I am alive!
[Laughing]
I can't maintain any altitude.
We'll never reach
the safety of rock.
Maybe that small rock.
Where are we,
do you think?
The south polar regions.
The forbidden area.
Hold on.
[Screams]
Hurry!
Take the stillsuits.
Hurry! This crash
might bring a worm.
[Groaning]
The signet.
A million deaths
are not enough for Yueh.
[Sobbing]
[Inner Voice] Where are my
feelings? I feel for no one.
The second moon.
[Navigator]
I mean Paul Atreides.
We want him killed.
[Paul's lnner Voice]
Why? Why do they want me killed?
It has to be something
to do with the spice.
But what?
[Wind Howling]
[Baron] He who controls the spice
controls the universe!
[Paul's lnner Voice]
This moon holds my future.
Never one drop of rain on Arrakis.
[Duke Leto's lnner Voice]
The sleeper must awaken.
[Inner Voice]
They will call me Muad'Dib.
Listen to me. Listen.
You wanted to know
about my dreams.
Well, I've just had
a waking dream.
Do you know why?
The spice!
It's in everything here.
Calm yourself.
Like the Truthsayer drug.
It's a poison.
You knew the spice
would change me.
But thanks to your teachings,
it's changing my consciousness.
I see it!
I can see it!
[lnner Voice]
Is he the one?
You carry my unborn sister
in your womb.
[Inner Voice]
He knows.
Father!
[Inner Voice] Father, I promise
one day the sleeper will awaken,
and I will avenge your death.
I will not stop until I destroy
the emperor and the baron.
Father.
[Groaning]
[Grunts]
[Groans]
Go now.
Take him to his desert...
to die.
[Chuckles]
Go.
[Laughing]
[Inner Voice] Yueh's left the plan
for the weirding modules.
[Thunderclap]
We have to get to
that mountain of rock.
We have entered the time when all
will turn against us and seek our lives.
[Electrical Storm Crackling]
It's further than I thought.
A worm is sure to come.
I'll plant this thumper.
That should divert it.
[Thunderclap]
[Rhythmic Thumping]
Remember, walk without rhythm,
and we won't attract a worm.
It will go to the thumper.
I'm ready.
[Thumping Continues]
[Roaring]
Faster!
It's deafening!
[Roaring Continues]
[Inner Voice]
The spice.
- Do you smell it?
- Yes!
Paul!
[Roaring Continues]
[Inner Voice]
A thumper.
[Thumping]
The worm! Spice!
Is there a relationship?
[Thumping Continues]
[Gasps]
What's happened?
[Crying]
Why did it leave?
Someone started
another thumper.
We're not alone.
[Electrical Storm Continues]
Man-carved steps.
Yes.
[Thunderclap]
[Jessica Whispering]
Such stealth.
I didn't hear them.
[Man] Perhaps these are the ones
the Shadout Mapes told us of.
I will take the boy-man.
[Coughs]
He shall have sanctuary
in my tribe.
[Growling]
[Grunts]
Stop! Get back!
She has the weirding way.
Great gods!
If you can do this
to the strongest of us,
you're worth ten times
your weight of water.
[Groans] As the leader of
my people, I give you my bond.
Teach us this weirding way,
and you both
shall have sanctuary.
Your water shall mingle
with our water.
Then I will teach you
our way of battle.
I give you the word bond
of a Bene Gesserit.
It is the legend.
I am Chani,
daughter of Liet.
I would not have permitted you
to harm my tribe.
[Inner Voice]
From my dreams. So beautiful.
Come with me.
I'll show you an easier way down.
You have strength.
You shall be known as Usul,
which is the strength
of the base of the pillar.
This is your secret name
in our troop,
but you must choose
the name of manhood...
which we will call you openly.
What do you call the mouse shadow
in the second moon?
We call that one Muad'Dib.
Could I be known
as Paul Muad'Dib?
You are Paul Muad'Dib.
And your mother shall be
a Sayyadina among us.
We welcome you.
[Inner Voice]
A dream unfolds.
[Gasps]
Moisture!
Wind traps.
Huge ones.
[Inner Voice]
Water.
Millions of decaliters.
A treasure.
Greater than treasure, Usul.
We have thousands
of such caches,
and only a few of us
know them all.
And when we have enough,
we shall change
the face of Arrakis.
[Musical Tone]
Tell me of your home world, Usul.
[Inner Voice]
"Tell me of your home world, Usul."
[Hysterical Laughing]
[Laughing Continues]
[Laughs]
Rabban! Rabban!
We're knee-deep in Atreides blood.
We've gutted them!
[Laughing Continues]
Rabban. Rabban!
[Chomping]
I place you in charge of Arrakis.
It's yours to squeeze
as I promised.
I want you to squeeze
and squeeze and squeeze!
Give me spice!
Drive them! Drive them
into utter submission!
Do not show the slightest pity
or mercy!
Never stop! Go! Go!
Show no mercy!
Yes, Baron.
[Laughing]
[Laughing, Yelling]
[Grunts]
Feyd.
[Baron Panting] And when
we've crushed these people enough,
I'll send you, Feyd.
Lovely Feyd.
[Gasping, Panting]
[Shouts]
Where's my doctor?
[Man]
Jessica...
our Reverend Mother is too old.
She has been calling
through space and time...
for you to come
and let her rest.
She asks that you pass within
and become our Reverend Mother.
If you be a Reverend Mother...
Iet Shai-Halud judge now!
[Inner Voice]
The Water of Life.
But what of my unborn child?
[Inner Voice]
One day, I will have to do this.
[Screaming]
[Princess Irulan Narrating]
Following the Bene Gesserit tradition,
the old Reverend Mother
surrendered her life...
as she surrendered her knowledge.
Jessica had successfully transmuted
the poisonous Water of Life.
[Inner Voice]
Every man who has tried has died.
Am I the one?
[Duke Leto's Voice]
The sleeper must awaken.
[Jessica Screaming]
[Princess Irulan Narrating] The
tremendous power of the Water of Life...
caused the premature birth
of Jessica's daughter, Alia.
Alia was born with all the knowledge
and powers of a Reverend Mother.
[Baron]
Feyd, even though he's aging,
Thufir's one of the finest Mentats
in the universe.
And he's mine, Feyd, all mine.
- Try it now.
- I will.
Come.
[Cat Meows]
Oh, Thufir!
I see they've installed
your heart plug already.
Don't be angry.
Everyone gets one here.
But this is not
why we're here.
We brought you
a little cat, Thufir.
You must care for it
if you wish to live.
[Cat Meowing]
A poison has been introduced
into your body, Thufir Hawat.
By milking this,
this smooth little cat's body,
you receive your antidote.
It must be done each day.
All I can see...
is an Atreides
that I want to kill.
Feyd! No, no!
Thufir's a Harkonnen now.
Aren't you, Thufir?
[Inner Voice]
My duke! How I've failed you.
Chani, I love you.
[Sighs]
I've always loved you.
[Paul's lnner Voice]
The Holy Warriors.
No one ever dreamed
there were so many.
I am Usul.
Paul Muad'Dib.
Our shared enemy, the Harkonnens,
are once again
in control of Arrakis.
Stilgar, your leader,
has asked me and my mother...
to teach you the weirding way
to crush the Harkonnens.
We must do more than this.
We must totally destroy
all spice production on Arrakis.
The Guild and the entire universe
depends on spice.
He who can destroy a thing
controls a thing.
I will take 100 of your warriors
and train them.
This 100 will train
the thousands that remain.
When the spice flow stops,
all eyes will turn to Arrakis.
The baron
and the emperor himself...
will be forced to deal with us.
Arrakis will become
the center of the universe.
Orato!
This obelisk
is of your hardest stone.
Kick it.
Hit it.
- Yell at it.
- [Laughter]
[Shouts]
Break!
[Laughter]
Korba... cut it.
Move back.
[Clicking, Electronic Humming]
Cha-a-a-a...
a-aksa!
[Together]
Muad'Dib!
This is part of the weirding way
that we will teach you.
Some thoughts
have a certain sound,
that being the equivalent
to a form.
Through sound and motion...
you will be able to paralyze nerves,
shatter bones,
set fires, suffocate an enemy
or burst his organs.
We will kill until no Harkonnen
breathes Arrakeen air.
[Together]
Muad'Dib!
Cha-a-a-a-aksa!
Stilgar!
- Muad'Dib!
- Hmm?
[Translating Machine]
Muad'Dib. Muad'Dib. Muad'Dib.
[Inner Voice]
My name is a killing word.
They are ready to fight.
Yet in order to lead them,
I must conquer the worm.
Conquer Shai-Halud.
Take the kiswa maker hook
of our sietch...
and ride as a leader of men.
[Together]
Mmmmmm. Shai-Halud.
[Thumping]
[Inner Voice] I must not fear.
Fear is the mind killer.
[Thumping Continues]
Only the very strong ones
travel this deep.
Usul has called a big one!
Again, it is the legend.
[Worm Roaring]
[Roaring]
[Low Roaring]
Look!
[Together]
Muad'Dib!
[Stilgar] Usul, these are 15
of our finest warriors...
to serve you as your guard.
The Fedaykin.
Cha-aksa!
Ooh!
Now.
Cha-a-aksa!
Cha-aksa! Cha-aksa!
Aaaah!
Cha-aksa!
[Inner Voice] When the spice flow
stops, all eyes will turn to Arrakis.
The baron and the emperor himself
will be forced to deal with us.
Muad'Dib. Muad'Dib.
What happened?
What happened to you and your men?
- Muad'Dib. Muad'Dib.
- What are you saying?
- Muad'Dib. Muad'Dib. Muad'Dib.
- What?
- [Crunch]
- [Grunts]
He's been repeating that name
ever since we found him.
Who is this... Muad'Dib?
Cha-aksa!
[Princess Irulan Narrating]
In the two standard years that followed,
Muad'Dib and the Fremen brought
spice production to a standstill.
Fearing for his life,
Rabban did his best...
to hide this fact
from his uncle, the baron.
Paul's sister, Alia,
matured at a frightening rate.
Her small body
harbored tremendous powers.
Paul and Chani's love grew.
We surprised
a band of smugglers.
Too bad.
I thought they were Harkonnen.
Cha-aksa!
[Screams, Grunts]
Cha-a-aksa!
Gurney!
You've no need of your weapons
with me, Gurney Halleck.
Paul? Paul?
Don't you trust
your own eyes?
They said you were dead.
They... they said--
Gurney! Gurney man!
- You young pup! You young pup!
- Gurney!
[Alarm Blaring]
[Translating Machine]
Emperor Shaddam the Fourth,
you have one last chance
to take matters into your own hands...
and bring the situation
under control on Arrakis.
- What do you mean one last--
- Silence! Do not speak!
Listen! You do not have
more than this one chance.
I represent the entire Guild
in this matter.
Our navigators warn you that
spice production is in great danger.
A new Fremen leader, Muad'Dib,
has stopped spice mining on Arrakis.
Our navigators suggest
he is not of Arrakis.
No one on the outside world
has been able to see him.
We do not know who he is.
The Harkonnens
cannot stop him.
Remedy the situation,
restore spice production,
or you'll live out your life
in a pain amplifier.
The emperor will stop him.
He won't take the Water of Life.
[Paul's lnner Voice]
That's why they want me killed.
They're afraid I'll take
the Water of Life.
I want 50 legions of Sardaukar
on Arrakis at once!
Fifty legions?
That's our entire reserves as well.
This is genocide: the deliberate
and systematic destruction...
of all life on Arrakis!
[Paul]
The emperor is coming. Chani! Chani!
[Gasping]
You were calling my name.
It frightened me.
Oh, Chani.
All the images
of my future are gone.
I have to drink
the Water of Life.
No. Paul. Please.
I've seen the men
who have tried.
- I've seen how they died.
- [Coughing]
I'm dead to everyone
unless I try...
to become what I may be.
[Gasping]
Only the Water of Life
will free what can save us.
Paul.
I must drink the sacred water.
[Paul]
We must go now.
Hurry. All I see is darkness.
Paul,
I will love you forever.
You are my life.
[Reverend Mother]
Many men have tried.
[Paul]
They tried and failed?
[Reverend Mother]
They tried and died.
[Paul] The worm is the spice.
The spice is the worm.
[Screaming]
[Paul]
The worms.
[Inner Voice]
They're not attacking. Why?
- Alia.
- Mother.
It's Paul.
He's taken the Water of Life.
[Reverend Mother]
There is a place...
terrifying to us, to women.
[Paul]
This is the place they cannot look.
Travelling without moving.
Now I truly control the worm...
and the spice.
And I have the power
to destroy the spice forever!
Paul.
Father!
Father, the sleeper has awakened!
[Fremen Chanting]
Muad'Dib. Muad'Dib.
[Chanting Ceases]
Arrakis.
Dune. Desert planet.
Your time has come.
A storm is coming.
Our storm.
And when it arrives
it will shake the universe.
Emperor, we come for you!
We come for you!
Long live the fighters!
[Together]
[Man On Radio] Suspicion confirmed:
The emperor's had Rabban seized.
Gurney, when the storm hits,
set off the atomics.
I want an opening through
the entire shield wall.
Stilgar, do we have wormsign?
Usul, we have wormsign the likes
of which even God has never seen.
[Roaring]
Bring in that
floating fat man,
the baron.
[Gasping]
Why have you brought me here?
Your Highness...
there must be some mistake.
- I never requested your presence.
- Ah.
But your lack of action
demanded it.
Your dreadful mismanagement,
your bad judgment...
in assigning to Rabban
the governorship.
You've forced me to come here
and set things straight, personally!
I am a messenger from Muad'Dib.
Poor Emperor!
I'm afraid my brother
won't be very pleased with you.
-Silence!
-Kill this child. She's an abomination.
[Reverend Mother]
Kill her!
Get out of my mind!
[Deep Voice] Not until you
tell them both who I really am.
Alia.
Daughter of
Duke Leto the Just...
and the Royal Lady Jessica.
Sister of Paul Muad'Dib.
Paul's sister?
Paul is Muad'Dib?
[Gasping, Screaming]
Alia keeps pace
with the storm.
[Paul] With the storm,
their air power will be useless.
On Arrakis,
it's desert power.
Gurney,
now!
Atomics!
[Alia]
My brother is coming...
with many Fremen warriors.
Impossible!
Not impossible!
I told you.
He is here now.
[Roaring]
[Inner Voice]
Father, today I will avenge your death.
[Roaring]
[Sardaukar On Radio] Emperor,
an impassable storm has descended.
The shield wall
has been penetrated by atomics.
Release the Sardaukar!
Baron, give this
little abomination to the storm.
[Inner Voice]
Wait for my brother, Baron.
[Roaring]
Cha-aksa!
[Weapons Firing]
[Inner Voice]
Wait for my brother.
[Shouting]
Cha-aksa!
Muad'Dib!
[Roaring]
Cha-aksa!
[Inner Voice]
Alia, now.
Come to me, Baron.
[Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
[Together]
Muad'Dib.
[Paul's lnner Voice]
Feyd Rautha.
Emperor Shaddam the Fourth,
there are Guild heighliners
above us...
containing many great
Houses of the Landsraad.
- Send them back!
- How dare you speak to me in that--
Stop your speaking!
You have some idea
of what I could do.
[Growling]
Don't try your powers on me.
Try looking into that place
where you dare not look.
You'll find me there
staring back at you.
- You mustn't speak--
- Silence!
[Screaming]
- I remember your gom jabbar.
- [Gasping Continues]
Now you remember mine.
I can kill with a word.
Aaaah! Aaaah!
[Fedaykin Soldier] And his word
shall carry death eternal...
to those who stand
against the righteous.
- The righteous?
- There is a Harkonnen among you.
Give the Harkonnen a blade,
and let him stand forth.
If Feyd wishes, he can meet you
with my blade in his hand.
- I wish it.
- This is a Harkonnen animal.
Let me.
Please, my lord.
The Emperor's blade.
[Drumbeats Continue]
Why prolong the inevitable?
I will kill you!
[Laughing]
[Grunting]
I will kill him!
Paul!
[Laughing]
Who is the little one?
A pet, perhaps?
Will she deserve
my special attentions?
[Paul's lnner Voice]
Poisoned.
You see your death.
My blade will finish you.
[Inner Voice]
I will bend like a reed in the wind.
Aaaaah!
Cha-aksa!
Muad'Dib!
Usul no longer needs
the weirding module.
[Princess Irulan Narrating]
Muad'Dib had become the hand of God,
fulfilling the Fremen prophecy.
Where there was war,
Muad'Dib would now bring peace.
Where there was hatred,
Muad'Dib would bring love,
to lead the people
to true freedom,
and to change
the face of Arrakis.
We Fremen have a saying.
God created Arrakis
to train the faithful.
One cannot go against
the word of God.
[Thunderclap]
And how can this be?
For he is the Kwisatz Haderach!