[Beeping]
[Water Dripping]
[Owl Hoots]
[Low-Pitched Tone]
Aahr!
Ahhr.
I think I see him!
This way!
[Engines Whir]
Aahr!
Ahhr...
Ahhr.
[Sirens Wail]
Five.
Oh, great.
You got an arrow
right in your chest.
Don't worry.
I got resurrection.
I'm
already undead.
I can
still throw
death spells.
Just trying
to help you.
Throw a spell
over the pizza man.
Where's our pizza,
man?
I'm ready to...
now to play.
I'm ready
to play now, guys.
We're in the middle,
Elliott.
You can't join
in the middle.
I got him!
What am
I asking for?
Papa oom mow mow.
O.K.
Mike?
It's for his mother.
Ask Steve.
He's game master.
He has
absolute power.
Steve?
Steve, can
I play now?
Go wait for
the pizza first.
Then I'm in?
You're in.
Figure out
your strategy.
You're playing
after Greg.
Plenty of sausage
and pepperonis.
Everything
but the little fishies.
Oops.
♪ Apapa oom
mow mow mow ♪
♪ Papa oom
mow mow ♪
[Garbage Can Rattles]
Harvey?
Harvey,
is that you, boy?
♪ I hear that sound
everywhere I go ♪
♪ Papa oom
mow mow ♪
♪ Apapa oom
mow mow mow ♪
Over here,
you guys.
Stop it.
Sorry.
♪ Papa oom
mow mow... ♪#
[Rattling]
Harvey?
All's you get
is those 40-year-olds.
How do you
win this game?
It's like life.
You don't win at life.
Mom! There's
something out...
Where's the pizza?
There's something
out there!
In the tool shed.
It threw
the ball at me.
Quiet!
Nobody
go out there.
Stop. Now, you guys
stay right here.
You stay here, Mom.
We'll check it out.
And put
those knives back!
It's OK, Elliott.
Let's go
get the flashlight.
Hold it.
Wait a minute.
Ooh, creep...
Creepy.
What exactly
did you see?
In there.
Woo... ha!
It's scary.
Woo!
There's
nothing in here.
The gate's open.
Look at these.
Coyote's come
back again, Mom.
OK, party's over.
Everybody
back inside now.
Get out.
Hurry up.
Quick. Hurry up.
Tyler, give me
that knife.
Oh, great.
Nice one,
Elliott.
It was an accident.
Who said you guys
could order a pizza?
Uh... him.
Huh? In
the house.
You geek, man.
Mom, it was real.
Douche bag.
No douche bag talk
in my house.
[Rattling]
[Whistles]
Elliott, you're crazy.
Runff.
[Rustling]
Aarh!
Aah!
[Whistles]
Hello.
Hello?
[Jangling]
What are you going as
for Halloween?
I'm not going
to stupid Halloween.
Go as a goblin.
Shut up.
It's not
that we don't
believe you, honey.
Well, it was real.
What are
you going as, Gert?
I'm going
as a cowgirl.
So what else
is new?
Maybe it was
an iguana.
It was no iguana.
Maybe a...
You know
how they say
there are alligators
in the sewers?
Alligators
in the sewers.
All we're
trying to say is
maybe
you imagined it.
I couldn't have.
Maybe
a deformed kid.
A deformed kid.
Maybe an elf
or leprechaun.
It wasn't that,
penis breath!
Elliott!
Sit down.
Ahem.
Dad would believe me.
Maybe you ought
to call your father
and tell him
about it.
I can't.
He's in Mexico
with Sally.
Wh-Where's Mexico?
Excuse me.
I'm going
to kill you.
If you see it again,
whatever it is,
don't touch it.
Just call me.
We'll have somebody
take it away.
Like the dogcatcher?
They'll give it
a lobotomy
or do experiments on it
or something.
Your turn
to do the dishes.
I set and cleared.
I did.
I did breakfast.
[Plate Breaks]
What's the matter, Mom?
He hates Mexico.
Damn it!
Why don't you
grow up?
Think how
other people feel
for a change.
[Rustling]
Ahhr...
Ma...
Mom.
Michael.
[Munching]
Ahhr.
Wow.
[Beeping]
[Munching]
OK, you're hot.
I'll be back.
Mary, can I
back the car out?
Not 1 foot past
the driveway.
[Scrape]
You were
outside last night
waiting
for that thing,
weren't you?
Going to live
if I go to work?
O.K.
No TV.
Come on.
Mommy, look
what Michael did.
This and...
I see them, Gert,
and when I catch him,
I'll catch him.
Come on.
Don't be afraid.
It's all right.
Come on.
Do you talk?
You know, talk?
Me human.
Boy.
Elliott.
Ell-i-ott.
Coke. See,
we drink it.
It's, uh...
It's a drink.
You know, food?
These are toys.
Little men.
This is Greedo.
And then this
is Hammerhead.
You see,
this is Walrus Man.
And then this
is Snaggletooth.
And this is
Lando Calrissian.
See?
And this
is Boba Fett.
Look. They
can even have wars.
Pffz!
Plzzaz! Plzzaz!
Aah.
And look. Fish.
The fish
eat the fish food,
and the shark
eats the fish,
but nobody
eats a shark.
See, this is Pez.
Candy.
You see, you eat it.
You put the candy
in here,
and when you
lift the head,
the candy comes out.
You want some?
This is a peanut.
You eat it.
But you
can't eat this one
'cause this is fake.
This is money.
You see?
We put the money
in the peanut.
You see? Bank.
And then...
This is a car.
This is what
we get around in.
See? A car.
Hey!
Hey,
wait a second.
No. You don't
eat them.
Are you hungry?
I'm hungry.
Stay.
I'll be right here.
OK? I'll be
right here.
Harv!
Aahr!
[Woof Woof]
Come on, Harvey.
He'll like this.
This.
Aah!
Aahr!
Are you OK?
Too much
excitement, huh?
Want a Coke?
Thirty-five pounds.
Thirty-five pounds!
You're so fat!
I wonder how tall you are.
I'm four-six.
You must be around
three...
This is where the water
comes from. See?
[Gags]
This is hot and this is cold.
Now, it all comes
from a big water tower.
It goes through pipes
and sometimes
dead bugs come through
and land in the bath.
It's real sick.
Anyway, look...
[Tube Squirting]
Are you thirsty?
Aarh!
[Ringing]
Aah!
I'll get it.
[Ringing]
Hi. Yeah, I'm fine.
Sure. Yeah, I still got a fever.
Yeah. Uh, no, get back.
I'm fine, Mom. Yeah.
Yeah.
No. Mom, I gotta get in bed now.
Okay. Goodbye.
Mom, I'm sick.
Mom, I don't need to go
to the doctor!
[Water Splashing]
Mom, I only had a fever
of 99 today.
Okay, "and a half."
Uh-huh. Okay, Mom.
Okay, bye.
[Gurgling]
I've got to throw up.
Mom, please.
I'm gonna throw up on the phone
if you don't let me go.
[Gurgles]
Mom, I've gotta throw up now.
Yeah, uh...
[Coughing]
Uhhh!
[Creature Gurgles]
You could drown in stuff
like this.
[Purring]
[Gurgling]
Is this your idea
of a good time?
[Purring]
♪ Accidents
will happen ♪
♪ But it's only
hit-and-run ♪
♪ There are
so many people to see ♪
♪ So many people
you can check upon ♪
♪ And add
to your collection ♪
♪ But they
keep you hanging on ♪
♪ Nothin' but health shit ♪
♪ And add
to your collection ♪
♪ But they
keep you hanging on ♪
♪ Accidents
will happen ♪
♪ But it's only
hit-and-run ♪
♪ You'll be
a victim of... ♪#
Mike, come in.
How you feeling,
faker?
I got something
really important...
Tyler said he got 69,000
on Asteroids yesterday.
Look, remember
the goblin?
You're so lame,
Elliott.
Come on, Michael.
He came back.
He came back?
Oh, my God!
One thing.
I have
absolute power.
Say it.
What have you got?
Is it the coyote?
No. Look...
O.K. Now, swear it...
The most excellent
promise you can make.
Swear as my only brother
on our lives.
Don't get so heavy.
I swear.
O.K. Stand over there.
You'd better take off
your shoulder pads.
You might scare him.
And close your eyes.
Don't push it, Elliott.
I'm not
coming out there
until your eyes
are closed.
O.K. They're closed.
Mom is going
to kill you.
Aah! Ohh! Ooh!
O.K. Swear it
one more time.
[As Yoda]
You have absolute
power. Eerrp!
Elliott! Look what
I made for you!
Aahr!
Aah!
Stop!
Aahr!
Aah!
Mmm!
Kids, I'm home!
Guys?
In the closet, fast.
Anybody up there,
kids?
Aah!
Aahr!
Anybody home?
Hi, honey,
how do you fee...
What happened
in here?
Oh, you mean my room.
This is no room.
This is an accident.
I was, um...
reorganizing.
I can see that.
Put those shelves
back on the wall.
Get the toys
off the floor.
Mmm!
Make your bed.
You're feeling better,
I see.
You guys watch
Gertie for me
while I take a shower.
Absolutely.
Bye, Mom.
Whew!
Uhhh.
Elliott...
I'm keeping him.
Ahhr...
What is it?
He won't hurt you,
Gertie.
We're not going
to hurt you.
Is he a boy or a girl?
He's a boy.
Was he wearing
any clothes?
No.
But, look...
you can't tell.
Not even Mom.
Why not?
Because, um...
grownups can't see him.
Only little kids
can see him.
Give me a break.
Well, do you know
what's going to happen
if you do tell?
Do it, Mike.
We have to.
Oh, no, please!
Don't do anything,
please!
Help me!
No, please!
Give it!
Promise?
Yes.
Do you promise?
Runff.
[Camera Clicks]
What are you
doing, Gert?
I'm going to play
in Elliott's room.
O.K. Don't let him
torture you.
I won't, Mary.
[Telephone Rings]
[Ring]
Hello?
Ahhr...
Jer-Jerry!
[Tap Tap Tap]
Come on, come on.
Hurry up.
Don't be pushy,
pushy.
A plant for you.
Maybe he's some animal
that wasn't
supposed to live.
I brought
some clay...
Like those
rabbits we saw.
Green, orange...
Could be a monkey.
A bald monkey?
Is he a pig? He
sure eats like one.
You could
make faces.
And make them
mean... and happy
and make them
get sharp teeth...
We are here.
We're here.
Use this.
You could make
all sorts of things.
O.K. We're here.
We are here.
Where are you from?
Ahhr...
I don't like his feet.
They're only feet,
you little twerp.
He's trying
to tell us something.
Earth.
Home.
What's he doing?
What's happening?
Elliott.
Oh, no.
Aah!
Elliott,
what is it?
I don't know.
Something scary.
[Beeping]
Got a pulse?
No, boss.
Hold it.
We got it right here.
Follow him.
O.K.
You think this house?
Hmm.
Mmm.
Mmrrr.
Did you
explain school?
How do you explain school
to higher intelligence?
Maybe he's not that smart.
Maybe he's a worker bee.
He's smart.
I hope we don't
wake up on Mars
surrounded by millions
of these squashy guys.
Hi, Elliott.
Hey, Elliott,
where's your goblin?
Shut up.
Did he come back?
Did he?
Yeah,
he came back.
But he's
not a goblin.
He's a spaceman.
As in extraterrestrial.
Where's he from?
Uranus? Get it?
Your anus?
He doesn't get it.
Get it? Your anus?
You're
so immature.
And you're
a cintus suprimus.
Zero charisma.
Cintus suprimus.
Shut up, Greg!
Zero charisma!
You wimp.
Let's go.
Come on.
Get in the car.
We'll be late.
[Shuffling]
Hummm.
OK, boys and girls,
today we will be doing
the actual frog dissection
for which
we've been preparing.
And you will find...
many similarities.
As you get
into the dissection,
you will discover
that the anatomy...
[Grrr]
[Whines]
The scalpel
is very sharp.
Use discretion
when you are cutting.
There will be
very little blood.
There may be
a few body fluids.
Yecchh!
[Woof]
As we
get started with...
[Belches]
the dissection...
Ew!
remember that the things
you are writing down...
Ahhr...
Urp!
Some of the things
that you should look
for during the dissection
is the heart,
and notice that
it is still beating.
Oof!
I'm going to once more
emphasize the similarities
of those things
which we see...
Mmm.
Similarities with
human anatomy.
First of all,
here's the heart.
The intestines
will be going
through their
peristaltic action.
X-W-V-U
A-F-P.
That is incorrect.
The correct spelling
of nuisance
is N-U-I-
S-A-N-C-E.
Yeow!
They're
pulling us up.
Class, these are
the cotton balls
with the chloroform.
As soon as I
get them all in,
put the lid on
right away.
Eww.
That's it.
That will start them
going to sleep.
They won't feel anything.
They won't be hurt.
It'll take a little while.
If you don't want
to watch them,
you don't have to.
Say hi.
Can you talk?
Can you say hi?
Ahhr...
Hic!
Mmm...
Hello.
Uncle Ralph!
It's Uncle Ralph,
long distance
from California!
This call
must be expensive.
Oh, no, no.
Anytime on Saturday
without an operator,
it's 5 minutes
for 85 cents plus tax.
If I talk less,
I pay less.
Let me talk to
that little fella, huh?
Lou, it's Uncle Ralph.
Hello, Uncle Ralph.
Save him.
Run for your life!
Back to the river!
Back to the forest!
Run! I want to save you!
Let's get out of here!
Get out!
I got to let him go!
You've got to save him!
Aah!
Let me handle this!
I can handle this.
Let me get this.
Aah!
Stanford, what's wrong?
I'm afraid Betsy Sue isn't
going to run tomorrow.
Oh, no. Is it
anything serious?
Harvey, I'm home.
Come here, boy.
Here he is.
Here's who?
The man from the moon,
but you've
killed him already.
As soon as I
unload the stuff, OK?
Mmm.
Med-bugs.
I want you
to meet somebody.
This stuff has
gone up so much.
I want you
to meet somebody.
When I finish putting
this stuff away, OK?
Stupid Ragu. I knew
it wouldn't come out.
"B."
[Telephone Rings]
What's with this?
[Ring]
Hello.
Yeah, this is she.
Basket.
Bandit.
Ball.
Basket, bandit, ball.
Bugs.
Bananas.
Intoxicated?
You sure you have
the right Elliott?
"B."
"Biscuits."
"B".
But "B"...
"B."
is for baseball and bat.
Y-You said "B."
"B."
You said "B."
Good.
"B."
Good...
I'll be right down.
Thank you.
Gertie, I have to go
pick up Elliott.
Will you be...
Mommy, he can talk.
Of course he can.
I'll be back.
Stay there.
Ladies and gentlemen,
little Grover here
will demonstrate
high-chinning himself
two times.
Two times?
Two times.
Start now?
Go ahead.
O.K.
Phone.
Phone...
Ph-Phone...
You want
to call somebody?
I am not paying
for frogs.
Be good. Be good.
Stay here. Stay.
Don't tell anybody.
No... Nobody.
Be good. Be good.
Move.
Oh, God!
Elliott.
What?
Elliott...
I taught him
how to talk now.
He can talk now.
Look what he brought
up here all by himself.
What's he need
this stuff for?
Elliott...
E.T. Can you
say that?
Can you say E.T.?
E.T.
E... T...
Ha! Ha!
E.T. E.T. E.T.
Be good.
I taught him that.
You should give
him his dignity.
This is the most
ridiculous thing
I've ever seen!
Phone...
Phone?
He said "phone"?
Can't you
understand English?
He said phone.
Home...
You're right.
That's E.T.'s home.
E... T...
home... phone.
E.T. phone home.
E.T. phone home!
He wants
to call somebody.
What's all this shit?
E.T. phone home.
Oh, my God,
he's talking now.
Home...
E.T. phone home?
E.T. phone home.
And they'll come?
Come...
Home...
Come on.
I promise, Mom.
What book?
Any one you want...
Spiderman...
We'll just put
a smile on our face.
That's all
I want to do.
We can't ask Cathy
to trick-or-treat
in the same sheet
she wore last year.
[Elliott]
Now I wish I would've
listened in science.
Think, Michael.
Just grab anything
he could make
a machine out of.
What would make a radar?
How the hell do I know?
You're the genius here.
You have absolute
power, remember?
"I found him.
He belongs to me."
You know, Elliott,
he doesn't look
too good anymore.
Don't say that!
We're fine!
What's all this
"we" stuff?
You say "we"
all the time.
Really, I think
he's getting sick.
Look, he's fine,
Michael!
OK! OK!
Forget I mentioned it.
Grab that Fuzzbuster.
Dad's shirt.
Remember when he
used to take us out
to the ball games
and take us
to the movies
and have
popcorn fights?
We'll do that again,
Elliott.
Sure.
Old Spice.
Sea Breeze.
"Peter says
The redskins
were defeated?
"Wendy and the boys
captured by
the pirates?
"I'll rescue her.
I'll rescue her.
"He leaps at his dagger,
"then at his grindstone
to sharpen it.
"But Tink rings out
a warning cry.
"Oh, that is
just my medicine.
"She says, Poisoned?
"Who could've
poisoned it?
"I promised Wendy
to take it,
"and I will,
after this.
"Tink sees
its red color
"and remembers the red
in the pirate's eye,
"nobly swallows
the draft
"as Peter's hand
is reaching for it.
"Why, Tink, you have
drunk my medicine.
"She flutters strangely
about the room,
answering him
in a faint tinkle."
Ouch!
Ouch.
"She says...
"She says she thinks
she could get well again
"if children
believed in fairies.
Do you believe?
Say quick that
you believe."
I do!
"If you believe,
clap your hands.
"Many clap,
some don't,
a few hiss..."
Ohh.
Mmm.
"But Tink is saved.
Thank you.
"Oh, thank you,
thank you,
thank you.
And now
to rescue Wendy."
Can you read it
to me again?
[Purring]
"Peter says..."
[Engine Idling]
He's putting it
together now.
I told you
he was smart.
I'm worried,
Elliott.
He could blow up
the house.
He knows
what he's doing.
Listen to
how he's breathing.
It's going to work.
What's he
feeling now?
He's feeling everything.
You're going
as a ghost.
You promised.
I'm only pretending
I'm going as a cowgirl.
O.K. Now, you know
the plans by heart,
don't you?
Meet you
at the lookout.
At the lookout.
I'm not stupid,
you know.
Listen, buster.
You won't get four blocks
in this neighborhood
dressed like that.
Please.
All the guys are.
I'm not stupid,
you know.
Ready?
Ready.
Oh, wait, Mom.
Don't look.
Oh, O.K.
OK, Mom.
You can look now.
Aah!
Oh, that's great.
Stay here.
Ooh.
Ohh.
Ouch.
Stop that!
No! Don't!
Ouch.
It's a fake knife.
It's a fake.
Ouch.
O.K.
All right.
Oh, you look great!
Thank you.
Aah! Oohh!
Be back one hour
after sundown.
No later.
Ohh.
Bye.
Aah!
Gertie, come here.
Come on.
Trick or treat.
Runff.
Home. Home.
Home. Home. Home.
Be back one hour
after sunset.
No later.
I'll try as fast
as I can, Mike.
You got to cover me.
Well, come on.
Help me.
We'll be waiting
for you, Elliott.
So come back for sure.
It's too bumpy.
We'll have
to walk from here!
E.T.!
Not so high!
Ah ha!
Don't crash, please.
Ugh!
I really can't believe
you did this.
Your father's going
to hear about this one.
Mexico.
Where's Elliot?
I'm asking you a question.
Anyways, why would Elliot
go to the forest?
Why would he
do such a thing?
Get in the car.
Get in the car now.
[Gasps]
Runff.
[Musical Tones]
E.T., it's working.
Oh.
It's working!
Home.
You did it!
It's working!
Home.
E.T., it's working!
[Geiger Counter Beeping]
We have to
go now, E.T.
We're so late
already.
[Coughs]
We have to
go home now, E.T.
Hmm?
You should
give them some time.
Ouch.
You could
be happy here.
I could
take care of you.
I wouldn't let
anybody hurt you.
We could grow up
together, E.T.
Home.
E.T.?
Uh, how was he
dressed when
last seen?
He was
dressed as a...
hunchback.
Hunchback.
Is there anything
to indicate
that he might
have run away?
Any family problems
or recent arguments?
Um... my husband and I
just separated recently,
and it hasn't been easy
on the children, but...
My father's
in Mexico.
But run away, I...
Where would he
have gone?
Elliott.
Oh, Elliott!
Don't ever do this
again, Elliott!
Oh, my. You're so hot.
Run up and draw him
a bath. Quick, Gert.
Sorry I yelled at you.
Um... thanks very much
for all your trouble.
Is he here?
You've got to
find him, Mike.
Where is he?
In the forest.
At the bald spot.
You've got
to find him.
E.T.!
[Thunder]
[Groaning]
No!
[Helicopter Approaches]
Mom, would you
come with me?
What is it?
Mary,
just come with me.
Michael, what?
Mom, remember
the goblin?
What are you
talking about?
Swear the most
excellent promise
you can make.
Michael.
That's terrific.
Mom.
We're sick.
I think we're dying.
Michael.
Mom, it's O.K.
[Groaning]
Downstairs.
He's not going
to hurt you, Mom.
He won't hurt you.
Michael,
get her downstairs.
It's the man
from the moon.
The man
from the moon!
You don't know him!
[Crying]
We can't
leave him alone.
Aah!
[Gasp]
[Train Whistle Blows]
This is my home!
[Gasping]
[Spacesuit Breathing]
Home.
Check the north
perimeter.
Is it fine?
Tent OK?
The collagen unit,
report to the blue level
immediately.
Regulate oxygen level
on countdown.
Does he sleep
at night?
I don't know.
What's the matter
with Elliott?
Have you noticed
any surface sweating?
No.
Has it lost hair?
He never
had any hair.
Are the children
all right?
Did it build
or write anything?
Uh, no.
You say it
has the ability
to manipulate
its own environment?
He's smart.
He communicates
through Elliott.
Elliott thinks
its thoughts.
No. Elliott...
Elliott feels
his feelings.
We've identified
his primary carrier protein.
It's definitely not Albumin.
The testing shows no deficits
on FNF and HTS testing.
EEG analysis shows complete
coherence and synchronization
of brain wave activity
between both subjects.
There's no response
at 20 per kilo.
Let's move
to hypertonic saline.
Cut five per kilo.
[Elliott]
You have no right
to do this.
You're scaring him.
You're scaring him!
Respiratory rate:12.
Good air entry but decreased
tidal volume on the boy.
Put him on 0-2-5 liters
and draw blood in 20 minutes.
Get a hypothermia blanket
and some warming rags.
Leave him alone.
I can take
care of him.
Set me up for
a 2-D cardiac echo.
Skin is cool and diaphoretic.
He's not refusing at all.
He needs anatropic support.
Ph is down to 7.03.
He's got a metabolic acidosis.
It could be sepsis.
We've drawn two sets
of blood cultures.
He needs broad
spectrum coverage.
[Tapping]
Elliott.
I've been
to the forest.
He shouldn't
talk now.
Well, he has to
talk now, Major.
Elliott,
that machine...
what does it do?
The communicator?
Is it still working?
It's doing something.
What?
I really
shouldn't tell.
He came to me.
Elliott,
he came to me, too.
I've been
wishing for this
since I was
10 years old.
I don't want him
to die.
What can we do that
we're not already doing?
He needs to go home.
He's calling
his people...
and I don't know
where they are.
He needs to go home.
Elliott, I don't think
that he was left here
intentionally.
But his being here
is a miracle, Elliott.
It's a miracle,
and you did the best
that anybody could do.
I'm glad
he met you first.
He's got DNA.
Incredible.
He's got DNA!
He doesn't have
four nucleotides like we do.
He has six.
Desynchronization
of the two brain waves.
E.T.!
The boy's condition
is stabilizing.
Blood pressure's
back up.
E.T.
Elliott.
He's speaking.
He's talking.
E.T...
stay with me.
Please.
Stay...
Together.
I'll be right here.
Stay...
Elliott.
Stay.
The creature's pressure
is bottoming out.
How's the boy?
He's converting back
to normal sinus rhythm.
They're separating.
Boy and creature
are separating.
What does
that mean?
The boy's coming back.
We're losing E.T.
E.T., answer me, please.
Please.
Just relax.
No!
E.T., don't go!
No blood pressure.
He's got no pulse
or respiration.
We can't
get a pulse
or blood pressure.
It doesn't look
like he's breathing.
[Groaning]
Leave him alone!
You're killing him!
Let's move it!
Get the boy out.
Stop it!
You're killing him!
Let's go.
Move it out.
You're killing him!
He came to me!
Let's ventilate him.
Any pulses?
Move it.
He came to me!
Let's start.
60 per minute.
Minimal breath sounds.
Calm down.
Calm down. Calm...
Let's try some
bertyllium.
Can we have
some bertyllium?
Getting a pulse?
5 milligrams.
Compressed air.
Compressed air's fine.
Thank you.
All IV push.
He's not ventilating.
His pupils are fixed
and dilated.
More drugs.
Quiet.
Defibrillate him.
Losing him.
We're losing him.
Let's go.
Everybody stand clear.
Clear.
We're losing him.
One more time.
Quiet!
It's still defib.
OK, let's go.
Let's go.
Elliott?
Mom.
He needs calcium
in his body.
Let's continue CPR,
please.
Would you people
stand back?
Something's
happening.
Ooh, they're
going to die.
Shut up, Greg.
Something is
definitely happening.
Anybody have
any ideas?
EEG's flat.
EKG's flat.
OK, I'm going
to call it.
I think he's dead.
No. I don't know.
What time
do you have?
15:36.
15 hours,
36 minutes.
O.K.
Let's pack him in ice.
Let's leave.
Is he dead, mama?
I think so,
sweetheart.
Can we wish
for him to come back?
Yeah.
I wish.
I wish, too.
Come on, Gert.
We'll wait for Elliott
in the front room.
Cardiac arrest
was terminated
at 1500 hours
and 36 minutes.
He received
intravenous
lidocaine,
epinephrine
on a lidocaine
drip,
2.7%
sodium-chloride
solution,
catheters from
the "A" line.
And the
intravenous line
should be sent
for culture.
He was monitored
with a...
EEG and an EKG,
he was
defibrillated.
They're going to have
to take him away now.
They'll just
cut him all up.
Would you like
to spend some time
alone with him?
Could we all step out
for a minute, please?
Look at what
they've done to you.
I'm so sorry.
You must be dead...
because...
I don't know
how to feel.
I can't feel
anything anymore.
You've gone
someplace else now.
I'll believe in you
all my life.
Every day.
E.T...
I love you.
Oh, my God.
E.T. phone home.
Ah ha!
Phone home.
Does this mean
they're coming?
Yes.
Aah!
E.T. phone home.
Stay.
Shut up.
Phone.
Phone home.
Quiet!
Phone! Phone!
Would you shut up?
Phone home.
E.T. phone home.
Elliott.
Stay.
[Crying]
Elliott,
why don't you
come with me?
No.
Why don't you
come with me?
No.
No. No.
It's all right.
No!
Would you like
the flower?
Aah!
He's alive!
All right!
It's glowing
right here.
Are they gone, mama?
Who's gone, honey?
The boys.
What boys?
I'm supposed to give you
this note when they're gone.
Give it to me now,
Gertie.
Oh, my God.
Give me
a hand with this.
Aah!
Where's your mask?
Back here.
Well, get it on!
I'm trying!
Hey, who are you?
I'm driving.
Open the door,
son.
Somebody's here.
What do I do?
What are you waiting for?
Let's go!
Let's get out of here!
I've never driven
forward before!
[Engine Starts]
Aah!
Get the bikes.
Meet us
at the playground
at the top
of the hill.
We'll all die,
and I'll never
get my license.
Where's
the playground?
It's near the preschool!
Where's that?
I don't know streets.
Mom always drives me.
Son of a bitch.
Where are you going?
To the spaceship.
Shh!
To the spaceship
to the moon.
Quiet!
Oh, my God.
Stop the van!
Don't pull it off!
That did it!
O.K. He's a man
from outer space,
and we're taking him
to his spaceship.
Well, can't he
just beam up?
This is reality,
Greg.
Keep her back!
No!
Hold her back!
No! No! No! No!
Where are they?
There's nobody here.
Runff runff.
Where are we going?
To the forest!
Follow me!
We got them
at the hill.
This is Unit 302.
We've cut
the kids off
at the bottom
of the hill.
Runff.
Let's split up.
OK!
Hang on!
Runff.
We made it!
Whoa!
Runff.
Tell me when it's over!
Home.
[Gertie]
Stop the car, Mama!
They're over there!
I just wanted
to say goodbye.
He doesn't know
goodbye.
Be good.
Yes.
Ahh...
Thank...
you.
You're welcome.
Come.
Stay.
Ahh...
Ouch.
I'll be...
right here.
Bye.
Edited By
Tameem666