eXistenZ.
Written like this.
One word.
Small "e."
Capital "X."
Capital "Z."
eXistenZ.
It's new.
It's from Antenna Research.
And it's here.
Right now.
We encourage consumer loyalty,
and we want you to help...
...with our product testing.
We're a team. Antenna and you.
Those of you who've come
to our seminars before...
...will know that I normally lead
the groups through our new games.
But tonight it won't be me.
No.
For our test launch
of eXistenZ, by Antenna...
...we've brought you
a seminar leader who's special.
Yes, it is.
The world's greatest
game designer is here...
...in person, to lead you,
our first test enclave...
...through her newest creation,
eXistenZ, by Antenna.
I give you the game-pod
goddess herself...
...Allegra Geller.
Allegra! Allegra!
The world of games
is in a kind of a trance.
People are programmed
to accept so little.
But the possibilities are so great.
eXistenZ is not just a game.
It's an entirely new game system.
And...
...it involves a whole lot
of new toys...
...which you're gonna be
the first to try out.
We have 12 prototype
MetaFlesh Game-Pods.
That means that for our first-wave
test enclave, we need 12 volunteers...
...who will port into these slave units
with the game-pod goddess herself.
Hold it.
Not so fast.
Right.
Did I miss the port-in?
Just the first wave.
You can be part of the second.
You and the guy at the back.
You, sir. This lady here.
Just come up. Thank you.
Noel Dichter?
Yes.
I have to scan you.
Weapons check?
More for recording devices. Lot of
money invested in these games, Noel.
Assistants will help you to port
your pod into your bio-ports...
...using Antenna Research's new...
What's in this case?
I brought my game-pod.
Original Marway tissue architecture.
I know it's kind of obsolete.
I couldn't afford the Antenna 15 upgrade.
I figured out this method--
You won't need it tonight.
Everything's provided for.
How are you doing?
You think two hours, tops?
Well, two, three hours.
So you're saying three hours?
Okay.
Everything's in order.
Are you ready, Allegra?
Sure. This is my favourite part.
Take it away.
All right.
I'm ready to download eXistenZ,
by Antenna Research, into all of you.
Now, I'm warning you,
it's going to be a wild ride.
But don't panic.
No matter what happens, okay?
I'll see you back here
in no time at all.
She seems to be very shy.
Never occurred to me
that a big star would be shy.
She spends most of her time alone
in a room, designing her games.
She'd like it best
if she never had to show them.
Death to the demoness
Allegra Geller!
Death to Antenna Research!
Get her out of here.
Save her!
There might be more of them.
Go on!
- Me? Take her?
- We have enemies in our own house.
Trust no one. Trust no one!
Miss Geller, you're coming with me.
I'm responsible for you.
You're supposed to come with me.
Well, what are we
gonna do out here?
Do you know your way around?
Do you know any country people?
Not country people.
Games people.
Countryside's full of games-development
people, project coordinators...
...little factories.
So you know your way.
We can hide out.
Maybe.
It seems like I have some enemies
I didn't know I had.
" Death to Allegra Geller."
How would you like to hear
someone scream...
..." Death to Ted Pikul"?
How'd you know my name?
You're labelled.
What's that?
My pink-fone.
Ted Pikul.
What hap--
What?
What did you do that for?
- That was our lifeline to civilization.
- That was a range-finder.
As long as you have that,
they know where we are.
- You mean head office?
- Anybody.
Pikul, why don't you have a gun?
What?
You're not armed.
They told me you're my security,
but you have no weaponry.
Who told you that?
I'm a marketing trainee.
Fucking hell.
I'm marked for death, and they send me
on the road with a PR nerd.
" Marked for death."
" Marked for death." Oh, Jesus.
Don't sweat it, Pikul.
Don't sweat it.
I'm gonna handle it.
And right now we need to stop.
We do? Why?
So we can have an intimate
moment together.
If you're gonna do it, do it.
Did somebody bite you?
What?
What I just dug out of you.
It's a tooth.
A human...
...tooth.
Let me see that weirdo pistol.
The bullets are human teeth.
This one's got a cavity.
That thing was designed to get past any
kind of metal or synthetics detector.
It's all flesh and bone.
I suppose the smaller calibre pistols
would have to fire baby teeth.
The tooth fairy could go
into the arms business.
Where were you just now?
I was wandering through eXistenZ.
The new system, I mean.
I like it in there.
Of course, without another player
you're only a tourist.
It's frustrating.
Why won't you let me contact Antenna?
They've gotta be going crazy
wondering what's happened to you.
I mean, it's not like
we've done something wrong.
We just ran because we didn't know
how many of them there were, right?
We owe it to Antenna
to let them know you're all right...
...and to get them to send
somebody to help you...
...who knows what he's doing.
Besides, I can't...
I can't just keep doing this,
whatever it is...
...you know, forever.
Not having any idea when it's going--
What are you doing?
Where's your bio-port?
Don't tell me you've
never been fitted.
I can't believe it.
I was never fitted.
What do you care?
You wanna get into the biz,
and you've never played my games?
You've never played any game?
Look.
I've been dying to play your games...
...but I have this phobia
about having my body penetrated...
...surgically.
You know what I mean.
No, I'm not sure that I do.
Getting a bio-port fitted.
I don't know. I can't do it.
It's too freaky.
Makes my skin crawl.
They just pop your spine
with a little hydro-gun.
They shoot the port plug into it.
It's like getting your ears pierced.
With only an infinitesimal
chance of permanent spinal paralysis.
- I've read all about it.
- It's your chosen profession.
Besides, once you're ported...
...there's no end to the games
you can play.
You can't seriously wanna
play games now.
Not here. Not while we're being
hunted down by crazy people.
My baby here took a huge hit
in the church, Pikul.
One of those UmbyCords
got ripped out of her.
Ripped out of her.
Just as the game architecture was being
downloaded from her to the slave pods.
That's a very vulnerable time for her.
She could be crying out
for help right here...
...right now.
The only way I can tell...
...if the game's
not been contaminated...
...the pod is not about to be crippled
for life because of my negligence...
...is to play eXistenZ...
...with somebody friendly.
Are you friendly?
Or are you not?
Sure.
Let's do it.
Let's do it now.
Let me see.
To get an illegal...
...unregistered bio-port installed...
...at about midnight...
...we just drive up to your local
country gas station, right?
Anything else I can do for you?
Well, Gas...
...you could check
your bio-port plugs.
The what? Spark plugs?
You heard me.
My friend here
has a bio-port problem.
A bio-port. Now...
...that's a sort of hole
in your spine, isn't it?
Lots of assholes around here,
but that's generally it.
I don't know why you'd be
talking to me about that, lady.
Sure you do.
Allegra Geller.
You've changed my life.
What was your life like before?
Before?
Before it was changed
by Allegra Geller.
I operated a gas station.
You still operate a gas station.
Only on the most pathetic
level of reality.
Geller's work liberated me.
Liberated?
Did you ever play her game ArtGod?
One word. Capital "A."
Capital "G."
I don't have a bio-port.
"Thou, the player of the game, art God."
Very spiritual.
Funny too.
God, the artist, the mechanic.
Funny.
Here we go.
Those are sterilized...
...aren't they?
Not to worry.
You could fire in a bio-port
in a slaughterhouse...
...and never generate an infection.
Then why the clean overalls?
It's a mental thing.
Helps me focus.
The one thing you don't wanna do
is miss with the stud-finder.
Oh, God.
God?
The mechanic.
Step into my office.
See? That didn't hurt, did it?
I didn't expect that to hurt.
I expect the next part to hurt.
That's what I expect to hurt.
I haven't crippled anyone yet.
How many have you done?
Three.
Well, you'll be my third.
Easy.
- What was going on, Gas?
- Hell...
...he's acting
like I'm attacking him.
People usually pay me to do this.
Yeah? All two of them!
As you can see...
...I've decided not to have
a bio-port installed.
This is it, you see.
This is the cage of your own making...
...which keeps you trapped and pacing
about in the smallest space forever.
Break out of your cage, Pikul.
Break out now.
The swelling doesn't last for long.
Tomorrow you won't even notice it.
I love it.
Great.
What's going on?
I can't move my legs!
The procedure comes...
...with its own epidural.
Just like when you have a baby.
Kind of instant paralysis
from the waist down.
That's why it didn't hurt you.
It'll wear off in no time.
I'm gonna go wash up.
You two make yourselves at home.
We don't have to wait
for the swelling to go down.
You're gonna port into me
while I'm paralysed?
You wanted to play my game,
didn't you?
Yeah, I did. I do, but--
Here? Now?
It's an instant-on world, isn't it?
What's that for?
Feels...
...cold.
New ports are sometimes
a bit tight.
Wouldn't wanna hurt you.
How come...
...bio-ports don't get infected?
I mean...
...they open right
into your body.
Listen to what you're saying, Pikul.
Don't be ludicrous.
Don't you think
you could call me Ted?
Maybe afterwards.
Shit!
Pikul!
I can't believe it.
You blew my pod!
You neural-surged.
What do you mean?
I jacked you into my pod
and you panicked.
It's totally fucked!
This is a disaster.
I was nervous,
but I didn't panic.
I was forced to trust you, and you
panicked and you neural-surged...
...and you blew my pod.
You can get a new pod.
Pikul.
In this pod...
...is the only, the original
version of eXistenZ.
An entire game system that cost
38 million to develop.
Not including prerelease
marketing costs.
And I'm locked outside my own game.
I can't get me in or it out.
Are you serious?
That's the only version that exists?
It's the only one
and it's stuck inside...
...and it's your fault.
I've devoted five of my most passionate
years to this strange little creature.
And I've never regretted it, Pikul.
I knew it was the only thing
that could give my life any meaning.
Why is it my fault?
I'm telling you, I didn't.
I did not neural-surge.
I didn't.
I didn't feel any surging.
It's not your fault.
It's my fault.
Oh, no, Gas. Not you.
I wouldn't try to use
that bio-port again.
Except maybe for a toaster
or something.
What's going on?
You're worth a lot of money
if you're dead.
What are you talking about?
You know what I'm talking about.
It's all over the countryside.
Five million dollars for her dead body.
No questions asked.
But she changed your life.
Yeah.
Now I'm gonna change hers.
Why did you install
a bad port into me?
There's a bonus for killing...
...Allegra Geller's latest game,
or whatever it is.
I think I just did that, didn't I?
But can you kill me, Gas?
Can you kill a person?
Can you do that?
Hide my body...
...contact the crazies...
...trust them to pay up?
Hand over my now decaying,
fucking grotesque corpse...
...really expect them to hand over
five mill cash?
I mean, don't you ever go
to the fucking movies?
I like your script.
I wanna be in it.
Oh, God, I think he's dead.
He wanted to kill you.
That's two people in one day...
...who wanted to actually kill you.
I've never been more popular.
Allegra, we need help.
You're right. I've gotta
get this pod fixed.
We're going skiing?
Look at that huge bug.
It's got two heads.
It's not a bug. it's a mutated
amphibian. it's a frog...
...salamander-lizard thing.
Sign of the times.
What happens if somebody comes up here
and really wants to ski?
Nobody actually physically
skis anymore. You know that.
No, don't use that!
And bring me the sterile wash.
My darling.
Allegra Geller.
I am so pleased...
...and so astonished to see you here.
Kiri Vinokur...
...my bodyguard, Ted Pikul.
Sterile wash.
I hear this ridiculous story...
...about some fatwa against you.
The company are desperately
trying to find you.
Is this really serious?
Are you in danger?
There have been a couple
of attempts on my life.
This is unbearable.
The company must stop this.
They owe you every kind
of protection.
I don't know if they can do anything.
It seems to be open season on me.
You're safe here.
I assure you.
I will contact Antenna right away
and have them send some people over--
No, Kiri, don't.
Tell no one we're here.
I can't be sure that Antenna
is completely safe for me.
I understand. Yes.
You know...
...you can hide out in one
of the guest chalets...
...as long as you like.
And I'll make sure
you get fresh towels.
And make sure I don't lose everything
I have in here.
You bet.
Take that.
Good.
Pull this back.
What did you port into?
Pikul's bio-port.
That's what caused
all the damage?
It was a flawed installation.
My first.
Well...
...it fried a lot of expensive...
...neural webbing.
You see?
Looks like an animal in there.
Feels like you're operating
on somebody's pet dog.
I told you, Landry,
we have become...
...glorified veterinarians.
Put a little in there, please.
The eXistenZ game-pod is basically
an animal, Mr. Pikul.
It's grown from fertilized amphibian
eggs stuffed with synthetic DNA.
Only Antenna has this.
Wow. Where do the batteries go?
Very funny.
He's not kidding.
He's a total PR nerd. it ports
into you. You're the power source.
Your body, your nervous system,
your metabolism, your energy.
You get tired, rundown,
it won't run properly.
Iandry here will finish up
the pod work. Now, let's...
...get that nasty bio-port out,
put a nice fresh one in.
It hurts.
I think it's infected.
No, it's not infected.
It's just excited.
It wants action.
I really don't think
I want action. Me, I mean.
The bearer of the excited bio-port.
My baby has now taken three major hits.
One in the church...
...one in the gas station
and one on the operating table.
The only way I can tell
if everything's okay...
...is to play eXistenZ
with somebody friendly.
Are you friendly or are you not?
You're telling me this thing
will run off my body's energy?
That's how they work.
See? You're humming along already.
EXistenZ.
Only from Antenna.
Here we go.
You've got a bit
of an unfair advantage.
How can I possibly compete
with the designer of the system?
Well, you could...
...beat the guy that
invented poker, couldn't you?
- You want that one?
- Yeah, that one.
- Are you sure you want that one?
- Yes.
- I wouldn't recommend it.
- Why not?
The graphics on this one are better.
There's no comparison.
- This is the one you want.
- That one?
That was beautiful.
I feel just like me.
Is that kind of transition normal?
That kind of smooth interlacing
from place to place?
Depends on the style of the game.
You can get jagged brutal cuts,
slow fades...
...shimmering little morphs.
This is amazing.
I had no idea.
Look at this.
Games I've never heard of.
Wait a minute.
That reminds me.
What precisely is the goal of the game
that we're playing now?
You have to play the game to find out
why you're playing the game.
It's the future, Pikul.
You'll see how natural it feels.
Look at this.
Can this be the future too?
Ever see anything like this before?
These are delicate.
You got to be...
...careful.
Yes, I can imagine.
Cortical Systematics...
...is the latest and the hottest.
Not just a new game...
...but a new system.
Will it work with an industry
standard bio-port?
I'm D'Arcy Nader.
Welcome to D'Arcy Nader's
Game Emporium.
Is there anything I can be
helping you with?
We're just looking.
I have...
...what you're looking for.
Who sent you?
It's none of your business
who sent us.
We're here.
That's all that matters.
God.
What happened?
I didn't mean to say that.
Your character said it.
It's a kind of schizophrenic feeling,
isn't it?
You'll get used to it.
There are things that have to be said
to advance the plot.
Those things get said whether
you wanna say them or not.
Don't fight it.
Just go with it.
But should you be saying this
in front of him?
Look at him.
- What's he doing?
- He's gone into a game loop.
He won't come out of it until you give
him a proper line of game dialogue.
This is tricky.
Start by repeating your last line.
Include his name so he knows
you're talking to him.
We're here, D'Arcy Nader...
...and that's all that matters.
Yes, you're right.
That is all that matters.
Now, you said you have
what we want.
We're waiting.
You're going to need
these micro-pods...
...to download your new identities.
I assume that you both
have had these...
...industry standard bio-ports...
...that you mentioned installed.
Yes, of course,
we both have bio-ports.
We do, don't we?
I assumed we did.
In the game, we might not.
We better check.
Yeah, it's there.
Looks a little different,
but it's there.
Yeah, I see what you mean.
Yes, we both have bio-ports.
Good.
Port in.
And this will tell you
all you need to know...
...for now.
I'm going to leave, while you two
finish up here because...
...it wouldn't be good for us all
to be seen together.
I assume that Nader is our
entry point into the game.
Yeah, kind of disappointing.
Nader?
He's not a very well-drawn character.
His dialogue was just so-so.
His accent...
The pods are so small...
...they plug directly
into the bio-port.
Oh, God.
What happened?
The whole pod just disappeared
into your back.
It disappeared into my back?
It's working its way
round my spinal cord?
Don't panic. it's just a game.
Do you feel anything yet?
No, I don't.
Not a thing.
I don't feel a thing.
Do you want me to do you?
What the hell was that?
That wasn't me.
It was my game character.
I wouldn't have done that.
Not here anyway.
Our characters are obviously
supposed to jump on each other.
It's most probably...
...a pathetically
mechanical attempt...
...to heighten the emotional tension
of the next game sequence.
No use fighting it.
What about our new identities?
Do you feel yours yet?
They'll take care of themselves.
I'm very worried about my body.
Your what?
Where are our real bodies?
Are they all right?
What if they're hungry?
What if there's danger?
They're just where we left them.
They're sitting quietly...
...eyes closed.
It's just like meditating.
I feel really vulnerable.
Disembodied.
Don't sweat it.
All your senses
are still operating.
You'll pop right out
of the game if there's a problem.
Trying to remember who you are?
Hey, it works!
I must be Yevgeny Nourish.
And you are new to trout farm.
Yes, I'm...
I'm very new.
Did you say "trout farm"?
Yeah, trout farm.
You know, raising baby trout from eggs
and releasing them in rivers.
Entire place used to be trout farm.
From outside, you would never guess
it's now factory for making game-pods.
Seems like most everything
used to be something else, yes?
You're new, but you seem
to know what you're doing.
It surprises me more
than it surprises you.
You're new, but you seem
to know what you're doing.
I've been trained by the very best.
So have I, my friend.
So have I.
Where are you planning
to have lunch?
I'm new here.
I have no plans for lunch.
May I suggest the Chinese restaurant
in the forest?
Everyone knows where it is.
Just ask.
Well, won't you be going there too?
Unfortunately, I have
other plans for lunch.
But I do suggest
you order the special.
And don't take no for answer.
All right, I'll do that.
Iarry.
Yes?
They need this in the back.
They asked for you.
I saw you make contact, Larry. What
did the guy on the assembly line say?
Can you believe the game version
of your pod?
It's sick...
...and so unconvincing! I mean,
using mutated animal organs...
...and nervous systems as game-pod parts
is certainly feasible...
...but everything's so dirty.
Absurd.
Grotesque.
I saw you make contact, Larry. What
did the guy on the assembly line say?
He told me where to have lunch.
We have nice sea bass today.
Shall I bring it for everyone?
We want the special.
Did you hear me, Chinese waiter?
The special is for special occasions.
I cannot give you the special.
But this is a special occasion.
It's her birthday.
A birthday is a special occasion.
I will therefore bring the special
for everybody.
I guess the special
isn't very popular.
I guess not.
I wanna put the game on pause.
The game can be paused, can't it?
I mean, all games
can be paused, right?
Yeah, sure. But why? What's wrong?
Aren't you dying to see
what's so special about the special?
I'm feeling a little disconnected
from my real life.
I'm losing touch
with the texture of it.
You know what I mean?
I actually think...
...there's an element
of psychosis involved here.
This is a great sign.
Your nervous system is fully
engaging with the game architecture.
EXistenZ is paused!
Did I do that?
I guess I did.
So how does it feel?
What?
Your real life.
The one you came back for.
It feels completely unreal.
You're stuck now, aren't you?
You wanna go back
to the Chinese restaurant...
...because there's
nothing happening here.
We're safe. it's boring.
It's worse than that.
I'm not sure...
I'm not sure here...
...where we are...
...is real at all.
This feels like a game to me.
And you...
...you're beginning to feel
like a game character.
Definitely not.
Let's go back.
Special order for the birthday girl.
Hope you enjoy it very much.
Look, it's our two-headed friend.
Doesn't look too healthy.
I think I lost my appetite.
Oh, a shame.
Mutant reptiles and amphibians...
...provide new and previously
unimagined taste sensations.
Shall I clear all this away?
We're happy.
Very good.
Enjoy.
Pikul, what are you doing?
I don't know.
I find this disgusting,
but I can't help myself.
Good.
"Good"? You think this is good?
Yeah.
It's a genuine game urge.
It's something your character
was born to do.
Don't fight it.
I'm fighting it.
But it isn't doing me any good.
Oh, my God.
This looks awfully familiar.
You sure this is okay?
Yeah, it should be okay.
Do you have that bridge
in real life?
Absolutely not.
My teeth are perfect.
Death to the demoness
Allegra Geller.
That's not funny.
Sorry.
But, you know...
...I do feel the urge
to kill someone here.
Who?
I need to kill our waiter.
Well, that makes sense.
Waiter!
When he comes over, do it.
Don't hesitate.
But everything in the game...
...is so realistic.
I don't think I really could.
You won't be able to stop yourself.
Enjoy it.
Free will is obviously
not a big factor...
...in this little world of ours.
It's like real life. There's
just enough to make it interesting.
He's too nice.
I won't do it.
What can I do to make
your lunch more pleasant?
I found this in my soup...
...and I'm very upset.
It's all right.
Just a little misunderstanding...
...over the check.
Pay no attention
and enjoy your meal.
I feel a serious game urge...
...to get out of here.
Through the kitchen. That way.
Did you like the meal
I prepared for you?
It was very...
...revealing.
It certainly was for me.
You both passed our little test
with flying colours.
- Why did the Chinese waiter have to die?
- A waiter hears...
...many things spoken when
people are relaxing and eating.
A waiter has many opportunities
for betrayal.
He betrayed you?
He betrayed us. Us!
Come. This way.
Come.
These are the breeding pools.
Breeding pools.
Is this...
Is this where you caught
today's special?
We originally were raising
these mutant creatures...
...for their nervous systems
for game-pods.
But then we found they
could be quite tasty.
So we opened the restaurant,
and now that is our cover.
We are also raising them
as components...
...for undetectable and
hypoallergenic weapons.
Right under the noses
of our enemies.
And speaking of our enemies,
it's important...
...that you go back to work
at Cortical Systematics.
We need to maintain as many
agents there as possible.
It's owned by Cortical Systematics?
Yeah. Their corporate slogan should be:
" Enemies of Reality."
Someday soon, we will
destroy trout farm...
...and all game-pods inside.
We love you.
Now that you have proven to be
true and trustworthy Realists.
We'll be in touch.
I'm looking for D'Arcy Nader.
Is he here?
Hugo Carlaw, is D'Arcy Nader here?
He's in the back.
You want him, there he is.
You shouldn't have killed
the Chinese waiter.
Why not?
He was your contact
at the trout farm.
Damn good man.
His dog brought me this.
We were contacted by Yevgeny Nourish.
He knew who we were.
Nader told him that you were coming.
Nader was a mole...
...for Cortical Systematics.
You're with the Realist Underground.
I was placed here
to keep an eye on Nader.
If Nourish isn't our real contact,
who is he?
He's a double agent
for Cortical Systematics.
He was working with Nader
to subvert the Realist cause...
...and doing it rather well. He got
you to assassinate your own contact.
But now you're gonna
put a stop to him.
I don't wanna be here.
Come on, Pikul.
You've just got a bad case
of first-time user anxiety.
I don't like it here.
I don't know what's going on.
We're both stumbling around together
in this unformed world...
...whose rules and objectives
are largely unknown...
...seemingly indecipherable
or possibly nonexistent...
...always on the verge...
...of being killed by forces
that we don't understand.
That sounds like my game, all right.
That sounds like a game that's
not gonna be easy to market.
But it's a game everybody's
already playing.
The cashier said it would be
in a familiar place.
Is there such a thing here?
My assembly bay.
Is that it over there?
God, it's ugly even for a game-pod.
I have a terrible urge to port into it.
What about you?
Sure. Yeah.
Desperate to port into it.
All right. Here we go.
- You wanna give me a hand?
- You're not serious!
That's a diseased pod.
You port into that--
Yes, exactly.
Help me.
How long does it take
for the infection to take hold?
No time at all.
Then you quietly port
into the other pods...
...and spread the infection to them.
Oh, God.
What's happening?
Something's wrong.
I'm gonna unport you now.
Oh, God! Don't!
That really hurts.
I'm gonna cut you free.
No! I'm afraid!
Pikul...
...I'm bleeding to death.