["CRIMSON AND CLOVER"
PLAYING DISTORTEDLY ON RADIO]
ANNOUNCER [ON RADIO]:
Yes, believe your eyes.
Those are, in fact, the northern lights
on view above the city...
...for the first time in nearly 80 years.
[DALE HAWKINS' "SUSIE Q"
PLAYING ON RADIO]
Ooh, Susie Q
Baby, I love you
DJ [ON RADIO]:
It's 5 a.m. Hello, New York.
The big story this morning, of course,
is the Amazins...
...taking the field today in Baltimore
for their final practice...
...before tomorrow's opener
of the 1969 World...
ANCHOR: Early this morning, sanitation
workers discovered the dead body...
...of another nurse
in a Dumpster in Queens.
This is the third nurse killed...
...in what New York papers are
now calling the Nightingale murders.
["CRIMSON AND CLOVER" PLAYING]
What a beautiful feeling
ANCHOR: All three victims have been
nurses, each of them found strangled...
...with their hands gruesomely bound
behind their backs with glass tape.
ANNOUNCER: The lights,
also known as the aurora borealis...
MAN:
Oh, look out!
Oh, my God!
Move it!
DISPATCHER:
Manhattan calling Eye of the Storm.
Engine company 12, ladder company 93.
Respond to Manhattan box 132
off-ramp on George Washington Bridge.
We're on our way.
DISPATCHER:
Confirm overturned tanker.
Confirm two Con Ed workers trapped
in an underground electric substation.
Frank, we're the second in.
- We got the rescue.
- Great.
[SIREN WAILING]
Commander, what do you need done?
That dike's about to go.
We're one spark away from losing the block.
- Is there another way in?
- Only that manhole leads to the vault.
Forget it, Sullivan.
Vault door's rusted shut
and they can't kill the juice.
You won't make it.
There's not enough time.
What? Miss the World Series?
Not a chance.
Give me my tools.
O'CONNELL:
Sullivan. Sullivan.
This is Commander O'Connell.
You hear me?
FRANK:
I hear you, commander.
O'CONNELL:
The gasoline is rising in the vault.
Those downed cables hit that gas,
it's gonna blow.
- Way to go, Gib.
- I should have been a goddamn mailman.
Clear this channel.
Explosion's imminent.
Hey, guys. Can you hear me?
MAN 1: We're here.
FRANK: Coming in.
MAN 1: Come on, get us out of here.
MAN 2: Hey, he's got a broken leg.
Frank, it's gonna flash. Get out of there.
The dike isn't holding.
MAN 1: Get us out!
BUTCH: Frank, do you hear me?
Yeah. Yeah, I hear you, Butch.
- Grab that axe.
- Here.
Give me a whack. No sparks.
Again.
- One more.
MAN 2: Come on.
Okay, stand back.
MAN 1:
Oh, thank God.
Hey, my leg's all busted up.
Please, hurry.
FRANK:
We're in, Butch.
Right, then get them
and get the hell out.
Hey, fellas. Time to go home.
MAN 1:
Hey, watch it. Watch it.
- It's falling. It's gonna break.
O'CONNELL: Frank, let's go.
That's an order. Everybody, go.
FRANK: All right, let's move
before the gas lights up.
Watch that wire.
Get out, for chrissake!
FRANK:
I got you.
Butch, Butch, we're coming out.
We're coming out right now.
Go!
You all right?
Watch your head. Watch your head.
Get up that ladder. Go ahead.
GIB: Come on. Come on.
- Get up. Get up.
Go on up.
- Go. I'm behind you.
- I'm going.
- Keep going.
- Pull him up.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Come on. I got you. I got you.
FRANK:
Ha, ha. Welcome to the company, Gib.
[HORN HONKS]
FRANK:
Fellas.
- Hey, Dad.
- Hey. Hey, Gordo.
- Hey, Mr. Sullivan.
- How you doing?
- How's my Little Chief, huh?
JOHN: Good.
FRANK: Where's your mother?
JOHN: Inside the house.
[MARTHA & THE VANDELLAS'
"HEAT WAVE" PLAYING ON RADIO]
FRANK:
Hey, Jules.
- Hey, bud.
ANNOUNCER:
That was "Heat Wave."
Martha and the Vandellas
here on WOR New York radio.
Hey, how about a little bit
of the king, huh?
Yeah, why not a little of the king?
Damn.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
I think I ruined the sauce. Again.
FRANK:
What's the matter?
[ELVIS' "SUSPICIOUS MINDS"
PLAYING]
Having trouble working
an eight-hour shift at the hospital...
...watching the kid,
whipping up a little Bolognese?
JULIA:
Didn't marry Donna Reed.
Hey, I'd go for you
and Chinese takeout over her any day.
[SINGING]
Because I love you too much, baby
[JULIA CHUCKLES]
Why can't you see
What you're doing to me?
- How was your tour?
- The usual, you know.
Butch called.
- Did he?
- He did.
It was under control, bud.
Butch, he's getting a little tight
in his old age.
Nothing wrong with old age, Frank,
long as you get there.
- With suspicious minds
- Suspicious
Baby, we can't build our dreams
On suspicious minds
So if an old friend I know
Drops by to say hello
Would I still see suspicion in your eyes?
FRANK: All right, Chief. When I let go,
I want you to keep pedaling.
Daddy, put the wheels back on.
I'm gonna fall.
Don't worry about falling.
You're ready to do this.
Come on. Spirit and guts, okay?
Okay. All right, keep pedaling.
I'm gonna let go. I'm gonna let go.
That's it.
Keep pedaling. Keep pedaling.
Keep pedaling.
- Yeah.
- Ow!
You all right?
- You all right?
- Johnny?
You okay?
- You hurt? You okay?
- I wanna go to my room.
JULIA:
Okay, go on, honey. It's okay.
Hey, come on, Chief.
Don't quit on me now.
Don't be so tough on him, Frank.
He's just a kid.
He just needs to know
you're behind him.
Okay, you're right.
All right.
MAN 1:
CQ-22, this is W2QYV, by for call.
MAN 2:
It's because of the solar activity.
MAN 1: It's beautiful. Got the sky
over my house lit up like a bonfire.
MAN 2: Word is sunspots
are shooting off flares...
...that stretch out
half a million kilometers.
Look, I've said it before.
MAN 1: Tell me about it. I'm picking up
signals in places I could never reach.
MAN 3: Francis, is that you?
How are you, my friend?
FRANCIS:
I'm doing just great. How you doing?
MAN 3: Oh, fantastic. My wife, Sophia,
she's gonna give me another baby.
So that's it, Samantha?
You're just walking out?
I've been walking out for six months, John.
You just didn't notice or care.
[SOBBING]
You're right.
We should've quit a long time ago.
I'm sorry.
I know it's my fault.
I can't change, Sam.
I wish I could, but I can't.
No, John. It's that you won't change.
And that's what hurts so much.
Goodbye, Chief.
[CROWD CHEERING IN MEMORY]
ANNOUNCER [VOICE OVER]:
Next up, Johnny Sullivan.
[BAT CRACKS AND CROWD CHEERS]
It's a hit up the middle.
And Johnny's gonna hold at first.
And now batting for Johnny's father,
Coach Newman.
ANNOUNCER [ON TV]:
Checks the runner and fires.
Lined hard to right.
No problem. One on, one out.
- Hi, Uncle John.
- I'm not your uncle, kid.
GORDO:
Hey, Sully, is that you?
Gordo, what are you guys doing
in my house?
My TV's out again.
Hey, uh, you want a brewski?
Yeah.
ANNOUNCER:
Deep fly to center field.
GORDO: Can you believe Linda
still won't let me cook in the house?
You know, I melt one lousy frying pan,
you know?
John, guess what?
Dad's taking me fishing.
- Wanna come?
JOHN: I wish I could, Gordy.
But you bring me back a big one, okay?
Hey, is it okay if Gordy
uses your old gear?
Yeah, I think it's somewhere
in the hall closet, if you can find it.
GORDO:
Gordy, have a look, huh?
Yeah.
So Yahoo went up
another five points today.
- Man, did I miss the boat on that one, huh?
- Should have, would have, could have, pal.
So, Sam called Linda.
GORDY:
Dad, John, come here.
GORDO: Gordy, what are
you doing back there, huh?
- Dad, check it out.
- Wow.
Fire Department. Can I open it up?
- Sure.
- Yes.
- Whoa!
- Hey, hey, hey, give me that gun.
All right?
- What's this, Dad?
- Oh, my God.
John, it's your dad's old ham radio.
Remember how we used to beg him
to let us talk on this thing?
- This is not a toy.
- Is not a toy.
GORDY:
Well, can we try it, Dad?
- Ask Uncle John.
- Can we try it?
What the hell.
GORDO:
All right.
Here, let's grab this baby out.
This is what we used when
I was your age.
Let's go over to the den, huh?
Plug it in, just like the old times.
We want CW or LSB.
Stand-by function. Operator. Come on.
I don't know what's going on.
Let's take a look under the hood, huh?
See what we got here.
Check this baby out. There she is.
So this is what people used
before the Net, huh?
Well, not exactly. I'll tell you.
Hams were...
- Bingo.
JOHN: Yeah.
These babies were different.
Not everybody had one of these.
And you needed a special license
just to be able to talk on them.
- Aw.
- Damn, I just... I just...
- I don't think it's gonna work, kid.
JOHN: It's junk, kid.
Nobody uses those things anymore.
LINDA:
Gordo, do you know what time it is?
- Hey, John.
JOHN: Hi, Linda.
Come on, Gordy. Let's go.
I'll catch you later, all right? If I'm lucky.
So feed him.
Put it down there for him.
I'm not gonna... We are not gonna speak
if you continue to say that word.
[LINE RINGING]
JULIA [ON RECORDING]:
This is Julia Sullivan.
Please leave a message after the tone.
[ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS]
Hey, Ma, it's me.
Just checking in.
You're probably at work.
Anyways...
...I'll see you tomorrow night.
- I love you.
- She had such fun on her birthdays.
She'd open her present and drift off...
...then look down, see her present
and get happy all over again.
That's what my father does
with his breakfast cereal.
The aurora borealis,
to anyone who's seen it...
...is one of the stunning events
of your lifetime.
They're brighter these days.
Is something going on there?
Do they tie in with your field?
- Where do they come from?
- It's a stunning sight. It's beautiful to look at.
I don't think we've seen one
quite this bright for 30 years...
...but from the point of view of physics
and string theory...
...there's nothing really that we gain
from studying the aurora borealis.
History does teach that every time
we thought we had it figured out...
...there was some major discovery
right around the bend...
...that required a complete dramatic change
in our understanding of the laws of physics.
HOST: This is a phrase people
have begun to hear, "string theory."
GREENE:
Yes, yes, that's right.
Now, string theory dramatically changes
our understanding of space and time.
For example, it turns out that
string theory requires our universe...
...to have 10
or possibly even 11 dimensions.
Strange thing is some physicists
are even pursuing the idea...
...there might be
more than one time dimension.
Time as we know it,
psychological time...
[INDISTINCT CHATTER OVER RADIO]
...which seems to organize events
in the universe...
...there may be a second time dimension.
- The universe evolves in a different manner.
HOST: Another phrase...
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
CQ-15, CQ-15, come in, 15.
Hello?
Hey, W2QYV here. Who have I got?
Name's John.
You licensed to broadcast, buddy?
Look, I really don't remember
how this thing works.
Listen, you can't broadcast
without a license.
Unless this is an emergency,
you're gonna have to get off the band.
JOHN: Pal, my whole life's an emergency.
- Where you transmitting from?
JOHN:
Queens, New York.
Well, what do you know?
Bayside, born and raised.
JOHN: No kidding? I thought these things
were for talking around the world.
MAN: Yeah, well,
the 15 band closes down at night...
...but during the day, you can
chew the band with China, if you want.
I can't believe people
are still using these things.
You must be a real old-timer, huh?
MAN: Days like this,
I feel like I'm getting there, you know?
So, Queens, uh,
you psyched for the Series, huh?
You know,
I really don't follow baseball anymore.
What?
- I just got fed up with all the bullshit.
- What are you talking about?
Let me tell you something.
A thousand years from now
when kids study about America...
...they're gonna learn about three things:
The Constitution, rock 'n' roll...
...and baseball.
- Ha-ha-ha.
How can you live in Queens
and not love the Amazins?
The Amazing Mets?
What, the '69 Series?
Man, I'll love Ron Swoboda
till the day I die.
MAN: Now I'm with you.
He's got the heart of a lion.
Mets can't win game one without him.
- Can you hear me?
- Game one? What are you talking about?
It was all over after Buford nailed
Seaver's second pitch out of the park.
[STATIC BUZZING]
MAN:
Hey, no way, buddy. Ain't gonna happen.
Hey, CQ-15? CQ-15, are you there?
[STATIC BUZZING]
Who the hell was that?
MAN: Queens, are you there, Queens?
Did I lose you?
Hey, Frank, give the radio a rest.
Your son wants to say good night.
All right. I'll be right there.
HOST [ON TV]: Would parallel universes
ever become aware of each other?
GREENE:
Who knows? It's a strange idea...
[DOG WHIMPERS]
Elvis, you all right? Oh, sorry.
JULIA: You okay, Frank?
- We're fine.
You all right, buddy?
Oh, you okay, buddy?
GREENE: Not just the aurora. The sunspots
are going to have a serious impact...
...on radio communication
for the next six or seven days.
In fact, quantum theory tells us that the
rigid notions of past, present and future...
...although useful in day-to-day life...
...may dissolve and be replaced
by a complex formulation...
...in which time is far more fluid
than anybody would have imagined.
[SINGING]
Take me out to the ball game
Take me out with the crowd
Buy me some peanuts and Cracker Jacks
I don't care if I never get back
'Cause it's root, root, root
For the home team
If we don't win
Two, three strikes, you're out
At the old ball game
MAN:
That's perfect.
FRANK:
Butch, you gotta turn the whole set.
BOY:
Can't wait till the game.
FRANK:
It's not the tuner. It's the antenna.
- Proby.
PROBY: What?
Point the antenna out
from under the house a little bit.
PROBY: Like this?
- There. There it is.
- Got it?
- I'll get a beer.
- Hey, hey, hey. Proby, walk away.
PROBY: Okay, walking away.
FRANK: If it ain't broke, don't fix it.
BOY: Come on!
FRANK:
Here we go, boys. Here we go.
Hey, Satch, grab a seat. Come on.
Sully, I think I need a new set of cleats.
You know, I lost my footing there.
- Yeah. Yeah, right.
- Dr. DeLeon, you decided to join us.
- You don't wanna know.
- Thank you.
DeLEON: Thirty-six hours,
I was bouncing off the walls.
That's why you're the doctor,
I'm the nurse.
- Hey, baby.
- Can I get you something?
- No, no. It's all right.
ANNOUNCER:
In left field, Don Buford.
Paul Blair is in center field.
MAN:
Sit down.
SATCH: How you boys doing?
- Good, Satch.
SATCH:
Okay. I got something for you.
ANNOUNCER: Born in Cuba...
- I can't believe it!
SATCH: And I got something for you.
- Whoa!
Dad, look!
What? You gotta be... Hey,
are you Santa Claus or something or what?
- Game three tickets.
SATCH: Yeah, that's me.
- Did you say "thank you"?
- Thank you, Uncle Satch.
SATCH: You're welcome.
FRANK: Thank you. Thank you, Satch.
SATCH: It's on.
- Hey, all right. Wait, wait, wait.
Everybody.
Everybody say, "Amazing Mets."
ALL:
Amazing Mets! Yeah!
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING]
Don't choke on your pride, Sul.
You never gonna find
another one like Sam.
She made up her mind, Satch.
- Nothing I do is gonna change it.
- Nothing you're willing to do.
- What's the story?
- Construction crew found a body.
Actually, a skeleton.
SATCH: Okay, well, be real careful
when you pull it out.
- Make sure you get the dirt around it.
- Yes, sir. Okay.
SATCH: So, what's this construction now?
JOHN: I think I'll visit the neighbors, Satch.
Yeah, okay.
- What did they tear down here?
OFFICER: Greek diner.
MAN:
I used to get breakfast there all the time.
Them Greeks were good people.
MRS. SHEPARD: Careful. It's hot.
- Thank you, Mrs. Shepard.
Once that McDonald's opened up
on Dyckman, they lost all their business.
- I see your son's on the job.
- Was.
Jack died a while back.
It's hard. I know.
It just seems like yesterday.
MR. SHEPARD:
My son lived and bled blue.
- Get out of here. Regards to Beth.
OFFICER: Okay, detective. Sure will.
This isn't gonna be anything but a
history lesson. Let's go back to the house.
- Hey, Barney. How you doing?
- Good.
- Here you go. Thank you.
- Bye.
- I thought it'd be nicer to eat here.
- Hey, sounds good.
I'm sorry Samantha couldn't make it.
Yeah, those grad school applications
are driving her crazy.
How's it coming?
I got the VCR hooked up.
It's just this frigging clock.
Heh. Doesn't matter.
- Damn it. I'm sorry, Mom.
- Hey, I know. It's all right.
- I'm sure everything will work out.
- What's that?
With Sam.
Oh, yeah, you know,
just a tough time right now, you know.
- So how are things at the hospital?
- Fine.
- Hey, Dr. Schwartz retired last month.
- No kidding.
- He must have been pushing 90.
- Close, yeah. Ha-ha-ha.
So how'd you like The Lion King?
Oh, I loved it. Sweet kid.
I wish you'd gone.
Yeah, I know. I'm sorry. It's work.
Yeah, you work too hard.
- Look who's talking.
- Ha-ha-ha.
- It's tomorrow.
- Thirty years.
I wish I could remember him better.
JULIA:
He was just a big kid.
He wanted to play baseball forever.
And fighting fires, he loved that.
And you.
He loved you.
JULIA:
Okay, guys. Bedtime.
Okay, Mom.
FRANK: Looking good.
We'll do it again tomorrow, Chief.
JOHN:
Good night, Dad.
FRANK [OVER RADIO]:
CQ-15. CQ-15.
W2QYV
calling unidentified station Queens.
CQ-15?
W2QYV
calling unidentified station Queens.
CQ-15, come in, Queens.
Hello.
Hey, hey, is that you? Hey, I've been trying
to cue you all night. Where you been?
Hey, how the hell did you do it?
Do what?
Do what? The Series.
You called Buford's homer.
How the hell did you do it?
It wasn't too tough, buddy.
The game happened 30 years ago.
Yeah, right, right.
Yeah, 30 years ago. Yeah, sure.
I suppose you could tell me
what happened in game two.
Yeah, sure. Top of the ninth,
Al Weis, game-winning RBI single.
[OVER RADIO] Brooks Robinson
grounds out to end the game.
Daddy, come up
and sing the baseball song.
Hey, Little Chief. You all right?
Okay, you just go on up.
I'll be there in a minute.
JOHN: Okay.
FRANK: All right.
- Sorry about that. That was my kid.
- What'd you say?
Sorry about that. My kid just came in.
You call your son Little Chief?
Yeah.
What did you say your name was?
Frank. Frank Sullivan.
Is this some kind of joke?
Gordo, is that you?
Are you messing with me?
I ain't messing with you.
I'm trying to figure...
You're telling me your name is
Frank Sullivan, you live in Queens...
...and you wanna know how I called
the first game of the 1969 World Series?
- Yeah, that's exactly what I wanna know.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Gordo, if this is you, so help me...
- What'd you say...?
- Gordo?
What'd you say your call station
or your call letters were?
W2QYV.
Now you listen to me.
My name is John Francis Sullivan.
I live at 34342nd Avenue,
where I lived my whole life.
And I saw the first game
of the 1969 World Series...
...right here in this house 30 years ago.
- Bullshit.
My father's name is
Francis Patrick Sullivan.
He was a firefighter
and a die-hard Mets fan.
- Every night when I went to bed...
- Bullshit.
...he sang to me,
"Take Me Out to the Ballgame."
Hey, who the hell are you?
Son of a bitch.
- What's going on?
- Nothing. Nothing's going on.
JOHN:
Oh, my God.
You burned the desk. I can see it.
Are you still there?
I said, you burned the desk. I can see it.
Hello.
Hello. Are you still there?
Come back. Talk to me.
Hello. Hey, hello?
Hey, hey, listen to me.
You listen to me right now.
I don't know who you are
or why you're doing this.
Let me tell you something, asshole.
You stay away from me and my family.
No, no, no. You gotta believe me.
I don't know how this is happening,
but it's me, Little Chief.
Hey, hey, hey, look, look.
I am warning you.
If you touch my kid, I will hunt you down
till the day I die. You got that?
But you already died.
What are you talking about?
The Buxton fire.
Oh, yeah?
And when did that happen, 30 years ago?
October 12, 1969.
Tomorrow. I'm gonna die...
I ain't dying in no fire tomorrow
or any other day. You got that?
- Tomorrow hasn't happened.
- It hasn't happened. Ain't gonna happen.
No, you listen to me.
It was an abandoned warehouse.
Butch told Ma it wasn't your fault.
You went with your instincts.
- I'm warning you.
- If you'd gone the other...
[STATIC BUZZING]
If you'd just gone the other way,
you would have made it. Hello?
[DISTORTED]
Hello.
Hello. Shit.
GORDO:
Sully, what are you doing, man?
I talked to him, Gordo.
I talked to my dad.
GORDO: Sully, go in the house, all right?
I'll come over and we'll hang out.
No, no, no. I gotta get him back
so he doesn't go in.
Go in? What do you...? Go in where?
The warehouse in Buxton. It's tomorrow.
[THINKING] Yeah, right, right.
Yeah, 30 years ago. Yeah, sure.
So I suppose you could tell me
what happened in game two, huh?
JOHN: Yeah, sure. Top of the ninth,
Al Weis, game-winning RBI single.
MAN 1: Come on.
MAN 2: Hit it, Al.
- Warm it up.
- That's good. That's good, yeah.
Look at the stats. Look at them.
MAN 1:
Let's go, Weis.
ALL:
Yeah!
[ALARM BLARING]
DISPATCHER: We have a three-and-two
response, Ladder 93.
You're first due. It's reported
to be an abandoned warehouse...
...at the foot of Water Street and 3rd.
- You got some construction, limited access.
ANNOUNCER: Weis is having a great series.
[SIRENS WAILING]
[ANNOUNCER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON RADIO]
Yeah, we won!
Frank, you all right?
BUTCH:
We know it's vacant.
Nobody goes in. Surround and drown.
Call for a tower.
WOMAN: Help!
- Shit, we got squatters inside.
Help!
Help! Help!
- My sister.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
She's up there. She passed out.
- Where's your sister? What floor?
- I tried to help.
- Tell me what floor.
- She's up there on the top floor.
I tried. I tried.
Please, help her. Please.
Butch, take her. Come on, proby.
- Anybody else there?
- No.
[BOAT HORN HONKING]
Ryan, get her medical treatment.
FRANK: Give me my gear.
MAN [OVER RADIO]: Fire on the top floor.
- Hey, Sul.
- Satch.
Hey, here he is.
So how you feeling, Sul?
JOHN:
What can I tell you?
WOMAN: Here you go.
JOHN: Thanks.
Better.
No visible fire, first or second floor.
Watch your step, proby.
This floor's rotten.
[OVER RADIO] Got fire on the third floor.
Need a line in place. We're going up.
We got two lines coming behind you.
- Back out. Wait for the line.
- Hell with the line.
- I'll find another way up.
- No, you can't help me here.
DISPATCHER: We don't need it
right now. Just be prepared.
So you doing okay, John?
Yeah. Tough day, you know.
Hey, here's to your dad, huh?
- Thirty years today.
- To your dad.
To my dad.
We're pulling everyone
out of the building.
FRANK: Get that to the top floor.
It's cooking up here.
So after that Halloween thing
with the fire truck, you remember that?
I remember riding around with Butch
and your dad.
- The whole neighborhood was watching.
- I remember. I wanted to go as a cop then.
Yeah, so then Jules makes your dad
buy you that cop kit for your birthday.
Oh, I remember that.
I was always the robber,
always being handcuffed.
SATCH:
That's right. I taught you to do that.
[WOOD CLATTERING
AND FIRE BLAZING]
[COUGHING]
10:45, I found the girl.
- She's breathing.
- Get them out.
Go!
Hang on.
What the hell is going on?
- Gino, what's the matter?
- The gear box, it's cracked.
BUTCH:
Frank, Frank, that ladder's jammed.
That ladder's jammed.
Frank, you gotta find another way out.
Frank, can you hear me?
It worked out okay, though.
You're a better cop than a fireman.
No doubt about it.
GORDO:
Worked out good for me too.
I'm glad I never spent 10 years
as his hose man.
SATCH:
Yeah, I bet you are.
[CHUCKLING]
JOHN [VOICE OVER]:
The Buxton fire. It wasn't your fault.
If you had just gone the other way...
ALL:
Cheers!
- Frank, we're losing the building.
- I know.
FRANK:
Hey, hey, hey. This is not...
- Hey.
JOHN: Daddy.
Blue.
Relax, Chief.
Hey, hey, hey. This is not a toy.
Hey, you wanna play?
- Wave to Ma.
JOHN: Mom, look at us.
Thank you all.
You're gonna be some ballplayer.
WOMAN:
Whoa, hey, careful.
John, you all right?
John, John.
- I'm sorry.
GORDO: What is it?
- Is everything okay?
- Yeah, can you just bring us a towel?
FRANK:
Get her up.
- Satch, my father didn't die in a fire, right?
SATCH: Huh?
Gordo, my father didn't die in a fire.
MAN:
Easy.
What are you talking about, John?
He had cancer.
Cancer,
because it was the cigarettes, right?
Yeah, lung cancer, 10 years ago.
Little Chief.
Gordo, I ain't dreaming here.
I talked to him. It was real.
FRANK:
Little Chief! Ha-ha-ha.
GORDO:
What are you talking about?
It was a ham radio.
That's how come he didn't die, you know.
FRANK:
Little Chief! Ha-ha-ha.
[CHUCKLES]
That's how come he didn't die.
FRANK:
John. John Sullivan, are you there?
Come on, answer me.
Chief, Chief, are you there?
JOHN:
I'm right here, Daddy.
Come here.
Come on.
- Where's Elvis?
- Sleeping.
Sleeping. Why aren't you sleeping?
- You woke me up.
- I did?
- Hey, I got an idea.
- What's that?
All right, Chief.
What do you say
we tame this bronco, huh?
- I'm scared.
- I know. And you know what?
I'm gonna be right here with you, always.
Daddy, I can't.
Well, we can. We can do it together.
You and me. Spirit and guts.
What do you say?
- Okay.
- All right. Come on.
Now, you just take your time.
I'm not gonna let go
until you say it's okay.
- Okay.
- All right?
All right, start pedaling.
That's it. Get your balance.
- Ready?
- Wait.
FRANK:
Okay, okay, I'm still here.
- Okay.
- All right.
- It's all you.
- Look at me.
It's all you. It's all you, Chief.
JOHN: Look at me, Dad.
- Hey, look at you.
JOHN: I'm doing it. I'm doing it.
- You're doing it. Look at you.
- You're doing it.
- I'm doing it.
FRANK: How's it feel?
- Good.
FRANK: Look at you, like a circus act.
- This is great, like a flying trapeze.
FRANK: Look at you.
- This feels great.
FRANK: You're going around the world.
- It's like flying.
FRANK:
Wait till your mother sees this, huh?
JOHN: Look at me.
- Let's wake up the world, huh?
[FRANK LAUGHING]
Oh, my God.
JOHN [OVER RADIO]:
Hello?
- Hello?
- John?
John Sullivan?
It's me.
You're the voice of an angel.
Reached right out of heaven
and you pulled my butt out of the fire.
Tell me I'm not dreaming here.
Tell me it's really you.
It's me, John.
This ain't no dream.
- But how could it be?
- I don't know. I don't know.
But we gotta be talking
off the mother sunspot of all time.
Yeah, I'd say so.
[CHUCKLING]
You okay, Chief?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You sure?
Uh, it's, uh...
Heh, it's, uh, tough to explain.
I mean, I've got all these new memories,
but it's like I don't know what to believe.
What do you mean?
Because I still remember what it was like
when you died in the fire.
But I'm the only one.
I don't understand
what you're talking about.
I remember both at the same time.
And it's like waking up from a dream
and you're not sure what's real.
I remember you being here,
but I also remember when you weren't.
Oh, I'm sorry, John.
- I'm sorry. I never thought that...
- Well, you gotta think about that.
And you gotta be more careful,
because I can't lose you again.
Not like that.
You won't, John. You won't.
I swear to God, no matter what,
not like that.
You got it? You hear me?
You hear me, Chief?
I hear you.
So how old are you?
Ahem. I'm 36.
Thirty-six?
You're all grown up. Ha, ha.
You gotta be married and everything.
No, I'm not married.
- What, you're too busy playing ball?
- No.
It didn't work out. I gave it up.
What happened?
I just blew my arm out my senior year
and didn't have a shot.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Johnny.
I know that had to hurt.
Yeah, thanks.
So, what did you wind up doing?
You join the department?
Actually, I went the other way.
I'm a cop.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
You're third-generation firefighter.
I thought you'd grow out of that cop phase.
Well, you got Satch to thank for that one.
You gotta be kidding me, huh?
Satch, he always crazy about you
ever since you were born.
You're still my Little Chief.
Right?
Yeah, I'm trying to be. I'm trying.
Well, tell me about yourself.
Tell me about your life.
I mean, uh, where do I start, you know?
FRANK:
Mustang? I don't own a Mustang.
JOHN:
Well, you will and you loved it.
- Fire-engine red. Four on the floor.
- Yeah?
FRANK: Seventy home runs?
That's a record that will never be broken.
I wouldn't be too sure.
The other guy hit 66.
Really? You mean like those
big field radios they use in the Army?
Smaller. Works off a satellite or something.
You carry it around in your pocket.
Hey, what about Apollo?
How'd it all work out?
It was a great series, Pop. Amazing.
- So we win, right?
- Hold your horses. I'm getting there.
Game three, Agee came through,
homered off Palmer in the second.
I knew it. I knew Agee
was gonna have a great series.
Forget about Agee. Wait until you hear
what happened to Cleon Jones.
- Now you sound like your mother.
- I'm serious.
Oh, come on. Your grandfather,
he smoked, what, two packs a day...
...and he's still kicking.
- Not you.
It's gonna get the better of you.
Okay?
FRANK:
Well, I just knew.
She melted my heart. That was it.
You got anybody?
Yeah, kind of.
Something I gotta work out, but...
...she's worth it.
No, you...
...go ahead and you get some rest.
I'm tired too.
I almost don't wanna click off here...
...like maybe we won't get this back.
- We will.
- Okay.
I'll be here tomorrow.
I know.
I love you, son.
I, uh...
I love you too, Dad.
And...
...I've missed you so much.
[CLEARS THROAT]
[LINE RINGS]
JULIA [ON RECORDING]:
Hi, this is Julia Sullivan.
Please leave a message after the tone.
[ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS]
Hey, Ma, it's me. Uh...
Just call me. We gotta talk.
[CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
- Take over for me?
- All right.
- Frank, what's going on?
FRANK: Nothing.
- I just wanted to see you, that's all.
- Yeah?
I'm not going anywhere, Jules.
Not for the rest of your life.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- I got a bad feeling today. I was worried.
- Huh?
- Look at me. Not a scratch.
- Where's Johnny?
He's at Gordo's. I tucked him in.
You give him his drops?
One in each ear.
- What would you do without me?
- Probably marry some rich doctor.
Never have to work.
Oh, my God. What is he doing?
Frank, I gotta...
- Doctor, is that benazepril?
- Yes.
I gave this patient 50 mils of Benadryl.
Mix them and he's dead.
- Why wasn't I made aware of it?
- It's in his chart.
[MOUTHS]
I love you. Bye.
I love you too.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
[JOHN PANTING]
FRANK:
Son?
Come on.
[GASPING]
[LINE RINGING]
- Hello, Ma?
WOMAN: Noah's Deli.
Oh, sorry.
[LINE RINGING]
WOMAN:
This is Noah's Deli.
[LINE CLICKS AND DIAL TONE HUMS]
- Sam, I gotta talk to you.
- Excuse me?
Look, I'm sorry, but I gotta talk to you.
How do you know my name?
- Who are you?
- Who am I?
Look, I don't know you.
You don't know me?
What do you mean, you don't know me?
Wait, I do know you.
You're Linda and Gordo's friend.
The neighbor. The cop.
What are you doing here?
Um...
I shouldn't have come here.
I didn't mean to upset you. I'm sorry.
SATCH:
Yeah, I'll take care of it.
- What?
- Another rough night?
- Is that it?
- Yeah, that's it.
Do not disrespect me, John.
Disrespect yourself all you want to,
but not me or anybody else here. Got that?
We got the preliminary forensics
back on the skeleton.
You wanna take a look at this.
Bad memories.
You imagine the odds of us
digging up a Nightingale murder?
- She makes 10.
- Ten?
No, I remember this case.
It was three. He killed three women.
What are you talking?
You know better than anybody, John.
You looked at these files
a thousand times.
No.
Dad, are you there?
[OVER RADIO]
Can you hear me?
Dad, I need you to be there.
FRANK: Yeah, yeah, Chief.
I'm coming, I'm coming.
Listen, there's something I need to t...
FRANK:
Right here, Chief.
- Chief?
- Something happened.
- Something pretty bad.
- What's the matter, Johnny? What is it?
- Mom. Something happened to her in...
- Your mom. What?
She's not here.
What do you mean, she's not there?
She died, but it's like
it just happened, though.
She died? Your mom just died?
No, Dad.
It happened a long time ago.
A long time ago for me.
When?
October 22nd, 1969.
That's now, Johnny. That's next week.
How...? You gotta tell me how.
- She was murdered.
- Murdered? What are you talking about?
Listen to me. There was this case, a serial.
They never caught him.
But he murdered three women, all nurses,
between '68 and '69.
They call him the Nightingale.
Nightingale?
We've been watching that on the news.
- I was worried about your mother. She said...
- Dad, we did something.
Something to make it worse.
- I don't understand.
- He didn't just kill three women anymore.
He's killed 10.
Something we did changed the past.
- But how come your mother...?
- Think about it.
Everything you did is different than if
you'd never gotten out of that warehouse.
Now, what did you do last night, Dad?
I talked to you, I put you on the bike...
...I tucked you in at Gordo's and I went
to see your mother over at the hospital.
Oh, shit.
That's it.
She wasn't supposed to be there.
Butch got her. It was the night of the fire.
He brought her home.
- Something happened at the hospital?
- That's the beginning.
It could've been anywhere, place, time
that she wouldn't have been if you'd died.
I'll take her away from here.
I have to take her away from...
- He cannot hurt her if I take her away.
- What about the others?
What about the others, Dad?
- I'll warn them.
- It'll never work. They'll think you're crazy.
But I gotta do something. You
don't even know what this guy looks like.
- You don't know who he is.
- No, because nobody got any...
Hold on. Wait a minute.
Dad, I may not know who he is...
...but I know where he's gonna be and what
he's gonna do before he gets there.
What do I do? Call the police?
They're not gonna believe me.
They will if they catch him in the act.
You can make that happen.
No, Johnny. I don't know.
- I don't know. I'm a firefighter, not a cop.
- I'm a cop. This is what I do.
This is something we have to do.
If the ham stops working?
- If I can't reach you?
- Get Mom the hell out.
But, Dad, those other women
were not supposed to die.
If we don't do something to try
to stop this guy...
...we're gonna have to live with that
for the rest of our lives.
Okay.
- Okay, tell me what to do.
- All right.
The next victim is Carrie Reynolds.
It happens tomorrow.
Case file says
she left the Roosevelt Hospital at 6...
...showed up at Cozy's Bar around 6:30...
...she walked out of that bar
around 7:30...
...and they found her dead
in an alley behind the bar at 8:00.
I want you to follow her, see if anybody's
watching her or hitting on her...
...because I'm betting
when she walks out of that place...
...somebody's gonna come out with her.
When they do, you call the cops.
MAN: Hi, Carrie.
- Hi, Glen. How you doing?
GLEN:
Really good.
CARRIE:
Thanks for ordering.
NIXON [ON TV]:
The American people want peace.
We believe in peace.
We have fought our wars in this century
because we wanted peace.
And we want to bring the war in Vietnam
to an end...
...in a way that will promote not a temporary
but a lasting peace.
DELANEY: busiest intersection
during tomorrow evening's rush hour.
BARTENDER: Two JBs on the rocks.
DELANEY: Steve Delaney, NBC News.
BARTENDER:
Yeah.
From the girls, pal. Cool.
ANCHOR: In Chicago, students from
Mundelein College, the capital school...
...have been passing out leaflets
in supermarkets to get support.
MAN: We're gonna have an evening vigil...
- Thanks.
ANCHOR: At Northwestern University
Law School, which held a rally today...
...60 percent of the students felt
that the U.S. should get out of the war.
FRANK: I was...
- Sit down.
FRANK: Yeah.
- Fireman, huh?
FRANK: Yeah, I'm not really...
- A married fireman.
- Yeah.
WOMAN 1: Oh, what the hell.
- What do they call you?
- Uh, Frank.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
Seven-four Homicide.
Yeah, it's me.
You're kidding.
Hold on.
Spell that for me.
Okay, okay. Thanks, Mario.
Our lucky break.
Mario ID'd the dental.
Her name is Mary Finelli.
Reported missing April 16th, 1968.
April 16th?
- That means she was the first.
- Which means he probably knew her.
This case just got hot.
JOHN:
She's gone.
Carrie Reynolds isn't in here.
Who?
He did it.
[OVER RADIO]
Carrie Reynolds is alive and well, Dad.
I'll be damned.
- Did you see him?
- No.
JOHN: Figure who he is?
- No, I messed up.
I kept talking.
I was afraid to let her out of my sight.
Whoever it was,
he must have backed off.
That's okay. We're gonna get him.
This is gonna work.
FRANK:
I hope so. So tell me, what else you got?
JOHN: We caught a break.
Found his first victim.
- Her name is Mary Finelli.
GORDO: Thanks, Mrs. Sullivan.
Yeah, hang on a sec, John.
Hey, Jules, there's somebody
I want you to talk to, okay?
Remember I told you about
this guy, John?
I want you to say hello to him.
- John.
- Yeah.
Say hello to my wife, Julia.
- Hi.
JULIA: Hi, John.
Frank tells me you're a cop.
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah? Well, my 6-year-old keeps telling us
he wants to be a policeman...
...right after he retires from the majors.
We just bought him a badge
and a whistle for his birthday.
Yeah, I remember. I used to play
cops and robbers all the time, but you...
My mom wouldn't let me have a toy gun.
Sounds like your mom and I
would get along.
JOHN: Yeah, she's pretty special.
I'm real proud of her.
JULIA: Well, I bet she's proud of you too,
huh, being a cop and all?
I hope so.
I hope she knows how much I love her.
JULIA:
Oh, she knows.
Moms always know
how much their kids love them.
Even if they don't tell them all the time
like they should.
Well, I gotta go.
It was good talking to you, John.
Yeah, you too.
JOHN: I wanna talk on Daddy's radio.
FRANK: Okay, Chief, go ahead.
JULIA: Okay. Say good night to John.
- Good night, John.
Good night, there, Chief.
JULIA:
Okay, guys, bedtime.
No, I wanna talk on the radio too.
FRANK: All right, Gordo. Come here.
JULIA: Okay, two minutes, then bedtime.
- I'm off to bed.
FRANK: Sit there.
JOHN: One more cookie.
JULIA: No.
- No more cookies.
JOHN: Just one more.
GORDO:
This is the space cowboy.
I'm an intergalactic traveler
from the federation planet Earth.
JOHN: Gordo?
- How do you know my name, mister?
FRANK: Come on, Elvis, let's go outside.
- Hey, listen, Gordo. Uh...
My name is Santa Claus.
And I'm going to give you the biggest
Christmas present that you ever had.
I better give you my address, then.
No, no, no, don't worry about it, kid.
Now, this is important.
Something you gotta remember
for a long time.
Yahoo.
What's that?
JOHN:
Well, it's a magic word. It's like...
Like abracadabra, but even better.
Try it out, kid. Yahoo.
- Yahoo.
- You got it, space cowboy.
Okay, Gordo. Your two minutes are up.
- Now go upstairs and write it down.
GORDO: Okay, mister.
- I mean, Santa.
FRANK: Come on.
Let's go.
Stay there, John. I'll be right back.
All right, come on, upstairs. There you go.
Jules, got a live one down here.
Coming your way.
Yeah, Chief.
- Are you still there?
- Yeah. What do we do now?
JOHN:
Okay. Sissy Clark.
- 423 Greenwich Street...
- Okay, hang on, hang on.
- Go ahead.
- Sissy Clark.
423 Greenwich Street,
Apartment 2E, tomorrow.
- Okay, 2E. All right.
- Nurse.
Moonlights as a cocktail waitress
at the Kaleidoscope on West 63rd.
Left work at 2 a.m.
Was killed in her apartment
between 2:15 and 5.
Okay, I got it.
Now, Dad, I don't know how long
this thing is gonna keep working.
Hope we'll be able to talk again.
Just be careful, all right?
WOMAN:
I'm happy you found her, detective.
It makes it easier now to know for sure.
You know?
JOHN: Can I keep these for a while,
Mrs. Finelli?
[SIGHS]
Okay, just let me walk you through it.
SATCH:
I'm all ears.
Three guys show up
in both the yearbook and diary.
First guy passed away 10 years ago.
Second guy died in Vietnam.
And the third one is Daryl Simpson.
So I ran him though BCI. Got a hit.
Busted for sexual assault eight days
after the last Nightingale murder.
March 22nd, 1970.
SATCH: So you think the murders stopped
because he was off the street...
...and by the time he got paroled...
...he had smartened up enough
to control himself?
It's not the first time that's been true.
I'm telling you, I got a feeling
about this guy. This is him, Satch.
[STEPPENWOLF'S "SOOKIE, SOOKIE"
PLAYING ON STEREO]
- Can I get you another?
- Yeah, another one.
Let it hang out, baby
Let it hang out now
Can I get you another one?
- No, thanks. I'm good.
- Okay.
Everybody work out
Anything else, sir?
JOHN:
Sexual assault, Daryl. Five years.
But you got lucky, right?
You got away with something else.
Something you figured
nobody knows about.
- What I know is what I told you.
JOHN: Let me tell you what I know, Daryl.
You went to St. Ambrose with Mary.
You lived five blocks from her.
You liked her, but she ain't interested.
- So that must have hurt, huh?
- So what?
- So, what did you do about it, Daryl?
- Nothing.
MAN:
Spare a smoke?
Yeah. Here, I'm trying to quit.
Oh, my God.
What is this?
Oh, Jesus. Jesus.
Get that away from me!
Sandra Moore, Patty Ryan, Mary Finelli.
These names mean anything to you, pal?
Julia Sullivan. Does she mean anything?
Well, she means something to me!
See you, fireman.
Don't talk so much next time.
Gus, will you run my tips
while I go change?
- Sure, Sissy.
- Thanks.
JOHN [ON MONITOR]:
You know, Daryl...
...sometimes despite all the training
that we cops go through...
...despite all that we are taught
about right and wrong...
...despite all that we would like
to honor in ourselves...
...we can come to a place...
...where we don't give a damn.
Know what I mean?
You're going to tell me everything
I need to know now.
John, you got a minute?
Yeah, sure.
He ain't the guy, John.
He didn't look at the photos.
Doesn't mean he isn't the one.
Not everyone fits the profile.
If he was gonna give up something,
he would've done it already.
[SHOUTING]
You following me?
I asked you a question, asshole.
Mary Finelli.
[GRUNTING AND SHOUTING]
[DOOR OPENS]
- Whoa. Dude, what happened to him?
MAN: It was a bad trip, man.
Little time kissing the porcelain,
he'll be fine. You know?
- Yeah, I understand that.
MAN: All right. Come on, pal.
Open up. Ms. Clark, open the door!
Open the door! It's the police!
Open the door!
It's okay, ma'am. Go back inside.
It's the police. Are you in there?
Open up. I know you're in there!
Sissy Clark. Open the door.
Open the door.
[THE HONEYDRIPPERS' "SEA OF LOVE"
LOOPING ON RECORD PLAYER]
Do you remember when we...?
FRANK:
He killed her.
- And I couldn't do a damn thing to stop it.
JOHN: Dad, I said it's not your fault.
Yes, it is.
We changed everything, Johnny, eh?
- It's like we cheated.
- All right, Dad, we can't go back...
...because you didn't die in that fire.
And no matter what you do,
nothing is gonna change it.
So all we can do is deal with this
and try to make it right.
- I'm not a cop. I'm not fooling anybody.
- I know, I know, but we can.
We can do it together.
Remember spirit and guts?
John, he's got my driver's license.
- What?
- He took my driver's license.
He knows where we live.
He took your dri...? He took your wallet?
Yeah, well, he tossed the wallet,
but he kept the license.
- Where's your wallet?
- It's in my pocket.
- Oh, God. We got him, Dad. You got him.
- What?
His prints. You got his prints.
- Listen, you gotta get me that wallet.
- How the hell am I supposed to do that?
As carefully as possible.
Take your wallet out.
- But just touch it on the corners.
- What?
- Please, Dad, just do it.
- Okay, all right.
- All right, all right.
- All right.
- Okay, all right, I got it.
- All right, now listen.
I want you to wrap it up.
Put it in one of the plastic bags
you keep extra transistors in.
- Yeah, I see where you're going, Chief.
- Beautiful. Okay.
Now I want you to hide it somewhere.
Somewhere where nobody's gonna find it
for the next 30 years.
- I think maybe, uh...
- Where?
The, uh, window seat in the dining room.
There's a loose board on the left,
on the bottom.
Perfect. Beautiful.
- It's in.
- Great. Okay, I'm after it.
We're in business!
Now just sit tight and don't worry!
Wow.
And the winner is...
Oh, man. It's a cop.
What the hell?
Son of a bitch.
JOHN:
Hey, Mr. Shepard. How are you?
SHEPARD:
Who's that? Oh, hi, detective.
Just came by to wrap things up over there.
Thought I'd say hello.
Glad you did. Glad you did.
- Come on in.
- Thank you.
- Buy you a cup of coffee?
- Sure.
- Black? Sugar? Milk?
- Oh, you know. It's all good.
You'll get black.
Fresh pot.
- You know Jack?
- Not really.
He's still on the job?
Well, he does a little PI work now and then,
but he's mostly retired.
Living off his pension, huh?
Jack got caught up
in them Knapp hearings.
Set up by some dirty cops
who needed a fall guy.
Hurt him bad.
Would have broke his mother's heart.
JOHN: Is she around?
- Who?
- Your wife.
- Oh, no. She passed on a long time ago.
Long time ago.
I'm sorry.
Well, that's okay.
Can I ask how she died?
Well, she...
She was murdered, detective.
An ugly one, to tell you the truth.
Mother of a cop, and they never found
the bastard who did it.
- Hey.
MAN: All right, I'll have another.
BARTENDER: All right.
You on the job?
A long time ago.
- Do I know you?
- I look familiar?
No.
- What house you work?
- The 7-4 Homicide.
- A hotshot.
- No, just working the job.
Yeah, I hear that, pal.
As a matter of fact,
I caught a case that goes back to your day.
One of the Nightingale murders.
- No kidding?
- No. Missing teenager.
Disappeared back in '68.
They found her bones last week.
Buried behind some old diner
out by Dyckman Street.
Mary Finelli.
Talk about dumb luck. The odds
of anybody finding that girl 30 years later...
...and the chances of hitting a dental,
heh, forget about it.
The best part is, she's the first victim.
And she knew the killer...
...so I'm betting those old bones
are gonna do a lot of talking.
Not for nothing. The past is a funny thing.
We all have skeletons in the closet.
You just never know when they're gonna
pop up and bite you in the ass.
Huh, Jack?
You changed your MO.
If they knew your mother was a Nightingale,
they would have looked at the family.
They would've looked at you.
What are you looking at?
Stealing your life away.
You went down 30 years ago, pal.
You just don't know it yet.
[BAND PLAYING "STAR
SPANGLED BANNER" ON TV]
FRANK:
A cop?
He's a cop? What the hell
am I supposed to do with that?
JOHN:
Call the FBI. Use a pay phone.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Don't give them your name.
Tell them Shepard killed Finelli...
...Clark and the others. He's the Nightingale.
JULIA: I'll get it.
Then tell them where Finelli's
body is buried.
- They can connect him to her.
- Right here?
- They search his place, they find souvenirs.
JULIA: Yes.
He always took a piece of jewelry
from his victims.
SATCH:
Hey, Frank.
What are you doing here?
Are you off today?
- We need to have a conversation.
JOHN: Dad?
Hang on a sec, John.
Uh, I'm kind of in the middle
of something important.
- Mind if we do this...?
- I'm sorry, Frank...
...but we need to step outside
right now and...
JOHN:
Dad, talk to me. What's going on?
Uh, John, Satch is here and he's...
- He's with his partner.
JOHN: What the hell's going on?
FRANK:
Just hang on a sec.
What's your partner doing here?
What happened to your eye?
FRANK:
I banged it up.
Let's go outside and talk.
We need to do that.
- About what?
- Let's go.
- Do us both a favor.
- All right.
- Okay.
Stay there, John. I'll be right back.
I'll be right back, all right?
So where were you last night, Frank?
Where do you think I was, Satch?
Same place I found this.
Under the body of a dead woman.
No, no. This isn't what you think, okay?
- No, this isn't what you think.
- I wanna be wrong here, Frank.
Let's just take a ride
down to the precinct and talk about it.
Yeah, I wanna talk to you too.
I need to talk to you.
- Come on, just take a ride.
- All right, let me just go inside...
...tell my family where I'm going, all right?
Be right back.
Everything's all right. Don't worry.
ANNOUNCER [ON TV]:
He's played in 10 World Series.
They loved him in his town.
- Chief, Chief, you there?
- Yeah.
- They found Sissy Clark. They think I did it.
- Frank.
JULIA: Frank, what's going on?
- Give me a second. You gotta talk to Satch.
FRANK: Just give me a sec.
- What's going on?
JOHN: Uncle Satch, don't.
- Stay with me.
What's going on?
Satch, what's going on?
I wanna talk to you right now!
You don't understand!
SATCH: Come on.
JOHN: Stop!
[SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Frank, come on!
JOHN:
Stop!
- He's a cop.
- A cop.
Jack Shepard.
He's a detective at the 15th precinct.
I swear, Satch.
And you got all of this
from the guy on the radio...
...from your son in the future.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
As nuts as that sounds, yeah.
Uh-huh.
You gotta listen to me.
You gotta open up your mind.
- Try to understand what I'm saying.
- Listen.
You got something going on with this girl,
that's one thing.
But you gotta tell me.
Are you listening to me?
You're in a world of shit.
An eyewitness put you
outside the dead girl's apartment.
Your prints are all over the place,
not to mention the goddamn driver's license.
Now Chuck is getting a search warrant
for your house.
- What's he gonna find there, Frank, huh?
- Nothing. Nothing.
You gotta give me something,
something I can believe.
[ANNOUNCER CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY
ON RADIO FROM NEXT ROOM]
[OFFICERS GROANING]
ANNOUNCER: Seventy-five for Dave McNally.
Two Mets are out in the fifth inning...
- What if I can prove it to you, huh?
- How's that?
World Series. Where are they right now?
What, fourth, fifth inning, huh?
Well, what if I was to tell you...
...that in the bottom of the sixth inning,
the Mets are gonna be down 3-zip?
And Cleon Jones,
he's gonna come to bat.
Now, he's gonna get hit in the foot
by a wild pitch.
It's gonna leave a shoe-polish mark
on the ball.
- Frank...
- Now, listen. Hear me out, all right?
He goes to first. Clendenon comes up.
He's gonna hit a 2-2 pitch
into the left field bleachers.
This is insane, Frank.
And then in the bottom of the seventh,
Weis is going to hit a solo home run.
And then Jones and Swoboda
score in the eighth.
The Mets,
they're gonna win that game 5-to-3.
You go watch.
If it don't happen, I'm a liar.
- Go watch the game? Watch the...?
- Yeah, watch the game.
Frank, they're gonna make you
for Sissy Clark's murder.
And they're gonna match that
with the Nightingale murders.
Do you understand what that means?
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Yeah.
MAN:
His wife is here.
She wants to talk to you.
- ball player from Pittsfield Massachusetts
High School, fouled out of play.
He has those loose actions in the field.
[SIGHS]
You can tell he must have been
quite a basketball player.
One-two pitch to him.
Fly ball to right.
- Swoboda waits and there's one down.
- Let's walk, Jules. Get a cup of coffee.
Dave McNally.
The guy just went crazy.
You know what I mean?
Started tearing things apart.
- He was throwing things.
OFFICER 2: Yeah.
- Hey.
OFFICER 1:
So I cuffed him...
MAN:
He must be exhausted, I think.
WOMAN: I know, I talked to them
several times, but they just won't listen.
- How you doing?
CLERK: Hey.
You got a collar in here
for the Nightingale murders?
- Yeah?
- Yeah, come on in.
OFFICER:
Come on now.
[CHEERING AND CHATTERING
ON RADIO]
Um, everything okay
with you and Frank?
Yeah, we're good. He works hard.
I work hard. We're good.
Who's Sissy Clark, Satch?
Do you know where Frank
was last night?
Yeah, he was working. He had a tour.
OFFICER 1: Come on, let's get him.
OFFICER 2: Let's put this guy away for me.
All right. Come on.
ANNOUNCER: Watch the delivery.
ALL: Yeah!
ANNOUNCER:
Number four for Koosman.
JACK:
Sit down.
Did you just hear what I said?
So how did you know?
- Hey, this guy's trying to kill me.
- What's up in here?
- Tell Satch Jack Shepard's in here.
- Shut up, asshole.
He's trying to kill me. Go find Satch.
Find Satch. He's trying to kill me.
What are you doing with my collar?
Listen, I'm sorry, pal.
I didn't mean to step on your toes.
They sent me up from downstairs.
I thought you'd be in there with him.
CHUCK:
What are you looking at him for?
JACK: He matches a description
of an armed robbery suspect.
SATCH:
So tell me about the radio.
- Who's he talking to on that thing?
- John.
He's a cop. He talks to him all the time.
I've talked to him too.
You talked to Johnny on the radio?
Yeah. John. What's going on, Satch?
You come into my house and you take Frank
and now you're talking to me like a cop.
I'm talking to you as a friend,
because as a cop, I wouldn't be here at all.
Listen, Jules.
They're gonna take me off of this case.
And then Frank is gonna tell them
what he's been telling me.
And then nobody
is gonna be able to help him, okay?
ANNOUNCER: left field
and Cleon Jones makes the catch.
[ALL CHEER]
OFFICER: Yes! Go, boys!
- Half the uniforms are either at the game...
...or on the street.
Gonna be a riot if they pull it off.
JULIA:
What is he telling you, Satch?
That he's talking to Johnny on the radio.
- Yeah, John, the cop. I told you that.
- No, no, no.
He says that John is your son, Johnny.
Little Johnny, on the radio, in the future.
On the radio. You see?
JULIA:
No, you misunderstood him.
- Jules, Sissy Clark?
- Yeah.
She's a nurse
and she was murdered yesterday.
And Frank is connected.
He is either a material witness
or an accomplice or the perpetrator.
ANNOUNCER: McNally who's
been thoroughly in command.
Cleon starts down to first base
and DiMuro calls him back.
Satch, you know him.
You know he didn't do this, right?
ANNOUNCER:
He's carrying the baseball.
He's coming over now.
Hodges showing the baseball to DiMuro.
- Can I see him?
ANNOUNCER: Hodges...
- We might have a shoe-polish play.
- No, I...
Remember the Nippy Jones shoe-polish play
in the 1957 World Series at Milwaukee?
Hodges showing it to Lou DiMuro,
who awards first base.
ALL:
Yeah!
- here at Shea Stadium.
My God.
Satch, what's going on?
Mind I go back to the fire boy?
Just wanna see what he's got.
SATCH: Jesus.
ANNOUNCER: He wants to see the baseball.
He says, "Let me see it.
Let me see the shoe polish."
Was Augie Donatelli, I believe...
...who called the shoe-polish play
on the '57 World Series.
OFFICER 1: Oh, man.
OFFICER 2: Where's the game?
OFFICER 3:
Hey, we got no power in here.
[ALARM BLARING]
[CHEERING]
[GUNSHOT]
[HORNS HONKING]
[SHOUTS]
[GASPING]
[PEOPLE CHEERING
AND FIREWORKS POPPING IN DISTANCE]
Frank.
Hey, bud.
MAN 1 [OVER RADIO]:
Go ahead, Avalanche.
MAN 2: See if Aviation's got a helicopter
to respond to my location...
...for commencing an air search
for body in water, okay?
Location remains the Greenpoint area
of the East River.
ANNOUNCER: It was a season
and World Series for the ages for the Mets...
...and series MVP first baseman
Donn Clendenon.
For the Mets' faithful,
the New York fans, wow.
With the streets of midtown and Times
Square still packed with celebrating fans...
...Mayor Lindsay has invited
all of New York...
...to a Fifth Avenue ticker-tape parade
tomorrow for our world champions...
JULIA:
Here's your coffee and your cigarettes.
In other news, in the skies over New York,
another amazing event is coming to a close.
- Say goodbye to the northern lights...
- I'll be upstairs.
...that have been lighting up the skies...
Astronomers say
the incredible sun storms...
...that have created the remarkable
aurora borealis have begun to cool.
And the auroras, already dimming,
will be over by morning.
FRANK [OVER RADIO]:
John, are you there?
John, I'm back.
- John, are you there?
- I'm here, Dad. I'm here.
We did it, son.
- What?
- We stopped him.
- We did?
- Yeah.
There's something...
Something's wrong. I don't r...
What? What's wrong?
Well, if we stopped him,
why isn't Mom here?
Why don't I remember her being okay?
But I killed him.
He's dead.
JACK:
My turn to steal your life away.
FRANK:
John, John, are you there?
[GRUNTING]
[GUNFIRE OVER RADIO]
Hey, bud.
Frank!
FRANK:
Julia! Julia!
JACK: Hello, Julia.
JOHN: Mommy?
No!
Mommy.
Hey, Johnny.
Hey, hey, it's okay.
It's okay, you little rascal.
What are you gonna do, Frank?
- Put the gun down.
- Let him go.
Well, put the gun down.
I'll snap his neck.
Put the gun down now.
Time to die, Sullivan.
[OVER RADIO]
Time to die, son.
FRANK:
Run, Johnny, run!
Run, run, run!
Julia, you all right?
You all right?
[GUN COCKS]
I'm still here, Chief.
GORDO:
Mine. I got it. Mine.
JULIA:
Come on, Satch. Come on.
MAN: Come on, Satch.
JULIA: Come on, Johnny.
Round the horn, round the horn.
WOMAN 1:
Julia, one more. Keep them going.
WOMAN 2: Go, baby!
JULIA: Okay. Come on, Frank.
WOMAN 2: Frank!
- Come on. No batter, no batter, no batter.
WOMAN 2:
Come on, Frank! Yes!
The Benz! Not the Benz!
[CROWD GROANS]
God, not the Benz.
Not the Benz. Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
SATCH:
Hey, nice hit, Frank.
Way to go.
- You can afford it.
- Thank you very much.
SATCH:
Come on. Play ball.
- Let's play some ball.
GORDO: You'll pay for that.
Come on. No batter, no batter, no batter.
- Go get it, go get it. He's slow, he's old.
- Go, baby!
Come on, man.
JULIA:
Go, baby!
- Come on, Johnny.
- Bring me home, Chief.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[English - US - SDH]