[Rumbling]
[Electronic beeping]
[Guns clicking]
[Groaning]
[Sighing]
[Laughing]
Stop!
Hey, y'all
[Upbeat techno music playing]
Little bugger!
Not live rounds, Lara.
He's in real pain right now.
This is a major remodel.
This is a disaster.
Was it programmed to stop before it
took my head off?
Ah, well, that would be a no.
But you said make it more challenging,
so....
Hence, the live fire.
Live rounds again.
Poor Simon.
What has she done to you?
[Music stops]
Oh. Very funny.
I'm only trying to turn you into a lady.
And a lady should be modest.
Yes, a lady should be modest.
[Bells tolling]
MAN: Brothers and sisters...
today is the 1 5th of May...
the first day of the planetary alignment...
and we are still no nearer to discovering
the location of the key.
It seems...
we are running out of time.
This is not acceptable.
Mr. Powell,
your explanation for this, please?
I have no explanation.
Certainly no excuses.
Except to once again
respectfully remind the council...
that we are working from clues...
based on
ancient cosmological models...
predating Aristotle.
But I'm happy to announce
that we're almost ready.
And I am supremely confident...
that we will have our answer in time
for the relevant planetary alignment.
So, we will have possession
of the key in...
one week.
Yes, indeed. One week.
This is good news, Mr. Powell,
but remember...
we have only a single opportunity...
to retrieve the two halves of the triangle.
And if we fail...
we must wait another 5,000 years.
I don't know about you,
but that's more time...
than I am prepared to commit
to this enterprise.
We shall be ready.
Trust me.
-We're not.... We're not ready, are we?
-No.
Good morning, Lara.
And what a beautiful morning it is.
Back to work, I'm afraid.
It's adventure time.
Egypt again.
It's nothing but pyramids and sand.
I know. Gets everywhere. In the cracks.
Spanish galleon?
Do you know what day it is, Hillary?
Yes, of course.
The 15th.
And that is never a good day.
I miss you, Daddy.
I wish we could get back the time
that was stolen from us.
LARA: My father
would loved to have seen this.
Tonight Pluto and Neptune
align with Uranus.
It's the first stage of the alignment
of all nine planets...
culminating in a full solar eclipse.
It only happens once every 5,000 years.
When is the eclipse?
One week from today.
But there is plenty to look out for
until then.
Incredible.
[Groaning]
I wish you could remember her.
She loved you so much.
Mummy!
I wish I could remember her, too.
-I still have you, Daddy.
-Yes, you do.
The exact alignment of the planets
necessary to activate the triangle...
only occurs once every 5,000 years.
But that will prove to be
just long enough...
for little Lara Croft to grow up...
and to find it.
[Clock ticking]
[Ticking]
[Ticking echoing]
Bryce!
Hello, fellas.
-How's business?
-Bryce!
Okay, okay. I'm coming. I'm coming.
We have 83 rooms.
Why can't you live in the house?
Well, I'm a free spirit, me.
Right.
What's that smell?
5:00 a.m. Let's go.
This had better be good.
It's a clock.
I found it last night. It was ticking.
Must be one of them ticking clocks, eh?
It was hidden in a secret room.
Bryce.
Don't start.
Well, Lara, it's a clock. It ticks.
It tells the time. It's wrong.
It started ticking...
last night during the first stage
of the alignment.
Oh.
Well, gonna need some coffee.
Okay, in we go.
Looks pretty ordinary to me.
Well, keep looking.
Your coffee, sir.
Decaf latte with non-fat milk.
Oh, champion. Steaming sump oil.
Wait. What did you do?
-I don't know. What did I do?
-Where is that?
I don't know.
I just took my hand off the fiber optics.
What is that?
-Oh, bugger!
-Bugger.
Screw 1 3 to quadrant four.
-Screw 14 to quadrant three.
-Oh, please.
It's my map,
so I know where they all came from.
It's camouflage.
Okay.
Hidden within.
What is that?
The All Seeing Eye.
Lot 1 21 , a Louis XV Ormolu
mounted bracket clock.
Showing on my left, £1 ,800,000.
£1 ,800,000. Thank you.
£1 ,800,000. £1 ,900,000.
£2,000,000. £2,000,000, now.
£2,1 00,000. £2,1 00,000, now.
£2,1 00,000.
Any advance on £2,1 00,000?
Any more?
£2,1 00,000. £2,200,000. Thank you, sir.
£2,200,000 now.
At £2,200,000. £2,300,000.
£2,300,000. £2,400,000.
Lady's bid, £2,400,000 now. £2,400,000.
Against you, sir. Two million five? No.
£2,400,000, then.
Lady's bid at £2,400,000.
£2,500,000.
In a new place at £2,500,000.
Any more at £2,500,000?
Sold.
Lara, my dear.
-Mr. Wilson.
-Let's go into my study.
Let me take that for you.
Lara Croft. I don't believe it.
-I'll just be a minute.
-Hi.
You still pretending to be
a photojournalist?
You know, I think it's really cool
that you still have a day job...
even though it's obviously just for show.
So, Alex, are you still pretending
to be an archaeologist?
Do we always have to fight like this?
I mean, maybe we don't.
-Maybe we do.
-Why?
-You stole my prayer wheels.
-Stole? Stole?
From you? You know, that's funny.
You know, it's....
It's not like you ever really owned them
or anything.
Hey, you're the tomb raider.
MAN: Mr. West, we are ready for you.
Oh, I think your clients need you.
Go ahead. You're wanted on the floor.
After all, as you once said
so memorably, "It's all just a business."
Right? So go do business.
Go.
Lara?
Lara, this is a unique object.
Only one of the dials is working.
It glows, like the eye, lesser.
But it seems to be getting brighter.
And it's also running backwards...
like it's not so much keeping time,
but counting down to something.
-Yes.
-And look at the back.
It's as though it fits into something,
almost like a key.
Yes. Yes, fascinating.
Incredibly beautiful.
My father once told me...
of a magical triangle
stamped with the All Seeing Eye.
He said it gave its possessor
extraordinary power...
the power to control time.
He called it the Triangle of Light.
Have you heard of it?
No. No, I haven't.
He always steered his own course,
your father.
He was a great man.
Would you like some port?
-It's really very fine.
-No.
I can't help you, Lara.
This clock truly is mystery.
[Phone ringing]
-Hello.
-Lara?
Hello, it's Mr. Wilson.
Yes. Well, I....
You see, I had a second thought...
about that clock.
There is a man
who may be able to help you.
l gave him your number.
His name is Manfred Powell.
You should see him.
Thank you. I will.
-Goodbye, Lara.
-You take care.
Thank you.
[Splattering]
Bugger.
Forgive me.
Lady Croft.
-Ah, Mr. Powell.
-Oh, no, no, no. Good heavens, no.
I'm actually his associate, Mr. Pimms.
-Mr. Pimms?
-Yeah, like the beverage.
[Soft instrumental music playing]
Yeah, she's here.
What does Mr. Powell do?
He's a lawyer. I'm his law clerk.
It's a fairly recent appointment,
but enjoying it, all the varied work.
-A lawyer.
-Isn't it obvious?
Lady Croft, my pleasure.
-Manfred Powell, Q.C.
-Good morning.
I believe you are quite an authority
on things ancient and mythological.
Well, I travel.
No, no, Mr. Wilson said
you were quite the archaeologist.
Please.
Oh, he's very sweet.
He knew your father, I believe.
Yes, they were great friends.
I had the honor of meeting him
myself once, in Venice.
I was so sorry to hear about his death.
This is the clock I spoke of.
Very interesting.
It's a shame
you only brought photographs.
Nevertheless, it is fascinating.
You said it started ticking the night
of the alignment.
Yes.
-You said you were a lawyer?
-Yes.
And the study of clocks is a hobby?
This is an obsession.
Really my specialty.
My practice centers around antiquities.
But the origin of this clock...
completely eludes me.
I think I've never seen anything quite
so beautiful...
that I know so little about.
This is a pleasurable torment.
My ignorance amuses me.
"My ignorance amuses me."
Yes, well, I've always found
your ignorance quite amusing.
Powell, however, is not ignorant.
He's a liar.
[Classical instrumental music]
-Anything you need?
-No. Thank you, Hillary.
-Don't you stay up too late.
-I won't.
[Techno music playing]
[Humming]
[Chattering over radios]
MAN: [Over radio] Forward team,
wait for my command.
ln position awaiting your order.
[Electronic beeping]
[Alarm bleeping]
Bastards!
Bloody hell!
MAN: [Over radio] On the left.
On the left.
Come on, Simon!
Bugger!
[Alarms blaring]
BRYCE: Lara, Lara, are you there?
Pick up!
Lara, can you hear me? Are you okay?
l'm in the equipment room.
They're stealing my bloody clock.
I know. I saw them.
-You have to be my eyes.
-Are you armed?
After a fashion, yes.
All right. Three bad guys.
Number one standing by
the Aston Martin.
Right.
Bingo!
-Next.
-Okay, number two...
crouched by the McLaren.
Oh, bugger!
-Are you okay?
-I just found my car keys.
[Beeping]
[Engine revving]
[Car alarms beeping]
[Horns blaring]
You're done, mate. Nice one.
I think they've all gone.
Well, they got what they came for.
Sorry about that.
That's fine.
[Bells tolling]
Hello?
[Get Ur Freak On by
Missy Elliot playing]
What the hell happened here?
-Morning.
-Lady Lara Croft?
Yes. You have something for me?
I woke up this morning,
and I just hated everything.
Right. Thanks.
Who's Stribling,
Clive and Winterset then?
-Sounds like a bunch of lawyers.
-They are a bunch of lawyers.
-Well, I'll shut my face again.
-You are nosy.
I'm not nosy. I just saw the name.
It was a funny name.
I just asked her what the name was.
Lara?
It's from my father.
It was written before he died...
and delivered today
as per his instructions.
-Blimey!
-Holy....
"To see a world in a grain of sand...
"and a heaven in a wild flower...
"hold infinity in the palm of your hand...
"and eternity in an hour."
William Blake.
The All Seeing Eye.
"My darling daughter...
"l knew you'd figure this out.
"lf you are reading this letter,
l am no longer with you"...
and I miss you,
and love you always and forever.
It also means I have failed...
and must place an awful burden
on your shoulders.
"Lara, by now l am sure you will have
discovered the cIock I conceaIed."
The clock is the key, Lara.
"lt will unlock the hiding place of two
pieces of a sacred icon."
This is the magical triangle I told you
about when you were a little girl.
The Triangle of Light.
But it is no bedtime story.
"The triangle was forged from metal
found in the crater of a meteor...
"that had faIIen to Earth
at the exact moment...
"of the previous alignment
of the nine planets.
"The people of the light built a great city
in this crater...
"where they worshipped the triangle
for its ability to control time.
"lt gave its possessor a power that
could be used for good or great evil.
"An abuse of this power
led to the destruction of the city.
"To be sure no man would ever again
wield this power...
"they split the triangle into two pieces...
"and hid them
at opposite ends of the Earth."
"Lara, do you remember the jasmine
that only grows in one temple...
"along the ancient Khmer trail
in Cambodia?
"Find that,
and you will have found the entrance...
"to the Tomb of the Dancing Light...
"where the first half of the triangle
is hidden."
You must be there
at the exact moment...
of the second phase
of the planetary alignment.
"You must hurry.
You have very little time.
"And as the planets move
into alignment...
"the world will be in great danger...
"for the secret society
known as the IIIuminati...
"devious, dangerous men...
"who seek to fulfill an ancient prophecy
by reuniting the two halves...
"and attaining the triangle's awesome
and terrible powers.
"This you must prevent at all costs.
"So, Lara,
l am asking you to complete my work...
"to find and destroy
both halves of the triangle."
How are you going to get to Cambodia
and get the clock back in 1 5 hours?
I'll be calling in a favor.
-What kind of favor?
-Well, that is a secret.
If I told you, I'd have to kill you.
MAN: [On radio] Lady Croft,
are you on target? Over.
Right on target. Thank you, boys.
Over and out.
Mr. Powell.
How predictable.
Alex West.
What are you doing here?
[All chanting]
We have 72 minutes
to the next alignment.
We have to work faster.
Come on, guys!
ALEX: Come on, guys! Come on. Pull!
Pull! It's coming!
Good.
[Girl laughing]
So, any sign of Lady Croft?
Not yet.
Lara's overrated.
She's good, don't get me wrong...
but she's in it for the glory...
whereas I'm in it for the money.
Fortunately.
-Into the belly of the beast.
-And out of the demon's ass.
[Girl laughing]
Jasmine.
[Rumbling]
[Men talking]
Wow.
Remember, what we are looking for
is hidden not only in space...
but also in time.
The clock is the key.
My God.
"Return the iron
to the stone's embrace...
"the wheel of heaven will turn.
"Exhume the light
from its watery grave...
"to receive the gift of heaven...
"as you are condemned
to the depths of hell."
Right. Pretty much touch anything
and you get your head chopped off.
POWELL: We have two minutes,
Mr. West.
You're the tomb raider. Figure it out.
Tempus fugit.
Yes, "time flies."
ALEX: It's the swords!
Come on, guys. Get up here.
Give me a hand here.
That's it. Come on. Coming down.
I want them all down.
Take them,
carry them across the ladders.
Come on, guys. Let's hustle.
ALEX: All right.
Now slide them into the slots over there.
POWELL: We place the clock here
at the exact moment of alignment.
ALEX: Come on. Let's go! Move it!
Too slow, ladies, too slow. Come on.
-That's it.
-Count it down.
-The timing needs to be exact.
-No shit.
ALEX: 60 seconds to go.
59, 58, 57....
56...
55, 54, 53...
52, 51 ...
50 seconds.
LARA: Mr. Powell!
Cease fire! Hold your fire!
-Keep counting.
-You're making a big mistake!
41 , 40...
-39...
-Alex West.
-...38...
-Hey, Lara.
-...37....
-Tourist visa?
-No, I'm working.
-Lady Croft, tell me...
is there a good reason
why I just kept you alive?
Yes. That is not the true eye.
-This is the true eye.
-It's not, actually.
-It's a mirror image.
-Miss Croft...
I think you're trying to cheat me
out of my little ray of sunshine.
Why would I try and cheat you out
of anything now?
I need you to get the piece
so I can steal it from you later.
You're bluffing.
Julius, make a mental note.
Kill Miss Croft
if she attempts any such thing.
Yes, sir, Mr. Powell.
Well, we can do it my way...
or we can all come back in time
for the next alignment...
and you are welcome
to try and kill me, then.
In, oh, say another 5,000 years.
Twelve, eleven...
ten...
nine, eight...
seven, six, five...
four, three...
two, one...
zero.
Well, I guess she was right.
The log must pierce the urn.
Come on!
ALEX: It's slowing down.
It's never gonna make it.
No.
[Groaning]
Pure light, fire and water.
[Grunting]
[Creaking]
Croft!
[Groaning]
[Panicked murmuring]
Get the clock.
Got it.
[Growling]
Blast!
[Screeching]
ALEX: Hold it right there!
[Gun clocking]
Lara.
Give it up.
Are you going to shoot me, Alex?
[Speaking in Cambodian]
My phone is wet.
[Cell phone ringing]
POWELL: Yes?
Lady Croft, how are you?
Alive.
And kicking, I hope.
-And you?
-Superlative.
Of course, I digress.
You have my half of the triangle.
And you have my father's clock.
Listen, my dear. Without each other
we are quite useless at this point.
We should reevaluate our positions.
Like it or not,
you and I are in business together.
We should have a business meeting.
You mean you'd love to have
another opportunity to try and kill me.
Oh, that's harsh.
But perhaps. Wait and see.
Come to Venice, Via Dolorosa.
Wonderful. Bye then.
Harder.
MAN: [On TV] Here it comes.
Hide, everybody.
[Phone ringing]
Look out. It's some sort of machine.
LARA: Bryce, it's me.
-Hello?
-Bryce, it's Lara. l found the temple.
-Ran into Mr. PoweII.
-Did you get the clock?
No, but I got the first piece.
Oh, beautiful, smashing.
Seems I'm level pegging
with Mr. Powell.
Well, won't he just want to kill you now?
No, silly.
His problem is that he needs the piece
that I have.
Until then, I'm his new best friend.
What about the other haIf?
The final alignment...
is in 66 hours and 53 minutes,
and we've still got no idea...
where the second piece is hidden.
He's going to tell me
where the second piece is.
-He will?
-Bryce, trust me. Pack for Venice.
Pack for where? HeIIo? Lara?
Bye then.
[All chanting]
Drink.
Rest.
There's no rest for the wicked.
You got what you came for?
-I did, yes.
-Too bad.
Bad for the world.
The world is safe now.
Little bit safer, perhaps...
because you will go on.
Your father said you will never give up.
My father? You knew my father?
Now, drink.
Finish your tea.
It tastes quite bad, but it is good for you.
See?
[Bells tolling]
Good evening.
You're with the Illuminati.
Beg your pardon?
There's no such thing.
It's just a bedtime story.
Illuminati.
The people of the light.
Have you brought my triangle?
No, of course you haven't.
You've hidden it somewhere.
Well, you can keep the triangle
you have...
and I will keep your father's clock,
and we can be partners.
Who sits here?
We can be partners
and go for the big prize...
the Triangle of Light.
Yes, but who sits here?
It's an incredible dream,
an awesome power.
It could set right so many wrongs.
I don't think you sit here, do you?
I sit here...
on God's right hand, as it were.
In fact...
I now sit exactly where your father sat.
You're lying.
No. No, he mentored me in the order.
It was truly an honor.
I don't believe you.
My father was not with the Illuminati.
-He would have told me.
-He had a great many secrets.
Not from me.
Especially from you.
I know what you want, Lara.
Oh, I doubt it.
Another life with your father...
a second chance.
It'll be within my power to give.
The triangle gives its possessor...
the power of God...
to move back and forth through time,
undo the past.
Help me, and you will get
what I know you want...
to have your father returned to you.
And how do I know
once I gave you that piece...
that you wouldn't then just try to kill me?
Would it make it easier for you...
on more familiar ground,
if I killed you now?
Will you reconsider?
[Door banging]
[Speaking in Italian]
-Hello, Alex.
-I suppose you think...
I'm a greedy, unscrupulous sellout...
-and do about anything for money.
-Yes, that's right.
Well, the money bit's true, I guess.
Is it, Alex?
If you cross me,
we may not be able to remain friends.
[Sighing]
Always a pleasure.
[Groaning]
Now for a cold shower.
PIMMS: I think we're in big trouble.
-Hold this, will you?
-Thank you.
They.... They already think that we have
Lady Croft's piece of the triangle.
Yes. They think it's in that box
you're carrying right now.
Is it?
Why don't you worry
about something else?
Of course it's not.
I don't understand. What chance of
success do we have without the piece?
Zero. Don't dwell on it.
But....
Lady Croft.
What a nice surprise.
Thank you.
Now, time to save
the universe again then, is it?
Absolutely.
Are we sure she's really necessary?
Well, one tomb raider is good.
Two, better.
Me bum's gone to sleep again,
all down the left cheek.
Really? That's fascinating.
-How much longer?
-A few hours.
We have to take the last hour over land.
Helicopters won't fly
near the ruined city.
It's a dead zone.
We take all doggies.
Much-o U.S. greenback.
All doggies.
[Dogs whimpering]
[Speaking in Russian]
[Dog barking]
[Chattering in Russian over radio]
Welcome to the dead zone.
It's not a country. It's an ice cube!
MAN: Come on!
[Tone resonating]
All right. Let's go.
MAN: Go on, get it!
Holy shit.
It's a time storm. Time is broken here.
We must find the eye! All of you! Hurry!
We're running out of time! Hurry! Hurry!
[Dogs whimpering]
It's begun.
$50 says the piece is inside the sun.
[Screaming]
MAN: For God's sake, hurry! The eclipse
will be over in a few minutes!
Alex, give me the clock.
I know what to do.
Lara!
Has she got the piece?
[Dogs whimpering and howling]
We will now...
unite these two parts...
the past and the present.
At last, we of the Illuminati...
will control time
and fulfill the sacred promise...
to our ancestors.
-Soon, the entire world will bow--
-Enough of this twaddle.
Go on! Go on!
ALEX: Not quite what you hoped for,
Mr. Powell?
Lara...
I have a gut instinct about this.
After all, you are the daughter
of a genius.
Let me test my theory.
[Groaning]
You had to let him go.
No more bubbles.
You show me
how to complete the triangle...
we can change his fate.
If you deliver me the power of God,
I will spare him.
It's only a little trip back in time.
But I'm pretty sure you've figured out
the answer to the problem.
And then, of course,
there's the loss of your father.
I can change that.
You'd better be ready for this.
-Unhook your laser sight.
-Do it.
"To see a world in a grain of sand."
[Groaning]
Daddy?
Lara.
Is this real?
It is a crossing...
of my past and your present.
Why did you not tell me
about the Illuminati?
You were only a child.
You could have written in yourjournals.
-You never mentioned it, not once.
-Lara, I burst to tell you everything.
But in the fierceness
of my own battles...
I strove to tell you
only that which would inspire you...
and keep you safe.
I love you so much.
But I've missed you.
And I have missed you.
I know why you came here...
why you took the power of the light,
but this must not happen.
Why? Why can't we use the power
just this once?
Why can't you stay?
We can't change time.
But time was stolen from us...
and it's not fair.
No, it's not fair.
But you have stolen time itself...
and you must give it back.
You must destroy the triangle.
Suddenly I feel so alone.
You're never alone. I am with you
always, just as I've always been.
No.
Move out!
[Groaning]
Lara.
Wait!
Your father begged for his life...
when we caught him betraying us.
He pleaded like a baby.
Surrender.
Never.
He seemed particularly concerned
that I shouldn't take this.
ALEX: Lara, no!
The place is coming down!
-This is insane!
-Get them out of here.
You just hurry.
[Chuckling]
There you go...
safe and sound.
No guns.
[Humming]
[Clattering]
Oh, my God!
Quiet.
[Bird chirping]
What?
[Mechanical whirring]