Look around you.
Just look around you.
Have you worked out
what we're looking for?
Correct.
The answer is...
This programme, "The Brain",
is sadly the last in the series,
and can be found
at the very end of your textbook.
Please ensure you have
your copybook at hand,
as you'll be asked to take down
notes from the screen
at various points
throughout the programme.
What is the brain?
If you don' t know that,
you've forgotten how to think.
You see, the brain is many things.
It's a calculator,
a dictionary, a battery,
a camera, a TV and radio.
In fact, it's all of these things
and more.
Pretty smart for something that
resembles a garden cauliflower.
The brain is basically
a wrinkled bag of skin
filled with warm water,
veins and thought muscles.
Think of it as a kind of modified
heart, only with a mind or brain.
It sits atop the body issuing its
orders to the various components,
controlling our walking
and jumping,
eye-to-eye coordination.
Regulating our size.
In fact, pretty much everything
we do is governed by its decisions.
It's a right old bossyboots!
The opposite of the brain
is probably the bum.
It's nowhere near as intelligent
as the brain.
It doesn' t have to be,
as it only needs to make
very basic calculations.
An experiment was carried out
to illustrate the effects
of brainial stimulation.
For this experiment,
we're going to use a small area
of our subject's brain
known as the broab.
Using a hand drill,
a small hole is formed
at the base of Nigel's skull.
You don' t have to be a brain
surgeon operate on the brain,
but you will need some training.
After all, you'd hardly call out
a hairdresser to fix a carburettor.
Now a thin probe is slowly inserted
into our hole
so that the probe probes the broab.
Observe the reaction and note
the results down in your copybook.
At first, Nigel appears
to experience some discomfort.
But this soon gives way
to a feeling of elation.
And as we force the probe deeper,
it induces this reaction.
A feeling of wanting to sneeze
but being completely unable to.
If you're trying this experiment
for yourself,
be aware that the effect
is often permanent.
Write that down
in your copybook now.
These days most of us know
someone who's had an EBE,
an electronic brain enhancement.
People get it done
for a variety of reasons.
For example,
if you want to read faster.
Or to think up funnier jokes
in social situations.
She seems to like it.
Tempting, isn' t it?
But just take a look
at this young man.
Don' t be a fool.
It's not just humans or animals
that have a brain.
Almost every living being has one.
If we look inside one of these
peas, we can see its tiny brain.
Look at the little ridges,
down which the pea sends
electrical impulses to other peas,
determining its daily duties
and its status in the pod.
Let's pop it back inside now,
and leave the pea be.
An experiment was carried out
to illustrate the brain's
powers of perception.
First, a human brain is lowered
gently into a solution of brine.
Next, we connect a 9-volt battery,
so an electrical current flows
through the brine into the brain.
Finally, a telephone line
is installed...
..and the experiment can begin.
We're going to set the brain
a simple problem,
so have your pen and paper ready.
Brain, how many nuts
are there in this jar?
The brain sets to work
until reaches its answer.
(PHONE RINGS)
Hello?
It's the brain.
Can I have your answer, please?
OK.
Hi.
Thank you. Goodbye.
Here's the brain's estimation.
54.
Let's see if the brain is right.
Exactly...
54 nuts.
Well done.
As a reward, the brain is fed.
What a clever little brain.
We hope you enjoyed this series
as much we enjoyed making it.
And so, we raise a glass to you,
the viewer.
There's no need to open
the champagne now.
Perhaps we'll save it
for the next series.
Until then, take care of yourself.
And remember, look around you.