You're watching Two.
And now for our weekly look at the
world of science and technology -
Look Around You.
On tonight's programme...
We'll be lifting the lid
on the toilet of the future.
We'll be looking at what
Pam gets up to while she's asleep.
And finding out which one of us
will be having plastic surgery
right here on the programme.
That's all on tonight's
healthy edition of Look Around You.
♪ Look Around You ♪
Hello, and welcome
to Look Around You.
Tonight's programme is all about the
most important thing in your life,
so important that without it
you wouldn't even be watching
this programme.
I'm talking, of course,
about your health.
Our healths have improved radically
over the past few decades.
In fact, if current trends continue
then by 2010 the average life
expectancy will be 400 years.
With most of us reaching puberty
at around the age of 80.
It's all thanks to advances
in medical science
and British technology
is leading the field
with familiar products
like asthma cigarettes,
the diarrhoea machine,
and, of course,
the controversial Psuicide Spray.
Thanks, Pam(!) But the next big
thing in modern healthcare
comes not from Britain or America,
or even Norway,
but from China.
So please welcome
the future of healthcare, Medibot.
'Medibot!'
Medibot is the only robot in the
world qualified to perform surgery
- and being a robot...
-'Medibot!'
Hello - he can work faster and more
accurately than a human surgeon.
So let's meet the man who works
with Medibot on a daily basis,
Dr Franklin Fu.
- Welcome to Look Around You.
- Hello.
You're going to be giving us
a demonstration of the Medibot.
Yes, I'm going to be performing
plastic surgery on Jack's face.
Now, I'm sure that
our female viewers are thinking,
and probably
one or two male viewers, as well,
how on earth
could you improve on this?
Well, I certainly try.
Through the course of my work
I have studied
hundreds and hundreds of faces,
analysing the proportions
and sizes of features
and it is this information
I will be applying to Jack
as I try to create
the optimum male face.
So Jack should end up
with perfect looks?
Well, I hope so.
And Dr Fu will be
assisted by Medibot...
-'Medibot!'
- Oh, I think he likes me.
- (Laughter)
- You better move round there, Jack.
Now, Doctor, Medibot is clearly
a pretty serious piece of kit.
Presumably he's quite expensive?
Oh, yes. Medibot is very expensive.
In fact, there are only
four Medibots in the world.
This one here and the other three
belong to Tony Curtis.
So just how good is the Medibot?
Is he as good as a human surgeon?
(Dr Fu) Oh, I'd say better.
He's so versatile.
He can do anything,
from complex surgery to, er...
taking a urine sample.
I won't keep you any longer.
Best of luck with the operation.
'Medibot!'
We'll be following Jack's progress
throughout the rest of the show.
Over the past few months
our newspapers have been filled with
horrifying accounts of a new disease
that has been spreading
at an alarming rate.
It's a disease for which
at present there is no known cure.
And it's all the more terrifying
because scientists don't even know
what causes the disease.
I'm talking, of course,
about geodermic granititis,
more commonly known as Cobbles.
(♪ Sad music)
Cobbles is a wicked disease
that strikes indiscriminately,
attacking
the central nervous system,
fooling it into calcifying
bodily tissue,
eventually turning the victim into
what is essentially a pile of rocks.
Cobbles sufferers try to lead
as normal a life as possible
but it's hard.
Extreme mental anguish,
coupled with almost insurmountable
physical difficulties
can make life intolerable.
But now there may be
a light at the end of the tunnel
because a British doctor claims to
have made an important breakthrough.
And he joins us in the studio now -
Dr Phillip Lavender.
Doctor, thank you
for coming on the show.
Thank you for having me on the show.
Now, you're a sufferer from
the condition yourself, aren't you?
- I am, Pam, yes.
- How long have you had Cobbles?
Just over two years now.
But you've been very busy,
haven't you?
I've spent most of that time
trying to find a cure
with my research team.
- And you're going to show us it?
- Certainly.
Now, Doctor, what exactly is it?
We've produced what is
essentially a body cream
which rejuvenates dormant tissue
and skin cells
and aims to reverse
the damaging effects of Cobbles.
I see. And what does it contain?
Well, cream, potassium, nitrates,
potassium nitrates
- and nitrate of potassiate nitrate.
- OK.
We're going to demonstrate
how it works.
That's right, Pam. So if you take
a small amount with your fingers.
- OK.
And just start applying that to me.
OK, where shall I put it?
- Er, no, not there.
- Oh, sorry.
Try higher up.
- Not in my mouth!
- I'm so sorry.
Let me just... Whoops.
Sorry, I'll just...
Right. Erm...
- So how about...there?
- Yeah, that's OK.
And so you can see
the cream is now working its way
slowly through my semi-porous rock.
Right. Now, just before
the programme started
we applied some cream to a small
area of Dr Lavender's body
so that we could see its effect.
That's right, Pam,
and if we just look,
it's just round here, by my bottom.
- (Pam) That is remarkable.
- (Dr Lavender chuckles)
We want to do this
for the entire body
but at the moment the cream only
lasts for about 15 minutes
before the skin
starts to become rock again,
so this is something
we need to work on.
Well, Doctor, we all hope you find a
cure for your terrible affliction.
Well, it's not all bad.
At least we can fly. Goodbye.
Well, I'm now in the special
operating area of the studio
with Dr Fu and Medibot,
the robotic surgeon.
Medibot's just about to perform
plastic surgery on Jack's face
under the supervision of Dr Fu here.
Doctor, what's happening now?
At the moment I'm in the final
stages of the preparation,
and, er, I'm about
to load Medibot up with
a very special
plastic surgery computer program.
So, Doctor, tell us,
how will Medibot be working tonight?
- (Computer program loading)
- Medibot will use a powerful laser
to carry out most of the remodelling
of Jack's features.
- I see.
- Medibot?
-'Medibot!'
- Please configure laser settings.
And how's our patient doing?
- I could do with a pint.
- Medibot?
-'Medibot!'
- Prepare the anaesthetic.
Doctor, may I ask, what is it you
keep putting into Medibot's mouth?
Oh, these are just hundreds
and thousands, he loves them.
'Medibot!'
OK, I think Jack
is ready to go under now
so if you would all like to say
goodbye - I mean, good night.
(Laughs) Just joking.
- Well, best of luck, old chap.
- Thanks, Pete.
- Nice knowing you, Jack.
- Thanks, Pealy(!)
- You look after our boy.
- Of course.
- Hope you're all right, Jack.
- I'll be fine. Bye-bye. Bye.
Bye-bye.
So, Jack, if you would like
to lie very still.
Very, very still. Thank you.
- Medibot!
-'Medibot!'
Administer the anaesthetic, please.
Well, sweet dreams, Jack,
and we'll be checking back on him
throughout the programme.
First you sense it -
feel it inside -
then you realise,
he's looking at you.
Go on, look at him.
Now he's waving at you -
he likes you.
Go on, smile at him. Smile.
But you can't
because of your disgusting teeth.
But now there's no need
to be ashamed of your smile.
Brush with Jenny
and you'll soon see the difference.
Jenny is gentle, mild
and kind to your teeth.
Now, ready for that smile?
Say goodbye to disgusting teeth
with Jenny, the mild toothpaste.
And now, new Lenny for men.
These days we're bombarded
with adverts for new toothpaste,
mouthwash or dental loaf.
In the last year a staggering
50 new brands of toothpaste
have been launched
in Great Britain alone.
But do these products
really do anything?
Well, new research has shown
that most of these
are no better than brushing with
good old-fashioned soap and water.
So it might be worth
investing in one of these -
an electric toothbrush
with a difference.
If you look at its head you'll see
that it doesn't have any bristles.
Well, because this toothbrush
doesn't use toothpaste
to clean your teeth but electricity.
The powerful electric current
not only burns away plaque
but it hardens the tooth enamel
making your teeth
up to 120 times stronger.
So let's put it to
the Look Around You test.
OK, then, Peter. Plug me in.
OK.
- OK?
- Yeah.
- Oh, I think you switched it off.
- Oh.
- (Electrical hum)
- And off we go.
Cleaning your teeth like this
is actually quite painful
but who cares when it leaves
your teeth strong enough
to be able to do this?
However, there is one side effect.
(Quickly) Because the current also
passes through your vocal cords
it can affect your speech patterns
so it won't be in the shops yet.
But we'll keep you posted.
- You still hungry, Pealy?
- Mm, I might finish the rest now.
- Medibot.
-'Medibot!'
Increase intensity by 2.4 per cent.
As you can see, Jack's plastic
surgery operation is in full swing.
- Medibot.
-'Medibot!'
Make an incision into the cartilage
just above the bridge.
Doctor, sorry to disturb you
but can you tell me,
how's the operation going?
Pretty good.
At the moment we are stripping away
the extraneous tissue
from Jack's face,
so hopefully we will be on course
to finishing in time.
And how's your assistant?
Oh, Medibot? He's doing a great job.
Aren't you, Medibot?
'Medibot!'
Now, I've heard that this Medibot
has a special, secret talent.
Oh, yes, er... Erm, I found out
that he can play the mouth organ.
- Really?
- Yes. Listen to this.
- (Plays random notes)
- That's great.
No, er, sorry, it's the wrong
way round. Here we go.
(♪ Chirpy tune)
(Laughing)
He's so... He gets me all the time.
Of legend told, brave lady of old
would sleep all night and day
With rump so soft and, oh, so oft
upon bed of feather and hay
So lady brave to you I say,
have a lovely sleep, my darling.
Have a lovely, lovely sleep...
my darling.
Sleep well.
- Good night.
- (Alarm clock ringing)
(Ringing stops)
Ah, 40 winks - sheer bliss.
You know, we spend almost
30 per cent of our lives asleep
yet we only know about 20 per cent
of what is happening to us
during this state.
In fact, scientists
are only about 10 per cent sure
as to why humans sleep at all.
So what does go on
when the lights go out?
Here at the National Sleep Research
Centre in St St Johnn's,
some fascinating studies
are being done
to try and solve
some of the mysteries of sleep.
Professor Keith Craven
is the Institute's director.
The Centre's been running
for about 140 years now.
It began life under the patronage
of Queen Victoria
but of course in those days
it wasn't a sleep institute
it was a sanctuary
for elephants and butterflies.
(Pam) At any one time there are
up to 20 full-time volunteers
who allow their sleeping behaviour
and even their dreams
to be monitored and analysed
by Professor Craven's research team.
One of the patients, Michael,
is wired up to a machine
called a Somnascope
which allows scientists to actually
watch dreams as they happen.
This is an intriguing piece
of equipment.
Can you tell us about
what we're looking at here?
Certainly, Pam.
This is one of
Michael's recurring dreams,
we call it the Montgomery Dream.
In it he sees himself as the
character of Montgomery the butler.
Er, Montgomery is about to
serve breakfast to his master
but suddenly has an urge
to eat all the jam.
And in a moment the mistress
of the house is going to come in -
there she is - and she gives him
a jolly good telling off.
Put that jam down at once!
It's the master's.
You know what this means?
- (Chuckles)
- You little turd!
Professor, what can we learn
from watching dreams?
Well, their hopes, their fears,
their sexual desires,
their worries, er...
Things that might not be apparent
on the surface.
Stop eating that jam,
you little shit!
(Pam) Professor Craven has an
extensive library of people's dreams
all captured on video cassette.
So, Professor,
what are we going to look at now?
Well, Pam, you're privileged,
if I may say so myself,
to watch one of my own dreams.
- Oh, thank you.
- Yes.
We were particularly happy with it
because it's a very clear recording.
OK, well let's take a look at it.
(♪ Gentle piano)
Craven! Craven?! Chapter nine!
Read!
(Gibbers)
What's the matter with you,
you filthy fool?
Idiot! Pidiot! Pridiot!
Peroxamidiot!
Cabbage hall idiot investment bond!
(Sobbing)
(Baby crying, echoing)
Where's my pipe?
You're an embarrassment, boy!
You've embarrassed the pipe!
(Craven moaning)
- Hello.
- (Distorted voice) Hello!
Do you like my perfume?
- (Craven) Mmm.
- (Woman moans in ecstasy)
(Both moaning)
I had that one last night.
Hola? Flamingo.
(Pam) Our unconscious minds
are actually extremely active
and Professor Craven's team
have been developing new ways
of harnessing the brain's powers
while we're asleep.
Well, you've seen just a fraction
of some of the work we're doing
here at the Institute.
And perhaps you might like
to be a volunteer
in one of our latest projects?
Of course,
but what would it involve?
It would involve driving
this motor car
at high speed around the test track.
- That looks like fun.
- But you will be fast asleep.
Hm, I might have known
there had to be a catch.
I'd better get on with my training
but I'm beginning to wish I'd never
got out of bed this morning.
(Quickly) You can see how Pam got on
at the end of the programme.
But now let's see
how Jack's plastic surgery is going.
- Doctor, what's happening?
- We're at the end now.
Just finishing off.
That was quick.
And how's the patient?
You can ask him yourself,
he's awake.
Jack?
- Mm?
- How are you feeling?
My face feels a bit numb
but I'm all right, thanks, Pam.
Well, why don't we, er...er, clean
him up so we can all take a look?
I can't wait.
Medibot,
give me some tissues, please.
'Medibot!'
While Jack's getting cleaned up,
let's remind ourselves
of what he used to look like
with this special report
from Loorizons,
the toilet industry's
annual exhibition in Bath.
(♪ Bleeping electronica)
(Jack) To the germs in your home
your toilet is like Las Vegas.
If you think about it,
when you use the toilet
you're leaving a meal
for millions of hungry germs
and that's not a nice thought.
There are dozens of products
on the market these days,
all promising to destroy germs,
from the bleach pill
to the toilet tarvunty.
But none of them
are 100 per cent effective.
But now there's a new British
invention which may be the answer
and here it is.
It's called the Sani-sac
and as you can see
it takes its inspiration
from the good old tea bag.
However, inside is not tea
but coffee.
Coffee has been used for centuries
as a powerful sterilising agent
which is why
most men normally drink tea.
So let's see the Sani-sac in action.
You just pop your Sani-sac
into the top of your cistern,
very simple, there it is.
Give your loo a good flush...
and now your toilet's so clean
you can even drink out of it.
Ahh.
(Quickly) The final of our Look
Around You Invention of the Year
is at the end of the series
and one winner will win this trophy
presented by His Royal Highness
Sir Prince Charles.
So that's certainly something
to look forward to.
And in honour of his remarkable
achievement against such adversity
the invention
we're putting forward this week
is the anti-cobbling cream,
created by Dr Phillip Lavender.
- (Lavender) Hello again.
- Congratulations, Doctor.
- Thank you very much indeed.
- And here's your rosette.
Ah, thank you, Pealy.
Ooh. (Chuckles)
And what a very quick voice
you've got. Goodbye.
Now it's the moment
we've all been waiting for
because it's time to unveil
Jack Morgan's brand-new face.
Doctor, how do you think
you've done?
Er, pretty good, Pete.
I think me and Medibot
have done a good job.
Don't you think, Medibot?
'Medibot!'
Let's remind ourselves
of what Jack looked like
before he went under the laser.
There he is.
So, Doctor, if you'd like to get
ready to do the honours.
- (Drum roll)
- (Jack) I hope he hasn't ruined me.
So let's all now take a look
at the brand-new Jack Morgan!
Well?
I love it.
I love it. I love it!
Jack, it's amazing.
You're absolutely gorgeous.
(Jack) Thanks, Pealy. I love it!
- I love it.
- Jack, you look amazing.
Doctor, I love it. I love it.
- Don't thank me, thank Medibot.
- Thanks, Medibot.
Give him some
hundreds and thousands.
- There we are. Good boy.
-'Medibot!'
What really sets it off is the tusk.
Unbelievable. I really love it.
Well, you've got to have it changed
back before next week's show.
Oh! But I love it.
That's all we've got
time for tonight.
Thank you to all our guests
for taking part -
to Dr Phillip Lavender,
to Medibot...
-'Medibot!'
- ..and, of course, Dr Fu.
Thanks, Doctor.
Thoctor.
We'll be back at the same time
next week
to give you a ringside seat
to the future of sport,
so don't miss it.
So in the meantime - what
a poseur - take care of yourself
and remember,
wherever you are, whatever you do...
-'Medibot!'
- (All) Look around you!
- (♪ Theme tune)
- Wow, absolutely...
But this is...
..I never though I'd look like this.
Good luck, Pam.
♪ Look Around You ♪
(Peter) If you'd like to find out
more information about Cobbles
you can pick up a leaflet from
your GP or local quarry, priced 1p.
'Medibot!'