Look around you.
Just look around you.
There.
Now take a closer look.
Have you worked out
what we're looking for?
Correct. The answer is...
This programme, "Calcium",
follows last week's module,
and will complete part one
of your textbook,
which accompanies this series.
Please ensure that you have
your copybook at hand,
as you'll be asked to take down
notes from the screen
at various points
throughout the programme.
Calcium.
You may know it as "Ginny"
or "Ninny", or "Peter's Peg".
But whatever you call it,
calcium, valency 1,
atomic weight 44,
is one of the most important
elements known to mankind.
As we have seen, calcium
occurs naturally within the tooth.
Thus, man's very existence
is inextricably linked
to the white element.
Without calcium, man would be
unable to process foods
and would starve.
In this programme, we will attempt
to show the many uses of calcium,
as well as a number of experiments.
An experiment was carried out
to ascertain whether calcium
is soluble in water.
First, a quantity of calcium
was obtained.
Using a mortar and pestle, the
calcium is ground into a fine dust.
The chalky dust
is poured into a beaker.
Next, the beaker is placed
under a running tap.
You can use distilled water,
but be aware of the cost.
The calcium-water mixture
is agitated
using a glass rod or pencil.
It is then allowed
to settle for a while.
So, is calcium soluble?
Look closely
before making your decision.
Have you observed the chalky
deposit at the base of the beaker?
If you have, then you'll have
reached the conclusion that...
There is a reason for this.
Can you work out what it is?
Correct.
If calcium were soluble, our teeth
would be open to corrosion
through daily contact with saliva.
Again, man would be unable
to process foods
and would starve.
Here is a model
of a calcium molecule.
Do you recognise the triple helix?
If you do, write it down.
The calcium molecule is built
on a semi-permanent structure
of four electrons
supporting three protons.
The protons feed
electrical information
to the core of the molecule,
where we find the central atom,
or "queen atom".
Were the queen atom
to leave the molecule, or "nest",
the effects would be disastrous,
as the entire structure
would come tumbling down.
This is known as
the Helvetica Scenario.
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
Luckily, Helvetica
is a very, very rare occurrence.
The Staffordshire Downs,
200 square miles
of rolling countryside.
It's here, amongst the jewel
of the north-west,
that we can observe
calcium in action.
Holdwick Park Refinery
has been producing industrial
strength calcium for over 20 years.
Chances are, if you've ever
written with a calcium nib,
or peered through a calcium lens,
they probably came from Holdwick.
Let's step inside.
Have your copybooks ready.
Every day, six tons of discarded
teeth and bones are brought here.
They're collected from calcic
drop-off points around Britain.
You may have seen one
in your town or village.
Because calcium perspires,
by the time it reaches Holdwick,
there's a lot of water
to be removed.
The teeth and bones
are poured into giant canisters,
and any excess run-off
is filtered away.
The dried calcium is then
pumped along these pipes.
When it reaches this trough,
a kind of glorified Bestal Heim,
it's bombarded with millions
and millions of caesium atoms.
This process compresses
the calcium into a viscous paste.
The calcic paste
is then heated in giant ovens
to 12,000 BC
before being left to cool.
From six tons of raw material,
and nearly 900 man hours later,
here are the results:
some twelve ounces
of pure industrial calcium.
This is then stored
in an underground lead chamber
to prevent the possibility
of Helvetica.
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
Now let's look at some of the ways
in which calcium is used.
Have your pen and paper ready.
Calcium can be used
to make powerful adhesives.
It's also used
as a strengthening agent
in bridges...
..windows...
..and was pivotal in the
development of Imsimil Berati-Lahn.
(BUZZES)
Calcium also occurs naturally
in liquid form.
You'll know it as milk.
In the Jewish religion,
it is forbidden to eat
milk and meat at the same meal.
Foods that contain dairy products
are referred to as "milchig".
Milchig.
Write that in your copybook now.
An experiment was carried out
to determine whether calcium
is a conductor of electricity.
First, a simple electrical circuit
is constructed.
The negative terminal
of a 9-volt battery
is connected to one end
of a Bestal Heim plate.
The other end of the Bestal Heim
is connected via an electrical lamp
to the positive terminal.
Now for the calcium.
A quantity is gently poured
into the Bestal Heim,
making sure that it forms
an unbroken line
between the negative and
positive end of the Bestal Heim.
If calcium conducts electricity,
the circuit will become complete
and the lamp will light.
Sadly, the lamp does not light.
From the results of this
experiment, we can conclude that...
Now let's see what happens
when we introduce
some sodium chloride.
You'll recognise it as common salt.
Let's take a look at the lamp now.
The calcium has reacted
with the sodium chloride
to produce calcium chloride.
Because calcium chloride is a
conductor, the little lamp lights.
Small quantities of Thomason's oil,
segnomin, are also produced.
Little wonder that calcium chloride
is used to power amplifiers
for electric guitars.
When calcium is burned,
calcium oxide is released
as a vapour.
Although not toxic,
if inhaled, this vapour can cause
temporary bodily paralysis.
For centuries magicians have used
calcium to simulate levitation.
This principle can be demonstrated
in the laboratory.
An experiment was carried out
to observe the effects
of helium gas upon calcium.
A pyramid of powdered calcium
is formed upon a work surface.
Next, an ordinary ping-pong ball
is placed carefully
on top of the pyramid.
Now we mark the mid-point.
Then helium gas is released
in the vicinity of the pyramid.
As our starting pressure,
we're using Cinderford's constant
of 2.5 quorums per second.
Observe the reaction and note
the results down in your copybook.
The pyramid of powdered calcium
has disappeared. Or has it?
The calcium seems to have moved
some eight inches away
from its original location.
Eight inches.
So, what's keeping
the ping-pong ball aloft?
Surprisingly, the pyramid
of powdered calcium is still there.
Only its image has moved.
This phenomenon is known as
Calcic Image Misplacement, or CIM.
Turn off the helium supply
and the image of the pyramid
of powdered calcium
is reunited with the actual pyramid
of powdered calcium.
Now let's see what happens
when we increase the flow
of helium by a factor of 5 qps.
The pyramid's image
fades as before.
This time it reappears
some 11.5 inches away.
11.5. Write that down.
Now we try a factor of 7.
This time,
the image of the calcic pyramid
appears over 500 miles away.
We've talked a lot about calcium
atomic weight 44.
But what of its sister element,
calcium atomic weight 42,
or intelligent calcium?
Intelligent calcium
is not intelligent in the sense
that you or I are intelligent,
but intelligent
in that it is sentient,
ie, it is aware of itself
and its surroundings.
In the laboratory,
scientists can communicate
with intelligent calcium
using a REMS Oscillating Converter.
The REMS measures
tiny chemical impulses
from within samples
of intelligent calcium.
An experiment was carried out
to demonstrate the cognitive
properties of intelligent calcium.
The REMS is connected
via its two thin probes
to the sample
of intelligent calcium.
Once the microphone is in place,
we turn on the REMS.
Get ready to take down
readings from the screen.
The scientist issues
interrogative statements
to the intelligent calcium
through the REMS,
which measures its response.
What is your atomic weight?
It can take a few moments
for the sample to respond.
The scientist repeats the question.
What is your atomic weight?
There we are. F...
O...
R...
T...
Y...
W...
O.
Forty-two.
Where are you?
I... N...
A...
T... E...
S... T...
T... U...
B... E.
In a test tube.
How do you feel?
C...
O...
L...
D.
Cold.
Now watch what happens
when we deprive
the intelligent calcium of oxygen.
The intelligent calcium
is completely neutralised.
Note that down
in your copybook now.
Over the course of this module,
we've learned a lot
about the nature,
manufacture
and uses of the white element.
But remember,
whether you're at home,
in school, or just out and about,
whatever you do,
never give a gypsy calcium.
Now hand in your copybooks
to your teacher or head of class.
In the next programme,
we will look at champagne.