Look around you.
Just look around you.
Have you worked out
what we're looking for?
Correct. The answer is...
This programme, "Ghosts",
is discussed in chapter 15
of your textbook,
which accompanies this series.
Please ensure you have
your copybook at hand,
as you'll be asked to take down
notes from the screen
at various points
throughout the programme.
Ghosts.
You may know them
as ghouls or phantoms,
or demons, or spirits,
or spirims, or spictrims.
From the sightings of the
headless spirit of King Henry VIII
to the poltergeist activity
of the ghost of Sir Ian Whitaker,
former General Secretary
of the TGWU,
ghosts are all around us.
But there's no need
to be scared of ghosts.
- (SCREAMS)
- It's a very childish attitude,
as the majority of them
are quite harmless.
This spirit is helping a girl
with her homework,
while this one is mending
its master's caravan.
Most of us are interested
in the spirit world,
and if we're not reading about it
in popular magazines,
we're paying a visit
to our local medium.
They usually have
something interesting to say.
Are you still making that lovely
onion soup for yourself, dear?
An experiment was carried out
to produce
a visualisation of a spirit.
In order to visualise, we'll
be using this piece of equipment,
a Gloriette 80 Materialiser,
a complex arrangement
of diodes, marbles and valves
which enables us to make
visual contact with the dead.
The machine is turned on,
and then primed
by inserting the crucifix.
(WHIRRING)
A candle is placed
on a map of Cornwall
and the scientist
begins his incantation.
Make sure you note it down.
Emarf wodniw eht gnitsud
saw aniram.
Emarf wodniw eht...
There's our spirit.
He appears to be in some distress.
Perhaps he's missing colleagues
or loved ones back at home.
He may even be missing you.
Do you know this man?
(GROWLS)
Now let's see what a ghost can do
under controlled conditions.
Can a spirit pass through
a solid surface?
Evidently, yes.
Drink a glass of orange squash?
Thirsty work. How about
trying on this hat for size?
It fits!
- (GLASS SMASHES)
- If the ghost misbehaves,
we administer
a strong electric current.
Note that down
in your copybook now.
Not all ghosts
are of living things.
This roll of sticky tape,
for instance, is a ghost.
So is this van.
Sometimes,
when a ghost materialises,
it leaves behind a physical
residue, known as ectoplasm.
It's perfectly safe to eat.
In fact many people have likened
the taste to that of pigs' milk.
One way in which ghosts
are different from man
is that they can' t whistle.
Try as they might, the most they
can muster is a rather feeble hiss.
Perhaps it's because
their lips are transparent
and their tongues are see-through.
But despite our differences,
man and ghost
can forge a successful partnership.
Let's look at this phenomenon
more closely,
as we step inside
the haunted laboratory.
An experiment was carried out
to demonstrate how man and ghost
can work together as a team.
Let's see how the partnership works
as together
they measure the effects
of nitric acid upon calcium.
Get ready
to write down your observations.
First, a bottle of powdered calcium
is placed upon the work surface.
Next, a small amount of calcium
is poured into the beaker.
Only about 4,000 million biligrams,
or 4 grams.
That's enough.
Ghosts can be
a little unpredictable at times.
The scientist fetches
a fresh beaker,
and the experiment continues.
Now for the nitric acid.
Nitric acid is highly corrosive,
so care must always be taken
when handling.
- (GHOST) Hello!
- Using a pipette,
the ghostly assistant
collects a few drops of the acid.
Now the ghoul is instructed to
release the acid into the beaker.
Come on.
(SIZZLING)
This is a naughty spirit.
That could have hurt.
The scientist will need
to rinse the affected area
with cold water immediately.
(ALARM)
(WHOOSHING AND GROANING)
It seems that for this spirit,
teamwork is not on the agenda.
The scientist has no choice
but to abandon the experiment.
Note that down
in your copybook now.
Over the course of this module,
we've learnt a lot
about the nature,
characteristics
and behaviour of ghosts.
So the next time you're playing
with your Ouija board,
take a moment out to remember this.
In the end, you too will die
and become a ghost.
It may be in fifty years,
it may be tomorrow.
It may even be...
today.
Now hand in your copybooks
to your teacher or head of class.
In the next programme,
we will look at reggae.
(REGGAE MUSIC)