Look around you.
Just look around you.
(GRUNTS)
Have you worked out
what we're looking for?
Correct. The answer is...
This programme, "Music",
can be found in chapter 9
of your textbook,
which accompanies this series.
Please ensure that you have
your copybook at hand,
as you'll be asked
to take down notes from the screen
at various points
throughout the programme.
Music is the name given
to any sequence of notes
designed by man,
and increasingly by women,
to effect mood change.
From the oom.pah.pah
of a traditional brass band
to the sounds of pop groups like
The Bensons or The Ombudsmen,
music permeates our lives
like no other force on earth.
But is it just man
that makes music?
It's a controversial issue,
because there are those
who actually believe
that this is music.
(TRILLS)
They call it birdsong,
but it's hardly a song.
There's no real tune to speak of,
just a random cacophony
of squawks and chirrups.
What a racket!
(SINGS FOLK SONG)
But regardless
of who creates our music,
it has the power to uplift us,
unite us,
filling our hearts
with laughter and joy.
One can only imagine a world
without music,
although we'd probably
get used to it after a while.
But for the moment at least,
music is here to stay.
An experiment was carried out
to demonstrate
how a modern song is composed.
Here's a state.of.the.art
songwriting computer,
the Harrington 1200.
You've probably never seen one
because it costs almost L1,000.
The Harrington 1200
compromises of keyboard,
console and banks
of oscillators and modulators.
But it's at the heart
of the Harrington
that we find the musical motors
that power this machine:
DNA samples taken from the
composers Gilbert and Sullivan.
This is Jack Morgan,
the scientist
who will be operating the machine.
He starts by informing
the Harrington of the song's key.
S.
It's in the key of S.
Write that down.
Next, the song's tempo.
Quite fast.
Finally, the scientist
must think of a title for the song.
He scans his surroundings,
looking for inspiration.
"Little Mouse."
It's a catchy title. Write it down.
The Harrington 1200 gets composing.
(ELECTRONIC NOODLING)
And a few moments later,
the song is written.
And we can now all listen to
Jack Morgan's song, "Little Mouse".
(PIANO INTRODUCTION)
♪ I remember the night
♪ Scratching at my door
♪ Furry, small and white
♪ I shook you by the paw
♪ 'Cause I like you, my friend
♪ I respect you, my friend
♪ I'll encourage you, my friend
♪ Through and through
♪ Hey, now, little mouse
♪ I hope we understand one another
. ♪ Show me what to do
. ♪ Little mouse!
♪ Hey, now, little mouse
♪ Something's moving
there in the back room
♪ Hey, now, little mouse
♪ Show me what to do
♪ Show them what to do
♪ It's enough for me and you ♪
That was "Little Mouse" there,
by Jack Morgan.
Who knows,
he may have a hit on his hands.
And from all of us here
at "Look Around You",
we wish Jack the best of luck.
An ordinary piano.
And if we go to the top
of the scale, we find this,
which houses the nineteen
forbidden notes.
The box is kept locked,
and for good reason.
We're going to show you just why
you should never attempt to play
any of these notes.
In the interests of safety,
we'll be turning down the volume
on your television set now.
(SILENCE)
Here are some pupils
from the music class of
St Heathen's Grammar in Grantham.
Helen. Rosy.
And Partario.
We're going to be giving them
a brief musical quiz.
You can join in too,
so have your copybooks ready.
Helen, how many notes are there
in a scale?
. Eight.
. Correct.
Rosy, how long
is a standard trombone?
. Extended or contracted?
. Contracted.
. 32 inches.
. Correct. Partario.
I was born in Portugal
300 years ago.
My belly has two holes in it.
I spend most of my time
under your chin. What am I?
Helen or Rosy?
. Is it a viola?
. Correct. Bonus point.
Fingers on buzzers.
Who have better singing voices,
men or women?
Rosy?
. Women.
. No, it's men. Popular music.
Which group had a number one hit
with "The Scarecrow Song"?
Helen?
. The Beatles?
. Correct.
What town was Schubert built in?
No one?
Schubert was born in Vienna.
That's the end of the quiz,
and we see that Rosy is the winner.
How did you fare?
Now we present Rosy with her prize,
a beautiful 17th.century harp.
But the others don' t go away
empty.handed.
They receive a consolation prize
of a "Look Around You" pencil.
Over the course of this module,
we've learnt a lot about music
and its many forms.
You may be thinking
of a career in music.
It's an exciting opportunity,
and could be
a very rewarding endeavour.
♪ Little mouse... ♪
You may not become the next
Mozart, but you might become
the next Grozart.
(SCRAPES VIOLIN TUNELESSLY)
Now hand in your copybook
to your teacher or head of class.
In the next programme,
we will look at dynamite.