This is BBC2. In a moment
we'll be stepping into the future
for our weekly look
at science and technology
with the Look Around You team.
But first let 's take a look
at the line-up
for this coming
St Frankenstein's Day.
(2nd man) Programmes for
St Frankenstein's Day on BBC2
begin at 4.35 with Watch The Dot.
Watching the dot this week
are Colin Buckles and Larry Matador.
At 4.55, six-sided fun
with The Hexagons.
Eyebrows are raised when Mofferty
goes on a date with a rectangle.
At 5.10 it 's Television's
Funniest Scientific Mishaps.
(Canned laughter)
Followed at 5.40 by The Colour Bars.
(Flat tone)
At six o'clock
it 's The Backwards News.
(Speaking backwards)
And at 6.30 we pay another
enchanting visit
to Tlentifini Maarhaysu.
A special St Frankenstein's Day
church service follows at 7.40,
broadcast live
from Dracula's Cathedral.
At 10.10 it 's The Honey Programme,
hosted by David Bumblebee,
whose guests this week include lead
singer of new pop group, The Police.
Imagine That! is at 11 o'clock
and this week
the businessmen are imagining
The Two Ronnies
having sex with each other.
And with pages from CEEFAX at 11.55
that rounds up viewing
for St Frankenstein's Day on BBC2!
(Man) Well, that 's certainly
something to look forward to.
But now let 's go to Shepherd's Bush
for Look Around You.
Feeling hungry now?
Hello, and welcome
to Look Around You.
As you've probably guessed,
tonight 's programme
is all about the future of food.
We've got a jam-packed show tonight.
We'll be visiting
the restaurant of the future
and sampling the latest
hi-tech cuisine.
Like this clever idea -
recycled food,
made using the leftovers
from hotels and hospitals.
But don't worry, none of this food
will be going to waste.
As you can see
it 's all being eaten by Tony Parker,
better known as the human dustbin.
He's raising money for charity
and he'll be eating
all the food you see tonight.
And believe me,
there's a lot of food.
Whoa! He won't be eating this.
It 's the latest birthday cake
from Japan
because today is Pam's birthday.
And later on we'll be trying a truly
futuristic birthday party for her
and you're all invited.
# Look Around You #
(Pam) Britain is fat.
Very fat.
And it 's hardly surprising
when you consider how many meals
the average Briton eats
every single day.
So what can be done
to get Britain back in shape?
The government have tried
everything,
from swimming lanes
alongside motorways
to on the spot fines for obesity.
But nothing has proved at all
successful.
Until now, with the launch of
a controversial new slimming aid.
(Man) I was very unhappy,
I never used to go out
because of me size.
I wasn't sure but I think me friends
made fun of me behind me back
but nothing was ever proved.
(Man) Andy Gough talks about Slimby.
I would eat anything
I could get me hands on.
One time I was so desperate
I even ate poisoned berries.
I tried everything
but nothing worked for me.
Until one day
a friend told me about Slimby.
(Man) Slimby is the fastest and most
convenient way to lose weight.
Take a glass of Slimby
at every meal time
then look at the special picture
and let Slimby do the rest.
It helped Andy Gough
become Slimmer of the Year.
I lost 52 stone in just six weeks.
And you can too.
Please welcome Slimmer of the Year
and the face of Slimby, Andy Gough.
- Welcome to Look Around You.
- Thank you.
- Firstly, you look fantastic.
- Oh, thanks.
And can I just say, Pam,
happy birthday.
Thank you. Now, Andy, clearly you
can lose a lot of weight with Slimby
but tell us, how does it work?
Well, Slimby is
a double action diet system,
the Slimby shake works by
loosening all your fat molecules
so it turns your body fat
into fluid.
Then when you look at
the special picture
it shocks your system so much
that it pushes the fat out
through the pores of your skin.
(Pam) Which you can shower off.
Yes, or scrape off,
or wipe down with a towel.
Now, what is it about the special
picture that makes it so effective?
It 's an exceedingly scary picture.
They spent months researching images
to come up with the one
that was the most shocking
and what they have is more
horrifying than you could imagine.
Well, we're going to show you
the special picture now.
We all saw it earlier on
and it is particularly terrifying.
So much so that the BBC have only
just granted us permission
to show it at all.
So if you have any children watching
please take them out of the room.
And if you're of
a nervous disposition
please look away from
your television screens.
May we now please show
the special picture.
And you may now
look back at your screens.
Clearly that is
a very disturbing image.
It is.
You must have seen it
hundreds of times.
I have to admit
I have seen it so much
I have become pretty immune to it.
So what do you do if you get
the urge to overeat again?
Well, I have my own visual aid -
and this is it.
I kept all the body fat I lost,
and every time I look at it
I just lose my appetite.
That is a good idea.
Gosh, you were carrying
a lot of weight.
Yes, I know.
- (Fat grunts)
- Is it alive?
I think it 's a bit alive.
Well, thank you very much, Andy,
for showing us Slimby
and your former self,
and best of luck with the campaign.
(Peter) In today's modern world
it seems that none of us
has any time to do anything
any more, least of all eat.
Which is why more and more of us are
turning to fast food establishments.
And when you hear
the words "fast food"
you automatically
think of one thing -
casserole.
You can hardly walk down
your high street now
without noticing the smell
of casserole being prepared
in one of Britain's
20,000 casserole cafes.
Most of us have a casserole
a couple of times a week
but for some - notably
fashion-conscious teenagers -
the figure can rise to three or
three casseroles every single day.
That 's great news
for the British meat industry,
and for O'Gravy's,
the market leader,
but now there's a new challenger
to the casserole crown.
Big C is a new company
which could revolutionise
the way we eat casserole.
And it 's all thanks to
British technology.
Clive Pounds
is the managing director of Big C.
..way forward in this company
is efficiency, basically,
and if you're gonna turn up late...
I've always loved casseroles,
ever since I was young,
but you go to these casserole places
these days and...
well, you'll pardon
my language, they're shit.
Terrible casseroles, rude waiters,
dirty surfaces,
toilets that stink, it 's disgusting.
So what 's so different about Big C?
Well, Big C is the world's first
totally automated
casserole restaurant.
We've designed it
so that every aspect,
from ordering
to receiving the casserole,
is controlled by a computer.
And you're going to give
Look Around You
a sneak preview of Big C
before you open?
That 's right.
And I'm sure you'll agree
that Big C is the casserole
restaurant of the 21st century.
- (Intercom buzzes)
- Excuse me.
- Clive, it 's ready.
- OK, Tammy.
- (Door opens)
- Ah, our casseroles.
You will join us for breakfast,
won't you?
How could I refuse?
There are some perks to this job,
you know.
Mm. Mm.
He does love his casseroles.
You can see the second part
of Peter's report
later in the programme.
(# Upbeat march)
- Hello, darling.
- Hello.
- How's space?
- Yes. Very pretty.
We're off to Neptune this afternoon.
That sounds nice.
Are you eating properly, darling?
I do worry about you.
Yes, I am.
Tonight I'm having my favourite -
roast turkey, potatoes and peas.
- And how is Rafferty?
- He's fine. He misses you.
- Give him my love.
- Will do.
(Both screech)
Well, today we might not all have
pet coravinians
but the food pill
has become a reality.
And it 's being used at the moment
on the British space mission
to destroy Mars.
Well, space-age food came to
Birmingham last week with Foodex,
the catering industry's
annual exhibition,
showcasing the latest food products
from all over the world.
Thousands of items were on display,
from an underwater supermarket
to an albino raisin.
Here's Look Around You's
pick of the crop.
If you've ever wondered how many
peas there are on your plate
then the electronic pea counter
could be for you.
It 's suitable for both domestic
and professional use
as it 's accurate to
one pea in a hundred million.
(Beeps)
(Pealy) This pizza
could be a real life saver
because it 's a medicinal pizza.
Designed by the NHS,
it 's prepared at the hospital
and delivered by ambulance.
(Jack) Here's a cheaper, sweeter
alternative to the banana.
Made from sugar turnip
and animal fats,
the nabana is just as versatile
as the real thing
but a fraction of the cost.
(Pealy) This item was a lot of fun.
From - where else? - Japan.
(Slurping)
Ahh...
But perhaps the most controversial
item at Foodex was this.
A substance known as SP4053.
It 's a modified elephant gene
that can be added to pigswill
to create oversized pigs.
The makers claim that these
Ele-swine, as they call them,
could yield massive amounts of meat.
However, some scientists
are urging caution.
Because such a beast would have
a bigger brain than humans
they might be reluctant
to be turned into sausages
and may be inclined
to settle a few old scores.
Certainly food for thought.
Earlier we showed you our pick of
the future of food exhibition Foodex
but we saved the real
star of the show until now.
So please welcome to Look Around
You, Teddy Clarke.
- Hello.
- Hello there.
Now it 's not actually you
who's the star, is it?
No, it 's these chaps over here,
my vegetables.
Let 's take a look. Believe me,
these aren't just any old vegetables
because this is the world's only
vegetable orchestra.
That 's right.
Well, how do you make a vegetable
make music?
Well, everything, as you know,
is made up of cells
and vegetables are no different.
These cells vibrate
at different frequencies
and by controlling these frequencies
using variable voltages
and a suitable amplification
system...
- Which you have here.
- Yes.
Let 's have a look at it. Now,
it does look rather complicated.
- It 's not too complicated actually.
- Is that a Beaumont Grill?
It is a Beaumont Grille,
and this whole system amplifies
the minutest vibration,
so we can make them sound like
any musical instrument.
Talk us through the various sections
of the orchestra. What are these?
- Tomatoes.
- And what instrument?
The first violins. Those are
the corn - that 's the violas -
and up there are the leeks -
they're the trumpets.
And the spring onions there,
they're the timpani.
- And what about this big fellow?
- The onion is the woodblock.
- And the peas?
- The peas are the flutes.
And this pea here
is a very good mimic
and he sometimes doubles up
for the bassoon.
So how do you get them
to learn a piece of music?
It 's pretty simple actually.
We sit the vegetables in a mulch
made of the sheet music of
the piece that I'm teaching them.
Fascinating! Last night Teddy Clarke
and the Vegetable Orchestra
performed at the Royal Albert Hall,
and there was
a very special guest there?
Mm, that 's right.
We were honoured to perform in front
of Sherlock Holmes's grandson.
(Jack) And did you get
a chance to meet him?
No, he had another engagement.
Well, I'm dying to hear
your vegetables in action,
so please tell us,
what will you be playing?
Well, we'll be playing...
the introduction from
the BBC Nine O'Clock News.
Well, take it away - Teddy Clarke
and the Vegetable Orchestra.
(# "Classical" version of
BBC Nine O'Clock News theme)
(Bell chimes)
(Applause)
(Jack) Bravo!
(Pealy) Marvellous!
- Well done.
- Teddy, when are you playing next?
- Sunday, in Lake Windermere.
- In Lake Windermere?
They'll empty it before the
performance and fill it again after.
Well, Teddy wins our
invention of the week nomination
for his vegetable orchestra.
And here's your rosette.
And we'll see Teddy again at the end
of the series for our live final
when he could win
this magnificent trophy,
presented by His Royal Highness,
Sir Prince Charles.
I'm now outside Big C, the world's
first automated casserole cafe.
It 's opening night but before then
managing director Clive Pounds
is giving Look Around You
an exclusive look inside.
Have you made a reservation, sir?
I'm only kidding. Come in.
Now, Clive, when you enter Big C
you immediately notice
that there are no staff.
It may seem a bit eerie but all
will be explained. Take a seat.
Oh, thank you.
Well, the first thing I do
is choose my casserole.
Hm. I think I'll go for the beef.
Waiter!
Ah, silly me, there are no waiters.
No problem.
I simply write down my order
on this sheet of A4 paper.
Now for the clever bit.
Clive, tell us what happens now.
OK, so now you...
Oh, good choice, sir.
Pop your order into the fax machine,
like so.
Punch in the number of the kitchen.
(Beeps)
Now that sound informs you that
the kitchen is awaiting your order.
One beef casserole for table nine.
(Peter) The computer calculates the
precise amount of casserole I need
before sending an electronic signal
to the automated collection pipe.
- And a few moments later...
- (Bell dings)
(Beeping)
No fuss, just piping hot casserole.
How's your casserole?
Mm, delicious.
Let 's hope the customers
think so too.
We'll find out at the grand opening.
Yeah. Fingers crossed.
Well, unfortunately
there never was an opening night.
Only hours after that piece
was filmed
Clive Pounds sadly died
from complications following
a wasp sting to his anus.
And so, as a mark of respect,
we will now observe
a one-second silence.
(Beep)
Well, it 's Pam's birthday,
and as promised we're throwing
a futuristic party for her.
And of course, you're all invited.
(All) Happy birthday!
- Immenstrades!
(Jack) This chicken wine's
delicious.
Thank you, everyone. Oh, my cake.
We managed to salvage most of it.
- (Laughter)
- Go on, make a wish.
(All) Hooray!
Well, Pam, we have a surprise
for you now - a very special guest.
- Who is it?
- Somebody you know extremely well.
Probably you better know than
anybody else in the world.
My mother? My doctor?
Now, Pam, no guessing.
This guest represents
a breakthrough in science.
In fact, some of the leading names
in physics and biology
have been working with
Look Around You on a secret project.
So may we have a drum roll, please.
(Drum roll)
Pam Bachelor, please welcome
your surprise birthday guest.
It 's yourself - Pam Bachelor -
at age 90.
Now, first of all, Pam,
I have to tell you
that you mustn't touch your
older self, for obvious reasons.
OK.
- Well, say hello.
- Hello.
Hello.
- How are you?
- You mean "how am I"?
We're the same person.
Oh, yes. What happened to your eye?
- It 's your eye too, dear.
- Sorry.
Well, you lose it in an accident
and they replace it
with this nuclear one.
It 's rather good, actually - look.
- (Chuckles)
- (Young Pam) My!
- Your husband never liked it.
- Husband?
First husband,
because you remarried three times.
Three times?
Connecticut doesn't work out
for you.
And then there's the fire and
the investigation and everything.
Anyway, the point is, it 's your
birthday - it 's our birthday -
so happy birthday from the future.
Thank you very much, Pam...
Seeing myself reminds me how happy
and surprised I was on this day.
Well, thank you very much,
Pam Bachelor from the future.
Unfortunately that 's all
we've got time for tonight.
Pam, we hope you've had
a fantastic birthday.
It 's been the best birthday ever.
And special thanks
to the Human Dustbin,
who's raised L14,000
for the relatives of the victims
of the Battle of Hastings.
Thanks also to Teddy Clarke and
the Vegetable Symphony Orchestra,
and of course to
Slimmer of the Year Andy Gough.
Thanks, Andy.
Thandy.
Next week it 's time
to get plugged in
as we take a look at
the world of computers.
So don't miss it.
So from both Pams and all of us here
at Shepherd's Bush,
take care of yourself, and remember,
wherever you are, whatever you do...
(# Piano introduction)
# Happy birthday to you
# Happy birthday dear Pam
# Birthdays are a time
for celebration
# A time when all around you
is good cheer
# So please all raise your glass
and hearty may you laugh
# And toast this merry fellow
that is here
# Happy birthday to you
# Happy birthday dear Pams
# From Look Around You #
- (# Theme tune)
- (Pealy) Happy birthday.
# Look Around You #
Viewers may be pleased to know
that Clive Pounds, who died
during the making of that programme,
has since come back to life.