Look around you.
Just look around you.
Have you worked out
what we're looking for?
Correct. The answer is...
This programme, "Germs",
is discussed in chapter 622
of your textbook,
which accompanies this series.
Please ensure that you have
your copybook at hand,
as you'll be asked to take down
notes from the screen
at various points
throughout the programme.
Germs.
Germs, germs, germs.
Everywhere, germs.
Dirty...
filthy...
germs.
But where do they come from?
Germs originated in Germany,
before rapidly spreading
throughout the rest of the world.
They're basically a form
of malevolent bacteria,
with one purpose, to spread germs.
An experiment was carried out
to illustrate just how fast
germs can multiply.
First, a solution rich in germs is
collected in a Bakerloo bell jar.
We're using some filthy drain water
from an overflowing sewer.
Next, several drops
of the germ-ridden solution
are removed
from the Bakerloo via a pipette.
This pipette is then
taken over to our subject.
This is Ashley Swain,
a first-year chemistry student
at the University of St Christmas.
Ashley's tongue is cupped,
and the scientist releases
a few drops of liquid sewage
into his mouth.
We're going to see how fast
the germs can spread
from inside Ashley's mouth
to this man,
Ashley's tutor at the faculty,
Professor Clifford Miles.
Now we take
the professor's temperature.
It's normal. 98.4 degrees.
Note that down in your copybook.
The scientist now instructs Ashley
to cough in the direction
of Professor Miles.
The germs have hit their target.
The Professor.
Let's see how fast
the germs get to work.
Get ready to take down
readings from the screen.
Let's see
if there's been any change
in the Professor's temperature.
It's gone up a little: 101 degrees.
Two hours have passed,
and the Professor's showing
signs of deterioration.
Let's check his temperature again.
It's now 103.8 degrees.
After three hours the Professor
is clearly highly feverish.
He's rambling and is obviously
in a great deal of discomfort.
And it's hardly surprising, as his
temperature is 107.2 degrees.
107.2. Write that down.
As we can see, in just a few hours,
Professor Clifford Miles' body
has become completely riddled
with the germs from inside Ashley.
Do get well soon, Professor.
You can pick up germs
from a variety of sources,
and because they're invisible,
they're almost impossible to see.
You can get them from nasty places.
For example, if you haven't
washed your hands properly
after wiping your bottom.
Sharing a friend's recorder.
Kissing a dog.
Or a tramp.
In the laboratory,
we can cultivate germs
in order to study
their behaviour in detail.
An experiment was carried out
to cultivate
the Milenius mytoteme germ.
The Milenius mytoteme germ
is unique
to one specific branch of moth,
the Brown Maiden,
seen here in our gribbin.
The Brown Maiden is normally found
in shrubland and thickets,
and feasts on tiny grubs
and leaves.
It's a different sort of moth
to one you'd enjoy in a sandwich.
They have a rather bitter taste,
but are ideal for our experiment.
A lamp is turned on, and the Brown
Maiden begins its futile flight.
As it flaps its tiny wings,
they brush up against
the inner walls of the gribbin.
The wings are rich in mytoteme,
and soon the walls
are coated in the germ.
The moth is now free to stay...
or go.
Next, a cotton bud is used
to scrape off germ samples
from inside the gribbin.
These are then wiped
in a petri dish containing agar.
The germs are now left
to grow overnight.
The next morning,
we can examine the results.
Have your pen and paper ready.
A strange reaction has occurred
in the middle of the petri
in the middle of the night.
The mytoteme germs
have multiplied so fast
that they have bonded
to form a plant-like organism.
Note the little leaves at the peak.
And underneath, tiny apples.
This is a fruit-bearing bush.
It's called Lepidopterus arboratus,
or moth-apple tree.
Moth apples are smaller
than crab apples. Sweeter, too.
But don' t be tempted to eat them
because they're highly explosive.
Now hand in your copybook
to your teacher or head of class.
In the next programme,
we will look at hitchhiking.
(HORN)