(FAINT WILDLIFE SOUNDS)
(LATIN MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(BEEPS)
(SIGHS)
(MUSIC STOPS)
- Hey, Lucky, how you doing?
- You're nothing.
You're nothing.
LUCKY: Thank you.
- Good morning, sweetheart.
- Hi, doll.
Plenty of cream and sugar,
just like you like it.
Perfect.
JOE: Lucky!
Oh, God.
- Those things are gonna kill you.
- If they could've, they would've.
(COUGHS)
- LORETTA: All right, see you.
- Oh, okay.
Bye, Lucky. See you, Joe.
JOE: What you stuck on now?
Uh...
...seven-letter word for augur...
...A-U-G-U-R.
I know.
Go on, honey.
Portend.
Portend. P-O-R-T-E-N-D.
LUCKY: That's it. Thank you, dear.
JOE: Give me that.
Well, this is easy.
I mean, what you gonna do
when you get the Sunday puzzle?
PAM: Give me another.
All right...
...a three-letter word
for asshole starting with a "J"?
(PAM CHUCKLES)
JOE: Clever.
Very clever.
(HORN HONKING)
(POWER TOOLS WHIRRING)
- Buenos días, Lucky.
- Buenos días.
- How are you today?
- So far, so good.
- Who's that again?
- BIBI: That's my youngest son, Juan.
Oh, yeah, yeah, that's John in English.
Like John Wayne. Juan Wayne.
He's gonna be ten on Saturday.
- Oh, that's great.
- It's his birthday.
Well, I gotta go. My shows are on.
Juan Wayne.
BIBI: Juan Wayne.
HOST: (OVER TV)
Go ahead and tell us about yourself.
CONTESTANT 1: Hi, I'm Stephanie Moreno!
I'm from Pueblo, Colorado...
...and I'm here to make some money!
CONTESTANT 2:
Hi, I'm David Mulbec. I'm from Chicago...
...and I'm here to make some money!
CONTESTANT 3: Hi, I'm Marlene Moscavitz,
Ann Arbor, Michigan...
...and I'm here to make some money!
HOST: Join us and find out who's gonna
walk away with a brand, new car...
...on, Take a Guess.
(OVER TV) Have you been turned down
for life insurance? If you are...
- They always yell at ya.
- ...you can obtain full-term li...
Oh, shit.
Is realism a thing?
Okay, so it's a thing, huh?
All right, and that's, uh, seven letters.
Hold on a minute.
Okay.
"Realism, noun."
"The attitude or practice
of accepting a situation as it is...
...and being prepared
to deal with it accordingly."
Now the other one.
"The quality or fact representing
a person, thing...
...or situation accurately...
...or in a way that is true to life.
I always thought
that what we all agreed on...
...was what we were looking at,
but that's bullshit...
...because what I see
is not necessarily what you see.
Realism.
R-E-A...
...L-I...
That's it. That's some heavy shit.
She's gonna blow it.
CONTESTANT 2: The Dark Ages?
HOST: (OVER TV) No, I'm sorry. The answer
you're looking for is "the Renaissance."
You blew it, honey.
There goes your fucking Buick.
(TV CLICKS OFF)
Okay, pal. Goodbye, I'll talk to you later.
ELAINE: Now you know me,
I don't like to cause a scene.
Hey, fuck you, I don't.
So that night, I decided to have
a coming-to-God meeting.
I locked the front door and sent
everybody back into the kitchen.
Took down my Saturday Night
Special over there. And I said, "Gentlemen...
...if you want to fuck me,
and I know you do...
...you should buy me dinner first."
Then I drew that peace-maker...
(MAKES SHOOTING SOUNDS)
...two rounds in the ceiling and I said...
"...I know...
...that all of you are stealing from me.
Just don't get greedy."
And I've been in the black ever since.
(EVERYONE LAUGHS)
I see her standing there,
the room was filled with gun smoke.
And everyone's just shitting
their goddamn pants.
I tell you, the sexiest thing I'd ever seen.
I wooed him with my feminine charm.
PAULIE: Nothing but class with this one.
Charmed.
ELAINE: You were good to Momma last night.
Lucky! Bloody Maria?
Por favor.
- Lucky!
- Hey, Paulie.
What's the good word?
Realism is a thing.
Oh, yeah? How do you mean?
It's the practice of accepting a situation...
...as it is...
...and being prepared
to deal with it accordingly.
So what you're saying is,
"What you see is what you get."
But what you see is not what I get.
PAULIE: Okay.
- LUCKY: Elaine!
- What?
LUCKY: Realism is a thing.
- Realism.
PAULIE: Here we go again.
Vincent, hand me my gun.
Easy, partner. You're a misdemeanor
fucking with a felony.
Hey, Howard.
- VINCENT: Howie, what are you drinking?
- Something strong.
What's the matter, Howard?
- President Roosevelt escaped.
- PAULIE: What are you talking about?
- LUCKY: Presidents.
- Which one?
- Roosevelt.
- Yeah, which one?
No, my tortoise,
President Roosevelt, he escaped.
How does a hundred-year-old tortoise escape?
I left the gate open
when I went to check the mail.
Where is your mailbox, Europe?
(ALL LAUGHING)
I saw him eyeing that gate the other day.
He had to have timed it out perfectly.
I searched our entire neighborhood.
Did you search your entire yard?
Hey, we're talking about
his best friend here!
- Thank you, Lucky.
- You're welcome, Howard.
You're right, you're right, I'm sorry.
We shouldn't make fun.
I'm gonna miss him.
He's outlived two of my wives.
- I'm going to the W.C.
- Okay, pal.
You know...
...friendship between animals and humans...
...is essential and special.
And friendship is essential to the soul.
What?
Friendship is essential to the soul.
It doesn't exist!
- What, friendship?
- (LOUDLY) The soul!
Hey, knucklehead, inside voices!
Hey, you gonna let your woman
talk to me that way?
I'm not his woman. He's my man.
As far as I'm concerned, he's just
been renting a room for 30 years.
- Sonny and Cher.
- ELAINE: I'll drink to that.
PAULIE: Hey, you know they got divorced.
ELAINE: Good thing we never got married.
- (LOUD THUD)
- (CERAMIC SHATTERS)
(LUCKY MOANS)
LUCKY: Jesus Christ.
(SNEEZING, COUGHING)
Jesus! God, this thing.
Can you... never mind.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Oh, God.
Why?
- Hey, buddy. How the hell are you doing?
- You tell me.
115 over 70, great.
Thank you, Debbie.
No broken bones. That's good.
CT scan was negative, no sign of concussion.
Blood pressure is good, heart is great.
Lungs are great, even though you smoke.
- How many packs a day?
- I don't know, maybe one.
Well, I really have no explanation for that.
It's a mystery,
some sort of scientific anomaly.
All I can figure is it's a combination
of genetic good luck...
...and you're one tough son of a bitch.
I would try to get you to quit smoking...
...but I'm afraid it would
do you more harm than good.
You're the only person I would say that to.
So, that's it?
To be clear...
...you were just standing there
and you got light-headed?
- I didn't get light-headed.
- So you just fell down?
Yeah. It was weird.
Well...
...I'll wait for these lab tests to come back
and then I'll let you know about that.
That's it?
- That's it.
- I'm not dying?
When it comes to most things like
heart disease or cancer, at your age...
- ...if it was gonna kill you, it would've.
- So?
Short of shooting you with a silver bullet
or stabbing you with a wooden stake...
...it seems the older you get,
the longer you're gonna live.
So, but why did I fall down?
- Were you drunk?
- No.
- Do you get light-headed often?
- I don't get light-headed.
- Now do you get much exercise?
- Yeah, I walk around all the time.
I do five yoga exercises every day,
twenty-one repetitions each, for years.
- Do your knees ever give out?
- No.
I could do a lot more tests,
but I think it's gonna turn out to be...
- ...exactly what I think it is.
- What's that?
You're old, and you're getting older.
- That's your diagnosis?
- It's all I got.
Well, that's bullshit.
The body is gonna break down at some point.
As far as I know, nobody has lived forever.
It's gonna happen to all of us.
I can do more tests, but I don't want to
do that and you don't want to have it done.
So what am I supposed to do?
At this point,
I think it might be a good idea...
...to get an assisted
living person hooked up.
- What?
- Assisted living.
They come by and they help you
cook meals, help you bathe.
Oh, I don't know, I'm on my own.
You never get lonely being alone?
There is a difference between
being lonely and alone.
You know, I saw this happen with my father.
He started to lose his eyesight,
and with it his ability to drive.
It wasn't getting older that bothered him,
it was the loss of his freedom, his mobility.
It's all fine as long as you realize
it's all part of the process.
Well, how is your old man?
Oh, buddy, he died a year ago.
Wow.
It was peaceful.
You know, most people
don't get to where you are.
They get hit by a bus
or get leukemia or something.
They never get to the moment
that you're in right now.
We have the ability to witness what you're
going through, and clearly examine it...
...and, more importantly, to accept it.
I know that's kind of heavy
for this hour of the morning...
...but you're in exceptional health
for a person your age...
...and if you need anything whatsoever,
you call me or you just come by.
Okay.
You've been very good today,
so you get one of these.
What do I do with this, stick it up my ass?
How about you just suck it?
Oh, boy.
You're nothing!
LUCKY: Yeah.
Everyday with this guy.
Kneedler said it was all right
for me to smoke.
Not in here.
- And when did Kneedler ever say that?
- This morning.
JOE: Oh, you know,
I was getting a little worried.
Bet you was getting that prostate checked.
I fell.
On my bony ass, I fell.
- Are you okay?
- That's subjective.
Pam! Loretta! Lucky fell down!
Let's not make a production out of it!
- Well, what did Kneedler say?
- He said I'm old.
- And that's news to you?
- LORETTA: Did he give you anything?
I don't know, man, it's all bullshit.
JOE: Wait, where you going?
- Buenos días.
Give me three packs today, honey.
Here you go, keep the change.
Are you okay?
(WHISPERS) I don't know.
You know, Juan Wayne's birthday
is on Saturday.
- Oh, yeah?
- We're gonna have a big fiesta...
...with a bouncy house, piñata,
mariachis, and lots of food.
Mariachis, huh?
Do you want to come?
To the fiesta?
Saturday.
- And where is it?
- It's at my home.
- You know where the school is?
- Yeah.
It's the yellow house
right behind the school.
Oh, yeah.
Well...
...let's keep it on the burner, okay?
- Okay.
- Gracias. Adiós.
HOST: (OVER TV)
And now we're bringing it over to you, Lisa.
What is the answer to the question?
LISA: Is it April 16, 1746,
the Battle of Culloden?
HOST: The answer to that question...
we'll have to wait until tomorrow.
Thank you for joining us
and we'll see you all tomorrow on...
...Make a Guess.
(TV CLICKS OFF)
Hey, man, how you doing?
Okay.
Hey, uh, I was just thinking
about something...
...I wanted to share with you, man.
You got a minute?
Yeah. When I was a kid living in Kentucky...
...I had this BB gun.
It didn't shoot straight.
So I was out one day shooting
at things, trees, leaves.
And there was a mockingbird
up in a tree singing his heart out.
And...
I aimed my gun just to scare him away...
...pulled the trigger...
...and the singing stopped.
It was the saddest moment in my whole life.
The silence it cast in the world...
...was devastating.
I haven't thought about
that bird since I was a kid.
I know.
All right.
Thanks, man.
(PHONE CLICKS ON CRADLE)
You been watching Deal or no Deal?
Are you kidding, it makes no sense.
Come on, man, you gotta give it
a second chance. It is...
Listen, listen, check it out.
You start with 50 briefcases...
...right, held by 50 hot chicks.
Right? And inside each briefcase, all 50...
...is a number and that number
is how much money you're gonna win...
...if you open that case.
So you choose one case
at the beginning of the game...
...that you're gonna open up
at the end of the game.
And then you systematically
open up all the briefcases...
...and the hot chicks show you
how much money you could have won.
And the whole time,
there's this hidden guy...
...and he's sitting off stage and he's
offering to buy the case that you chose.
So by the end of the game,
you've opened up all the cases except two.
And you have to decide whether to take
the money from the hidden guy...
...the money that's already in your case
or the case that you haven't chosen yet.
But you don't know what's in your case
or the case you haven't chosen...
...until you actually open it.
So a guy picks a case and I've gotta
wait a fucking hour to see what's in it?
Yeah.
It's a convoluted piece of shit.
Lucky, how you doing, buddy?
I haven't a clue, man.
- Someone's in a mood.
- Leave him be. He'll snap out of it.
Right, pal?
- ELAINE: Two more cases?
- VINCENT: Yeah, that'll do.
- If you want, I can...
- Watch me lift stuff?
Can I help it if I have a strong mind,
but a weak back?
Sit.
I know that look.
Used to see it all the time.
You know where? In the mirror,
my reflection staring back at me.
- VINCENT: And then he met Elaine.
- Hey, who's telling the story?
I'm sorry, but it hasn't exactly
been un-told.
I've told this? You've heard this
before from me? When?
All the time, that's when.
I bet he's heard it, too.
- I've told this? You've heard this?
- Ungatz.
Holy shit, that's right! Ungatz.
- Nothing. I was nothing.
- You were a bum.
PAULIE: I was a bum.
I had no plans. I had no ambitions.
- A two-bit hustler.
- PAULIE: That was me.
- And you knew it.
- PAULIE: I did.
I'd look into the mirror
and all I'd see was ungatz.
I hated myself.
- And then what happened?
- You met Elaine.
Jesus, I can't believe it,
you really listen to me.
- That's amazing.
- (LAUGHTER)
Anyway, I met... I met this fantastic woman.
And she met a bum, a deadbeat.
Did she try to change me? No.
Did she expect me to change myself? No.
- She accepted me for who I was.
- Who you are.
Who I am.
I'm still ungatz, nothing.
But I've got everything.
- Isn't that something?
- Something for you.
No, what I'm trying to say is,
if this could happen, you know, to me...
...then it could happen to anyone.
- Even you.
- (SNICKERS)
Bullshit.
Jesus Christ.
MAN: I believe we can just get by with
a will and a medical power of attorney.
Howard, where have you been?
I've been waiting for you.
Who's this?
Hey, Lucky. This here
is my attorney Bobby Lawrence.
- Nice to meet you, Lucky.
- LUCKY: Hello.
You know why sharks don't eat attorneys?
- Uh...
- Professional courtesy.
Right, that's an oldie but a goodie.
So did you come here to help find Roosevelt?
No, he's here to help me with my plan.
- What plan?
- End-of-life plan.
Are you dying?
No, he's just preparing for the unexpected.
What's unexpected?
Well, I mean, none of us
make it out of this thing alive.
So, knowing that, it'd be a sin
not to prepare for the well-being...
...of your loved ones.
What loved ones do you have, anyway?
When I go, I want to leave all
my possessions to President Roosevelt.
- Your turtle?
- Well, you know, this might not...
Tortoise! And he's still got
at least 100 years left in him.
- A hundred years?
- HOWARD: Yeah.
- You know, Lucky, you remind me...
- Shut the fuck up!
Okay.
Didn't Roosevelt just run away?
Yeah, but this is for, you know,
when he comes back.
- Is he a homing turtle?
- Tortoise. And no, he's not.
He's gone, Howard, and you're all alone.
We come in alone, and we go out alone.
That's awfully bleak.
It's beautiful.
"Alone" comes from two words, all-one.
- It's in the dictionary.
- I miss him!
It'll be okay, Howie.
A tortoise is an amazing creature, Lucky.
They're as noble as a king,
and as kindhearted as a grandmother.
I miss my friend, his company.
I miss his personality.
He's not missing, Howard. He's just not here.
He's there, wherever the fuck that is.
And if he's not there, then he's nowhere.
- Well, I'm sure he's okay.
- Why don't you go fuck yourself?
Oh!
You don't give a shit about him.
You're just here to suck him dry.
You lamprey, leach, vulture.
Con him out of his last dime,
just to leave everything to a turtle.
Tortoise! He's a tortoise!
You know that saguaro near your yard?
That thing was barely a twig
when Roosevelt was born.
They're contemporaries, you know?
They watched each other grow up.
President Roosevelt was born
in a hole in the desert.
At that time, a little creature
smaller than my thumb.
And something clicked inside
that little Roosevelt brain...
...and he scampered up out
of that hole and faced the world.
You all think of a tortoise
as something slow.
But I think about the burden
he has to carry on his back.
Yeah, it's for protection.
But ultimately, it's the coffin
he's gonna get buried in...
...and he has to drag that thing
around his entire life?
Go ahead and laugh...
...but he affected me.
You know what I'm saying? He affected me.
There are some things in this universe,
ladies and gentlemen...
...that are bigger than all of us.
And a tortoise is one of 'em!
You asshole.
I want to teach you a lesson.
WOMAN:
Lucky! No fighting in my bar, goddammit!
- Then we'll take it outside.
- MAN: Seriously, Lucky?
You know, Mr... Mr. Lucky, I...
- ...I don't think...
- You don't think I can take you?
I fought the fucking Japs!
You don't think I can take you?
No. I don't think it's a good idea for you.
Outside. Five minutes. Fisticuffs.
- Lucky...
- Five minutes!
Lucky?
Lucky!
Is he coming out?
Are you kidding? He doesn't wanna fight you.
- I wouldn't want to fight me, either, pal.
- Easy, Lash LaRue.
Let him live this time, okay?
Forty years ago, I wouldn't have
given him a fuckin' option.
Forty years ago, he'd have been in diapers.
Forget about him! Okay?
Okay.
(DISTANT ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Where you going?
Go home, Lucky.
(ROCK MUSIC GETS LOUDER)
Paulie?
(ROCK MUSIC CONTINUES)
(MUSIC STOPS)
(PHONE RINGING)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
LORETTA: Hey, there!
How ya' doing?
How did you get here?
- I... drove?
- How did you know where I live?
- Everybody knows where you live.
- They do?
This is a tiny town.
Don't you know where I live?
Yeah, over by the church?
There you go.
So, what do you want?
Well, I was worried about you so I thought
I'd come by and check on you.
You're welcome.
Nice outfit there, cowboy.
Thanks for coming by.
Jesus Christ. How'd you get in here?
I thought you'd left.
I'm sorry, I knocked, the door was unlocked.
You scared me to death.
You were such a cute, little boy.
And such a handsome young man in uniform.
This photo at the beach, are these your kids?
No.
- Were you ever married?
- No.
Were you?
No.
- You got somewhere to be, sailor?
- Uh... no.
Do you like game shows?
Do you smoke grass?
LORETTA: This isn't a game show.
LUCKY: It's ended.
This... he is amazing. Who is this?
Liberace. Didn't you ever hear of him?
Yes, I've heard of him.
He's wonderful.
LUCKY: I feel like such an asshole.
When this guy first came on the scene...
...I wrote him off as just another
extravagant fruit.
If you stop and listen to him,
you'll see he's brilliant!
And I don't know how the hell he plays
with all those rings on his fingers...
...that's even more impressive.
Look at him.
I don't know why I ever gave a shit about
who he was screwing in the first place.
If he was getting laid, more power to him.
Hmm, I can hardly get it up anymore.
LIBERACE: (OVER TV)
I hope I didn't leave anybody out.
Oh, we did leave out somebody.
All you kids...
Oh, shit, I gotta go. I'm late.
I gotta get back to the diner.
Joe is going to kill me.
All right.
LIBERACE: Bunch of liars. (LAUGHTER)
- I'll see you later.
- Okay.
Bye.
- Hey.
- Yeah?
Can I tell you a secret?
LORETTA: Absolutely.
You won't tell anyone?
I'm scared.
I know.
Did you ever think about
before you were born?
JOE: No, never did.
What are you talking about?
New beginning.
Is that... in the crossword today?
No.
I was just thinking about something that
happened to me when I was about...
...12 or 13 years old.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
I was at my Aunt Beulah's house, alone.
I don't remember why.
And only once, I got this anxiety attack.
I panicked and I was scared to death.
I started thinking there's nothing out there.
It's all black, there's nothing.
And I was... I was scared shitless, man.
13?
Yeah.
What happened?
I don't know, my aunt came back
and that was the end of it.
(DOOR OPENS)
- Hey, Bob, how we doing?
- BOBBY: Little bit worse, I'd be perfect.
JOE: Sit anywhere you like.
Hey, you know what, Joe?
I'll just take a coffee to go.
Oh, okay. Well, I got a pot brewing.
It'll be a minute.
All right.
Morning.
Hi.
Howdy.
So, no, uh... no sign of The President yet.
I hope he turns up soon,
for Howard's sake. The two of them...
- ...are like heterosexual partners.
- Only one thing worse...
...than awkward silence...
...small talk.
Okay, I hear you.
So you doing okay?
Fragile.
Oh.
Why is that?
I fell down.
Ooh, yeah, yeah, that's... that's bad.
Yup. It rung my bell.
A couple years ago...
...I was heading to my daughter's
school to pick her up.
And as I'm turning around the corner,
you know, going to the parking lot...
...there's a garbage truck that...
...I mean, just barely missed me.
There was no more room between my car
and that truck than between me and this tie.
A half a second...
...a half a second made all the difference.
Two minutes later, my daughter hops into
the car as if nothing's happened, and...
...I guess nothing has.
But, uh...
...it really shook me to the core.
Yeah, I got hair standing up
on my arms just thinking about it.
- Here we go, Bob.
- Oh, thank you.
Gratis, counselor.
Thanks, Joe.
Do you mind if I sit down?
Well, sit down.
Do you have any kids, Lucky?
None that I'm totally sure of, no.
- You married?
- Never been married.
Ever in love?
Yeah, I guess so.
Ah, so it goes, huh?
Well, "The future's not ours to see."
Hell, I've made a whole career out of that.
Wills and trusts, you know, it's about
planning for things that you can't foresee.
Just because you can't see 'em,
doesn't mean they're not gonna happen.
- It is written.
- Mm-hm, somewhere.
You know, I came home
with my daughter that day...
...and I sat down, I made a will.
I wrote end-of-life directives,
I upped my life insurance.
I paid up front for my cremation.
So now, if something happens to me...
...when something happens to me...
...my family doesn't have to worry
about the bureaucracy of death.
You know?
They just call one number...
...and my body's gone
by the end of the day...
...and they don't have to worry about
anything for the rest of their life.
Well, this doesn't change
anything for you, this scenario.
- Why not?
- You're still dead.
How are you doin'?
Hey, how you doing, sweetheart?
Hey, Lucky.
- What's her name?
- Fiona.
Hey, Fiona, you're a fine cut of a dog.
- Yeah.
- Do you have any pets?
- No.
- You ever think about adopting one?
No.
I got plenty inside who need a forever home.
A what? What's a forever home?
That's when someone adopts an animal and
then they have a permanent place to live.
Nothing is permanent.
Come inside, I'll show you around.
It's like the wild kingdom in here.
Aren't they beautiful?
Yeah, and loud.
- Do you have any mockingbirds?
- No, but I can order you one.
No, thanks.
- LUCKY: Are these tortoises?
- FRANCES: No, they're baby turtles.
My friend Howard's tortoise ran away.
- Oh, no.
- Yeah.
He said they could live to be 100 years.
Oh, absolutely. In some cases,
I've heard of 200 years.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah.
Wow.
- And what are these?
- Crickets.
Can you adopt these, as well?
No. People buy them to feed their reptiles.
Oh.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
LORETTA: Good morning, darling.
Anywhere you like.
Marines, huh?
Yes, sir.
- You?
- Navy.
Okay, okay. You guys are great.
You always gave us a lift to the fight.
I read somewhere where the Marines
didn't have the mental capacity...
...to understand
the inner workings of a ship.
World War II, huh?
- Pacific.
- Yeah, same here.
Did you ever get around the Philippines?
Yeah, I spent a couple years
in that slice of heaven.
Yeah, me, too, but I never got off the boat.
Consider yourself lucky.
Can I get you a cup of coffee?
- Yes, please, black.
- Mm-hm.
- FRED: A piece of that apple pie?
- Absolutely. You want that warmed up?
- No.
- All right.
Thank you, though.
Well, uh, mind if I come over and join you?
No. Come on over here.
Fred Sparks.
They call me Lucky.
I was a cook. On paper, that's supposed
to be the easiest job in the Navy.
- That's why they called me Lucky.
- What were you riding in?
L-S-T.
L-S-T? Landing Ship Tank, right?
We called it a large, slow target.
We were hauling ammunition
for the big battleships.
More like riding a stick of dynamite.
You ever get a ship shot out
from underneath you?
Almost once.
Every day in the evening glare...
...the suicide planes
came in low over the water...
...with the sun behind them,
to hit our ships.
So one day, this suicide plane was coming...
...right towards our ammunition ship.
And all at once...
...about 100 yards away...
...it went up into the air
and slid back down into the water.
Some of our small arms fire
had hit the pilot.
- Lucky shot.
- Not for the pilot.
Did you go straight to
the Philippines from boot camp?
No, we stopped in Tarawa
and Okinawa on the way...
...just to show them what fer.
Tarawa, Jesus Christ.
- Here you go.
- Oh, thank you, dear.
- You're welcome.
- Thank you very much.
I still think about those people
on the islands, hiding away in caves...
...afraid of us.
The Japs said that we were going
to rape and kill them all.
So, we secured the beach...
...and the locals who survived
that goddamn fire fight...
...start throwing their children off
the cliffs, and then following them.
I guess they thought suicide
was better than facing us.
I remember this little girl,
couldn't have been more than seven...
...in rags.
I don't know, she saw us coming,
I guess, and right out of nowhere...
...out of a hole or wherever it was...
...and she had this...
...God, this beautiful smile on her face.
And it wasn't a facade, it was
coming from somewhere inside...
...from the center of herself.
Good Lord, in that shit hole...
...something like that really stands out.
It stopped us in our track. Here we were...
...all covered with shit,
pieces of people everywhere...
...and I couldn't see a tree left.
And she's grinning from ear to ear.
So I said to my corpsman, I said...
"...Look at this, we got somebody
who's happy to see us."
And he said, "She's not happy
to see you. She's a Buddhist.
She thinks she's gonna be killed,
and she's smiling at her fate."
When I think about that little girl's
beautiful face, and that smile...
...in the midst of all that horror...
...and how she summoned...
...joy.
They don't make a medal
for that kind of bravery.
(MARIACHI MUSIC PLAYING)
(MAN SINGING IN SPANISH)
Hi, Lucky. I brought you some flan.
I made it myself.
- Oh, thank you.
- And this is my mother, Victoria.
She speaks a little English.
Lucky.
- Hola.
- Nice to meet you, darling.
- Mucho gusto.
- Bueno, I'll be right back, okay?
Now, um...
...what does the name Victoria
mean in English?
- Victory.
- Victory, ah, Che Guevara said...
"...Hasta la victoria siempre."
(IN SPANISH) You speak Spanish?
(IN SPANISH) Very little.
My pronunciation is good.
But my conversation is very limited.
But this is fantastic.
Your pronunciation is perfect.
It sounds so natural.
My daughter always speaks highly of you...
...and she says
you are keen on Mariachi music.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Excuse me.
(ALL SINGING SPANISH)
(SINGING STOPS)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
LUCKY: (SINGING) Este amor apasionado
Anda todo alborotado
Por volver
Voy camino a la locura
y aunque todo me tortura
Sé querer
Nos dejamos hace tiempo
pero me llegó el momento
De perder
Tú tenías mucha razón
Y le hago caso al corazón
Y me muero por volver
Y volver, volver
Volver
A tus brazos otra vez
Llegaré hasta donde estés
Yo sé perder, yo sé perder, quiero volver
Volver, volver
Nos dejamos hace tiempo
Pero me llegó el momento
De perder
Tú tenías mucha razón
Y le hago caso al corazón
Y me muero por volver
Y volver, volver
Volver
A tus brazos otra vez
Llegaré hasta donde estés
Yo sé perder, yo sé perder, quiero volver
Volver, volver
Lucky!
One of you will betray me.
Bullshit. We'll all betray you.
(ALL LAUGHING)
You look peppy. Where have you been?
Uh, to a fiesta. Did you ever have flan?
- No.
- I love it.
It has an unusual consistency.
Howie, you find that reptile of yours yet?
No, but thank you for asking.
It's okay, I've let it go.
I kept thinking about how much time
he spent planning his escape.
And how much care he took
in making sure I couldn't find him.
And then I started to realize
that he wasn't leaving me.
He was just going off someplace else to
do something he thought was important.
I even felt guilty for standing
in his way for so long.
So I stopped looking for him.
If it's meant to be, I'll see him again.
He knows where I am,
and I'm leaving the gate open.
LUCKY: To Roosevelt!
Hey! What, the rules don't apply to you?
Since when did you think
you could smoke in here?
Well, you could in '68.
Well, it ain't '68 anymore, sweetheart.
One of these days,
I'm just going to light up.
My place, my rules.
Ownership is a fallacy.
Why can't you just live by the rules?
Authority is arbitrary and subjective.
This is the same kind of attitude
that got you 86-ed from Eve's.
- What do you know of it?
- I know you lit up.
That's what you think happened.
If you didn't light up,
why did they kick you out?
They didn't kick me out, I walked out.
- That's a good story.
- I like that story.
- It's not a story.
- ELAINE: Then what is it?
- It's the truth.
- The truth is, you lit up!
It's not about the cigarettes,
it's about what I know happened...
- ...and what you think happened.
- I wish I had been there.
You could have been there
and still have missed it.
You broke the rules.
You got busted and banned.
- That's the truth.
- How about if we all agree to disagree?
No. I know the truth and the truth matters!
It's a thing. Right?
Yes, truth is a thing.
It's the truth of who we are and what we do.
And you have to face that, and accept it.
Because the truth of the universe is waiting.
- I'm lost.
- The truth of what is...
...for all of us.
Which is?
That it's all going to go away.
You, you, you, you, me,
this cigarette, everything...
...into blackness, the void.
And nobody's in charge.
And you're left with...
...ungatz.
Ungatz.
- Nothing.
That's... that's all there is.
- And what do you do with that?
- What do we do with that?
You smile.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)