My name is Neon Joe.
I dedicate my whole life
to hunting werewolf in the hope
that one of these time
it turn out to be my daddy.
Hello, son.
You know what these are?
The severed heads
of all the werewolf I kill!
This here right here
gonna go right here.
You chew the math.
Aah!
So what are you gonna do now?
Suppose it's time
to start following my dreams.
As for hunting werewolf,
I'm officially retired.
Hey, Joe, looks like
the margarita volcano
needs a new batch.
Oh, yeah?
He-yump.
I made one this morning.
Added a little extra 'rita.
Gonna call it
the more-garita.
- Get it?
- No, I tell you what to do.
Moon is alive.
Yeah, we hear you.
Okay, Uri, it's closing time.
She doesn't understand.
You don't understand.
Mm-hmm.
The moon is alive.
We got it.
Closing time.
Good night, Uri.
Man, oh, man, that
one drunk Russki, huh, Cleve?
It's last call, ma'am.
That's, uh, Neon Joe,
Werewolf Hunter, right?
Yeah, but he doesn't really
go by that name anymore.
That's who he is now.
Neon Joe,
regular everyday duck hunter.
Start off as more of a gimmick
to draw customers,
but it didn't really work,
and so that's when we thought of
the margarita volcano,
but that didn't really
work, either.
So we're looking
for a new gimmick.
So you're his sidekick.
Yeah, I guess I am his sidekick.
That's hot.
I'm into number twos,
if you know what I mean.
Can I get a selfie?
No.
Joe doesn't like selfies.
With you.
Oh, okay.
Hey.
Hmm. Thanks.
See you around.
Okay.
See you later.
Number twos?
Hey, Joe.
That girl was so into you
that she wanted to take
a selfie with me.
No, I think it sounded
like she into you, Cleve.
What? No.
The only reason
she would ever date me is
so she could have
an affair with you.
Look, I'm gonna
go tally receipt.
Why don't you clean up?
You got it, boss.
Hey, Joe, do you ever think
of me as your sidekick?
What?
Nothing.
♪
What are you, moon?
Huh? Huh?
Coming!
I see moon.
I love moon.
Oh.
♪
Oh, babe.
How did we do tonight, Joe?
Yeah, not very good, Cleve.
Somebody tipped with
a half-eaten sandwich.
Ooh!
♪
Bar ain't doing too good, Cleve.
All my tropical dreams
is slowly turning
to tropical dust.
You mean sand?
Need new gimmick.
And don't be bringing up
that wet t-shirt contest again.
I told you I ain't
comfortable showing my nips.
Joe, you think maybe
if you told people
you were the world famous
werewolf hunter...
That ain't my life no more.
Well, that girl Ashley
recognized you.
I bet there's a lot of people
that would love buying drinks
from a world famous
werewolf hunter.
Do that again.
Do what again?
That...
That... That little, teeny,
tiny drink you just did.
Do... Do it again.
Yeah, that's it!
Sips!
We gonna start
charging people by the sip!
That's our new gimmick!
Listen to this.
Oahu Joe's...
Just one sip, it worth the trip.
Or loose lips drink sips.
Oh, that pretty good!
Now we're talking.
Oh, you know what, though, man?
I can't really afford
that right now.
Listen.
You're Neon Joe,
and you can do anything.
As they say, where there's
a will, there's a...
He-yump!
Let's do this!
Let's give people the sip
they never knew they needed.
All right.
He-yump.
He-yump, he-yump, ah!
He-yump!
♪
♪ Whoa-ho, baby
♪ Don't forget that tip
♪ After enjoying
♪ Your sippy sippy sip
♪ Whoa,
you sip it to the left ♪
♪ You sip it to the right
♪ You do the sippy sip sip
♪ And we're sipping all night,
yeah ♪
♪
Can I get four more sips?
Coming up.
♪
Cleve! Come on!
Do a naval sip! Come on!
No.
Where you been, moon?
I've been looking.
Oh, baby.
Yeah, I told you those were
gonna be for, Cleve, right?
Teeny tiny sip cup.
People go crazy for that stuff.
People weren't even
ordering drinks sometimes
'cause they were
just watching you, Joe.
Yeah, a little bit of he-yump,
a little bit of he-yump,
got the he-yump on the he-yump,
and a little bit of he-yump.
All right, we got 10 plus 5.
Carry the he-yump,
and we got a he-yump.
What is it, Joe?
How much did we make?
Uh...
A little under $15.
Guess Joe got to show his nips
after all.
I'm sorry, Joe. I'm the one
who gave you this idea
when you saw me
sipping the beer.
You know what? Let's cheer
ourselves up with some gossip.
"Tip of the Buzz"
"Tip of the Buzz."
How's this for a load of buzz?
Sources say Hollywood
is ready to take
a bite out of
famed werewolf hunter
and international playboy
Plaid Jeff
by bringing his life story
to the big screen.
And it was confirmed today
that he will be played
by Kids' Choice Award nominated
actor Jason Sudeikis.
I'm really, really excited
about this role.
It's got everything.
You got werewolves,
you got guns,
you got cool clothes.
It should be a hell
of a good time.
I mean, and this guy's a trip.
You camera guys,
you better watch yourself,
'cause Jason just asked me
if I'd be willing
to do part-time work
as a paparazzi hunter.
Uh-oh!
The film will be financed
by Elon Musk-type
billionaire inventor
Vance Dontay.
What the hell was that?
Oh, uh, hey, guys, sorry,
but the bar is closed.
Come back tomorrow
around noon for a sip on me.
Tomorrow at noon?
We just got into town.
We're ready to drink.
How you been, Neon Joe?
Looks like retirement's...
done you pretty good.
I'm sorry, but, uh...
the bar is closed.
Oh!
That's no way to treat
your former rival
and new number-one
hot-shot werewolf hunter.
Yeah, I'm glad to hear things
working out for you okay,
Plaid Je-yump.
It's Plaid Jeff.
And I'm doing more than okay.
I just had my 100th kill.
I suppose you didn't
see the tweet tonight.
Taye Diggs retweeted me.
That's why we're here, Joe.
We're here to celebrate
my 100th kill.
Yeah, I tell you something,
Je-hump,
you like an Olympic sprinter.
I mean, yeah,
sure, you... you fast,
but the only reason
you got any gold
is due to the retirement
of the real fastest guy.
Usain He-yump.
Ooh!
Hey, Plaid Jeff,
do you need some ointment?
Because you just got
b-b-b-b-b-burned!
Ssst!
This is Vance Dontay.
He's my Elon Musk-type
associate.
I think he can make keeping
your bar open worth your while.
How does $500 sound
to keep the bar open
for the night?
How do 500 "no thank
you he-yump" sound?
How about $200,000
to keep it open permanently?
♪
I mean, this place
is worth, what?
150 tops?
Bar is closed.
Your money no good he-yump.
Oh. Well, if my money
is no good,
I may as well just burn it.
♪
Good night.
Cleve. Back room.
Now.
Shouldn't we put out the fire?
No!
I need to punch the living hell
out of your face.
Me?! What?
I could not show weakness
to Plaid Jeff.
Now I got all this
contained fury
that need to be released.
I take it out on your face,
that cancel out the rage.
No! No!
Don't you remember the other day
you was asking about
becoming my sidekick?
Yeah. Okay.
If this is gonna help you deal,
I am not only happy to do it,
I would consider it an honor.
That's my Cleve.
Appreciate that.
And I fell right on my face.
And every time I stood up,
I kept slipping
and fell right on my face,
and it happened like 20 times.
Oh, you poor thing.
Ashley's here for you now.
Uh-oh.
Hey! Morning, Joe!
Hey, no hard feelings
about yesterday.
All right, I know we came late
and you were trying to close.
But the good news is,
is that I bought an apartment
right up the street.
So that means I get
to come all the time.
Well, hey,
that great news, Je-yump.
Matter of fact, here you go.
First sip on the house.
Gentlemen, welcome
to the neighbor-he-yump.
So what do you think
about my new duds?
You don't have a problem with
my new color scheme, do you?
Of course not.
I don't blame you
for wanting to wear neon.
Look good on almost everybody.
Almost.
You know what else
almost looks good on everyone?
Rings.
I love the way this one fits.
You want to try it on?
♪
No, thanks.
Nice ring, though.
Damn it!
I'm trying to get
a rise out of you!
No!
You know why I'm on your dick?
'Cause it's so meaty?
Maybe it's because
you stole my ex-wife
and left her for dead!
No one fall in love
with this guy!
Because at some point
in the future,
you will end up
in a dangerous situation,
and he will leave you for dead
like he left my ex-wife!
♪
Let's go.
You're being a good sidekick!
Joe feel better.
♪
How... How many times
have I told you?
Hey, hey! I told you.
We cannot show intimacy
in public.
It's too risky.
Just...
Just be patient.
Everything will go our way.
Did you really steal
Plaid Jeff's wife?
I didn't steal nobody's wife.
Yeah, they was married,
but then True Love Joe
came to town.
And I huffed,
and I puffed,
and then she blew my heart out.
Huh?
♪
He-yump.
He-yump!
♪
Forget Plaid Jeff.
I never loved him.
I always loved you.
I know you didn't abandon me
at the pretzel factory.
If there ever came a time
we battled a werewolf
and one of us were in danger,
we agreed that the other
had to save themselves.
He-yump!
I would have done the same
if the tables were turned.
He-yump, he-yump, he-yump. Listen to me.
It's not your fault.
No.
Make love to me, Joe.
Yeah.
♪
Okay. Naked.
Oh.
Hey there, Joe.
How can I help you?
Hey, man.
I need you to make
a life-size copy
of this photo
right he-yump.
And when you use the paper,
use the paper
that feel most like skin.
♪
He-yump.
He-yump! He-yump.
Oh, he-yump. Oh.
Oh, he-yump. Oh, he-yump.
Oh, he-yump! Oh, he-yump!
Oh, he-yump!
Oh, oh, he-yump!
Oh, he-yump.
♪
Joe?
Hello, hello, hello!
Joe!
Joe! Wake up!
Hey.
Aah!
Oh, hey, Cleve.
Hey. Oh, my.
What time is it?
It's late.
Oh, man. Hey.
Oh, sorry, man.
Guess you caught me
after a good time with...
with Leann.
Ooh! Ouch!
What the he-yump?
Are you okay?
What happened here?
Whoa.
Got a little paper
cut on my dick.
Let's go to the bar.
I'll tell you about it there.
Yeah, uh, about that.
I don't know if I'm going
back to the bar
because Plaid Jeff
offered me a job
as his personal assistant.
I'm sorry, Joe.
It's all right, Cleve.
You a good friend.
You want to take that job,
it'll be no hard feeling.
But if I ever take my rage
on Plaid Jeff face,
that his blood gonna be
on your hands.
Ooh.
Now go get me some Band-Aids
and Neosporin.
I got cut right across the tip.
Yes, sir.
You ever had a Band-Aid
on your dick?
I don't see how the thing
gonna stay on.
Get me some duct tape, too!
Yeah, he-yump.
Oh, hey.
Good morning, Chris.
How you doing?
Good to see you, man.
What's up?
Oh, uh, whoop.
Had a paper cut on my dick.
It's a long story.
Get it?
I called my dick long.
I got the Band-Aids.
Oh, hey, Chris.
Hey, you know, I hadn't
seen you around the bar
since we started that
sip campaign, man.
You got to come by.
It fun.
I do, like, a lot of move
behind the bar.
Do like a little Tom Cruise
and cocktail like...
You got to come by
and get a sip, Chris.
It fun, man.
You...
You got to come by one night
and bring Linda.
How's she doing, by the way?
Oh, Linda's fine.
Joe, you're under arrest
for the murder of Plaid Jeff.
Say w-what? He-yump?
"Breaking Buzz."
We come to you with a sad
Buzz-breaking
news story tonight.
Famed werewolf hunter
and international playboy
Plaid Jeff has been
brutally murdered.
Police say
the suspect in custody
is retired
werewolf hunter Neon Joe,
who also owns Oahu Joe's
Tropical Beach Cantina,
better known as
the Home of the Sip.
I think I speak on behalf
of everyone here
at "Tip of the Buzz"
when I say today marks
a tragic loss
for the show-biz community.
But stick around
after the break,
where we say goodbye
to the top 20 buns
we lost this year.