(♪ "In This Country" by Eddie Money)
Regiment...
Dismissed.
(cheering)
(boy) We did it!
You made it.
- You got a fine boy there.
- Thank you.
- Deliveries in the rear.
- I'm picking up Cadet Cutler.
- OK. Pass, sir.
- Thanks.
Who's he?
Smile, everybody.
What's he doing here?
Excuse me.
Can I get you to pay attention?
Forget about him.
Pay attention to me.
I'm trying to get a picture here.
Smile.
(boy) Oh, thanks, Dad.
Hey, are we gonna get to see Ma?
Is this the Michael Cutler Limo?
- Yes, sir.
- Where's my grandfather?
He'll be arriving at the airport
in an hour.
- (youth) Cutler!
- Yes, sir!
- The colonel wants to see ya.
- Right away, sir.
Wait here.
(indistinct chatter)
- ColoneI Finley.
- Sir.
The colonel wishes to see me, sir.
- Your father wishes to, Cadet.
- My father?
- Yes. He's come to drive you home.
- Hello, Mike.
- I don't have a father, sir.
- This is your father, Michael.
My grandfather has instructed me
to go home with no one
besides himself or my mother.
Your mother has legal custody
over you. Not your grandfather.
And it is her request
that your father bring you home.
- Sir, may I ask a question?
- Of course.
May I see some identification
on this man?
- That's not called for, Cadet.
- That's OK.
I'm ready.
Are we going in this?
Why can't we fly?
Your mother thought it'd be a good
way for us to get to know each other.
How long will it take?
Well, I have one more pickup
and, say, two, three
days we'll be in California.
And your mother doesn't go
into surgery until Wednesday morning.
(sighs) Do you really think you can make
up ten years in two to three days?
No.
- Here, let me help you.
- I can do it myself.
- I'd like to say something, sir.
- Sure.
This truck is disgusting.
I don't know, Mike. It's just old.
Once in a stretch up to Vegas,
this thing got up to...
Sir. There's no need to make
any conversation for my sake.
So much for small talk.
OK. Here we go.
- Can I ask you a question, sir?
- Sure.
How did you get
all these pictures of me?
- Well, your mother sent 'em to me.
- Why?
I've been writing to her
for a long time
and I asked for pictures so
I could see how you were growing up.
Looks good.
If you two had been writing,
how come I never got a birthday card,
or a letter, or anything?
- What are you saying, Mike?
- I never heard from you.
I've written to you 100 times.
Birthdays, all the time.
What do you mean, I never...
You must have sent 'em to the wrong
address, cause I never got anything.
Could you pull over?
I'm feeling sick.
- What's wrong?
- Would you please pull over, sir?
(man) Hey! Mike!
(honking)
- Mike!
- Look out!
- Hey, what the hell are you doing?
- Put a leash on that kid!
Mike, Mike. Stop it. Stop it.
- Stop it.
- (crying) I hate you.
Then hate me.
We have to start someplace.
OK?
Come on. Let's go back.
- You said you took care of it.
- I did, but...
- Forget it. Forget it!
- Yes, sir.
The boy's mother called, Mr. Cutler.
She insisted that Michael leave
with his father.
Don't you understand?
My daughter is in no condition
to make that kind of a decision.
I didn't fly all the way up here
to be simply told
you turned my grandson
over to that worthless bastard!
I can't tolerate stupidity.
I'll bring this up
to the attention of the board.
I'm sorry about the...
I'm sorry about the jacket.
It's no problem.
You'll get the bill.
I'm sure.
(sighs)
If you're hungry, there's a great
place up here for good steak.
What do you say we stop?
You're going to be a victim
of cholesterol poisoning.
Later in life,
you'll just start to rot away.
You're just full of good humor,
aren't you, Mike?
Well, let's try it, anyway.
- Hey, Linc.
- How you doing, Tom?
Just fine.
- Hook me up?
- No problem.
Let's eat, Mike.
(♪ "Bad Night" by Frank Stallone)
(man) Hey, Linc. Good to see you, man.
How do you like the place, Mike?
I never did like the zoo, sir.
Why don't you sit down?
- Hey, Linc. Hi. How are you doing?
- Hi, fine.
- Martha, this is my kid Mike.
- Well, Mike.
- How do you do, ma'am?
- Ma'am? Whoo! I like that.
So, what'll it be?
A couple of big steaks?
For me. Mike'll have chicken.
- Fried bird. Sure.
- No. Excuse me.
For a man who exercises,
you don't know much about nutrition.
A fried chicken dinner
with mashed potatoes
has 1,000 calories and 50% fat.
These fats have been linked
to heart disease and some cancer.
So, what would you like?
Tuna salad, whole wheat toast
and spring water with lemon.
- (Martha) OK.
- Double that.
All right.
If you want, we can go
to McDonald's or something.
You Hawk?
- If you're hungry...
- I said, are you Hawk?
- What can I do for you?
- I'm the Smasher.
That's a nice name.
All I've been hearing on the road
is this Hawk is the man to beat.
- Can't believe everything you hear.
- I don't believe anything!
I got 1,000 that says
I can tear your arm off.
You want it?
(man) He's trying to back out.
I said, you want it?
Why not?
Let's get this table ready.
I wanna show this guy something.
- Come on.
- Break his arm off.
- Are you gonna fight that guy?
- I can't talk right now, Mike.
Where are you going?
Gotta go to work.
- (man) Three on the Hawk!
- (man #2) Four!
(all shouting)
Come on, Linc.
Linc, this guy's insane.
(yells)
- (man #3) Three on the Hawk.
- (man #4) Linc, he's yours.
- What are you doing with that guy?
- He's my father.
Too bad.
(man) All right!
Start the fight! Start the fight!
Get ready.
Get ready. Go!
Shit.
You ain't got it!
Get him, Linc!
Come on, Linc! Get him!
Come on! You can do it! Come on!
(grunts)
Over the top!
Aaagh!
Come on, Linc!
(cheering)
Come on, jerk. Give me the money.
Give me the money!
I ain't givin' you no money.
He cheated!
You wise guy, you.
(♪ "Gypsy SouI" by Asia)
So you got lucky again, huh, Hawk?
- How you doing, Bull?
- Better than you.
Right now, double or nothing.
What do you say?
Let's just wait for Vegas.
Let's do it now.
I feeI like kicking ass.
- Let's wait till Vegas, OK?
- You ain't got a prayer in Vegas.
- We'll see.
- (chuckles)
Too bad your old man's yellow, kid.
I'll see you in Vegas.
Get out of the way. Back up.
I'm sorry about that, Mike.
You're a hustler. You hustled
that man back there for money.
- No...
- I'd like to call my mother.
You have to give it time, Michael.
You have to be patient.
I know how you feeI,
but you must do it. It's important.
I know you want me to do it,
but I don't even know him.
I want you to try.
It's important to me.
Why? I thought everything was fine.
There's so much more to life
than what you've seen.
- But he left you.
- He had his reasons.
Look, I have to go now,
but I want to talk to your father
first, OK? I love you.
OK. I love you too. Bye.
- She wants to talk to you.
- Thanks.
How you doing, honey?
Mike, would you hold that? Thank you.
Hi, honey. How are you?
Yeah, we're having a great time.
Yeah, he's very helpful. As a matter
of fact, he's helping me right now.
(♪ "AII I Need Is You" by Big Trouble)
(music stops)
That was a nice song.
(music starts)
(music stops)
- (music starts)
- (music stops)
Mike, I think we're wearing out
this knob here.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Sure.
Are you still dealing drugs, sir?
Are you?
You think of that all by yourself?
My grandfather gave me the facts.
The truth is I never did what
your grandfather said I did, Mike.
The only mistake I ever made
was leaving. I admit that.
So how'd you like the arm-wrestling
match back there?
- It's an experience.
- It sure was.
(♪ "AII I Need Is You")
Christina.
How are you, darling?
- Are you angry with me?
- Angry?
- Have I ever been angry with you?
- Tell me the truth.
All right, I'll tell you the truth.
I'm not angry.
But I am disappointed.
I just wanted him to know his father.
Michael's father is no good.
Your wanting to bring him
back in this family is all wrong.
Christina, I know you're worried
about leaving Michael alone.
But surely you understand I'm all
the family Michael will ever need.
You're not his father.
I have been his father for 12 years!
Let's not talk about this anymore.
It's going to turn out all right.
Trust me.
Rest now, sweetheart.
I'll come by a little later.
(indistinct chatter)
If there are any calls
for my daughter, I wanna know.
Yes, Mr. Cutler.
From the reports,
they can't find him.
I want my grandson found.
I don't care how you do it. Do it!
Yes, sir.
(♪ "I Will Be Strong" by Eddie Money)
- Why'd you stop?
- Well, I think we all need a rest.
I don't see a hotel.
Well, Mike, I thought we'd stay
in the truck tonight.
A lot of truckers do it.
- If you can do it, I can do it.
- That's the spirit.
- Well, good night, Mike.
- Good night, sir.
By the way,
if your neck gets sore tonight,
you can use my shoulder for a pillow.
Thanks anyway, sir,
but I think I can manage.
- You sure?
- Positive, sir.
Cause I don't mind. It's all right.
Maybe tomorrow,
we'll exercise a little bit.
Good night, sir.
Good night, Mike.
I think we'll get along fine, Mike.
You're a good kid.
(♪ "Meet Me Half Way" by Kenny Loggins)
See how I do this?
You put your wrist into it,
you lean forward,
and you put a lot of weight in there.
You have to use
your whole body to it.
It's like your body is one piece
of machinery. You try it.
That's it. Good grip.
That's right, lean into it.
You can do it.
Keep your wrist straight. Good.
That's it, Mike.
Now put some muscle into it.
There's more to life
than just muscles.
Meaning what?
Meaning I don't see any books around.
You don't read much, do you?
No offence, but you're just simply
on a different social scale.
Oh, you wanna tell me more
about this social scale?
It's been said that the average
mental age for an adult is 15,
just three years older than I am.
For a trucker, it has to be
in the 11 to 13 year range.
Maybe 14, if they have good genetics.
You know, Mike, it's really
great driving with such a...
...tremendous intellectual like you.
It's a real blessing.
Why are you stopping?
You're aggravated, aren't you?
Boy, I passed aggravation
about a mile back.
- Are you gonna get violent?
- Wanna give me a break?
Since you think it takes
no brains at all,
and I have to be stupid to drive
a truck like this, I tell you what.
Why don't you just
come on over into my seat
and let's see if you can move
this machinery around, OK?
- What?
- Drive, genius.
OK, Mike. We got miles to go.
This is an unfair test.
I've never driven a truck before.
- Child's play.
- Let's see, what's the big deal?
Just step on the clutch,
press the gas and switch the gear.
This is no problem.
I once drove a dune buggy.
Mike, I'm impressed. Really.
This'll be no problem at all.
(chuckles)
You're doing great, Mike.
Why don't you turn the key? OK?
Now you see
that little silver button?
Push it.
(engine starts)
Magic, huh? Well, Mr. Dune Buggy,
you ready to drive?
OK. Push the clutch in all the way.
Give it a lot of leg.
- I don't have anymore.
- No, you can do it. Hold it in.
A little bit more. That's it. Good.
Now, give it some gas. Are you ready?
OK. Here we go, Captain Dune Buggy.
Blastoff, right?
Go.
Gas, Mike. A little more gas.
You got an interesting style, Mike.
Hold it steady, Mike.
Good. Good. Get it out there.
I'm getting a little sick, Mike.
I always wanted to be a milkshake.
We're hitting a lot of turbulence.
Let's shift to second gear, OK?
- Clutch all the way in?
- Yeah.
Give it some gas.
You ready? OK, shift.
Wow. I'm impressed. Not bad.
I think we have a natural here.
OK. I think you're about ready
to do it by yourself.
- No!
- Gotta go now, friend.
Go on. Hold it steady.
This is great. I'm really doing it.
This is great!
Now, that wasn't so hard, was it?
- What, sir?
- Smiling.
You're a real natural.
Keep your eye on the road.
(honks horn)
- Here comes Mike.
- All right!
No. You stay out of it
from now on. Right.
- Tim?
- Yes, sir.
We're going to have to deal
with this in another fashion.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
That cake didn't have much
of a chance.
- I was reaI hungry.
- Driving a truck can do that to you.
- You ready?
- Yeah. Let's go.
- Can I call Mom?
- That's a good idea.
You feeI good?
- Yeah, why?
- I mean, do you feeI strong?
Why?
- Come with me.
- Where are we going?
You'll see.
Excuse me.
Did any of you boys ever
arm-wrestle?
Why?
I got a kid here that could beat
any one of you guys
- two out of three times.
- He's a practical joker. Sorry.
He's just a shy kid.
I'm so sure
I'm willing to put money on it.
Kid, if I couldn't beat you,
I'd kill myself.
- This is getting too intense.
- Relax.
You don't have a chance
against this kid.
Yes, he does.
Ten to one odds.
Your one against my ten. Fair?
All right. Let's go.
Ten to one odds. Right here.
(Hawk) Two out of three times.
You should take that off.
That's not fair.
- You'll take him easy.
- (Hawk) No gloves allowed.
OK. Concentrate, Mike. You can do it.
All right, let's start.
Ready, wimp?
His skin feels like a girl's.
- Maybe he is a girl.
- Probably.
Don't listen to 'em. You hear?
- Kill him.
- You're gonna show 'em now.
You're gonna do it.
Over the top, Mike. Ready?
- Start. Come on.
- Break his arm.
Get this little wuss!
Blow the fruit away!
- Come on, man! All the way!
- Come on!
- Yeah!
- Yeah, man!
- Aw, look at the baby.
- Aw, little baby. Little baby.
- Two out of three.
- Ten out of ten.
- Any day, man.
- We'll take anything, man.
Mike!
What are you trying to do?
All you wanted to do
was embarrass me. You did it, OK?
Grandfather said you were a loser.
You're trying to make me one
and I hate you for it!
Mike, I don't care what your
grandfather thinks about me, OK?
All I care about is you.
Now you lost back there
because you beat yourself.
You let yourself get beat.
I know you can do it.
You're a special kid.
You're my boy, do you understand?
But you're also a spoiled, rich brat
who's always had everything
done for him.
It's time to do it for yourself,
and you can do it.
The world meets nobody halfway.
Do you understand that?
If you want it, Mike,
you gotta take it.
Do you hear me? Go in there and try.
I know you can win.
But even if you don't, so what?
So you lose.
As long as you lose like a winner,
it doesn't matter.
Cause you did it with dignity.
If you don't go in there,
you're gonna be sorry.
You'll regret it your whole life,
you know what I mean?
Go on. I know you can do it.
Will you do it for me?
Come on. Let's get him.
You can beat him.
You're twice as strong as he is.
You just gotta believe. All right?!
I thought you said he was strong.
Well, my boy was just
feeling generous.
Now it's time to go to work.
Huh, Mike?
- It's time to go to work, kid.
- Yeah.
- Does he think he can take me?
- I don't think so.
- Lock wrists.
- What a joke.
(boy) Through the table. Smash him.
This is gonna hurt, wimp.
What do you think of that?
- I think your breath stinks.
- Go!
- (boys shouting)
- Come on, Mike. That's good.
Come on, Mike. Drop the weight.
Over the top, Mike. Come on.
Get tough. Pump it, kid.
You got him, Mike.
You got him! You got him!
Come on! A little bit more.
You got him!
All right!
All right. Way to go.
- Come on, man. Do it again!
- He cheated. Come on. One more time.
Let's go, Mike. Right away.
- I'm gonna break your arm, punk!
- Come on. Get mad. Ready? Go!
(Hawk) Come on, Mike.
You can beat him.
Harder, Mike. Over the top.
Pump it, kid.
The power, Mike.
Over the top.
Hey! Good, Mike.
All right. Way to go.
You're a tough little sucker,
aren't you?
That was great. Pay up now.
- Money, please.
- Money.
- How did he do that?
- Good genetics.
- Thanks. Let's go.
- Let's talk to Mom.
- I'll beat you every day, man.
- Come on. Right now!
I drove Dad's truck and
I'm a good driver.
Great driver.
And I had this arm-wrestling match
with some guy who was bigger.
- Maybe 5'6".
- Bigger.
- No, 5'9".
Mom, you wouldn't believe it.
This guy was a monster!
Oh, that's good, darling.
I'm so proud of you.
Is your father there?
Let me speak to him, OK?
- I love you, sweetheart.
- OK. I love you too.
- She sounds so weak.
- She'll be all right.
- I'm gonna be outside.
- OK, champ.
Hi, honey.
Oh, yeah, it was a great idea
he and I spending time
like this together.
I hope so. I know it won't be easy.
Oh, no, everything's gonna be great.
I know it is. So, how you feeling?
Linc, whatever happens,
I want you to stay with him.
I know how difficult it is for you,
but it's really important.
- He needs you, honey.
- I will.
Please try to make things work
between you and my father.
He's too set in his ways to change,
maybe you can try and understand him.
I'll try.
OK. I can't wait to see you both.
Christina, he's a great kid.
And I'll see you soon, OK?
OK.
- Dad!
- OK. Bye.
Mike!
- (Mike) Dad!
- Mike!
Come on. (grunts)
(Mike) Dad! Dad!
- Why are you doing this?
- Shut up!
- Come on, Dad!
- Quiet, kid.
(honking)
He's still coming.
- Oh, shit. Here he comes.
- Dad!
Come on! Let's get the hell
out of here! Hurry!
He's staying with me!
You tell him that! You tell him!
- You OK? You all right?
- Yeah. Are you OK?
- I'm all right.
- Yeah, you'll live.
Thanks. Come on.
You sure you're OK?
Yeah.
Who were those guys anyway?
Better ask your grandfather.
- (sighs) Look at my truck.
- Oh, man.
(siren)
- I got here as soon as I could.
- Yes.
We don't have much
of a custody case.
Why the hell is that?
I had my best researchers run down
every applicable court case
for the last 100 years.
Bottom line, Jason: no judge is going
to award you custody of Michael.
The court will give him to Hawk
unless he can't support him.
How can he support him?
The son of a bitch lost everything.
He can't even support himself!
Anyway, there's always
a way to bend the law.
Isn't it your job?!
Why don't you find the loophole?
I want my boy.
- Come on. Over the top. (chuckles)
- Over the top.
Oh, oh. Mercy, mercy, mercy.
You're getting too good.
You're gonna be a great one, kid.
- Almost as good as you, right?
- Well...
I think you'll be better than me.
Think you're gonna
do good in Vegas?
I'm betting on it.
I'd like to get enough money together
and buy a small company,
and hire some smart guy
like you to be president.
- That's not a bad idea.
- It's a great idea.
- But what if you lose?
- You're not supposed to say that.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Sure.
Why'd you leave us?
Well...
- I had some reasons.
- That's not an answer.
All I can say, Mike,
is I made a mistake. I know that.
Sometimes it happens in life.
We all make mistakes.
But it won't happen again.
- Yeah, you're gonna be a great one.
- Think so?
Yes. I'm glad I'm not going
against you, tough guy.
We saved the patient.
But before in the ICU...
...well, we had a little problem.
- You OK?
- Yeah. How do I look?
You look great.
You're not nervous, are you?
Come on, let's go see her.
Excuse me,
could you tell me what room
- Mrs. Christina Hawk is in, please?
- What is she admitted for?
Heart surgery. She'd probably be
in a private room.
- Can I ask who you are?
- I'm her husband.
Possibly you'd rather talk to one
of the doctors on the case.
- Why, what's wrong?
- Excuse me.
Mr. Hawk, I'm sorry.
Your wife died this afternoon
in the operating room.
No.
Mike.
Mike!
(crying)
Mike.
If you wouldn't have come
to pick me up, I would've seen her.
I wouldn't be riding around in that
truck while she was dying.
Nobody knew, Mike.
You've never been around
when anybody needed you.
Taxi! Take me to the Cutler estate.
I'm going home.
Mike.
Mike!
(minister) We are gathered here
to commit the body
of Christina Marie Cutler Hawk
to the ground from which it came.
We commend her souI to the Lord
that in His mercy...
That must be the husband.
(minister)... that in His mercy,
she may attain everlasting life.
And now, let us pray
with the Psalmist.
The Lord is my shepherd,
I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie down
in green pastures.
He leadeth me
beside the still waters.
He restoreth my souI.
He leadeth me in the paths of
righteousness for his name's sake.
Surely goodness and mercy shall
follow me all the days of my life
and will dwell
in the house of the Lord forever.
Yes?
I'd like to talk
to Jason Cutler, please.
You're not wanted here.
Would you tell him Lincoln Hawk
would like to talk to him?
Like I said, you're not wanted here.
I want to see my boy.
Move it out.
Move. Get this thing the hell
out of here before I call the police.
(engine starts)
That guy ain't coming back.
He's a loser.
(guard yelling)
(guard) Stop! What are you doing?!
Get back here!
(guard #2) Call the cops!
I'm going around back!
Mike! Mike!
Hawk!
What the hell have you done?
Mike.
Come with me, please. Mike, please.
Do you actually think that you can
get away with what you've done?
You think you can come in here,
destroy my home
and take Michael with you?
Michael Cutler is my boy!
You deserted him years ago!
That's a fact that you can't change
no matter what you do! Damn you!
Damn you.
Dad! Dad!
Come on, let him go!
- Go to your room.
- Please! Dad!
- Come on, Grandfather!
(siren)
Go to your room now! Go!
Mike. Mike.
We got him. Let him go.
Keep his arms behind him.
You have the right to remain silent.
If you give up the right
to remain silent...
All the way out. Slowly.
Move your ass.
You Hawk? Let's go.
Wait here.
Straight ahead.
There's somebody here
to see you, Hawk.
- Yeah, right over there.
- Sit down.
I'll make this brief, Hawk.
I'm Tim Salanger,
Mr. Cutler's personaI secretary.
As you can see, you've got
a serious problem on your hands.
More than ever now, you'll need money
for attorneys, additional expenses.
What we want is for you
to leave the state.
Don't come back, we won't prosecute.
If you decide to contest
the whole matter of legal custody,
you won't have a prayer.
We retain the finest law firms.
That's it. What do you say?
- What's Mike say?
- Ask him yourself.
Michael.
At ease, Mike.
Now, you're not gonna tell me
to leave too, are you?
No.
That's good. I was beginning
to think I wasn't popular.
I don't know what to think.
Mike, I know you don't trust me.
I don't blame you.
I haven't earned that yet.
I just feeI like I have a home here.
You know, I...
I mean, if I went with you,
where would we go?
Where would we end up?
Together is all I can guarantee.
You say this now, and then you leave.
Mike, I'm just a father who messed up
pretty bad, I know that.
I've done things real wrong.
Now I want to try to fix
everything up as best as I can.
And I want to...
...give you what's inside of me.
I may not have much
and I may never have a lot.
But I've got something inside
I want to give to the only person
who means something to me.
You.
I can't.
I can't go with you.
Can't?
I'm sorry.
I understand.
Mike, I want you
to remember something.
The world meets nobody halfway,
remember that.
You gotta do what's best for you.
Always do that.
Should I draw up the papers?
Yeah.
(♪ "Meet Me Half Way")
(man) I appreciate your feelings
about your truck.
Best offer I can make,
cash though, 7,000.
- Take it or leave it.
- Not giving me much of a choice.
OK, you got a deal mental.
I'd like to keep the hawk,
though, OK?
(man) Take it.
(announcer) Good morning. I'd like to
welcome all of you to this year's...
- What are the odds on Lincoln Hawk?
- The odds on Hawk?
Lincoln Hawk's 20 to one.
20 to one, paI. ReaI long shot.
I'd like to bet 7,000 on him.
That's what I call gambling.
(man) Linc Hawk...
John Grizzly: 238.
190? Thanks.
That's wrong. Excuse me, buddy.
Hold on a second. John Grizzly: 238.
(announcer) Italian competitors,
report to your coach.
What are you doing?
Where are you going? Stop!
(announcer) Arm wrestling is
a combination of
speed, strength and technique,
coupled with mental attitude
and dedication.
- (driver) Come on!
- Move it! Go!
(announcer) Soon,
the preliminaries will be under way.
- (car horn)
- (man) Hey, you idiot!
(announcer) Welcome to the arm wrestling
world championship competition.
(cheering)
(announcer) There are seven different
weight classes for men and women.
They come from all over the world:
Japan, France, Italy, Switzerland.
Truly the best arm wrestlers
in the entire world.
(yells)
One reminder, once again,
this is a double elimination
competition.
You have to lose twice to be out.
In other words, if you lose once,
you still have one more chance.
The preliminary rounds this morning
and the men's finals tonight.
And don't forget the women. They're
competing for $50,000 in prize money.
Are we ready, referees?
Start the competition!
Good luck to all of you!
Ready? Go!
(♪ "Winner Takes ItAII" by Sammy Hagar)
You ain't shit!
(referee) Winner: Bull Hurley.
(announcer) A win for the five-time
world champion, Bull Hurley!
(referee) Go!
Winner!
That's a winner!
(announcer) Frenchman André Bouvier,
and a newcomer, Lincoln Hawk.
And Hawk takes the win!
He'll be one to watch.
On to the teamster.
Harry Bosco has the win.
Hey, boy. You just can't leave
this truck here like that.
You can keep it.
Hey, you! Come back here!
Come here, you!
(announcer) Billy Bob from Texas,
the southern champion.
He'll be tough to beat here.
There. There's our car.
Take me to Mr. Cutler's plane.
Go!
- Go!
(yells)
Winner!
(announcer) We have trouble
with our German friend.
Looks like an injury on table three.
(yells)
Ready? Go!
Winner!
Chicken shit.
(announcer) We're already down
to the last 32 competitors.
Bull Hurley.
He's still the man to beat.
He's not to make it to the Hilton.
Is that understood?
Yes, sir.
Come on! Grizzly!
- (growls)
- (yells)
Come on!
Come on! Come on!
Winner!
(announcer) And that concludes
the women's competition.
Mr. John Grizzly!
- Winner!
- (cheering)
- Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome back to our
world championship competition.
We're approaching the main event.
First of all, the semifinals.
Fighting will take place
on these four tables
and the eight best arm wrestlers
in the world will be competing.
- There's Michael.
- I'll cover the back.
(announcer) They've come from
every nation on earth.
500 competitors started.
Now we're down to the final eight.
Let me remind you.
Let me remind you, please.
This is a double elimination
competition.
If you lose twice, you're out.
Double elimination competition.
They've come from everywhere
for a chance to win $100,000
in prize money.
They will also have
the opportunity to win
a $250,000 Volvo White tractor truck.
Right now, though, let's introduce
our eight semifinalists.
They're the best
in the world of arm wrestling.
Let's introduce John Grizzly,
three-time winner from the
World Arm Wrestling Association.
When I get to the table, that person,
I don't care who they are,
is my mortal enemy.
I hate them.
(announcer) John Grizzly, right here.
Also coming up here, Mad Dog Madison.
I'm not so enthused about people
patting me on the back,
saying "You're the best. "
I don't need people to do that to me.
If I win, it's just because I wanted
to be the best, one time in my life.
Mad Dog Madison.
Harry Bosco, right here.
My whole body is an engine.
This is a fireplug and
I'm going to light him up.
- (yells)
- (announcer) Harry Bosco!
The Canadian champion,
two years running: CarI Adams.
I should be able
to blow them away real easy.
There's a lot more
technique involved,
and you can't beat experience.
(yells)
(announcer) CarI Adams,
ladies and gentlemen.
And the newcomer from the truckers'
division, Lincoln Hawk, over here.
To tell you the truth, the truck
is the most important thing for me.
I don't really...
It doesn't matter
if I become the champion or anything.
That's not the most important...
I need this truck.
(announcer) Lincoln Hawk,
from the truckers' division.
And finally,
five-time arm wrestling
world champion Bull Hurley!
- Let's hear it for Bull.
- (audience) Bull! Bull! Bull!
I drive truck,
break arms and arm wrestle.
It's what I love to do,
it's what I do best.
(announcer) Bull, ladies and gentlemen,
trying for an unprecedented
sixth championship title.
Being number one is everything.
There is no second place.
Second sucks.
(announcer) And now, semifinalists,
will you please take the tables?
This is a double elimination
tournament.
Two losses and you're out.
Yeah, John! Come on!
(announcer) All right, gentlemen.
Let's start the competition.
Good luck.
We have Linc Hawk
and John Grizzly competing.
- Get him off my thumb.
- (announcer) This'll be a tough match.
Get him off my thumb.
(man) Hey, what the hell
is that kid doing there?
(announcer) There are two
basic styles...
- He's still got my thumb.
- His thumb's OK.
Ready? Go!
Watch your position!
- (man) Winner, Harry Bosco!
- Winner, Harry Bosco!
Winner!
(announcer) On table number two,
Lincoln Hawk and John Grizzly!
This should be a tough match.
Grizzly's getting him over the top.
Grizzly looks like
he's got Linc Hawk in trouble.
(audience cheering)
(announcer) John Grizzly is our winner.
Grizzly has won again.
And the newcomer, Lincoln Hawk,
has lost his first finals match.
Remember, ladies and gentlemen.
This is a double elimination.
Each of these semifinalists
have another chance.
You have to lose twice
to be out of the competition.
(all shouting)
Get him up to my suite.
I wanna talk to him.
Yeah. A little harder.
I hope I didn't tear anything.
Yeah, that's better.
- Hawk?
- What do you want?
Mr. Cutler wants a word with you.
He's waiting
in the presidential suite.
- Ed?
- (Ed) Yeah.
- How long before I go on again?
- You got about a half-hour.
I'll be there.
Come in, Hawk.
You want a drink?
You don't have to stay sharp.
I understand you already
lost your first match.
- What do you want, Cutler?
- We don't have to be enemies.
I never wanted to be your enemy.
All right, then.
Let's get right to it.
With Christina gone...
I have no family left in my life,
except for Michael.
You never had anything,
so you have nothing to lose.
Hawk, you can believe
what you want to.
You're a deserter, plain and simple.
You deserted your wife and your son.
You were tearing us apart.
Don't try to clear your conscience
at my expense.
You're a liar. You deserted them.
- Are you finished?
- I'm not through with you yet.
Come on outside.
I want to show you something.
Come on!
Down there in the parking lot
in front of the hotel.
That's the finest rig
that money can buy.
If you want it, it's yours.
Here's a check for $500,000.
- Take it and get out of my life.
- What are you trying to do?
I gave you custody of the boy.
What more do you want?
I'm making things easy for you.
You don't need Michael
as a meaI ticket anymore.
So take the truck, take the money.
Start a new life.
Start your own family!
I got a family.
When this is over,
I'm coming to get him.
You're going back on your word.
- Yeah.
- You signed over custody.
He'll never go with you
because you're a loser.
You've always been a loser!
- Mr. Cutler is talking to you.
- I'm through talking.
We continue
with our semifinal series of matches.
You're mine.
(announcer) This is a
double elimination tournament.
Any competitor who loses twice out
of the eight on these four tables...
I'm going through you
like gas through a funnel.
You're mine, mister. (grunts)
- Get him off of my thumb.
- Keep your elbow in the cup!
- I don't see it.
- Put your elbow in the cup!
I don't see it.
Ready?
Go!
(yells)
(cheering)
(announcer) Mad Dog Madison will be
the next opponent for Linc Hawk.
Bull Hurley has beaten Harry Bosco
and goes on to the finals.
CarI Adams is our winner.
CarI Adams goes on to the finals.
We're ready for the last matches
of the semifinal series.
The winners go on to the finals.
Over here, we have Mad Dog Madison...
(yells)
Come on! Come on!
Winner, Lincoln Hawk!
(announcer) Linc Hawk
has beaten Mad Dog Madison!
And Linc Hawk goes on to the finals.
(man) Next cab. Move it up.
(announcer) We're approaching
the most important event
of this unique and exciting
competition: the final phase.
In the world of arm wrestling
we call this "Over the top".
Ladies and gentlemen,
let's bring on our four finalists.
Our first finalist,
from Jacksonville, Florida,
undefeated in five years.
Let's bring him on. Bull Hurley!
(audience) Bull! Bull! Bull!
(announcer) His opponent,
two-time Canadian champion,
Slammin' CarI Adams!
From Boston,
pride of the teamsters, Harry Bosco.
(whistles)
And finally, the newcomer
from the independent truckers,
Lincoln Hawk!
(cheering)
Whoo!
(announcer) Ladies and gentlemen,
let's give our four finalists
a big round of applause!
- I can't lose, Hawk.
- (referee) Shut up!
- Say it.
- (referee) Get your elbows down.
I can't lose. Come on, let's go.
I can't lose, Hawk.
(announcer) Hawk is trying to stay calm,
but inside you know
he has to be boiling. Look at him!
A lot of talking
to the referee going on, too.
Dad, over here!
Dad! Go, Dad!
- First you, then Hurley.
- That's two fouls!
- I'm psyching up the son of a bitch.
- Get your elbow in there!
- Dad!
- Michael, come with me.
Come here, Michael!
Come here! Stop! Come back.
Ready? Go!
(announcer) He wears him out.
OK, ladies and gentlemen.
Bull Hurley and CarI Adams
going at it right over there.
Come on, man!
Get your shoulders square.
I'm not gonna start
until we got it squared.
Lock it back. Ready? Go!
Winner: Lincoln Hawk!
- I wasn't ready yet!
- It was fair! You lost!
Man, I wasn't ready!
Hey, I've been cheated!
I wasn't ready, I said!
Set it off, man!
(grunting)
(announcer) Bull Hurley goes on to the
final match of the competition.
Dad!
- Dad!
- Mike.
- What are you doing here?
- Hi, Dad.
- I had to see you.
- How'd you get here?
Dad,
it's a long story, but...
Listen, I want to stay with you.
- Mike, do you?
- Yeah.
I want you to stay, too,
but I don't think your grandfather
is gonna let that happen.
But I want to be with you, Dad.
I want to be with you too,
but, Mike...
I don't have any money.
I sold the truck.
That's OK. You're going to win
like you said, remember?
You'll win that big old truck
and you can start your own business.
Mike, in this last match
I think I pulled a little too hard.
And this guy I'm going against,
Bull Hurley,
he hasn't lost
in about five years and...
I don't know, he's good, Mike.
He's real good and...
I just don't know.
Are you saying you're gonna lose?
I might.
I don't believe this.
All that talk about never giving up
was all lies. You never believed it.
And what you said to me, remember?
Now is the time to do it
for yourself.
The world meets nobody halfway.
If you want it, you take it.
You weren't talking about me,
you were talking about yourself.
Mike, please.
Now is your chance,
Dad, don't you see?
I don't care about
what happened before,
so stop trying to prove yourself.
It doesn't matter
if you win or lose, Dad.
I don't care about that.
All I care
about is being with you, Dad.
- I love you.
- I love you too, Mike.
We'll try, OK?
That's a big guy.
Well, so are you.
(announcer) Ladies and gentlemen,
the final match.
(cheering)
The referees from the International
Arm Wrestling Council.
The finalist,
undefeated in five years,
five-time world champion,
Bull Hurley.
And, ladies and gentlemen,
the sole remaining challenger,
Lincoln Hawk, the man who
has surprised everybody here today.
If you want it, you gotta take it.
(announcer) The challenger
and the champion.
- You're mine!
- Bull Hurley and Lincoln Hawk.
Or should we say David and Goliath?
The winner here tonight
will walk out with the world cup,
a $250,000 truck
from the Volvo White company,
$100,000 in cash, and the title
of arm wrestling world champion.
He doesn't belong
on my arm wrestling table.
That's my area, that's my game.
He's got no shittin' business there.
(announcer) Our two finalists are now
psyching each other out.
Linc Hawk's giving away just
about 100 pounds to Bull Hurley.
That's a lot to give away
in arm wrestling.
- You're mine.
- Let's go.
(announcer) Let the competition begin.
May the best man win!
Come on, chicken shit.
(referee) Place your elbows here.
Hawk, you too.
What I do is, I just try to take
my hat and I turn it around,
and it's like a switch that goes on.
And when the switch goes on,
I feel like another person, I feel...
I don't know, I feeI like a...
Like a truck, like a machine.
I own you.
You've been ducking me for years.
You've got no chance. You know that?
- Hawk, back in here now.
- Don't let him psych you!
Remember what you told me.
You can do it. I know!
- Get in here! Come on!
- (referee) Square up the shoulder.
You got no power, Hawk.
You got no power.
I'm gonna give you
a world of hurt, little man.
And all I want to do is hurt him,
cripple him, get him off the table,
and so he never dares
try to compete against me again.
Ready? Go!
Get him, Dad!
Down! Down!
Way to go!
Pull it! Pull it, Dad! Over the top!
- He's letting go.
- No, he's not.
- He's letting go!
Go! Go! Get him!
Hawk!
- He let go!
- Take your hands away.
You asshole!
- You touch the referee once more.
- You don't know what you can do.
You're mine.
Can't you understand that?
You're mine, asshole!
When the two arms come apart,
the strap will be put on.
- Put your elbows down.
- I'll rip your shittin' arm off.
(announcer) They won't be able
to slip after this.
I own you!
(referee) Open your thumbs.
Michael, we're going home
as soon as this is over.
Dad, come on, you've got to win.
You can do it, I know you can.
You're a chicken shit.
- You can't get away from me now.
- That's two fouls!
You all right?
Your nose hurt, Hawk?
Dad, come on, take him.
Over the top, Dad! Over the top.
Get in here. Come on!
Ready? Go!
You ain't shit!
Oh, what a move by Bull Hurley!
He has Linc Hawk over the line.
Linc Hawk is in trouble,
in big trouble.
He's going down!
I'll break his shittin' arm!
- Come on, Dad!
- (announcer) He's coming back!
This match is unbelievable.
You're nothing, I tell you!
You ain't nothing!
Dad!
(announcer) Bull Hurley
with a great move!
Move it!
(announcer) It looks like Hawk
is in big trouble.
Bull Hurley looks like he's got him.
It looks like
Hawk's strength is going.
- (grunts) I own you!
- Dad!
Dad, get him!
(announcer) All of a sudden, here we go.
Linc Hawk's making a comeback.
It looks dead even right now.
This match has been going on
for over a minute.
What a match this is.
It's all gonna boil down
to who wants it most.
Dad, yeah.
Maybe Bull Hurley's just too strong.
Maybe he's just too strong.
It looks like Hawk's
in big trouble right now.
Bull Hurley looks like he's got him.
(yells)
- Go, Bull!
- Get him!
Come on!
Go! Go! Go!
(announcer) And now it's dead even.
What a match!
Yeah!
(yells)
Winner!
(announcer) The new world champion.
Hawk is the new champion!
Champion of the world,
ladies and gentlemen!
Incredible! Unbelievable!
The world champion has been defeated.
We have a new world champion:
Linc Hawk!
A new world champion.
This is unbelievable!
A challenger out of nowhere.
Nobody ever thought
he'd have a chance to win.
We have a new world champion!
(♪ "In This Country")
(announcer) Linc Hawk!
Bull Hurley has been defeated!
Out of nowhere, the challenger,
the winner, Linc Hawk.
This is unbelievable!
- All right!
- Yeah!
Why don't we start
our own trucking company?
We could call it "Son and Hawk".
- Son and Hawk.
- I like it.
That's not too bad.
But how do you think
"Hawk and Son" sounds?
- Hawk and Son?
- What do you think of that?
Hawk and Son.
Hey, I think it just might work.
Come on.
(♪ "Take It Higher" by Larry Greene)
Hey, can I drive later, Dad?
You're an equal partner, aren't you?