1
00:04:55,044 --> 00:04:56,336
What the hell?

2
00:05:02,218 --> 00:05:04,177
Hey.

3
00:05:09,225 --> 00:05:12,686
You know which side of the border you're on?

4
00:05:12,770 --> 00:05:15,230
You got a name, boy?

5
00:05:16,441 --> 00:05:19,151
Guess...

6
00:05:19,235 --> 00:05:22,154
somethin' must have
cut your tongue off.

7
00:05:24,365 --> 00:05:26,366
Either that, or...

8
00:05:28,411 --> 00:05:33,332
you've got somethin'... to hide.

9
00:05:33,416 --> 00:05:37,085
Ah.

10
00:05:37,170 --> 00:05:39,087
Never can tell.

11
00:05:41,883 --> 00:05:45,844
You hear me plain enough.

12
00:05:50,224 --> 00:05:52,142
Ah.

13
00:05:54,437 --> 00:05:56,438
"Walter R. Henderson."

14
00:05:59,108 --> 00:06:01,276
Now, I want to ask you
one last question.

15
00:06:03,529 --> 00:06:06,531
You see this here card?

16
00:06:06,616 --> 00:06:08,617
Is it you?

17
00:06:09,911 --> 00:06:12,621
Or a relative of yours?

18
00:06:14,832 --> 00:06:18,210
Well, I'm gonna call up this number...

19
00:06:18,294 --> 00:06:21,797
and see if they can tell me who you are.

20
00:06:21,881 --> 00:06:25,884
I ain't got beds enough
to be puttin' up mutes.

21
00:06:33,559 --> 00:06:37,270
Operator, I need a line out, please.

22
00:06:39,565 --> 00:06:42,526
Los Angeles, California.

23
00:06:42,610 --> 00:06:44,611
Area code -

24
00:06:52,620 --> 00:06:55,122
Uh, what?

25
00:06:55,206 --> 00:06:59,418
Well, can you - Can you tell me the exact
location of your hospital down there?

26
00:07:01,087 --> 00:07:03,463
Uh, where the hell's that?

27
00:07:05,258 --> 00:07:08,218
Oh, okay. All right.
Yeah, um -

28
00:07:08,302 --> 00:07:11,138
Okay, I'll be there.
I'll get there as fast as I can.

29
00:07:11,222 --> 00:07:14,808
Just - Will you tell him
that I'm coming, okay? Okay.

30
00:07:20,523 --> 00:07:23,275
Steven, I think you will have to change that.

31
00:07:23,359 --> 00:07:24,317
This section right here?

32
00:07:24,402 --> 00:07:26,153
Yeah, because it's in the copy.

33
00:07:26,237 --> 00:07:28,780
Anne, honey?

34
00:07:28,865 --> 00:07:32,784
- I just got the strangest phone call.
- Who from?

35
00:07:32,869 --> 00:07:36,830
From some hospital in South Texas -
a place called Terlingua.

36
00:07:38,374 --> 00:07:40,292
They say they found Travis.

37
00:07:40,376 --> 00:07:42,252
Oh, no.

38
00:07:42,336 --> 00:07:44,754
What are you going to do?

39
00:07:44,839 --> 00:07:48,091
- Well, I'll go down and-and get him.
- Oh, Walt.

40
00:07:48,176 --> 00:07:50,677
What am I gonna do?
I can't leave him down there.

41
00:07:54,390 --> 00:07:56,224
What about Hunter?

42
00:07:56,309 --> 00:07:58,351
What am I supposed to tell him?

43
00:07:58,436 --> 00:08:01,980
Uh, well, just tell him
I had to go on a business trip.

44
00:08:02,064 --> 00:08:04,107
I mean about Travis.

45
00:08:09,947 --> 00:08:12,199
Well.

46
00:08:12,283 --> 00:08:14,618
I guess you better
tell him the truth.

47
00:08:35,848 --> 00:08:37,724
10 to Van Horn.

48
00:08:37,808 --> 00:08:40,268
90... to Alpine.

49
00:08:40,353 --> 00:08:42,270
118 south.

50
00:08:44,315 --> 00:08:46,274
Terlingua.

51
00:09:16,847 --> 00:09:19,099
You must be the brother of the mute.

52
00:09:20,601 --> 00:09:22,519
- Mute?
- Ja.

53
00:09:23,646 --> 00:09:27,107
They couldn't squeeze
the time of day out of him.

54
00:09:28,734 --> 00:09:31,444
Must be in a kind of jam, huh?

55
00:09:32,863 --> 00:09:35,365
I don't know.
I haven't seen him in over four years.

56
00:09:36,367 --> 00:09:38,493
Is that right?

57
00:09:38,578 --> 00:09:42,998
Well, a lot can happen to a man
in four years, I guess.

58
00:09:44,000 --> 00:09:48,003
All kinds of trouble - expensive trouble.

59
00:09:48,087 --> 00:09:49,879
What do you mean?

60
00:09:49,964 --> 00:09:52,007
Well, down here...

61
00:09:52,091 --> 00:09:55,093
a man gets himself
into a fix sometimes.

62
00:09:55,177 --> 00:09:58,096
And it costs a little to get him out.

63
00:09:58,180 --> 00:10:00,181
You understand what I mean.

64
00:10:01,183 --> 00:10:03,643
I don't understand you.

65
00:10:03,728 --> 00:10:06,605
I wish you'd get to the point,
'cause I'd like to see my brother.

66
00:10:08,691 --> 00:10:10,609
All right, sir.

67
00:10:10,693 --> 00:10:14,029
But first I would like
to ask you something.

68
00:10:14,113 --> 00:10:18,366
Did your brother ever get hisself
into a car wreck?

69
00:10:22,163 --> 00:10:25,957
Uh, car wreck.
No, uh, not that I know of.

70
00:10:26,042 --> 00:10:30,253
Then he must be mixing
with some hard company.

71
00:10:30,338 --> 00:10:34,758
I'd like to see my brother now,
if you don't mind.

72
00:10:36,135 --> 00:10:39,763
- He disappeared.
- You mean he's not here?

73
00:10:39,847 --> 00:10:41,765
After I came all this way?

74
00:10:41,849 --> 00:10:45,185
He's been gone since early this morning.

75
00:10:46,604 --> 00:10:49,939
We have his possessions nevertheless.

76
00:10:50,024 --> 00:10:53,485
Saved them.

77
00:10:53,569 --> 00:10:55,904
We'd be glad to turn 'em over to you...

78
00:10:55,988 --> 00:11:00,700
as soon as you take care
of our little reward.

79
00:12:33,836 --> 00:12:35,336
Travis?

80
00:12:38,340 --> 00:12:40,341
Travis. Hey.

81
00:12:44,096 --> 00:12:46,598
Don't you recognize me?
It's Walt.

82
00:12:54,356 --> 00:12:56,274
It's your brother - Walt.

83
00:13:14,251 --> 00:13:18,671
What the hell happened to you anyway?
You look like 40 miles of rough road.

84
00:13:29,517 --> 00:13:31,643
Come on. Let's get in the car. Trav?

85
00:13:33,312 --> 00:13:35,230
Come on.

86
00:13:37,733 --> 00:13:39,651
Yeah.

87
00:13:44,698 --> 00:13:46,616
Come on.

88
00:14:27,366 --> 00:14:29,659
Here, Trav. Here's your stuff.

89
00:14:31,662 --> 00:14:33,663
I got that back at that clinic back there.

90
00:14:35,583 --> 00:14:39,627
Sure picked a hell of a spot to land in.
I don't blame you for running out of it.

91
00:14:44,633 --> 00:14:47,844
Um, look, Trav...

92
00:14:47,928 --> 00:14:50,388
we got quite a bit of travelin' to do here.

93
00:14:50,472 --> 00:14:52,807
You're not gonna clam up
the whole way, are you?

94
00:14:54,018 --> 00:14:55,768
I mean, it'll get kind of lonely.

95
00:15:00,274 --> 00:15:02,275
Trav?

96
00:15:03,819 --> 00:15:07,739
Would you mind telling me where you
disappeared to for the last four years?

97
00:15:12,953 --> 00:15:15,330
Uh, have you seen Jane or talked to her?

98
00:15:18,459 --> 00:15:21,669
Gee, Anne and I, we sort of gave up on you.

99
00:15:21,754 --> 00:15:25,590
We actually -
We thought you were dead, boy.

100
00:16:01,877 --> 00:16:03,836
It's pretty, uh -

101
00:16:14,723 --> 00:16:16,724
Okay.

102
00:16:24,984 --> 00:16:26,985
Well -

103
00:16:27,069 --> 00:16:29,320
Yeah.

104
00:16:31,407 --> 00:16:34,242
Well, gee, Trav,
maybe you wanna get cleaned up...

105
00:16:34,326 --> 00:16:36,494
you know, take a shower or something?

106
00:16:36,578 --> 00:16:39,831
Um, I think I'll go back into town
and get you some new clothes.

107
00:16:39,915 --> 00:16:41,916
You could use a new set of clothes,
couldn't you?

108
00:16:44,086 --> 00:16:46,004
Wh-What size shoes you wear?

109
00:16:47,673 --> 00:16:49,882
Right. We'll see.

110
00:16:53,721 --> 00:16:55,638
I'm probably one size bigger, huh?

111
00:16:58,058 --> 00:17:00,893
So, where'd you find that beard?

112
00:17:00,978 --> 00:17:04,147
It's pretty snazzy.

113
00:17:06,400 --> 00:17:09,652
Okay. I'll zip into town
and zip right back.

114
00:17:11,113 --> 00:17:13,072
I won't be gone long.

115
00:17:20,330 --> 00:17:22,790
You'll be okay, won't you, Trav?

116
00:17:25,294 --> 00:17:27,920
Yeah, I'll - I'll be right back.

117
00:19:19,491 --> 00:19:21,492
Damn it.

118
00:20:19,301 --> 00:20:22,428
You mind telling me
where you're headed, Trav?

119
00:20:25,974 --> 00:20:28,267
What's out there?

120
00:20:34,274 --> 00:20:36,275
There's nothin' out there.

121
00:20:38,820 --> 00:20:40,821
Don't you trust me or somethin'? Huh?

122
00:20:44,451 --> 00:20:47,495
I'm just trying to help you, Trav.
That's all.

123
00:20:52,668 --> 00:20:54,877
Now come on. It's all right.

124
00:20:54,962 --> 00:20:58,172
Come on with me in the car. Huh?

125
00:22:03,905 --> 00:22:06,824
Kind of feels good
to be in new clothes, huh?

126
00:22:29,765 --> 00:22:32,683
- Hello.
- Hi. Hunter? It's Daddy.

127
00:22:33,685 --> 00:22:37,438
- I thought you'd be in bed already.
- I'm watching TV.

128
00:22:37,522 --> 00:22:40,775
Guess who I'm visiting here in Texas.

129
00:22:41,860 --> 00:22:44,945
- Who?
- Your father.

130
00:22:45,030 --> 00:22:47,031
Do you remember your father?

131
00:22:48,325 --> 00:22:50,701
- No.
- Not at all?

132
00:22:50,786 --> 00:22:53,621
I remember he was kind of skinny.

133
00:22:53,705 --> 00:22:56,832
- He was?
- I think he was.

134
00:22:56,917 --> 00:22:59,710
- Well, guess what.
- I don't know.

135
00:22:59,795 --> 00:23:01,921
I'm gonna bring him home to visit.

136
00:23:16,728 --> 00:23:18,646
Travis.

137
00:23:21,024 --> 00:23:24,693
Do you remember your little boy? Hunter.

138
00:23:27,656 --> 00:23:30,074
Well, he's with us.

139
00:23:30,158 --> 00:23:33,452
He's been living with Anne and me
ever since you disappeared.

140
00:23:35,163 --> 00:23:38,958
We didn't know what else to do,
so we just kept him.

141
00:23:41,002 --> 00:23:43,462
One day, he was just standing at the door.

142
00:23:44,464 --> 00:23:48,551
All he could tell us was that
someone brought him there in a car.

143
00:23:49,845 --> 00:23:52,638
He didn't know
what had happened to you or Jane.

144
00:23:53,849 --> 00:23:57,601
We tried everything we could think of
to find you or Jane.

145
00:23:57,686 --> 00:23:59,854
We tried to locate her.
She'd vanished too.

146
00:24:01,189 --> 00:24:03,399
We didn't know what else to do.

147
00:24:08,780 --> 00:24:10,865
Travis...

148
00:24:10,949 --> 00:24:13,117
I don't know
what kind of trouble you got into.

149
00:24:14,536 --> 00:24:16,579
I don't know what happened.

150
00:24:18,039 --> 00:24:20,708
But, damn it, I'm your brother, man.

151
00:24:22,335 --> 00:24:24,378
You can talk to me.

152
00:24:27,716 --> 00:24:29,842
I'm tired of doing all the talking.

153
00:25:13,261 --> 00:25:15,221
Fill it with unleaded, please.

154
00:25:17,724 --> 00:25:20,142
You know, I'm gettin' a little sick
of this silence routine.

155
00:25:20,227 --> 00:25:23,312
You can talk.

156
00:25:32,322 --> 00:25:34,490
I can be silent too, you know.

157
00:25:37,619 --> 00:25:40,204
I'd just as soon that both of us keep our mouths
shut for the whole rest of the trip.

158
00:25:40,288 --> 00:25:43,415
- Paris.
- You know - What?

159
00:25:45,293 --> 00:25:47,294
Paris.

160
00:25:51,967 --> 00:25:55,636
Paris?

161
00:25:57,430 --> 00:25:59,974
Did you ever go to Paris?

162
00:26:01,101 --> 00:26:04,895
- No.
- Could we go there now?

163
00:26:07,315 --> 00:26:09,233
It's a little out of the way.

164
00:26:12,612 --> 00:26:15,406
Uh, no, I've never even been to Europe.

165
00:26:15,490 --> 00:26:17,616
Anne keeps wanting to go there.

166
00:26:17,701 --> 00:26:19,827
'Cause, well, she's from France,
you remember?

167
00:26:21,037 --> 00:26:25,082
But we never seem to find the time
'cause my company keeps me kind of busy.

168
00:26:40,348 --> 00:26:42,349
Let's go, Trav.

169
00:26:45,270 --> 00:26:48,147
- What's the matter?
- Where we going?

170
00:26:48,231 --> 00:26:50,274
We're gonna fly to L.A.

171
00:26:50,358 --> 00:26:52,610
You're not afraid of flying, are you?

172
00:26:52,694 --> 00:26:54,820
We're... leaving the ground?

173
00:26:54,904 --> 00:26:58,073
- Yeah.
- Why?

174
00:26:58,158 --> 00:27:00,576
Because it's too far to drive.

175
00:27:00,660 --> 00:27:02,953
It would take an extra two days.
I can't afford the time, Trav.

176
00:27:03,038 --> 00:27:05,205
- Why?
- Be -

177
00:27:05,290 --> 00:27:07,333
Look, it's just easier to fly, Trav.

178
00:27:07,417 --> 00:27:10,377
It's faster. Come on.

179
00:27:29,064 --> 00:27:31,023
Let's get you home, okay?

180
00:27:31,107 --> 00:27:33,901
I'm gonna get you home, get you settled,
and then you can do whatever you want.

181
00:27:33,985 --> 00:27:35,569
Let me out, or I'll jump.

182
00:27:35,654 --> 00:27:38,864
Sir, we can't stop the plane
every time somebody gets terrified.

183
00:27:38,948 --> 00:27:42,242
You don't get on a plane
and then refuse to leave the ground.

184
00:27:42,327 --> 00:27:45,663
You don't do things like that.
This isn't the wilderness.

185
00:27:45,747 --> 00:27:47,831
You're living with people now. Okay?

186
00:27:47,916 --> 00:27:49,458
You should've hired a private plane.

187
00:27:49,542 --> 00:27:51,669
Do you realize how many people
you're detaining?

188
00:27:51,753 --> 00:27:53,671
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.

189
00:27:53,755 --> 00:27:55,673
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Okay?

190
00:27:55,757 --> 00:27:58,634
- Okay, I'm fine now.
- Bye now.

191
00:27:58,718 --> 00:28:01,428
This is getting a little ridiculous, Travis.

192
00:28:02,847 --> 00:28:05,307
Are you gonna leave me?

193
00:28:05,392 --> 00:28:07,393
No, I'm not gonna leave you.

194
00:28:08,603 --> 00:28:10,854
It's all right if you leave me.

195
00:28:10,939 --> 00:28:12,981
I don't know, honey, no.

196
00:28:13,066 --> 00:28:15,317
He just - He just panicked or something.

197
00:28:16,820 --> 00:28:19,071
Well, it won't do any good
to try another plane.

198
00:28:19,155 --> 00:28:22,658
It wasn't the plane.
He'll just get off again.

199
00:28:22,742 --> 00:28:25,160
Well, we're just gonna
have to drive it. That's all.

200
00:28:25,286 --> 00:28:29,123
Message for Joy Stockwell. Joy Stockwell.
Yeah, it'll take a good two days.

201
00:28:29,207 --> 00:28:31,583
Austin will arrive at any minute.

202
00:28:31,668 --> 00:28:35,212
I don't understand why you have to have
the very same car you had before.

203
00:28:35,296 --> 00:28:36,922
They're all alike.

204
00:28:37,006 --> 00:28:41,260
All the cars we have here are 'birds,
Olds, Chevies or whatever.

205
00:28:41,344 --> 00:28:43,387
I'm not even sure I can locate
the same car you had before.

206
00:28:43,471 --> 00:28:46,890
I know, I know. Uh, my brother
left something in the car.

207
00:28:46,975 --> 00:28:49,017
We're hoping we can search the car
and find it.

208
00:28:49,102 --> 00:28:52,521
Oh, well, I'll just contact our lost and found
department for you if that's the case.

209
00:28:52,605 --> 00:28:55,315
No, no. We have to have the very same car.

210
00:28:55,400 --> 00:28:58,026
Well, I can't do that.
There's no way I can trace that car for you.

211
00:28:58,153 --> 00:29:01,697
- Why not? You got the license number right
on your form there. - Well, yes, but -

212
00:29:01,781 --> 00:29:03,699
Just give us the license number.
We'll find it.

213
00:29:03,783 --> 00:29:07,161
But I can't allow you on the lot, sir.

214
00:29:07,245 --> 00:29:08,912
Why not? We're already on it.

215
00:29:08,997 --> 00:29:11,498
I just have to ask you
to come back to the office with me.

216
00:29:13,668 --> 00:29:15,878
Travis!

217
00:29:15,962 --> 00:29:17,755
What?

218
00:29:17,839 --> 00:29:20,382
I don't think we're gonna get
the very same car.

219
00:29:20,467 --> 00:29:24,011
But I can rent you a model
that's just like the one you had before, sir.

220
00:29:25,138 --> 00:29:28,348
We need the same car, Walt.
How are we gonna go in another car?

221
00:29:30,101 --> 00:29:32,019
Give us the number,
will you, please?

222
00:29:33,062 --> 00:29:35,063
Come on. Pretty please.

223
00:29:36,608 --> 00:29:40,068
All right. That number is 667DJP.

224
00:29:40,153 --> 00:29:40,986
Six - Remember that?

225
00:29:41,070 --> 00:29:43,071
- 667DJP.
- That's right.

226
00:29:43,156 --> 00:29:45,699
- It's - It's got a bump on the hood.
- Yes, it does.

227
00:30:01,132 --> 00:30:03,926
- What's that?
- What?

228
00:30:04,010 --> 00:30:06,553
That - what you got in your hand.

229
00:30:06,638 --> 00:30:09,389
- A picture.
- Oh? Picture of what?

230
00:30:10,391 --> 00:30:12,726
A picture...

231
00:30:12,811 --> 00:30:16,438
of, uh, Paris.

232
00:30:16,523 --> 00:30:18,315
Paris? Really?

233
00:30:18,399 --> 00:30:20,859
Yes. Picture of a piece of Paris.

234
00:30:20,944 --> 00:30:23,320
Where'd you get a picture of Paris?

235
00:30:23,404 --> 00:30:25,405
- Can I see it?
- Yes.

236
00:30:26,908 --> 00:30:29,660
This is it? This is Paris?

237
00:30:29,744 --> 00:30:31,995
Looks just like Texas to me.

238
00:30:32,080 --> 00:30:33,872
It is.

239
00:30:33,957 --> 00:30:36,708
Paris, Texas?

240
00:30:36,793 --> 00:30:39,294
- It's right here on the map.
- There's really a place called Paris, Texas?

241
00:30:39,379 --> 00:30:41,380
It's right here.

242
00:30:43,633 --> 00:30:46,635
Well, how come you got a picture
of a vacant lot in Paris, Texas?

243
00:30:47,637 --> 00:30:49,555
It's mine.

244
00:30:49,639 --> 00:30:52,683
I know that, but how come you got it?

245
00:30:52,767 --> 00:30:56,854
Uh, I purchased it in-in the mail...

246
00:30:56,938 --> 00:30:59,022
a long time ago.

247
00:30:59,107 --> 00:31:01,358
You bought a picture of a vacant lot
in the mail?

248
00:31:01,442 --> 00:31:04,236
No. I bought the land.

249
00:31:05,280 --> 00:31:06,905
- Oh, you bought that lot.
- Yes.

250
00:31:06,990 --> 00:31:08,991
Oh. Let me see it again.

251
00:31:10,910 --> 00:31:12,327
There's nothin' on it.

252
00:31:12,412 --> 00:31:14,788
Empty.

253
00:31:16,040 --> 00:31:19,459
Why in hell would you want to buy
a vacant lot in Paris, Texas, for Chrissake?

254
00:31:21,963 --> 00:31:23,922
Um...

255
00:31:30,346 --> 00:31:32,306
I forgot.

256
00:31:33,975 --> 00:31:36,643
Here, Trav.

257
00:31:42,650 --> 00:31:46,236
Do you remember
what Mama's very first name was?

258
00:31:46,321 --> 00:31:49,239
- Mary.
- No, I know.

259
00:31:49,324 --> 00:31:52,951
I mean, uh, her -
before she found Daddy.

260
00:31:53,036 --> 00:31:55,662
- Her maiden name?
- Yeah.

261
00:31:55,747 --> 00:31:58,206
You don't remember her maiden name?

262
00:31:58,291 --> 00:32:00,375
No.

263
00:32:00,460 --> 00:32:03,045
Zaquine.

264
00:32:03,129 --> 00:32:06,089
Zaquine. Yeah, Spanish.

265
00:32:06,174 --> 00:32:09,009
- Her father was.
- Yeah?

266
00:32:15,433 --> 00:32:17,434
I don't believe it.

267
00:32:18,937 --> 00:32:20,979
You finally decided to eat.

268
00:32:21,981 --> 00:32:24,107
Eating and talking.

269
00:32:24,192 --> 00:32:27,027
Before you know it, you'll be back
in the land of the living, Trav.

270
00:32:31,407 --> 00:32:33,450
You want me to drive?

271
00:32:33,534 --> 00:32:36,411
Sure. You think you remember how?

272
00:32:36,496 --> 00:32:38,497
My body remembers.

273
00:32:43,419 --> 00:32:46,380
You can sleep while I drive.

274
00:32:46,464 --> 00:32:48,298
Okay.

275
00:33:02,397 --> 00:33:04,940
Well, Trav...

276
00:33:05,024 --> 00:33:07,526
think maybe you're ready to...

277
00:33:07,610 --> 00:33:10,153
tell me what the hell happened to you
over the last four years?

278
00:33:12,448 --> 00:33:14,449
No, not yet.

279
00:33:49,861 --> 00:33:51,194
Travis?

280
00:33:51,279 --> 00:33:53,280
What?

281
00:34:07,128 --> 00:34:12,716
Where are we, Travis? What happened?

282
00:34:12,800 --> 00:34:15,260
Why'd we get off the highway?

283
00:34:15,344 --> 00:34:17,304
Jesus Christ.

284
00:34:17,388 --> 00:34:20,057
I can't even sleep for five minutes
without some crisis.

285
00:34:20,141 --> 00:34:22,142
Why'd you turn off?

286
00:34:25,188 --> 00:34:28,190
I don't know where I turned off.
Didn't have a name.

287
00:34:30,693 --> 00:34:34,112
That's great. That's just dandy.

288
00:34:34,197 --> 00:34:37,949
Here we are in the middle of the Mojave Desert
in a place that doesn't have a name.

289
00:34:40,244 --> 00:34:42,245
I can find the highway again.

290
00:35:03,643 --> 00:35:06,728
Trav, I need to talk to you
a little bit about Hunter.

291
00:35:06,813 --> 00:35:08,772
How old is he now?

292
00:35:08,856 --> 00:35:12,359
He's eight in January.

293
00:35:12,443 --> 00:35:14,486
- He's seven then.
- Yeah.

294
00:35:15,613 --> 00:35:19,449
See, what I wanna talk about is, uh -

295
00:35:19,534 --> 00:35:24,704
Well, he's - he's like part of the family now.

296
00:35:26,582 --> 00:35:29,042
Anne and me are like his parents now.

297
00:35:30,211 --> 00:35:33,463
- Anne's your wife.
- Yeah. You remember her, don't you?

298
00:35:33,548 --> 00:35:36,550
No. Does he think that you're his father?

299
00:35:38,469 --> 00:35:42,430
Well - Anne told him you were coming.

300
00:35:44,183 --> 00:35:45,976
Well, who does he think I am?

301
00:35:46,060 --> 00:35:50,230
I - I told him you're his father.

302
00:35:51,315 --> 00:35:53,650
But, see -

303
00:35:53,734 --> 00:35:56,319
Well, you've been gone a long time, Trav.

304
00:35:56,404 --> 00:35:59,114
How long have I been gone?
Do you know?

305
00:36:00,616 --> 00:36:02,868
Four years.

306
00:36:02,952 --> 00:36:05,579
Is four years a long time?

307
00:36:07,456 --> 00:36:10,000
Well, it is for a little boy.

308
00:36:11,919 --> 00:36:13,628
It's half his life.

309
00:36:15,631 --> 00:36:17,591
Half a boy's life.

310
00:36:21,262 --> 00:36:24,472
- I remember now.
- What?

311
00:36:27,894 --> 00:36:31,188
- Why I bought that land.
- Oh. Why?

312
00:36:31,272 --> 00:36:35,025
Well, Mama once told me that, uh...

313
00:36:35,109 --> 00:36:38,904
that's where she and Daddy
first, uh, made love.

314
00:36:40,156 --> 00:36:43,909
- Oh. In Paris, Texas?
- Yeah.

315
00:36:43,993 --> 00:36:46,036
- She told you that?
- Yeah.

316
00:36:48,164 --> 00:36:50,123
So...

317
00:36:51,459 --> 00:36:54,753
I figured that that's where I - I began.

318
00:36:54,837 --> 00:36:58,632
I-I mean me, Travis Clay Henderson.

319
00:36:58,716 --> 00:37:01,551
They named me that.

320
00:37:01,636 --> 00:37:03,553
I started out there.

321
00:37:05,181 --> 00:37:07,974
- Paris, Texas, huh?
- Yeah.

322
00:37:11,979 --> 00:37:14,272
So, you think maybe
you were conceived there?

323
00:37:15,900 --> 00:37:19,152
- Yeah.
- Well, you could be right, Travis.

324
00:37:20,988 --> 00:37:23,240
Daddy always had a joke about it.

325
00:37:24,242 --> 00:37:26,910
What was the joke?

326
00:37:26,994 --> 00:37:31,581
He, uh - He would introduce Mama
as the girl he met in Paris.

327
00:37:32,583 --> 00:37:37,045
And then he'd wait, uh,
before he said "Texas"...

328
00:37:37,129 --> 00:37:41,800
till everybody thought that... he meant -

329
00:37:41,884 --> 00:37:45,220
He would wait before he said "Texas"
till everybody thought -

330
00:37:45,304 --> 00:37:48,807
after everybody thought he was
talking about Paris, France.

331
00:37:48,891 --> 00:37:51,226
He-He always laughed real hard about it.

332
00:37:54,522 --> 00:37:57,315
So you live in Los Angeles, huh?

333
00:37:57,400 --> 00:38:01,945
Well, we live in the suburbs,
but I got my business in town.

334
00:38:02,029 --> 00:38:04,072
Yeah? What's your business?

335
00:38:04,156 --> 00:38:06,533
I make billboard signs for advertising.

336
00:38:07,618 --> 00:38:11,371
Oh, yeah. So you're the one
who makes those, huh?

337
00:38:11,455 --> 00:38:14,291
I love those.
Some of them are beautiful.

338
00:38:14,375 --> 00:38:17,168
I'm not the only one in the world
that makes 'em, Trav.

339
00:38:40,943 --> 00:38:43,445
Trav? This way.

340
00:38:43,529 --> 00:38:46,573
Nice, huh? Just been in here three months.

341
00:38:46,657 --> 00:38:50,327
I really like it, but I took a beating
on the financing, I tell ya.

342
00:38:50,411 --> 00:38:53,663
Like everybody else nowadays, I guess.

343
00:38:59,587 --> 00:39:03,340
Hi, baby.
Mmm, everything okay here?

344
00:39:03,424 --> 00:39:05,967
Oh, sure. We just missed you a lot.

345
00:39:06,052 --> 00:39:09,054
Yeah. I missed you too.

346
00:39:09,138 --> 00:39:11,222
- Come on in.
- Travis.

347
00:39:16,270 --> 00:39:18,229
My God.

348
00:39:18,314 --> 00:39:22,025
We were beginning to wonder
if we'd ever see you again.

349
00:39:22,109 --> 00:39:24,694
It's been so long.

350
00:39:24,779 --> 00:39:27,238
Did you have a good trip?

351
00:39:27,323 --> 00:39:29,324
Yeah, it was fine.

352
00:39:32,411 --> 00:39:34,329
Hunter?

353
00:39:45,216 --> 00:39:49,469
Hunter, this is Travis.

354
00:40:03,317 --> 00:40:09,697
Hi.

355
00:40:18,249 --> 00:40:21,709
I bet it was really hot coming across
the Mojave Desert.

356
00:40:24,130 --> 00:40:26,381
Yes.

357
00:40:26,465 --> 00:40:28,675
Too bad you had to drive.

358
00:40:28,759 --> 00:40:31,261
What happened?

359
00:40:31,345 --> 00:40:34,848
Well, Travis just, uh, didn't feel like flying.

360
00:40:34,932 --> 00:40:36,766
Oh, I don't blame you.

361
00:40:36,851 --> 00:40:41,896
I can't stand airplanes anymore,
especially since we live in this house.

362
00:40:41,981 --> 00:40:45,358
All we hear is planes
day in and day out.

363
00:40:45,443 --> 00:40:47,861
I like 'em.

364
00:40:54,743 --> 00:40:57,120
You used to fly, didn't you, Travis?

365
00:40:59,206 --> 00:41:01,499
No.

366
00:41:02,585 --> 00:41:07,255
Oh. I thought I remembered Jane
telling me once...

367
00:41:07,339 --> 00:41:12,385
that you flew to Dallas together...
or somewhere.

368
00:41:12,470 --> 00:41:14,804
Um -

369
00:41:14,889 --> 00:41:16,806
Maybe I'm mistaken.

370
00:41:37,411 --> 00:41:42,540
Honey, he hasn't slept in a bed
since we started for here. I swear to God.

371
00:41:42,625 --> 00:41:45,001
I don't think that's even necessary.

372
00:41:45,085 --> 00:41:47,378
Where has he been sleeping then?

373
00:41:47,463 --> 00:41:50,381
Well, he doesn't sleep.

374
00:41:50,466 --> 00:41:52,759
He has to sleep somewhere.

375
00:41:52,843 --> 00:41:56,971
Okay, but I don't think
he's even gonna use it.

376
00:41:57,056 --> 00:41:59,098
He's got to get tired sometime.

377
00:42:03,145 --> 00:42:06,147
Oh. There is a towel for you, Travis.

378
00:42:06,232 --> 00:42:09,400
And some underwear
and socks from Walt.

379
00:42:09,485 --> 00:42:11,694
- Oh.
- Good night.

380
00:42:11,779 --> 00:42:14,280
Good night.

381
00:42:14,365 --> 00:42:16,366
Thank you.

382
00:42:17,701 --> 00:42:20,870
Okay.

383
00:42:20,955 --> 00:42:23,540
Get some shut-eye.

384
00:42:23,624 --> 00:42:25,875
Okay.

385
00:42:25,960 --> 00:42:27,919
- Sweet dreams.
- All right.

386
00:43:37,114 --> 00:43:39,115
You polished them.

387
00:43:41,243 --> 00:43:44,037
That's very nice of you, Travis.

388
00:43:45,164 --> 00:43:47,665
Would you like to come in
and have some breakfast?

389
00:43:49,960 --> 00:43:51,878
Aren't you hungry?

390
00:43:52,880 --> 00:43:56,049
We are going to have strawberry waffles.

391
00:43:56,133 --> 00:43:58,509
Do you like them?

392
00:43:58,594 --> 00:44:00,553
Do you want some?

393
00:44:09,563 --> 00:44:13,441
Well, there is hot coffee on the stove
if you want some.

394
00:44:16,403 --> 00:44:18,404
Look at that truck.

395
00:44:56,568 --> 00:44:58,194
Hi.

396
00:45:33,522 --> 00:45:36,441
- Decided to rough it, huh?
- Yeah.

397
00:45:37,776 --> 00:45:39,694
What'd you do - spit-shine these?

398
00:45:39,778 --> 00:45:41,696
I can get you a job at the airport
doing that.

399
00:45:43,407 --> 00:45:47,910
Hey. You wanna trade these new boots
for those old boots?

400
00:45:47,995 --> 00:45:50,163
Yeah, you can wear 'em.

401
00:45:52,499 --> 00:45:54,459
Thank you.

402
00:46:20,444 --> 00:46:22,403
Travis?

403
00:46:22,488 --> 00:46:26,115
I have to rush off
to get Hunter to school on time.

404
00:46:26,200 --> 00:46:28,201
We will be back this afternoon.

405
00:46:28,285 --> 00:46:31,245
Walt's office number
is on the dining room table.

406
00:46:31,330 --> 00:46:33,289
See you later.

407
00:46:33,373 --> 00:46:35,208
- Okay.
- Bye.

408
00:47:09,660 --> 00:47:11,577
- Anne?
- Yeah?

409
00:47:11,662 --> 00:47:14,997
I was just thinking. Maybe, uh, I can
meet Hunter after school...

410
00:47:15,082 --> 00:47:17,458
and we could walk home together
if he wants to.

411
00:47:17,543 --> 00:47:20,419
Oh, that sounds like a great idea, Travis.

412
00:47:21,964 --> 00:47:25,424
Walk home?
I don't wanna walk home, Mom.

413
00:47:26,760 --> 00:47:29,846
- Why?
- Nobody walks. Everybody drives.

414
00:47:29,930 --> 00:47:32,098
- Come on, Hunter.
- No.

415
00:47:32,182 --> 00:47:34,016
It won't hurt you to walk home
once in your life.

416
00:47:34,101 --> 00:47:37,812
- No, no. I don't want to.
- I don't wanna walk, Mom. Everybody else -

417
00:47:37,896 --> 00:47:40,022
- Travis, I insist. He'll wait for you out in front.
- Everybody will see me.

418
00:47:40,107 --> 00:47:43,317
Walt can tell you how to get there.
It's not far.

419
00:47:43,402 --> 00:47:45,820
And get in the car, Hunter.
We are late as it is.

420
00:47:50,659 --> 00:47:52,577
You're mean.

421
00:48:38,957 --> 00:48:41,334
Awesome!

422
00:48:47,466 --> 00:48:49,383
I flunked kindergarten.

423
00:48:54,723 --> 00:48:57,141
- Can I come with you?
- Sure.

424
00:49:35,514 --> 00:49:37,890
I'm really sorry about this, Travis.

425
00:49:39,393 --> 00:49:42,395
It's not easy for him, Anne.

426
00:49:48,610 --> 00:49:50,736
Anne, it's okay. He's in here.

427
00:49:58,745 --> 00:50:00,663
What are you doin'?

428
00:50:00,747 --> 00:50:02,957
Driving.

429
00:50:03,041 --> 00:50:07,003
- Where to?
- Just driving.

430
00:50:07,087 --> 00:50:09,755
You're not hiding out in there, are you?

431
00:50:09,840 --> 00:50:11,841
No.

432
00:50:16,680 --> 00:50:20,641
Hunter, Travis is your real dad.
You know that, don't you?

433
00:50:22,894 --> 00:50:26,772
Dad, when are they gonna make spaceships
like they make cars?

434
00:50:29,609 --> 00:50:32,445
Hunter, I'm asking you a question.
Can you answer it?

435
00:50:32,529 --> 00:50:34,655
What?

436
00:50:37,743 --> 00:50:43,122
Well, Travis went to meet you at school,
and he wanted to walk you home.

437
00:50:43,206 --> 00:50:46,042
Nobody walks.

438
00:50:46,126 --> 00:50:48,335
That's not the point.

439
00:50:48,420 --> 00:50:53,549
Travis is your real dad,
and he wants to talk to you.

440
00:50:56,470 --> 00:50:58,721
Why? What about?

441
00:51:00,640 --> 00:51:03,976
Okay, come on.
Let's go have dinner. Come on.

442
00:51:13,695 --> 00:51:15,738
Hey, Trav, do you remember the time...

443
00:51:15,822 --> 00:51:18,908
that Anne and me came down to visit you
about five years ago?

444
00:51:20,577 --> 00:51:23,037
No.

445
00:51:23,121 --> 00:51:26,248
You and Jane were down in Texas,
right there on the coast.

446
00:51:26,333 --> 00:51:30,920
Hunter was about three.
Don't you remember that?

447
00:51:34,508 --> 00:51:38,010
- No.
- I remember. We went fishing.

448
00:51:38,929 --> 00:51:43,849
Yeah. I took some Super 8 on that trip.
And I put it all together.

449
00:51:43,934 --> 00:51:45,601
I thought maybe you might like
to see some of it.

450
00:51:45,685 --> 00:51:47,853
Wh-What is it?

451
00:51:47,938 --> 00:51:50,106
Movies. You know, Super 8.

452
00:51:50,190 --> 00:51:51,774
Oh.

453
00:51:51,858 --> 00:51:55,194
Walt, maybe Travis doesn't want -

454
00:51:55,278 --> 00:51:57,947
What?

455
00:51:58,782 --> 00:52:02,701
Well, maybe he'd like to wait a while
before he looks at it.

456
00:52:02,786 --> 00:52:06,205
Well, it's up to him.

457
00:52:06,289 --> 00:52:08,332
I just thought maybe
you'd like to see some of it.

458
00:52:08,416 --> 00:52:10,751
Movies? Sure.

459
00:52:10,836 --> 00:52:12,962
Great. There's some great stuff in it.

460
00:52:13,046 --> 00:52:15,089
Some great shots of Hunter in it.

461
00:52:15,173 --> 00:52:17,216
I've already seen it.

462
00:52:17,300 --> 00:52:20,302
Well, you have to see it again.

463
00:52:20,387 --> 00:52:23,305
- Come on. Help me set up the projector.
- Okay.

464
00:53:50,894 --> 00:53:55,105
- That's me driving.
- I know. You're gonna be good.

465
00:56:59,749 --> 00:57:01,750
Time for bed now, Hunter.

466
00:57:01,835 --> 00:57:04,962
Aw, Mom.

467
00:57:05,046 --> 00:57:07,047
Don't complain. It's past 10:00.

468
00:57:09,551 --> 00:57:11,468
- Good night, Dad.
- Good night, baby.

469
00:57:11,553 --> 00:57:13,303
Mmm.

470
00:57:17,725 --> 00:57:19,726
Good night, Dad.

471
00:57:25,024 --> 00:57:28,026
Do you think he still loves her?

472
00:57:28,111 --> 00:57:31,071
How would I know that, Hunter?

473
00:57:31,156 --> 00:57:33,157
I think he does.

474
00:57:34,534 --> 00:57:38,287
- How can you tell?
- Well, the way he looked at her.

475
00:57:38,371 --> 00:57:40,747
You mean when he saw her
in the movie?

476
00:57:40,832 --> 00:57:43,917
Yeah, but that's not her.

477
00:57:44,002 --> 00:57:46,462
What do you mean?

478
00:57:46,546 --> 00:57:48,547
That's only her in a movie...

479
00:57:50,049 --> 00:57:52,801
a long time ago...

480
00:57:52,886 --> 00:57:56,680
in a galaxy far, far away.

481
00:58:33,092 --> 00:58:36,887
- What are you looking for?
- Uh, I'm looking for...

482
00:58:36,971 --> 00:58:39,431
uh, the father.

483
00:58:39,516 --> 00:58:44,228
- Your father?
- No, no. Just a father. Any father.

484
00:58:44,312 --> 00:58:46,355
What does a father look like?

485
00:58:46,439 --> 00:58:49,441
There are many different kinds
of fathers, señor Travis.

486
00:58:49,526 --> 00:58:51,610
Well, I just - I just need one.

487
00:58:51,694 --> 00:58:55,531
- You think you're gonna find him in there?
- Well, I don't know where else to look.

488
00:58:55,615 --> 00:58:59,034
Oh, I see. You want to look like a father.

489
00:58:59,118 --> 00:59:00,827
- Yeah.
- Mmm.

490
00:59:00,912 --> 00:59:02,829
Ahora. Tell me.

491
00:59:02,914 --> 00:59:05,832
Do you want to be a rich father?

492
00:59:05,917 --> 00:59:08,210
Uh, no.

493
00:59:08,294 --> 00:59:10,420
- A poor one?
- No.

494
00:59:10,505 --> 00:59:12,548
Pues, ¿cómo pues?

495
00:59:12,632 --> 00:59:16,593
- Uh, in between.
- No, no. There is no in between, huh?

496
00:59:16,678 --> 00:59:19,054
You either have to be a rich father
or a poor one.

497
00:59:19,138 --> 00:59:21,056
- Rich.
- Bueno.

498
00:59:21,140 --> 00:59:23,141
Un momento. A ver.

499
00:59:24,269 --> 00:59:26,478
Ahora, sí. Okay.

500
00:59:27,480 --> 00:59:29,481
A ver. Huh?

501
00:59:33,903 --> 00:59:35,988
- ¿Qué tal? ¿Eh?
- Está bueno.

502
00:59:36,072 --> 00:59:38,574
Okay. One thing you must remember.

503
00:59:38,658 --> 00:59:40,951
To be a rich father, señor Travis...

504
00:59:41,035 --> 00:59:44,037
you must look to the sky
and never at the ground, eh?

505
00:59:44,122 --> 00:59:46,123
Mire.

506
00:59:46,207 --> 00:59:47,791
Little higher.

507
00:59:47,875 --> 00:59:49,835
Eso. Mm-hmm.

508
00:59:49,919 --> 00:59:51,962
Ahora. Camine.

509
00:59:55,883 --> 00:59:58,760
No. Este -

510
00:59:58,845 --> 01:00:00,846
You must walk stiff, señor Travis.

511
01:00:04,892 --> 01:00:07,185
Con confianza. ¿Me entiende?

512
01:00:07,270 --> 01:00:09,438
Um, con respeto.

513
01:00:09,522 --> 01:00:11,648
- Uh, dignity.
- Eso.

514
01:00:11,733 --> 01:00:14,192
Con dignidad.

515
01:00:14,277 --> 01:00:16,194
Ahora.

516
01:00:23,870 --> 01:00:25,871
Mm-hmm.

517
01:00:28,249 --> 01:00:30,292
You got it.

518
01:00:50,104 --> 01:00:52,105
Who is that guy?
You know him?

519
01:00:53,107 --> 01:00:55,400
Yeah. He's my father's brother.

520
01:00:57,987 --> 01:01:01,782
No. They're both brothers.

521
01:01:01,866 --> 01:01:05,243
No. They're both -
They're both fathers.

522
01:01:07,580 --> 01:01:09,623
No. Aw, forget it.

523
01:01:09,707 --> 01:01:12,668
- But both whose father?
- My father.

524
01:01:12,752 --> 01:01:15,128
How-How can you have two fathers?

525
01:01:15,213 --> 01:01:18,215
Just lucky, I guess.

526
01:01:18,299 --> 01:01:20,842
- Well, bye.
- Bye.

527
01:03:12,705 --> 01:03:14,664
That's my dad's suit.

528
01:03:15,875 --> 01:03:17,334
I mean Walt.

529
01:03:17,418 --> 01:03:19,419
That's okay if you call him "Dad."

530
01:03:20,546 --> 01:03:23,548
Yeah, I borrowed it from him.
He said it was okay.

531
01:03:28,971 --> 01:03:30,889
What are those pictures?

532
01:03:30,973 --> 01:03:32,891
That's my dad -

533
01:03:34,018 --> 01:03:36,269
and your grandfather.

534
01:03:39,857 --> 01:03:42,984
- What was his name?
- Travis.

535
01:03:43,069 --> 01:03:46,196
- Same as yours.
- Mm-hmm.

536
01:03:46,280 --> 01:03:48,240
Where is he now?

537
01:03:49,408 --> 01:03:53,620
He died... couple of years after this picture.

538
01:03:53,704 --> 01:03:55,622
In that car.

539
01:03:55,706 --> 01:03:57,916
- Oh. He's dead.
- Mm-hmm.

540
01:03:59,085 --> 01:04:02,003
But can you feel that he's dead?

541
01:04:02,088 --> 01:04:03,797
What do you mean?

542
01:04:03,881 --> 01:04:07,509
You know when he was walking around
and talking, right?

543
01:04:07,593 --> 01:04:10,887
- Yeah.
- So can you feel that he's gone?

544
01:04:12,765 --> 01:04:14,391
Yeah, sometimes.

545
01:04:14,475 --> 01:04:16,476
I know he's dead.

546
01:04:17,603 --> 01:04:20,063
I never felt like you were dead.

547
01:04:20,147 --> 01:04:24,401
I could always feel you walking around
and talking someplace.

548
01:04:24,485 --> 01:04:27,737
- Yeah?
- I feel Mom too.

549
01:04:27,822 --> 01:04:29,865
- You do?
- Don't you?

550
01:04:31,284 --> 01:04:33,201
Yeah.

551
01:04:35,955 --> 01:04:38,039
That's me when I was in the navy.

552
01:04:38,124 --> 01:04:40,208
Hmm. You were a general?

553
01:04:40,293 --> 01:04:42,711
No. That's when I was -

554
01:04:42,795 --> 01:04:44,212
That's when I was in the band.

555
01:04:44,297 --> 01:04:46,965
- Oh.
- The high school band.

556
01:04:48,426 --> 01:04:50,176
Now, here's you.
I like this picture.

557
01:04:50,261 --> 01:04:54,180
That - Look at that.
That is really wild.

558
01:04:54,265 --> 01:04:57,475
It's weird when it - when it -
when there's water in between.

559
01:04:57,560 --> 01:05:00,645
And then it turns into nothing.
Then it goes - pshh.

560
01:05:00,730 --> 01:05:03,231
Yeah. That's a great picture.

561
01:05:03,316 --> 01:05:05,775
And this is my mom.

562
01:05:07,486 --> 01:05:09,487
Your grandmother.

563
01:05:14,201 --> 01:05:16,161
I don't know.

564
01:05:19,498 --> 01:05:23,543
It just seems like everything
has changed between us so fast -

565
01:05:23,628 --> 01:05:26,129
ever since Travis came.

566
01:05:26,213 --> 01:05:27,964
What's changed?

567
01:05:29,759 --> 01:05:31,676
I'm just afraid.

568
01:05:33,179 --> 01:05:36,723
- Afraid of Travis?
- No.

569
01:05:36,807 --> 01:05:38,725
Then what?

570
01:05:40,811 --> 01:05:44,022
Of what will happen to us
if we lose Hunter.

571
01:05:46,359 --> 01:05:49,194
We're not gonna lose Hunter.

572
01:05:49,278 --> 01:05:52,530
Then why do you keep
pushing them together?

573
01:05:52,615 --> 01:05:55,700
It's almost as if you wanted him to leave.

574
01:05:55,785 --> 01:05:59,412
- Who?
- Hunter.

575
01:05:59,497 --> 01:06:01,957
You know what I'm talking about.

576
01:06:02,041 --> 01:06:05,627
You keep promoting
this father-son business between them.

577
01:06:05,711 --> 01:06:07,837
It's not "business."

578
01:06:07,922 --> 01:06:11,758
Travis is his father,
and Hunter is his son.

579
01:06:11,842 --> 01:06:15,887
That's a fact. We've known that all along.

580
01:06:17,056 --> 01:06:20,517
- Travis happens to be my brother.
- I know he is.

581
01:06:20,601 --> 01:06:23,353
Well, what's this promotion bullshit?

582
01:06:23,437 --> 01:06:28,233
You want us to go on pretending
that we're the parents of my brother's son?

583
01:06:28,317 --> 01:06:30,485
How long do you expect Hunter to buy that?

584
01:06:30,569 --> 01:06:32,988
I was never pretending.

585
01:06:33,072 --> 01:06:36,950
I love him, just like he was
my own flesh and blood.

586
01:06:38,285 --> 01:06:40,286
So do I.

587
01:06:50,506 --> 01:06:53,842
- Hi, Anne.
- Hi, Travis.

588
01:06:53,926 --> 01:06:56,720
You don't sleep much, do you?

589
01:07:05,730 --> 01:07:08,356
Travis.

590
01:07:08,441 --> 01:07:10,608
There is something I have to tell you.

591
01:07:10,693 --> 01:07:16,114
I was not going to, because somehow
it makes things easier that nobody knows.

592
01:07:17,408 --> 01:07:20,410
I never even told Walt or Hunter.

593
01:07:21,954 --> 01:07:23,955
Well, what is it?

594
01:07:26,125 --> 01:07:29,335
After Hunter came to live with us...

595
01:07:29,420 --> 01:07:33,506
Jane used to call asking about him.

596
01:07:34,884 --> 01:07:39,220
She made me promise
not to tell anyone she was calling.

597
01:07:39,305 --> 01:07:41,306
Did she ask about me?

598
01:07:43,893 --> 01:07:46,478
Yes, in the beginning.

599
01:07:50,566 --> 01:07:53,359
Where did she call from?

600
01:07:53,444 --> 01:07:55,403
Places in Texas.

601
01:07:55,488 --> 01:07:57,405
What places?

602
01:08:00,743 --> 01:08:02,660
Let me finish, Travis.

603
01:08:05,498 --> 01:08:09,751
After what happened
between you and Jane...

604
01:08:09,835 --> 01:08:12,337
she decided Hunter should be with us.

605
01:08:14,173 --> 01:08:16,841
She said she couldn't be a mother
to him anymore.

606
01:08:24,934 --> 01:08:28,103
She stopped being a mother to him
a long time before that.

607
01:08:41,033 --> 01:08:45,370
Travis, I don't want to feel
I'm hiding something.

608
01:08:52,378 --> 01:08:54,462
She was young.

609
01:08:59,385 --> 01:09:02,804
She wanted something.
I just couldn't figure out what it was.

610
01:09:10,187 --> 01:09:13,439
I just didn't realize
how much rage I had.

611
01:09:21,699 --> 01:09:25,076
A little more than a year ago,
she stopped calling.

612
01:09:25,161 --> 01:09:27,412
I haven't heard from her since then.

613
01:09:28,539 --> 01:09:30,456
Nothing?

614
01:09:31,750 --> 01:09:34,127
Not a word.

615
01:09:34,211 --> 01:09:36,129
But on the last call...

616
01:09:37,256 --> 01:09:40,425
she asked me to open a bank account
for Hunter.

617
01:09:41,677 --> 01:09:43,178
A bank account?

618
01:09:43,262 --> 01:09:46,097
All I know about Jane now is...

619
01:09:47,224 --> 01:09:52,187
she goes to this bank
on the fifth of each month...

620
01:09:52,271 --> 01:09:54,772
and wires money for Hunter.

621
01:09:59,111 --> 01:10:01,863
Jane still sends him money?

622
01:10:01,947 --> 01:10:04,699
Sometimes a hundred dollars.

623
01:10:04,783 --> 01:10:07,994
Sometimes 50 or five.

624
01:10:08,078 --> 01:10:10,622
For Hunter's future.

625
01:10:10,706 --> 01:10:12,957
I had the bank trace the wire.

626
01:10:14,126 --> 01:10:16,127
It comes from a bank in Houston.

627
01:10:16,212 --> 01:10:17,837
What bank?

628
01:10:19,465 --> 01:10:22,717
I wrote it down if you want it.

629
01:10:25,721 --> 01:10:29,807
- What's the date today?
- The first of November.

630
01:10:34,647 --> 01:10:37,398
"I don't think we should do that anymore."
"You're right."

631
01:10:39,652 --> 01:10:43,404
"Heh. I meant the other thing." "Oh."

632
01:11:02,007 --> 01:11:06,928
You will all be caught with your diapers down!

633
01:11:07,012 --> 01:11:09,264
That is a promise!

634
01:11:09,348 --> 01:11:13,893
I make you this promise
on my mother's head!

635
01:11:13,978 --> 01:11:19,774
For right here, today,
standing on the very head of my mother...

636
01:11:19,858 --> 01:11:22,902
which is now on God's green earth...

637
01:11:22,987 --> 01:11:26,739
which everybody who wasn't born
in a fuckin' sewer...

638
01:11:26,824 --> 01:11:31,661
ought to know and understand
to the very marrow of their bones!

639
01:11:33,122 --> 01:11:36,541
They will invade you in your beds!

640
01:11:36,625 --> 01:11:40,378
They will snatch you from your hot tubs!

641
01:11:40,462 --> 01:11:45,300
They will pluck you right out
of your fancy sports cars!

642
01:11:45,384 --> 01:11:47,635
There is nowhere...

643
01:11:49,638 --> 01:11:55,143
absolutely nowhere
in this godforsaken valley -

644
01:11:55,227 --> 01:12:00,148
I'm talking about from the range
of my voice right here...

645
01:12:00,232 --> 01:12:05,653
clear out to the goddamn Mojave Desert
and beyond that -

646
01:12:05,738 --> 01:12:08,364
clear out past Barstow...

647
01:12:09,408 --> 01:12:13,494
and everywhere else in the valley
all the way to Arizona.

648
01:12:13,579 --> 01:12:17,332
None of that area
will be called a safety zone!

649
01:12:17,416 --> 01:12:19,625
There will be no safety zone!

650
01:12:19,710 --> 01:12:23,629
I can guarantee you the safety zone
will be eliminated!

651
01:12:23,714 --> 01:12:26,049
Eradicated!

652
01:12:26,133 --> 01:12:31,429
You will all be extradited
to the land of no return!

653
01:12:31,513 --> 01:12:34,682
It's a navigation to nowhere!

654
01:12:34,767 --> 01:12:37,769
And if you think that's going to be fun...

655
01:12:37,853 --> 01:12:40,855
you've got another thing comin'.

656
01:12:42,107 --> 01:12:44,525
I may be a slime bucket...

657
01:12:44,610 --> 01:12:46,527
but believe me...

658
01:12:46,612 --> 01:12:49,530
I know what the hell I'm talking about!

659
01:12:49,615 --> 01:12:51,741
I'm not crazy!

660
01:12:51,825 --> 01:12:54,702
And don't say I didn't warn you!

661
01:12:54,787 --> 01:12:58,122
I warned you! I warned all of you!

662
01:13:09,218 --> 01:13:11,636
Thought you were afraid of heights.

663
01:13:11,720 --> 01:13:14,972
No, I'm not afraid of heights.
I'm afraid of falling.

664
01:13:15,057 --> 01:13:18,976
- Oh, yeah? Well, just don't look down.
- No.

665
01:13:19,061 --> 01:13:23,648
Uh, too bad things don't look the same
on the ground.

666
01:13:23,732 --> 01:13:25,650
What do you mean?

667
01:13:25,734 --> 01:13:29,153
Well, things are clearer up here.

668
01:13:30,447 --> 01:13:32,365
Might clear things up.

669
01:13:32,449 --> 01:13:35,368
Yeah, I had a talk with Anne last night.

670
01:13:35,452 --> 01:13:37,370
Yeah, she's pretty upset.

671
01:13:37,454 --> 01:13:39,455
Yeah, I know.

672
01:13:41,083 --> 01:13:43,000
I'm gonna leave.

673
01:13:43,085 --> 01:13:45,002
- What?
- I'm leaving.

674
01:13:45,087 --> 01:13:48,005
Hey, I didn't tell you this
in order to make you leave.

675
01:13:48,090 --> 01:13:50,091
- I'm not trying to get rid of you, Travis.
- I know that.

676
01:13:50,175 --> 01:13:54,429
What good is that gonna do?
That's not gonna solve anything.

677
01:13:54,513 --> 01:13:56,514
I'm gonna find Jane.

678
01:13:58,183 --> 01:13:59,892
How are you gonna do that?

679
01:13:59,977 --> 01:14:02,270
It's been four years.
She's completely disappeared.

680
01:14:02,354 --> 01:14:04,647
I tried to find her.
I tried everything. I couldn't find her.

681
01:14:04,731 --> 01:14:07,400
Yeah, well, I haven't tried yet.
I can find her.

682
01:14:07,484 --> 01:14:10,778
- What makes you so sure?
- I just know.

683
01:14:10,863 --> 01:14:13,781
- Can we go down now?
- No!

684
01:14:13,866 --> 01:14:17,952
Goddamn it!
You tell me what happened, Travis!

685
01:14:18,036 --> 01:14:20,455
I'm sick of this fuckin' mystery.

686
01:14:20,539 --> 01:14:23,958
I've been treating you like a spoiled kid
ever since I picked you up in the desert.

687
01:14:24,042 --> 01:14:27,211
Now you tell me
what happened with you and Jane!

688
01:14:28,213 --> 01:14:30,131
Shit!

689
01:14:30,215 --> 01:14:32,842
I know. It's none of my business.

690
01:14:34,011 --> 01:14:37,430
Uh, I'm gonna need to take, uh...

691
01:14:37,514 --> 01:14:40,475
money, credit cards.

692
01:14:40,559 --> 01:14:42,477
All right, sure. You can have 'em.

693
01:14:42,561 --> 01:14:45,438
- You know you'll get it back.
- Forget that. You can have it.

694
01:14:45,522 --> 01:14:48,024
I'm gonna find her, Walt.

695
01:15:13,175 --> 01:15:15,176
Hunter!

696
01:15:24,394 --> 01:15:26,229
Is that your car?

697
01:15:29,733 --> 01:15:33,152
Yep. Come on.

698
01:15:33,237 --> 01:15:35,446
Radical!

699
01:15:49,169 --> 01:15:51,337
This is not bad stuff.

700
01:15:52,881 --> 01:15:55,299
Anne puts it in lunch every day.

701
01:15:55,384 --> 01:15:58,302
La vache qui rit. Sticky.

702
01:15:58,387 --> 01:16:00,388
La vache what?

703
01:16:01,974 --> 01:16:06,185
Rit. Rit.

704
01:16:07,229 --> 01:16:09,230
I like it.

705
01:16:10,649 --> 01:16:12,900
- Dad?
- Yeah?

706
01:16:12,985 --> 01:16:15,486
Where'd you go all that time?

707
01:16:18,115 --> 01:16:20,032
Mexico.

708
01:16:20,117 --> 01:16:22,118
How come?

709
01:16:23,328 --> 01:16:26,038
I didn't know where else to go.

710
01:16:26,123 --> 01:16:28,833
Where did Mom go?

711
01:16:29,918 --> 01:16:31,836
I don't know.

712
01:16:31,920 --> 01:16:34,338
But right now, she's somewhere in Houston.

713
01:16:34,423 --> 01:16:36,716
That's where the space center is.

714
01:16:36,800 --> 01:16:38,801
Yeah.

715
01:16:40,470 --> 01:16:43,389
That's what I wanted to talk to you about.

716
01:16:43,473 --> 01:16:46,392
- I gotta go away now.
- Why?

717
01:16:46,476 --> 01:16:48,769
Because I'm gonna find her.

718
01:16:48,854 --> 01:16:51,063
What about me? You just found me.

719
01:16:51,148 --> 01:16:53,065
Can I come with?

720
01:16:56,778 --> 01:16:58,696
What about Walt and Anne?

721
01:16:58,780 --> 01:17:02,033
You mean we'd never come back here?

722
01:17:02,117 --> 01:17:04,201
Well, sure, but...

723
01:17:04,286 --> 01:17:06,662
I don't know when.

724
01:17:15,213 --> 01:17:17,214
I want to come with.

725
01:17:20,218 --> 01:17:23,679
I wanna find her too.
When do we go?

726
01:17:28,143 --> 01:17:30,061
Right now.

727
01:17:30,145 --> 01:17:32,313
Then come on. Let's go.

728
01:17:32,397 --> 01:17:35,316
First we gotta stop
and get supplies for the trip.

729
01:17:35,400 --> 01:17:37,401
Okay.

730
01:17:51,583 --> 01:17:55,419
We gotta buy jackets, T-shirts,
toothbrushes - stuff like that.

731
01:17:55,504 --> 01:17:57,421
Maybe even walkie-talkies.

732
01:17:57,506 --> 01:17:59,423
Walkie-talkies? What for?

733
01:17:59,508 --> 01:18:01,509
Just in case.

734
01:18:10,686 --> 01:18:13,354
- Do you know what?
- What?

735
01:18:15,273 --> 01:18:17,191
This whole galaxy...

736
01:18:17,275 --> 01:18:19,193
the whole universe...

737
01:18:19,277 --> 01:18:23,614
used to be compressed
into a tiny spot this big.

738
01:18:23,699 --> 01:18:27,034
- And - And do you know what happened?
- What?

739
01:18:27,119 --> 01:18:29,870
It went -
and blew up.

740
01:18:29,955 --> 01:18:35,418
All the spar - Everything went flying
all over the place and formed space.

741
01:18:35,502 --> 01:18:39,463
- It was just gas. It was floating around.
- The Earth was?

742
01:18:39,548 --> 01:18:42,216
Yeah. The Earth was really gas.

743
01:18:42,300 --> 01:18:45,803
And - And the sun formed,
and it was so hot that -

744
01:18:45,887 --> 01:18:50,141
that the Earth
just formed into one hard, big ball...

745
01:18:50,225 --> 01:18:53,853
- Yeah?
- of oceans - nothing but ocean.

746
01:18:53,937 --> 01:18:56,063
- Yeah?
- So there was sea animals.

747
01:18:56,148 --> 01:19:00,901
Then under the water, a volcano went -

748
01:19:00,986 --> 01:19:06,699
And the hot lava hit the water
and formed rock to make land.

749
01:19:18,503 --> 01:19:20,921
You know how to make a collect call?

750
01:19:21,006 --> 01:19:24,216
- You dial the operator and tell her that you're -
- I know.

751
01:19:24,301 --> 01:19:26,886
Good. Then call Walt and Anne.

752
01:19:26,970 --> 01:19:28,888
Why?

753
01:19:28,972 --> 01:19:32,433
Because - So they don't worry about you,
so they know where you are.

754
01:19:32,517 --> 01:19:35,436
- What am I gonna say?
- Just tell 'em the truth.

755
01:19:35,520 --> 01:19:39,440
Tell 'em, uh, that you're with me
and that we're going to Texas.

756
01:19:39,524 --> 01:19:41,442
They're gonna flip out.

757
01:19:41,526 --> 01:19:44,445
I know. But you can handle it.

758
01:19:44,529 --> 01:19:47,281
- Okay?
- Why can't you do it?

759
01:19:47,365 --> 01:19:49,784
I can't do it.

760
01:19:49,868 --> 01:19:51,619
Why?

761
01:19:51,703 --> 01:19:54,205
Because it has to be you.

762
01:19:56,875 --> 01:19:58,793
Gee.

763
01:19:58,877 --> 01:20:01,253
Why can't he do it? I mean -

764
01:20:07,719 --> 01:20:09,637
- Hello?
- Hi, Dad.

765
01:20:09,721 --> 01:20:11,639
Hunter. Where are you?

766
01:20:11,723 --> 01:20:14,642
You know what time it is?
I've been calling everywhere looking for you.

767
01:20:14,726 --> 01:20:17,812
Travis got a truck. He was talking about -

768
01:20:17,896 --> 01:20:20,147
Yeah, yeah.
Hunter, just listen to me now.

769
01:20:20,232 --> 01:20:22,149
Where are you exactly?

770
01:20:22,234 --> 01:20:24,652
In San Bernardino.

771
01:20:24,736 --> 01:20:27,154
San Bernardino?

772
01:20:27,239 --> 01:20:30,157
Hunter, what do you mean
you're in San Bernardino?

773
01:20:30,242 --> 01:20:32,660
- Let me talk to him.
- Wait, honey. How did -

774
01:20:32,744 --> 01:20:34,662
- Let me talk to him.
- All right, all right.

775
01:20:34,746 --> 01:20:36,664
Hunter?

776
01:20:36,748 --> 01:20:38,666
Are you all right?

777
01:20:38,750 --> 01:20:40,668
Yeah.

778
01:20:40,752 --> 01:20:43,671
- What are you doing?
- I'm on a trip, Mom.

779
01:20:43,755 --> 01:20:45,673
- With Travis?
- Yeah.

780
01:20:45,757 --> 01:20:48,175
We bought some walkie-talkies,
and I -

781
01:20:48,260 --> 01:20:51,595
- Where are you going?
- We're on our way to Texas.

782
01:20:52,722 --> 01:20:54,557
Tell me where you are, Hunter.

783
01:20:54,641 --> 01:20:56,559
Just tell me where you are.

784
01:20:56,643 --> 01:20:58,561
We're at a gas station.

785
01:20:58,645 --> 01:21:00,563
What's the name of it?

786
01:21:00,647 --> 01:21:03,190
- Texaco.
- Oh, my God.

787
01:21:04,276 --> 01:21:08,779
Hunter, you tell Travis to turn around...

788
01:21:08,864 --> 01:21:11,657
and come back here right now.

789
01:21:11,741 --> 01:21:13,659
Do you understand me?

790
01:21:13,743 --> 01:21:15,744
Let me talk to him.

791
01:21:16,788 --> 01:21:18,539
What should I do?

792
01:21:18,623 --> 01:21:21,333
Just... hang up.

793
01:21:23,795 --> 01:21:26,005
Bye, Mom. Gotta go now.

794
01:21:27,257 --> 01:21:29,258
Hunter.

795
01:21:30,677 --> 01:21:32,678
Hunter!

796
01:21:48,820 --> 01:21:50,738
Did they flip out?

797
01:21:50,822 --> 01:21:52,740
Yeah, she did.

798
01:21:52,824 --> 01:21:55,701
- You're not sorry you came, are you?
- No.

799
01:21:55,785 --> 01:21:58,704
Well, you can go back to them
anytime you want.

800
01:21:58,788 --> 01:22:02,458
- You just tell me. Okay?
- I don't wanna go back.

801
01:22:02,542 --> 01:22:06,045
Well, I know, but just in case
you change your mind.

802
01:22:51,758 --> 01:22:54,802
I'm so used to calling her "Mom."

803
01:22:56,137 --> 01:22:58,055
Anne?

804
01:22:58,139 --> 01:23:00,140
Yeah.

805
01:23:05,063 --> 01:23:07,398
She sounded so sad.

806
01:23:10,402 --> 01:23:12,569
I know.

807
01:23:15,365 --> 01:23:18,367
What do you think Mom will look like now?

808
01:23:22,747 --> 01:23:24,748
I don't know.

809
01:23:27,335 --> 01:23:29,253
Do you remember her?

810
01:23:29,337 --> 01:23:31,255
Not really.

811
01:23:31,339 --> 01:23:34,174
Only from that little movie we saw.

812
01:23:43,351 --> 01:23:45,102
You look happy then.

813
01:23:46,187 --> 01:23:48,188
Yeah.

814
01:23:52,527 --> 01:23:55,612
Mm-mmm. You keep that.

815
01:24:13,631 --> 01:24:17,634
Night.

816
01:24:56,674 --> 01:25:01,261
Dad, if a guy put a baby down...

817
01:25:01,346 --> 01:25:04,765
traveled at the speed of light
for an hou -

818
01:25:04,849 --> 01:25:07,768
If he traveled at the speed of light...

819
01:25:07,852 --> 01:25:10,771
he would -
he would come back in an hour.

820
01:25:10,855 --> 01:25:15,859
He would be an hour older,
but the little baby would be a very old man.

821
01:25:17,153 --> 01:25:19,071
Oh, yeah?

822
01:25:19,155 --> 01:25:22,157
Well, how long would it take him
to get to Houston?

823
01:25:24,035 --> 01:25:27,329
Uh, if-if they were to travel -

824
01:25:27,413 --> 01:25:29,623
I'd say about three seconds.

825
01:25:30,917 --> 01:25:33,919
Uh, over.
I didn't get that last part.

826
01:25:35,713 --> 01:25:39,967
It would take them three seconds
to get from California to Houston...

827
01:25:40,051 --> 01:25:42,386
on light speed.

828
01:25:51,062 --> 01:25:53,939
- This is Houston?
- Yep.

829
01:25:54,023 --> 01:25:57,276
How are we gonna find her
in a big city like this?

830
01:25:57,360 --> 01:25:59,778
- I know where she'll be.
- Where?

831
01:25:59,863 --> 01:26:03,574
A bank. She's going to deposit some money
in a certain bank today.

832
01:26:07,036 --> 01:26:09,288
This is a bank?

833
01:26:09,372 --> 01:26:11,790
What kind of bank is this?

834
01:26:11,875 --> 01:26:13,792
Looks like a drive-in.

835
01:26:13,877 --> 01:26:16,795
I've never seen a bank like that.

836
01:26:16,880 --> 01:26:19,131
Me neither.

837
01:26:19,215 --> 01:26:22,634
There'll be so many cars,
we'll never find her.

838
01:26:22,719 --> 01:26:24,970
Oh, yeah, we will. Come on.

839
01:26:25,054 --> 01:26:28,807
W-We'll split up,
and then we'll cover more ground. Okay?

840
01:26:28,892 --> 01:26:31,310
Yeah. We could use the walkie-talkies.

841
01:26:31,394 --> 01:26:33,312
Hey. Now you're goin'.

842
01:26:33,396 --> 01:26:36,148
- I'll let you out here.
- Okay.

843
01:26:43,031 --> 01:26:45,115
Can you hear me, Dad? Over.

844
01:26:45,200 --> 01:26:47,117
Loud and clear.

845
01:26:47,202 --> 01:26:49,745
Good.

846
01:27:14,979 --> 01:27:17,064
Hunter in position one. Over.

847
01:27:17,148 --> 01:27:21,026
Travis in position two.
We got it covered.

848
01:27:21,110 --> 01:27:24,238
I told you these weren't toys.
Over.

849
01:27:24,322 --> 01:27:26,740
10-4. Over and out.

850
01:29:05,882 --> 01:29:08,800
Dad! She's just leaving the bank!

851
01:29:08,885 --> 01:29:10,802
Get over here!

852
01:29:10,887 --> 01:29:13,555
Dad, can you hear me?
Can you hear me?

853
01:29:18,895 --> 01:29:22,856
She's leaving the bank! Get over here!

854
01:29:22,940 --> 01:29:25,025
Dad!

855
01:29:25,109 --> 01:29:27,652
Come on! Dad!

856
01:29:27,737 --> 01:29:31,198
Wake up! Wake up! She's leaving!

857
01:29:31,282 --> 01:29:33,658
She's leaving the bank!

858
01:29:33,743 --> 01:29:35,369
Dad! Wake up!

859
01:29:36,454 --> 01:29:38,705
Wh-Where is sh -

860
01:29:38,790 --> 01:29:41,458
I-I'm on my way!

861
01:29:42,543 --> 01:29:45,087
Oh, no!

862
01:30:03,481 --> 01:30:05,399
She went that way!

863
01:30:05,483 --> 01:30:07,901
- Which way did she go?
- That way!

864
01:30:07,985 --> 01:30:10,904
You sure it's her?
Come on, come on, come on!

865
01:30:10,988 --> 01:30:12,989
Let's go!

866
01:30:28,423 --> 01:30:31,842
Hunter, did you really
get a good look at her, or what?

867
01:30:31,926 --> 01:30:34,511
It must have been her. I know it was her.

868
01:30:34,595 --> 01:30:37,514
Oh, God, I hope we haven't lost her.

869
01:30:37,598 --> 01:30:40,725
Can't this piece of junk go faster?

870
01:30:40,810 --> 01:30:43,728
There's 10,000 cars here, Hunter.
How are we gonna find her?

871
01:30:43,813 --> 01:30:47,065
- Which one is it?
- Go faster, Dad! Go faster!

872
01:30:47,150 --> 01:30:49,568
What col - W-What color -
The car was red, right?

873
01:30:49,652 --> 01:30:53,029
Yeah. A little red Chevy.

874
01:30:53,114 --> 01:30:55,115
Well -

875
01:30:56,659 --> 01:30:59,578
You see anything?
I don't know which one it looks like, Hunter.

876
01:30:59,662 --> 01:31:01,913
You'll have to help me.
Look. Can you see it?

877
01:31:01,998 --> 01:31:03,999
No, not yet.

878
01:31:06,377 --> 01:31:09,629
- I see her! I see her!
- Where? Where?

879
01:31:09,714 --> 01:31:12,299
Over in that lane! In that lane!

880
01:31:12,383 --> 01:31:14,426
- Which lane?
- The right one!

881
01:31:14,510 --> 01:31:17,179
All right, all right.
Settle down. I see it.

882
01:31:18,890 --> 01:31:20,599
Okay.

883
01:31:20,683 --> 01:31:23,393
Is that her? Look at -
See if it's her. Can you tell?

884
01:31:25,396 --> 01:31:28,106
- I can't tell.
- Wait a minute.

885
01:31:28,191 --> 01:31:32,652
There's two red cars now.
Which one is it?

886
01:31:32,737 --> 01:31:35,155
- Huh?
- Uh, the right - The left one!

887
01:31:35,239 --> 01:31:36,990
- You sure?
- Yeah. The left one.

888
01:31:37,074 --> 01:31:40,744
Okay.

889
01:31:43,915 --> 01:31:46,917
- You sure this is the one now?
- Yeah.

890
01:31:51,297 --> 01:31:53,173
I hope you're right, Hunter.

891
01:31:53,257 --> 01:31:57,010
If we're following the wrong car,
we're gonna have to wait a whole other month.

892
01:31:57,094 --> 01:31:59,513
- I'll be eight then.
- You'll be what?

893
01:31:59,597 --> 01:32:01,515
I'll be eight then!

894
01:32:07,230 --> 01:32:09,648
Let's get closer. We could wave!

895
01:32:09,732 --> 01:32:12,526
No, no, no. We don't wanna get too close.

896
01:32:12,610 --> 01:32:15,445
We might scare her,
and she'd have a wreck or somethin'.

897
01:32:17,114 --> 01:32:19,032
- Okay?
- Okay.

898
01:32:19,116 --> 01:32:21,117
I guess so.

899
01:32:29,418 --> 01:32:31,378
Well -

900
01:32:31,462 --> 01:32:34,047
I wonder where she's going.

901
01:32:34,131 --> 01:32:37,384
Maybe to work. What do you think?

902
01:32:37,468 --> 01:32:39,469
Yeah. Could be.

903
01:33:49,999 --> 01:33:52,959
Looks like a girl's car to me.

904
01:33:53,044 --> 01:33:54,961
Could it be hers?

905
01:33:57,048 --> 01:33:59,799
Could be. Get in the truck,
and I'll tell you my plan.

906
01:33:59,884 --> 01:34:01,384
Okay.

907
01:34:08,893 --> 01:34:11,311
Roll the windows up, lock the doors.

908
01:34:11,395 --> 01:34:15,815
And if anybody talks to you, tell 'em
your daddy's inside and he'll be right back.

909
01:34:15,900 --> 01:34:17,817
- Okay?
- Okay.

910
01:34:17,902 --> 01:34:19,903
- You okay?
- Yep.

911
01:34:45,388 --> 01:34:47,847
Could y'all put some ice on it?
I'm still rehearsing.

912
01:34:47,932 --> 01:34:50,600
Sergeant Jojo, call for you, Booth 22.

913
01:34:50,685 --> 01:34:53,019
Sergeant Jojo, Booth 22.

914
01:34:53,104 --> 01:34:56,064
Okay, new bit, new bit.
You guys are gonna love this.

915
01:34:56,148 --> 01:34:59,484
The girls here spend so much time with a guy
that most of them live alone.

916
01:34:59,568 --> 01:35:01,945
But it's tough living alone in a city like this.

917
01:35:02,029 --> 01:35:03,655
A lot of violent things happen here.

918
01:35:03,739 --> 01:35:07,951
Stuff like - like rape, like murder.
Especially from the police force.

919
01:35:09,829 --> 01:35:13,123
Uh, Tupperware parties - violent things.

920
01:35:13,207 --> 01:35:15,375
And when you live alone,
you gotta think about...

921
01:35:15,459 --> 01:35:17,377
"Do I need some kind
of protection at home?"

922
01:35:17,461 --> 01:35:21,256
And if you're a girl, you can live with a guy
or you can live with a dog.

923
01:35:21,340 --> 01:35:23,800
That's a tough decision, let me tell you.

924
01:35:23,884 --> 01:35:26,553
- What normal-thinking adult wants to live...
- Nurse Bibs, you're needed in Booth 7.

925
01:35:26,637 --> 01:35:29,597
- With something that hates to take a bath...
- Nurse Bibs, Booth 7.

926
01:35:29,682 --> 01:35:33,852
And that throws up on the carpet,
that chews on your underwear.

927
01:35:33,936 --> 01:35:36,396
Dogs, on the other hand, are real cute.

928
01:35:36,480 --> 01:35:38,815
They got cute little noses, cute little tails.

929
01:35:38,899 --> 01:35:41,317
- Again?
- A lot of sick people out there.

930
01:35:41,402 --> 01:35:45,155
- This looks like the dog act to me.
- Yeah, right.

931
01:35:45,239 --> 01:35:49,033
Let's hear some rock 'n' roll.
Hey, how's it going?

932
01:35:49,118 --> 01:35:51,911
Let's hear you play.
Give us something good.

933
01:35:51,996 --> 01:35:54,205
You're getting better all the time!

934
01:36:16,937 --> 01:36:19,397
All the girls are downstairs.

935
01:36:19,482 --> 01:36:22,192
Guys, this is the -

936
01:36:22,276 --> 01:36:24,944
Please get it right 'cause I'm getting -
I'm getting cranky.

937
01:36:40,336 --> 01:36:42,962
Mother Dana, call for you, Booth 19.

938
01:36:43,047 --> 01:36:45,757
Mother Dana, Booth 19.

939
01:37:15,871 --> 01:37:17,789
Hello?

940
01:38:21,687 --> 01:38:23,688
Yeah. Who do you want?

941
01:38:23,772 --> 01:38:28,735
I want to see a blonde girl with kind of
short, straight hair, about 25 years old.

942
01:38:28,819 --> 01:38:32,822
Okay. She's coming down.
Stay on the line.

943
01:38:50,466 --> 01:38:52,800
Hello, honey.

944
01:38:54,970 --> 01:38:56,888
Oh, mercy.

945
01:38:56,972 --> 01:39:01,434
You know, 23 - I've worked 23
of the 24 booths in this place.

946
01:39:01,518 --> 01:39:03,519
Uh -

947
01:39:03,604 --> 01:39:05,605
Poolside makes 24.

948
01:39:05,689 --> 01:39:08,691
So, what can I do for you today, hmm?

949
01:39:10,736 --> 01:39:12,779
I've got an idea.

950
01:39:12,863 --> 01:39:15,365
How about water polo?

951
01:39:16,575 --> 01:39:19,035
Having fun. Lots of fun.

952
01:39:20,496 --> 01:39:23,873
No? Uh, well, tell you what.

953
01:39:23,958 --> 01:39:26,876
Why don't you just tell, uh, Nurse Bibs
where the pain is?

954
01:39:26,961 --> 01:39:30,338
- Maybe I can find a cure, hmm?
- Why don't you look at me?

955
01:39:30,422 --> 01:39:32,423
I am looking at you.

956
01:39:32,508 --> 01:39:35,301
No, but I'm over here.
Can't you see me?

957
01:39:35,386 --> 01:39:39,430
Listen, sweetheart, if I could see you,
I wouldn't be working here.

958
01:39:39,515 --> 01:39:42,809
Well, what do you see?

959
01:39:42,893 --> 01:39:44,894
I see what you see.

960
01:39:44,979 --> 01:39:49,816
Nurse Bibs.
N urse Bibs and a rubber horse.

961
01:39:49,900 --> 01:39:52,819
Oh. Oh, I see.

962
01:39:52,903 --> 01:39:56,656
Th-Thank you, N urse Bibs.

963
01:39:56,740 --> 01:39:58,700
Thank you.

964
01:41:08,062 --> 01:41:11,230
Hi.

965
01:41:13,859 --> 01:41:15,860
Are you out there?

966
01:41:17,571 --> 01:41:22,075
Well, I see your light's still on,
so I guess you must be out there.

967
01:41:22,159 --> 01:41:24,077
Hmm?

968
01:41:26,580 --> 01:41:29,582
It's okay if you don't wanna talk, you know.

969
01:41:29,666 --> 01:41:32,710
I don't wanna talk either sometimes.

970
01:41:32,795 --> 01:41:35,797
I just like to stay silent.

971
01:41:42,596 --> 01:41:50,596
Do you mind if I sit down?

972
01:41:59,029 --> 01:42:01,531
No.

973
01:42:03,283 --> 01:42:05,201
Thanks.

974
01:42:05,285 --> 01:42:09,872
My legs get a little tired
from standing all the time.

975
01:42:12,417 --> 01:42:15,628
Is this your first visit here?

976
01:42:15,712 --> 01:42:20,049
- Yes.
- Oh!

977
01:42:20,134 --> 01:42:23,928
Well, this whole thing
must seem kind of strange to you, huh?

978
01:42:24,012 --> 01:42:27,807
You realize that I can't see you
even though you can see me?

979
01:42:27,891 --> 01:42:31,727
Well, that takes a little gettin' used to.

980
01:42:31,812 --> 01:42:33,729
Oh.

981
01:42:33,814 --> 01:42:37,316
Am I - Am I looking at your face now?

982
01:42:45,742 --> 01:42:48,703
Oh, God. It don't matter.

983
01:42:48,787 --> 01:42:51,581
Oh.

984
01:43:01,675 --> 01:43:03,926
If, um -

985
01:43:04,011 --> 01:43:07,305
If there's anything you wanna talk about,
I'll just listen.

986
01:43:07,389 --> 01:43:09,307
All right?

987
01:43:09,391 --> 01:43:12,894
I'm a real good listener.

988
01:43:25,699 --> 01:43:28,409
Is there somethin' -

989
01:43:28,493 --> 01:43:32,205
I don't know.
Is there somethin' I can do for you?

990
01:43:40,923 --> 01:43:43,925
Do you mind if I take off my sweater?

991
01:43:45,636 --> 01:43:47,762
I'll just take off my sweater.

992
01:43:47,846 --> 01:43:50,389
No, no. No. Don't.

993
01:43:50,474 --> 01:43:52,850
Please. Please leave it on.

994
01:44:00,567 --> 01:44:02,485
I'm sorry.

995
01:44:06,573 --> 01:44:10,076
I just don't know exactly what it is you want.

996
01:44:11,620 --> 01:44:14,121
I don't want anything.

997
01:44:16,041 --> 01:44:19,126
Well, why'd you come here then?

998
01:44:27,803 --> 01:44:30,304
I - I want to talk to you.

999
01:44:50,867 --> 01:44:53,869
Is there something you want to tell me?

1000
01:44:56,873 --> 01:44:58,916
No.

1001
01:45:03,380 --> 01:45:06,382
You can tell me. I can keep a secret.

1002
01:45:15,559 --> 01:45:20,646
This, uh - Is that all you do is just talk?

1003
01:45:25,068 --> 01:45:27,111
Well, yeah.

1004
01:45:28,697 --> 01:45:30,906
Yeah, mostly.

1005
01:45:30,991 --> 01:45:32,908
And listen.

1006
01:45:37,080 --> 01:45:39,582
What else do you do?

1007
01:45:49,843 --> 01:45:52,762
- Why are you laughing?
- I'm sorry.

1008
01:45:57,851 --> 01:46:00,311
I'm sorry.

1009
01:46:00,395 --> 01:46:02,897
So what else do you do?

1010
01:46:04,858 --> 01:46:06,776
Nothin' really.

1011
01:46:09,613 --> 01:46:12,740
Oh, well, we're not allowed
to see the customers out here.

1012
01:46:14,618 --> 01:46:17,203
Where do you see them then?

1013
01:46:17,287 --> 01:46:19,288
Do you go home with them?

1014
01:46:20,665 --> 01:46:22,666
No, sir, we don't.

1015
01:46:25,003 --> 01:46:28,839
We're not allowed to have any
outside relationships with the customers.

1016
01:46:28,924 --> 01:46:31,884
Yeah, but you can really see 'em
if you want to, can't you?

1017
01:46:31,968 --> 01:46:34,970
I mean, you can go home with 'em
if you want to. All these places say that.

1018
01:46:35,055 --> 01:46:39,558
How much extra money do you make? How much -
How much money do you make on the side?

1019
01:46:51,071 --> 01:46:55,533
I'm sorry, sir. I think you'll maybe
want to talk to one of the other girls.

1020
01:46:55,617 --> 01:46:57,910
I'll see if I can find one for you.

1021
01:46:57,994 --> 01:47:00,454
No. No, no, no!

1022
01:47:00,539 --> 01:47:02,540
Please. Please.

1023
01:47:04,126 --> 01:47:06,127
Please don't go.

1024
01:47:10,674 --> 01:47:13,926
I just don't think
I'm the one you want to talk to.

1025
01:47:16,346 --> 01:47:18,722
Please.

1026
01:47:18,807 --> 01:47:21,142
Please don't go. I'm sorry.

1027
01:47:29,818 --> 01:47:32,361
All right.

1028
01:47:38,034 --> 01:47:42,496
I'm, um - I'm sorry. I'm sorry.

1029
01:47:47,419 --> 01:47:50,463
That's okay.

1030
01:47:58,847 --> 01:48:00,848
You know, I -

1031
01:48:00,932 --> 01:48:04,435
I know how hard it is to talk
to strangers sometimes.

1032
01:48:09,733 --> 01:48:11,692
Just relax.

1033
01:48:13,153 --> 01:48:15,571
Relax and tell me what's on your mind.

1034
01:48:17,908 --> 01:48:19,867
I'll listen...

1035
01:48:21,912 --> 01:48:23,871
to you.

1036
01:48:28,376 --> 01:48:30,878
I don't mind listening.

1037
01:48:38,762 --> 01:48:41,430
I do it all the time.

1038
01:49:02,494 --> 01:49:04,745
She was there, wasn't she?

1039
01:49:43,243 --> 01:49:45,160
What's that?

1040
01:49:50,625 --> 01:49:52,543
A vacant lot.

1041
01:49:52,627 --> 01:49:57,298
I bought that land when we were all together,
with your mom.

1042
01:50:00,302 --> 01:50:03,304
I thought we might live there someday.

1043
01:50:05,682 --> 01:50:07,391
Where?

1044
01:50:07,475 --> 01:50:10,686
Paris, Texas.

1045
01:50:10,770 --> 01:50:12,688
Where's that?

1046
01:50:14,024 --> 01:50:16,692
It's close to the Red River.

1047
01:50:21,072 --> 01:50:23,449
Do you like it?

1048
01:50:23,533 --> 01:50:26,118
You mean we'd live on dirt?

1049
01:50:41,259 --> 01:50:44,261
Why do you drink that stuff?
It stinks.

1050
01:50:46,222 --> 01:50:49,725
- Wait a minute. Where are you going?
- To the truck.

1051
01:51:10,413 --> 01:51:12,414
Have another one?

1052
01:51:53,373 --> 01:51:55,290
Come on, Dad.

1053
01:52:21,025 --> 01:52:23,861
This is not a place to bring a fancy woman.

1054
01:52:26,948 --> 01:52:31,744
Would you say? If you had a fancy woman,
would you bring her in a place like this?

1055
01:52:31,828 --> 01:52:34,288
What's a fancy woman?

1056
01:52:51,097 --> 01:52:54,308
Oh! God.

1057
01:52:54,392 --> 01:52:56,602
My mother -

1058
01:52:57,937 --> 01:52:59,855
Not your mother...

1059
01:52:59,939 --> 01:53:02,608
but my mother...

1060
01:53:02,692 --> 01:53:05,277
was not a fancy woman.

1061
01:53:05,361 --> 01:53:07,780
She was -

1062
01:53:13,161 --> 01:53:17,790
She never wanted to be a fancy woman.
She never even pretended to be a fancy woman.

1063
01:53:17,874 --> 01:53:20,626
Then what was she?

1064
01:53:20,710 --> 01:53:23,253
She was just plain.

1065
01:53:25,507 --> 01:53:27,466
Just plain and good.

1066
01:53:27,550 --> 01:53:30,427
She was very good.

1067
01:53:30,512 --> 01:53:32,429
But my daddy -

1068
01:53:35,016 --> 01:53:37,893
See, my daddy had, uh -

1069
01:53:37,977 --> 01:53:39,978
He had this idea -

1070
01:53:40,063 --> 01:53:44,191
he had this idea in his head
that was kind of-

1071
01:53:44,275 --> 01:53:48,111
kind of-kind of a sickness.

1072
01:53:48,196 --> 01:53:50,113
What idea?

1073
01:53:50,198 --> 01:53:52,658
He had this idea about her...

1074
01:53:52,742 --> 01:53:54,660
and...

1075
01:53:56,120 --> 01:53:58,831
he looked at her...

1076
01:53:58,915 --> 01:54:01,416
but he didn't see her.

1077
01:54:03,920 --> 01:54:07,589
He - He saw this idea.

1078
01:54:11,427 --> 01:54:15,305
And he told people that she was from Paris.

1079
01:54:16,933 --> 01:54:19,685
It was a big joke...

1080
01:54:19,769 --> 01:54:21,687
but he started telling everybody
all the time...

1081
01:54:21,771 --> 01:54:23,772
and finally it wasn't a joke anymore.
He st -

1082
01:54:27,277 --> 01:54:29,444
He started believing it.

1083
01:54:30,864 --> 01:54:34,032
And he actually believed it.

1084
01:54:37,287 --> 01:54:39,371
And she -

1085
01:54:39,455 --> 01:54:41,790
Oh, God.

1086
01:54:41,875 --> 01:54:44,710
She would get so embarrassed.

1087
01:54:46,462 --> 01:54:48,505
She -

1088
01:54:48,590 --> 01:54:50,924
She was so -

1089
01:54:53,094 --> 01:54:55,429
She was so shy.

1090
01:55:43,978 --> 01:55:45,979
Vámonos, muchacho.

1091
01:56:14,801 --> 01:56:16,718
Left, Dad.

1092
01:56:31,401 --> 01:56:33,735
Hunter, it's me.

1093
01:56:36,906 --> 01:56:40,409
I was afraid I'd never be able
to say the right words to you...

1094
01:56:40,493 --> 01:56:42,786
in person...

1095
01:56:42,870 --> 01:56:46,832
so I'm trying to do it like this.

1096
01:56:49,794 --> 01:56:52,921
When I first saw you this time...

1097
01:56:53,923 --> 01:56:55,882
at Walt's...

1098
01:56:57,176 --> 01:57:00,679
I was hoping for all kinds of things.

1099
01:57:02,598 --> 01:57:06,268
I was hoping to show you
that I was your father.

1100
01:57:08,354 --> 01:57:10,522
You showed me I was.

1101
01:57:14,027 --> 01:57:17,029
But the biggest thing I hoped for...

1102
01:57:19,198 --> 01:57:21,199
can't come true.

1103
01:57:23,536 --> 01:57:26,038
I know that now.

1104
01:57:27,707 --> 01:57:30,208
You belong together with your mother.

1105
01:57:32,545 --> 01:57:35,338
You belong together with your mother.

1106
01:57:36,966 --> 01:57:40,135
It was me that tore you apart...

1107
01:57:40,219 --> 01:57:43,722
and I owe it to you to bring you back together.

1108
01:57:45,141 --> 01:57:47,684
But I can't stay with you.

1109
01:57:47,769 --> 01:57:51,354
I could never heal up what happened.

1110
01:57:51,439 --> 01:57:54,900
That's just the way it is.

1111
01:57:54,984 --> 01:57:58,361
I can't even hardly remember what happened.

1112
01:57:58,446 --> 01:58:00,822
It's like a gap.

1113
01:58:00,907 --> 01:58:03,617
But it left me alone in a way that...

1114
01:58:03,701 --> 01:58:06,078
I haven't gotten over.

1115
01:58:06,162 --> 01:58:09,748
And right now, I'm afraid.

1116
01:58:11,459 --> 01:58:14,586
I'm afraid of walking away again.

1117
01:58:14,670 --> 01:58:17,172
I'm afraid of what I might find.

1118
01:58:18,674 --> 01:58:21,384
But I'm even more afraid of...

1119
01:58:21,469 --> 01:58:24,763
not facing this fear.

1120
01:58:24,847 --> 01:58:27,349
I love you, Hunter.

1121
01:58:28,518 --> 01:58:31,269
I love you more than my life.

1122
01:58:42,281 --> 01:58:46,201
Hey.

1123
01:58:50,706 --> 01:58:53,458
Can I tell you something?

1124
01:58:55,002 --> 01:58:57,712
Sure. Anything you like.

1125
01:58:59,215 --> 01:59:01,174
It's kind of long.

1126
01:59:02,218 --> 01:59:04,553
I got plenty of time.

1127
01:59:27,952 --> 01:59:30,328
I knew these people.

1128
01:59:30,413 --> 01:59:32,372
What people?

1129
01:59:33,624 --> 01:59:35,625
These two people.

1130
01:59:40,715 --> 01:59:43,216
They were in love with each other.

1131
01:59:45,720 --> 01:59:48,430
The girl was... very young...

1132
01:59:48,514 --> 01:59:52,184
about 17 or 18, I guess.

1133
01:59:53,603 --> 01:59:57,105
And the guy was... quite a bit older.

1134
01:59:58,649 --> 02:00:01,776
He was kind of raggedy and wild.

1135
02:00:02,904 --> 02:00:05,363
And she was very beautiful, you know?

1136
02:00:07,366 --> 02:00:09,284
Yeah.

1137
02:00:09,368 --> 02:00:13,538
And together they turned everything
into a kind of an adventure...

1138
02:00:14,790 --> 02:00:17,709
and she liked that.

1139
02:00:17,793 --> 02:00:21,588
Just an ordinary trip
down to the grocery store was...

1140
02:00:21,672 --> 02:00:24,716
full of adventure.

1141
02:00:24,800 --> 02:00:28,553
And they were always laughing
at stupid things.

1142
02:00:28,638 --> 02:00:31,765
He liked to make her laugh.

1143
02:00:31,849 --> 02:00:33,850
And...

1144
02:00:35,394 --> 02:00:38,104
they didn't much care for anything else...

1145
02:00:38,189 --> 02:00:42,108
because all they wanted to do
was be with each other.

1146
02:00:43,861 --> 02:00:46,363
They were always together.

1147
02:00:46,447 --> 02:00:49,074
Sounds like they were very happy.

1148
02:00:49,158 --> 02:00:51,993
Yes, they were.

1149
02:00:52,078 --> 02:00:54,913
They were real happy.

1150
02:00:54,997 --> 02:00:58,333
And he - he loved her more than...

1151
02:01:00,836 --> 02:01:03,004
he ever felt possible.

1152
02:01:06,008 --> 02:01:10,595
He couldn't stand being away from her,
uh, during the day when he went to work.

1153
02:01:16,018 --> 02:01:19,020
So he quit...

1154
02:01:19,105 --> 02:01:21,773
just to be home with her.

1155
02:01:21,857 --> 02:01:25,986
Then he'd get anotherjob
when the money ran out...

1156
02:01:26,070 --> 02:01:28,613
and then he'd quit again.

1157
02:01:28,698 --> 02:01:31,533
But pretty soon, she started to worry.

1158
02:01:35,913 --> 02:01:38,748
- About what?
- Money, I guess.

1159
02:01:38,833 --> 02:01:40,750
- Not having enough.
- Mmm.

1160
02:01:40,835 --> 02:01:43,211
Not knowing
when the next check was coming in.

1161
02:01:45,339 --> 02:01:48,133
Yep, I know that feeling.

1162
02:01:48,217 --> 02:01:52,971
So he started to get kind of torn inside.

1163
02:01:56,642 --> 02:01:59,019
How do you mean?

1164
02:01:59,103 --> 02:02:02,188
Well, he knew he had to work to support her...

1165
02:02:02,273 --> 02:02:05,275
but he couldn't stand
being away from her either.

1166
02:02:06,944 --> 02:02:08,862
I see.

1167
02:02:08,946 --> 02:02:12,449
And the more he was away from her,
the crazier he got...

1168
02:02:13,576 --> 02:02:16,578
except now he got really crazy.

1169
02:02:20,041 --> 02:02:22,584
He started imagining all kinds of things.

1170
02:02:24,337 --> 02:02:26,254
Like what?

1171
02:02:27,923 --> 02:02:32,135
He started thinking
that she was seeing other men on the sly.

1172
02:02:33,471 --> 02:02:36,306
He'd come home from work
and accuse her of...

1173
02:02:36,390 --> 02:02:38,850
spending the day with somebody else.

1174
02:02:38,934 --> 02:02:41,686
He'd yell at her and break things in the trailer.

1175
02:02:44,190 --> 02:02:46,107
The trailer.

1176
02:02:51,280 --> 02:02:53,698
Yes.

1177
02:02:53,783 --> 02:02:56,284
They lived in a trailer home.

1178
02:03:11,050 --> 02:03:15,178
Excuse me, sir,
but were you in to visit me the other day?

1179
02:03:15,262 --> 02:03:17,597
I don't mean to pry.

1180
02:03:19,308 --> 02:03:21,893
No.

1181
02:03:21,977 --> 02:03:23,895
Oh.

1182
02:03:25,356 --> 02:03:29,025
I thought I recognized your voice for a minute.

1183
02:03:30,486 --> 02:03:33,488
No. Wasn't me.

1184
02:03:34,865 --> 02:03:36,825
Mm-hmm.

1185
02:03:38,828 --> 02:03:40,829
Please go on.

1186
02:03:43,249 --> 02:03:47,585
Anyway, he started to drink real bad...

1187
02:03:47,670 --> 02:03:50,839
and he'd stay out late to test her.

1188
02:03:52,675 --> 02:03:55,552
What do you mean "test her"?

1189
02:03:55,636 --> 02:03:58,304
To see if she'd get jealous.

1190
02:03:59,306 --> 02:04:01,975
Mm-hmm.

1191
02:04:03,727 --> 02:04:07,564
He wanted her to get jealous, but she didn't.

1192
02:04:07,648 --> 02:04:10,066
She just worried about him...

1193
02:04:10,151 --> 02:04:12,652
but that got him even madder.

1194
02:04:13,863 --> 02:04:16,281
Why?

1195
02:04:16,365 --> 02:04:18,700
Because...

1196
02:04:18,784 --> 02:04:22,203
he thought if she never got jealous of him
that she didn't really care about him.

1197
02:04:23,873 --> 02:04:28,293
Jealousy was a sign of her love for him.

1198
02:04:28,377 --> 02:04:30,795
And then one night -

1199
02:04:30,880 --> 02:04:35,008
one night she told him that she was pregnant.

1200
02:04:35,092 --> 02:04:37,969
She was about three or four months' pregnant...

1201
02:04:38,053 --> 02:04:40,305
and he didn't even know.

1202
02:04:40,389 --> 02:04:43,641
And then suddenly everything changed.

1203
02:04:43,726 --> 02:04:47,687
He stopped drinking and got a steadyjob.

1204
02:04:47,771 --> 02:04:52,734
He was convinced that she loved him now
because she was carrying his child.

1205
02:04:52,818 --> 02:04:56,779
And he was going to dedicate himself
to making a home for her.

1206
02:04:57,948 --> 02:05:00,658
But a funny thing started to happen.

1207
02:05:00,743 --> 02:05:02,368
What?

1208
02:05:02,453 --> 02:05:04,871
He didn't even notice it at first.

1209
02:05:04,955 --> 02:05:07,582
She started to change.

1210
02:05:07,666 --> 02:05:12,587
From the day the baby was born, she began
to get irritated with everything around her.

1211
02:05:12,671 --> 02:05:15,423
She got mad at everything.

1212
02:05:15,508 --> 02:05:19,010
Even the baby seemed to be an injustice to her.

1213
02:05:19,094 --> 02:05:22,055
He kept trying
to make everything all right for her -

1214
02:05:22,139 --> 02:05:26,476
buy her things,
take her out to dinner once a week.

1215
02:05:26,560 --> 02:05:29,312
But nothing seemed to satisfy her.

1216
02:05:29,396 --> 02:05:33,066
For two years,
he struggled to pull them back together...

1217
02:05:33,150 --> 02:05:36,528
like they were when they first met...

1218
02:05:36,612 --> 02:05:41,115
but finally he knew
that it was never gonna work out.

1219
02:05:42,535 --> 02:05:44,661
So he hit the bottle again.

1220
02:05:44,745 --> 02:05:47,789
But this time, it got mean.

1221
02:05:47,873 --> 02:05:50,416
This time, when he came home late at night...

1222
02:05:50,501 --> 02:05:53,836
she wasn't worried about him orjealous.

1223
02:05:53,921 --> 02:05:56,297
She was just enraged.

1224
02:05:57,800 --> 02:06:02,220
She accused him of holding her captive
by making her have a baby.

1225
02:06:04,139 --> 02:06:07,100
She told him that she dreamed about escaping.

1226
02:06:07,184 --> 02:06:11,062
That was all she dreamed about - escape.

1227
02:06:11,146 --> 02:06:15,024
She saw herself at night,
running naked down a highway...

1228
02:06:15,109 --> 02:06:17,235
running across fields...

1229
02:06:17,319 --> 02:06:19,279
running down riverbeds.

1230
02:06:19,363 --> 02:06:21,281
Always running.

1231
02:06:21,365 --> 02:06:25,702
And always, just when she was
about to get away, he'd be there.

1232
02:06:25,786 --> 02:06:29,080
He would stop her somehow.

1233
02:06:29,164 --> 02:06:31,833
He would just appear and stop her.

1234
02:06:34,712 --> 02:06:39,257
And when she told him these dreams,
he believed them.

1235
02:06:39,341 --> 02:06:43,177
He knew she had to be stopped,
or she'd leave him forever.

1236
02:06:43,262 --> 02:06:45,930
So he tied a cowbell to her ankle...

1237
02:06:46,015 --> 02:06:50,018
so he could hear at night
if she tried to get out of bed.

1238
02:06:50,102 --> 02:06:53,980
But she learned how to muffle the bell
by stuffing a sock into it...

1239
02:06:54,064 --> 02:06:57,108
and inching her way out of the bed...

1240
02:06:57,192 --> 02:06:59,110
and into the night.

1241
02:07:00,321 --> 02:07:02,196
He caught her one night
when the sock fell out...

1242
02:07:02,281 --> 02:07:04,824
and he heard her trying to run to the highway.

1243
02:07:04,908 --> 02:07:07,577
He caught her,
dragged her back to the trailer...

1244
02:07:07,661 --> 02:07:10,705
and tied her to the stove with his belt.

1245
02:07:12,541 --> 02:07:17,211
He just left her there and went back to bed...

1246
02:07:17,296 --> 02:07:21,174
and lay there, listening to her scream.

1247
02:07:21,258 --> 02:07:25,511
Then he listened to his son scream.

1248
02:07:25,596 --> 02:07:28,097
He was surprised at himself because...

1249
02:07:28,182 --> 02:07:31,017
he didn't feel anything anymore.

1250
02:07:32,603 --> 02:07:35,605
All he wanted to do was sleep.

1251
02:07:37,524 --> 02:07:39,734
And for the first time...

1252
02:07:39,818 --> 02:07:42,612
he wished he were far away...

1253
02:07:45,741 --> 02:07:50,536
lost in a deep, vast country
where nobody knew him...

1254
02:07:50,621 --> 02:07:53,289
somewhere without language...

1255
02:07:53,374 --> 02:07:56,084
or streets.

1256
02:07:56,168 --> 02:08:00,171
And he dreamed about this place
without knowing its name.

1257
02:08:00,255 --> 02:08:03,591
And when he woke up, he was on fire.

1258
02:08:06,595 --> 02:08:10,556
There were blue flames
burning the sheets of his bed.

1259
02:08:10,641 --> 02:08:13,351
He ran through the flames...

1260
02:08:13,435 --> 02:08:16,938
toward the only two people he loved...

1261
02:08:17,022 --> 02:08:18,940
but they were gone.

1262
02:08:21,610 --> 02:08:25,613
His arms were burning,
and he threw himself outside and -

1263
02:08:27,282 --> 02:08:29,951
and rolled on the wet ground.

1264
02:08:32,204 --> 02:08:34,205
Then he ran.

1265
02:08:35,457 --> 02:08:37,959
He never looked back at the fire.

1266
02:08:40,462 --> 02:08:42,672
He just ran.

1267
02:08:48,554 --> 02:08:51,222
He ran until the sun came up...

1268
02:08:52,433 --> 02:08:55,560
and he couldn't run any further.

1269
02:08:56,729 --> 02:08:59,230
Then when the sun went down...

1270
02:08:59,314 --> 02:09:01,315
he ran again.

1271
02:09:07,156 --> 02:09:11,075
For five days, he ran like this...

1272
02:09:11,160 --> 02:09:14,036
until every sign of man...

1273
02:09:16,790 --> 02:09:18,791
had disappeared.

1274
02:09:29,845 --> 02:09:31,804
Travis.

1275
02:10:14,348 --> 02:10:17,600
If you turn the light off in there,
will you be able to see me?

1276
02:10:26,026 --> 02:10:28,027
I don't know.

1277
02:10:32,533 --> 02:10:34,534
I never tried.

1278
02:10:53,303 --> 02:10:55,471
Can you see me?

1279
02:10:56,974 --> 02:10:59,684
Yeah.

1280
02:10:59,768 --> 02:11:01,936
Do you recognize me?

1281
02:11:04,022 --> 02:11:05,940
Oh, Travis.

1282
02:11:13,407 --> 02:11:15,908
I brought Hunter with me.

1283
02:11:28,005 --> 02:11:30,339
Don't you want to see him?

1284
02:11:32,426 --> 02:11:34,343
Yeah.

1285
02:11:42,978 --> 02:11:47,523
I wanted to see him so bad
that I didn't even dare imagine him anymore.

1286
02:11:53,655 --> 02:11:56,490
Anne kept sendin' me pictures of him...

1287
02:11:59,453 --> 02:12:01,954
until I asked her to stop.

1288
02:12:08,170 --> 02:12:11,213
I couldn't stand the... pain...

1289
02:12:11,298 --> 02:12:14,300
of seeing him grow up and missin' it.

1290
02:12:23,185 --> 02:12:26,187
Why didn't you keep him with you, Jane?

1291
02:12:29,316 --> 02:12:31,317
I couldn't, Travis.

1292
02:12:35,447 --> 02:12:38,449
I didn't have what I knew he needed.

1293
02:12:45,082 --> 02:12:48,751
I didn't want to use him
to fill all my emptiness.

1294
02:12:54,132 --> 02:12:56,467
Well, he needs you now, Jane...

1295
02:12:56,551 --> 02:12:58,511
and he wants to see you.

1296
02:12:58,595 --> 02:13:00,596
He does?

1297
02:13:03,058 --> 02:13:04,976
Yes.

1298
02:13:09,106 --> 02:13:11,607
He's - He's waiting for you.

1299
02:13:11,692 --> 02:13:13,609
Where?

1300
02:13:16,113 --> 02:13:18,614
Downtown...

1301
02:13:18,699 --> 02:13:20,700
in a hotel.

1302
02:13:22,577 --> 02:13:24,495
The Meridian.

1303
02:13:26,456 --> 02:13:28,416
Room 1520.

1304
02:13:33,296 --> 02:13:35,256
1520.

1305
02:13:36,341 --> 02:13:39,176
You're not going, are you?

1306
02:13:53,859 --> 02:13:56,360
I can't see you, Jane.

1307
02:13:58,238 --> 02:14:06,238
Don't go yet.

1308
02:14:24,806 --> 02:14:26,766
I -

1309
02:14:28,977 --> 02:14:32,646
I used to make up long speeches to you
after you left.

1310
02:14:37,694 --> 02:14:40,404
I used to talk to you all the time...

1311
02:14:40,489 --> 02:14:42,823
even though I was alone.

1312
02:14:46,161 --> 02:14:49,663
I walked around for months talking to you.

1313
02:14:53,710 --> 02:14:56,212
Now I don't know what to say.

1314
02:15:00,801 --> 02:15:03,803
It was easier when I just imagined you.

1315
02:15:11,686 --> 02:15:14,688
I even imagined you talking back to me.

1316
02:15:19,319 --> 02:15:22,238
We'd have long conversations...

1317
02:15:23,782 --> 02:15:25,783
the two of us.

1318
02:15:29,412 --> 02:15:31,914
It was almost like you were there.

1319
02:15:36,211 --> 02:15:38,212
I could hear you.

1320
02:15:38,296 --> 02:15:40,297
I could see you, smell you.

1321
02:15:42,384 --> 02:15:44,385
I could hear your voice.

1322
02:15:47,389 --> 02:15:50,057
Sometimes your voice would wake me up.

1323
02:15:52,894 --> 02:15:54,895
It would wake me up in the middle of the night...

1324
02:15:54,980 --> 02:15:57,231
just like you were there in the room with me.

1325
02:16:05,740 --> 02:16:07,700
Then...

1326
02:16:10,537 --> 02:16:12,538
it slowly faded.

1327
02:16:14,624 --> 02:16:17,126
I couldn't picture you anymore.

1328
02:16:20,755 --> 02:16:24,008
I tried to talk out loud to you like I used to...

1329
02:16:24,092 --> 02:16:26,594
but there was nothin' there.

1330
02:16:29,973 --> 02:16:32,349
I couldn't hear you.

1331
02:16:37,606 --> 02:16:39,565
Then...

1332
02:16:44,404 --> 02:16:46,405
I just gave up.

1333
02:16:52,829 --> 02:16:54,997
Everything stopped.

1334
02:16:56,791 --> 02:16:58,709
You...

1335
02:17:02,464 --> 02:17:04,632
just disappeared.

1336
02:17:10,805 --> 02:17:13,057
Now I'm working here.

1337
02:17:18,605 --> 02:17:21,440
I hear your voice all the time.

1338
02:17:25,737 --> 02:17:29,657
Every man...

1339
02:17:29,741 --> 02:17:31,992
has your voice.

1340
02:17:50,679 --> 02:17:54,181
I'll tell Hunter... that you're coming.

1341
02:17:59,104 --> 02:18:01,689
- Travis?
- What?

1342
02:18:05,485 --> 02:18:07,486
I'll be there.

1343
02:18:12,158 --> 02:18:14,076
Good.

1344
02:18:19,040 --> 02:18:20,958
Meridian Hotel.

1345
02:18:21,042 --> 02:18:22,960
Yeah.

1346
02:18:26,548 --> 02:18:30,259
Room 1520.

1347
02:19:39,120 --> 02:19:41,872
Yeah!

1348
02:19:41,956 --> 02:19:44,708
"Why, you little" -

1349
02:19:44,793 --> 02:19:47,836
Yeah!

1350
02:19:47,921 --> 02:19:51,715
Yeah.

1351
02:21:19,679 --> 02:21:22,181
Your hair, it's wet.

1352
02:21:31,232 --> 02:21:33,484
Oh!

