[Dogs Barking]
Hey ya! Hey ya!
[Man Shouting To Dogs]
[Siren]
Why, Smilla?
My baby.
Isaiah!
He was playing on the roof.
He fell.
All right, nothing to see now.
Come on.
I just need a few
from this angle.
O.K.
I f-f-found him.
What made him run?
Who are you?
I'm the lady who lived
upstairs from him.
He's the gentlemen
from the ground floor.
Well, you're not
allowed up here.
I'll need the footprints
of the deceased.
I don't know why the hell
he was playing up here,
running around wild
without supervision.
A strange way to play,
don't you think?
Take these people
downstairs.
The tracks go in a straight
line towards the edge.
No child in the world
would play like that.
Can you just
go down now, please?
Why so many accidents,
Smilla?
First my husband,
and now my baby.
Why, Smilla?
I don't know.
How am I going to go
to the morgue tomorrow?
If they think
it's an accident,
why are they doing
an autopsy?
They told me
to show up and...
sign papers,
and get his things.
I'll go, Juliane.
Let me go.
I had hoped he would
live a long life.
Yes. All parents hope that
for their children.
I have children
of my own.
I know how
you must feel.
My deepest
condolences.
I'm not his mother.
We were friends.
Beat it,
you little shit.
[Speaking Foreign Language]
Wanna read me a story?
No, I won't
read you a story.
[Bell Rings]
[Ding Ding Ding]
Persistent little bastard,
aren't you?
I can't be your
little friend. O.K.?
I have nothing
to offer you.
Just go away.
Hmm?
Look, there's absolutely
no future in this.
"A point is that which
cannot be divided.
A line is a length
without breadth."
This can't possibly
interest you.
Hmm.
"A semicircle
is a figure
contained within
a diameter
and the circumference
intersected
by the diameter."
You smell bad.
I don't mean to say this
to hurt your feelings,
but you really
stink.
What interests you?
Do you know anything
about Greenland?
Hmm.
You should
know something
about where you're from.
Why?
Because it tells you
who you are.
It's important
to know who we are.
Do you know
who you are?
No.
Did your mom
read you stories?
She told me stories.
About what?
About Greenland.
When she used to hunt,
stories like that.
Miss Smilla,
can we go home?
Why, are you tired?
No, home to Greenland.
What do you want me to do,
lie to you?
Tell you we'll go to Greenland
and then not go?
Get your hopes up?
If Inuits
who are feuding
wish to reconcile,
they touch each
other's breasts,
and say ilaga.
Ilaga.
It means friend.
When a child
dies like that,
it's a tragedy.
Terrible accident.
It wasn't an accident.
I see.
Who did the autopsy?
It was routine.
That's not
what I asked you.
Doctor Loyen.
Johannes Loyen?
Isn't he the head of
the Institute of Arctic Medicine?
Mm-hmm.
Why would such
a famous man
do an autopsy
on a 6-year-old?
It was routine.
So you've said.
I'm so sorry
for your loss.
Do you think
his feet were cold?
He always wore
those sneakers.
When I saw him
lying there in the snow,
his soles were
so run-down.
His feet
must have been cold.
Would you like
something to drink?
I may be from Greenland,
but I don't drink.
Are you...
Are you hungry?
Look, I don't want to share
anything with you. O.K.?
O.K.
Perhaps you can sleep.
Go-G-Good night.
Do you always stutter?
No.
I make you nervous then?
Don't you think I see
the way you look at me?
What did you think,
we'd get drunk
and fuck all night,
fueled by our mutual grief?
Is that what you thought?
It's O.K., Smilla.
I loved him, too.
Yeah.
Of course you did.
Dr. Loyen.
You're of Greenlandic descent.
My mother was Greenlandic.
You were the one
who examined Isaiah?
Yes.
What I would
like to know is
what did he die of?
He fell from
a height of 5 stories.
The organism as a whole
simply collapses.
Was there any trace
of violence?
None at all.
What makes you think that?
Is it possible
to see the report?
You wouldn't
understand it.
Look, both we
and the police
are interested in
the most thorough
investigation possible.
In a case like this,
if there's even
the slightest doubt,
we look for everything
and we find everything.
A child defends itself,
gets skin cells
under its nails.
There was nothing like that,
nothing at all.
We looked at
the police report.
The footprints
show quite clearly
that the boy was
alone on the roof
before he fell.
There was nothing
to indicate
that this was anything
but an accident.
It's tragic, of course,
but the case is closed.
Now, please drop by again,
my dear lady,
if there's anything else
that troubles you.
I'm filing a complaint
with the district attorney.
What makes this your business?
A 6-year-old boy was murdered.
I'm making it my business.
I've told you there's
no forensic evidence
to indicate foul play,
none whatsoever.
I don't really care about
your forensic evidence.
I knew him,
and that's my evidence.
We all have our phobias.
Do you know what
Isaiah's was?
It was heights.
Nevertheless,
he was up there.
Yes, he was.
And what puzzles me...
what keeps me
awake at night
is wondering what made him
go up there at all.
May I please spend the night?
[Shouting And Loud Music]
Hello!
We're going
to miss the film.
You're late.
I've called the agency twice.
It's not the baby-sitter, dear.
Come in.
We get 1,000 cases a year.
I can't be expected
to remember every single one.
Unburden yourself, Lagermann.
You'll feel better.
We were very busy
the night he was brought in:
drunk drivers,
Christmas parties.
You're not squeamish,
are you?
No.
I have a little trick,
the kind of thing
you invent in any profession.
I hold a light bulb
inside his trousers.
In one leg,
there is a perforation.
I examine the boy again.
All of this is routine.
I find a hole in his thigh.
There's no bleeding,
and the tissue hasn't contracted.
You know what that means?
No.
It means that
whatever happened at that spot
occurred after his heart
had stopped beating.
I take a closer look
at his trousers.
There's a little indentation
around the hole.
This rings a bell.
So I get out
a biopsy needle,
a kind of syringe, quite big,
attached to a handle.
You plunge it into the tissue
to get a sample.
The hole in his trousers
was where someone in a hurry
shoved it in
with a good whack.
Someone had taken
a muscle biopsy from him
after he died.
The ambulance men?
I talked to the driver
and the medics
and the orderlies
who received the body.
They all swore
on a stack of Bibles
that they didn't do it.
Why didn't Loyen
tell me this?
I was just beginning the autopsy
when Loyen arrived.
He was surprised
I'd started on the boy.
He pulled me off it
and took over.
What do you think
was after him on the roof?
I don't know.
But I won't be much
in the Christmas spirit
until I find out.
Please don't come here again.
One more thing.
The night he died
wasn't the first time
I'd seen him.
He came in once a month.
Loyen examined him...
alone.
I don't suppose
there are any records.
I've already looked.
Nothing.
Man:
Blessed be the God and Father
of our Lord Jesus Christ
who had blessed us with
all spiritual blessings,
and heavenly places
of the Christ...
...the foundation
of the world...
that we should be holy
and without blame before Him.
[Continues, Muffled]
And love, having predestinated us...
...by Jesus Christ
who Himself...
...in praise of
the glory of His grace,
wherein He hath
made us accepted...
in whom we have redemption
through His blood,
the forgiveness of sins,
according to
the riches of His grace...
[Continues Indistinctly]
Who was that man
at the funeral?
What was he trying
to give you?
I don't want
his money no more.
Dirty money.
What money?
Why does he
give you money?
They always try
to buy me out.
First my husband,
now my kid.
Who's they?
"We wish to inform you
that the directors
of Greenland Mining
have decided to grant you
a widow's pension
following the death
of your husband...
Norsaq Christiansen."
It's signed Elsa Lubing.
Who's she?
Who's Elsa Lubing?
Can I take this?
Oh, yes.
I filmed this
as you came back
from the hunting trip
with your mother.
You'd had bad weather
with a lot of fog.
You were lost.
Everyone had given up hope.
Your mother said
you suddenly pointed
with complete conviction.
You knew the way home.
No one could explain it.
From that day on,
they always strapped you
to the front of the sledge
whenever they went
on a hunting trip.
[Laughing Quietly]
You knew exactly
how to get home.
Yeah, Father.
How the hell
do you explain that?
I don't know.
I just knew.
You were a regular
little Eagle Scout.
A real little
Nanook of the North.
Cut it out, Benja.
You should try Brentan.
What?
Brentan. For fungus
between the toes.
It's not fungus.
People don't get that
till they reach your age.
Yeah, adolescents do, too.
Especially if
you work out a lot.
And it spreads quite easily
to the crotch.
What do you know
aboutJohannes Loyen?
He's a...
very talented man.
He created the Institute
for Arctic Medicine.
What's his interest
in forensic medicine?
He started out
as a pathologist.
He did an autopsy
on a 6-year-old boy.
Ha.
Must have been
a good career move.
Since our school days,
Loyen has always wanted
to be recognized
as the best in the world,
not just in Denmark,
but in the universe.
It wasn't a flame
like in the rest of us.
It was a conflagration.
He wrote this as his thesis
for his professorial degree.
"Mesozoan Parasites."
What are they?
Prehistoric worms.
Write me a prescription, Father.
Are you sick, Smilla?
With this piece of paper,
you can save my life
and keep your
hippocratic oath.
It has to be
5 figures.
I let someone down.
A child.
It'll take money
to do something about it.
I'm afraid that check
won't be nearly enough.
He only gives you money
because you make him
feel so guilty.
He told me that.
And he only gives you money, Benja,
because you're such
an amusing little fuck.
But one day,
like all of us,
you'll wake up
and your perfect tits
will be starting to sag,
and your perfect
little piquant ass
will be starting to go.
Then what, Benja?
By then, Smilla,
you'll be dead,
and I won't care.
Come for Christmas dinner?
I don't celebrate Christmas.
It doesn't mean
anything to me.
They hunted seals
by their igloos.
They stalked them
with screens on the ice.
"They waited for them
on a floe edge,
and they harpooned them
from kayaks."
They hunted them
in the bluish darkness
of the winter night.
To the Inuits,
the seal was life.
Isaiah, what did I just say?
Isaiah?
Tell me what I just said.
Tell me.
What did I just say?
My God.
Juliane?
Juliane, Isaiah's gone deaf.
He's gone deaf
from having 3 ear infections
from you not taking care of him!
Doctors say he was O.K.
What doctors?
Who told you he's O.K.?
He's not O.K.
There's nothing
to worry about.
Ilaga.
I'm not mad at you.
Stop it.
Ilaga, ilaga.
Yes, you're my friend.
Ilaga, Isaiah.
Please...
don't be frightened.
I'm from the district
attorney's office.
Do you always
make house calls?
Let's just say it's
the nature of this case...
and because of your
thought-provoking letter.
I spoke to Professor Loyen.
He told me that
you came in to see him.
There were tracks
in the snow.
I read the report
and looked at the pictures.
You have to have special
lenses and lights
or it doesn't show up.
What doesn't show up?
They were acceleration tracks.
When you take off
from the snow or ice,
a pronation occurs
in the ankle joint
like when you walk
barefoot in the sand.
If the movement
is too fast,
not firm enough,
they'll be
a little slip backwards.
As with any child
who is playing--
If you're used to
playing in the snow,
you don't leave
that kind of track
because the movement
is not efficient.
He grew up in Greenland.
He was used to snow.
You don't believe me?
I didn't say that.
The truth is
I've felt uncomfortable
about this case
from the beginning.
And when you wrote
your letter,
that confirmed it for me.
There was so little
to go on.
What do you
want me to do?
Find out
what was after him.
I'll do my best.
You have my word.
Thank you.
I don't know
your name.
Ravn.
I'll be in touch
with you.
Thank you, Mr. Ravn.
Thank you for
believing me.
Hello?
My name is
Smilla Jaspersen.
I have some questions
about Greenland Mining.
I'm sorry,
I can't help you.
I don't work there
anymore.
Who is it?
Delivery for Elsa Lubing,
from the florist.
She isn't home.
Could you buzz me in,
please?
We have strict
instructions
not to open the door
for nonresidents.
They're orchids,
Mrs. Schou,
straight off the plane
from Portugal,
and they'll die
if I leave them out here.
[Buzzer]
I can see you!
You won't get away
with anything.
I remember this letter
quite well.
She said
she had flowers.
It's all right,
Mrs. Schou.
At this time of day,
I'm normally in prayer.
Norsaq Christiansen's death
was a tragic accident,
especially for the boy.
A child needs
both parents...
one of the reasons
why marriage is sacred.
Mr. Lubing would be
pleased to hear that.
There's no Mr. Lubing.
I am the bride ofJesus.
The boy is dead.
4 days ago,
he fell off a roof.
I met him once.
When I saw him
I knew why it was written:
"Unless we become
as little children,
we cannot enter paradise."
I hope his mother
finds her way toJesus.
Only if one can find Him
at the bottom of a bottle.
Oh, He is everywhere,
even there.
Someone chased the boy
off the roof.
He was murdered.
The devil assumes
many forms.
It's one of those forms
that I'm looking for.
Do you know
a Professor Loyen?
No.
Was he on the payroll
of Greenland Mining?
I don't remember.
You said that
you met Isaiah.
When?
Greenland Mining
began to hire Inuits
for the geological expeditions,
and it was on
one of those expeditions
in the summer of 1993
on the Gela Alta glacier...
that the father died.
When we awarded
the pension,
the son and his mother
came to my office.
How did
the father die?
An explosion.
You are interested
in the past, Ms.Jaspersen.
I'm interested in why
the chief accountant
of Greenland Mining
has such
a guilty conscience
that she's writing
notes in the margins
of pension awards.
May I see the report
of that expedition?
They're in the safe
in the archive department.
There's nothing to see.
Thou shalt not lie,
Ms. Lubing.
I think you should go now.
Why do you think
someone was chasing
the little boy?
There was snow on the roof
that he fell from.
I saw his footprints.
The way you have
a sense of God,
I have a sense
of snow.
Ms.Jaspersen?
Hello?
Would you come back up
for a moment?
[Buzzer Rings]
Just now when you left,
I opened...it at
the Book of Revelations.
"And the fifth angel sounded,
and I saw a star
fall from Heaven
onto the earth,
and to him
was given the key
of the bottomless pit."
The key to hell.
Miss Jaspersen,
how far will you go?
Try me.
There are 2 archive sections
in the basement
of our building
on Strand Boulevard.
That's where the expedition
reports are kept.
Naturally, I cannot mention
that there's
a passkey system
nor that the abloy key
on the wall behind you
is for the main entrance
to the building.
Ms. Lubing: Someone has
to guard the gates of hell.
[Dog Barking]
Good doggie.
[Growling Softly]
Ah!
Why were you
following me?
I've been thinking
about what you said...
about the footprints.
If you're right,
you're in danger.
You can, um...
sit.
Isaiah and I were friends,
you know.
He used to make me laugh.
He had this little game
where he used to put his head
in his hands like this,
and when he'd come up,
he would be...
a monkey or a rabbit
or Frankenstein or whatever.
I used to see him, um...
come home sometimes
in a cab.
I--He always seemed so...
so afraid.
They examined him every month
at the hospital.
I think that's
what scared him.
Why? What do you think
they were looking for?
I don't know.
Someone shoved
a biopsy needle into him
after he died,
and a very important doctor...
I do...appreciate it when someone
makes me something good.
Thank you.
Don't go.
Isaiah's father
was on an expedition
for Greenland Mining
when he died.
That prick Loyen
was the medical consultant.
I saw his name in here.
Try to read it.
It'll be good for
your dyslexia.
Smilla.
Why does such a nice person
have such a rough mouth?
I'm sorry if I've
given you the impression
it's my mouth
that's rough.
I try to be
rough all over.
[Ding Ding]
[Ding]
Miss Jaspersen,
I'd like to talk to you, please.
Talk.
Would you mind coming
to the station with us?
I would mind.
I'm sorry, you must.
Keep your hands off me.
I'll come with you,
just take your hands off.
Get your hands off me!
You don't have to go
if you don't...
f-f-feel like it.
Will I be driven home?
To your door.
Can't resist a man with manners.
See you later.
"Smilla Jaspersen,
born the 1 6th ofJune, 1 960,
in Quanaaq, Greenland.
Parents:
Ann Qaavigaaq Jaspersen,
a local hunter,
and Moritz Jaspersen,
American physician.
In 1989, employed by
the Geodetic Institute.
From 89-93,
scientific participant
in expeditions
to the ice cap,
the Arctic Ocean,
and arctic North America."
Various references
are attached...
all of which
state unanimously
that if you want to know
anything about ice,
you would benefit by
consulting Smilla Jaspersen.
Captain Telling here,
however,
has gathered
some information
of a different character.
Moved to Denmark in 1967
after the death
of your mother.
Expelled from 4 boarding schools.
Admitted to Copenhagen University,
asked to leave a year later."
Then there are these
other references,
all of which state
that you have created trouble
wherever you've been.
Arrested twice.
Once in Canada.
I was tagging polar bears.
Bears don't read maps,
so they don't respect
national boundaries.
This paints a picture
of a woman
who has never completed
a course of study,
who has been unemployed
for years, who has no family,
who's created conflict
wherever she's been:
someone who has never
been able to fit in.
Anyone with any sense
would keep a very low profile
in your position.
Is it my clothes
you don't like?
What we don't like
are your fruitless
and damaging attempts
to meddle in the investigation
of this case
which I have already promised you
I would look into.
I remember
what you promised me.
Screw you, Ravn.
[Door Opens]
These belong to
Greenland Mining.
We found them
in your flat.
Imprisonment in
a little soundproof room
with no windows is,
I've been told,
particularly difficult
if you've been brought up
in Greenland.
This would cause you
extreme distress.
It's true,
is it not?
They say
it's something about
those vast spaces,
the horizon.
That what it is?
All that space.
Good.
Then we mustn't
let that happen.
We've reached
an agreement, then.
Will you say that
louder, please,
so I can hear you?
[Hoarsely]
Yeah.
We've reached
an agreement.
You may go home now.
[Ding]
[Ding Ding
Ding Ding]
[Telephone Rings]
[Ring]
Smilla, this is
your father.
Could you come for lunch
tomorrow at the club?
Call me--
Anything is better
than suicide?
How can you have
6 spelling mistakes in 5 words?
I'm not suicidal.
Suicide is for cowards.
Sometimes one just wants
to be left alone, that's all.
There was an earlier
expedition in '66.
There was an accident
that time, too.
2 of the 8 men died.
Loyen was on both expeditions.
I can't be
part of this.
I came to
tell you that.
I'm out of it.
Good luck.
Smilla.
W--
What did they d--
do to you?
They threatened
to lock me up.
And I can't be locked up.
I'm quite ashamed.
Really, I am.
I just can't be locked up.
Don't.
It's O.K.
Do you think I need you
to understand me?
God. Sorry.
What is it about you
that always makes me
want to insult you?
When my father
first brought me here
from Greenland,
I refused to sleep indoors.
I couldn't stand it:
the heat.
I was used to the snow,
the air.
I made a tent
out on the lawn.
[Chuckles]
Poor Moritz.
He was so embarrassed.
Even now my idea of hell
is to be locked up.
Where...
Where was your mother?
She went out one day
to hunt.
They found her kayak
a few days later.
The side had been
staved in.
No one who falls
into the water in Greenland
ever comes up again.
The sea is less than
39 degrees Fahrenheit,
and at that temperature,
all the processes of
decomposition stop.
- How old were you?
- 6.
That's when
you came here?
That's when my father
brought me here.
But you were never
happy here?
The only thing
that makes me truly happy
is mathematics,
snow, ice,
numbers.
To me, the number system
is like human life.
First you have
the natural numbers,
the ones that are whole
and positive,
like the numbers
of a small child.
But human consciousness expands,
and the child
discovers longing.
Do you know the mathematical
expression for longing?
Negative numbers.
The formalization
of the feeling
that you're missing
something.
Then the child discovers
the in-between spaces
between stones,
between people,
between numbers,
and that produces fractions.
But it's like
a kind of madness,
because it doesn't
even stop there.
It never stops.
There are numbers
that we can't even
begin to comprehend.
Mathematics is a vast,
open landscape.
You head towards the horizon
that is always receding...
like Greenland.
And that's--that's what
I can't live without.
Smilla.
That's why I can't be locked up.
Can I kiss you?
Smilla.
It's Christmas Eve.
Toast with me.
To what?
To Isaiah.
Don't you understand?
My heart is broken.
Then to
a merry Christmas.
And a happy New Year.
[Opens Door]
[Closes Door]
Smilla.
Merry Christmas,
Juliane,
you look wonderful.
2 days, Smilla.
No drink.
Merry Christmas,
Smilla.
He hid this box good.
You should keep it now.
Open it.
His Walkman.
You gave it to him
last Christmas. Remember?
It was his best present.
They let Isaiah
go with them
on the expedition?
The Greenland Mining people
were looking for men
in Greenland.
My husband signed on.
They told us that
Isaiah could go with him,
so how dangerous
could it be?
They were digging
inside a glacier.
Something
must have happened.
Isaiah was outside.
They took his dad
in a helicopter
to the hospital,
and there his dad died.
He never saw him again.
What really happened,
Juliane?
Be careful, Smilla.
It was not an accident.
There was something
in the melt water.
Isaiah told me so.
In the melt water?
How would Isaiah know?
His daddy told him.
But he couldn't
have done.
You just said they flew
your husband away...
Smilla, please.
...in a helicopter.
No more questions.
Who brought Isaiah home?
This doctor. Loyen.
Was Isaiah sick,
Juliane?
Is that why Loyen
examined him every month?
Smilla, please.
No more questions.
I'm scared.
But I'll do it anyway.
I knew you would.
The Inuit believe
that if you kill something,
you offend its soul.
I need his soul
to be at peace.
[Glasses Clink]
Did you ever hear
the phrase,
"She was so drunk
that she didn't know
what she was doing"?
That's why I'm doing this
before I drink anything.
Go back inside.
Smilla.
What?
Don't answer the phone
from now on.
Smilla.
What a surprise.
We weren't expecting you.
I thought you didn't
celebrate Christmas.
I don't.
So what do you
celebrate, Smilla?
Oh, I celebrate
the loners,
the outcasts,
the shy girl
with pimples,
the fattest boy
in class,
dyslexics,
the stutterers,
the premature
ejaculators.
You're such a freak.
Some men died
on an expedition
to the west coast
of Greenland.
I need to know why.
Will you look
at them for me?
I thought you wanted
to have lunch with us.
Do this for me, Moritz.
I'm happy today for
the first time in ages.
The man with
the white hair.
Do you know him?
Dr. Andreas Tork.
Scientist.
Leading specialist
in arctic mineralogy.
Powerful man.
Very ambitious.
Head of Greenland Mining.
Why? You want to meet him?
Why would someone
examine a child
every month
at a hospital?
If he'd been exposed
to a virus, to, uh...
Why would someone
shove a biopsy needle
into a dead 6-year-old?
Oh, gross. I'm not eating now.
Forget it.
Answer me.
I'm not eating
a bloody thing, Moritz.
I don't know, Smilla.
To measure the progress
of something...you know.
Thank you.
Call me when you've
looked at that.
I was following you.
He recognized me
from the funeral.
He stopped me
and asked me
how Juliane was doing.
You were with him.
I was not with him!
We started to talk.
I thought I could
learn more about
Greenland Mining.
I was following you there.
Smilla.
Don't you trust me?
No.
Juliane:
I told you, we have nothing!
Nothing!
You fucking bastard!
[Grunts] Oh...
Leave us alone!
[Whimpers]
Isaiah.
What happened?
[Whimpering]
It's O.K.
It's me, Smilla.
Isaiah.
[Door Opens]
[Footsteps]
[Knock Knock Knock]
Smilla?
[Man Speaking Indistinctly]
[Static]
[Indistinct]
How did you find me?
It wasn't hard.
You're considered
the best ear in Copenhagen.
You called about a tape.
It was left next to
an electrical box.
Maybe that's what affected
the sound on it.
I can't make it out.
[Indistinct]
Sounds like some kind
of an announcement.
[Static]
I can't hear anything.
That's because
you haven't
trained your ear.
[Garbled Voices]
Hear it now?
It's not live.
It's coming
from a loudspeaker.
An intercom.
Maybe in a hospital
somewhere.
Can you hear
the doctor's beeper?
No.
And there's someone
whispering, too.
What's he saying?
He's in a lot of pain.
[Beeping]
There's an EEG
in there as well,
monitoring his heart.
[Distorted Voices]
What's he saying?
[Man Speaking
Foreign Language]
It's difficult to say.
It's an East Greenlandic dialect.
[Voice Continues]
He's...
He's talking to his son--
Isaiah.
He's trying to tell
what happened
in an ice cave.
[Loud Static]
[Airplane Engine]
Did you hear that?
That's a Sikorsky R1 7
overhead.
Late '93, early '94.
This must be the hospital
in the American air base
in Thule.
I'm amazed you can
conclude so much
from so little.
Blindness sharpens
the sense of hearing.
Is there any way
you can clean up
the tape?
Come back in an hour.
Woman: Are you
finished with that?
Man: Yeah,
that's all right.
Hello?
Were you really
just following me?
Yes.
I want to kiss you again.
Would you like that?
Yes.
Smilla, where are you?
[Ship Horn]
Smilla?
[Dial Tone]
[Ship Horn]
Mr. Licht?
[Heavy Door Slams]
[Footsteps]
[Metal Scraping]
Open the door!
Open it!
[Explosion]
Talk to me.
You have to
talk now, Smilla.
Snow. Talk to me
about snow.
So many.
There's too many kinds.
Say them!
Qanik.
What's that? Hmm?
Talk.
It's falling snow.
What other kinds?
- [Siren Passes]
- Aquilluqqag.
It's wet, wet snow.
It's not firm enough
to build a snow house with.
You must never
use it for that.
I won't.
Promise me?
I promise.
- [Sirens]
- More. Come on, more.
Did you hear the tape?
They killed Isaiah for it.
[Crying]
Did you get it?
No.
He could have made it.
Not like Smilla,
the fake.
The fake Greenlander
with her fine clothes
and manners.
I let him die.
No, you didn't.
The tablets will
start to work
in a few minutes.
Then it won't
hurt so much.
You must sleep now.
When I was little,
I knew where
I was going.
Yes.
I'm very lost now.
Stay with me.
I'm right here.
Lie down with me.
Kinngusaqattaarpoq.
What does it mean?
Say it.
I can't say it.
To practice rolling over
in a kayak.
Makittaqanngitsoq.
Pff. Jesus.
[Laughing]
Someone who has never
mastered the art
of rolling over
in a kayak.
Umiiarneq.
A shipwrecked person.
You're not shipwrecked.
Pilluaqaanga.
It's to be deeply happy.
I'm sorry,
I have to go.
Smilla?
You cannot stay
in your apartment.
They've already tried
to kill you once,
and if they know
you're alive,
they won't make the
same mistake again.
Now go to your
father's house.
You'll be safer
with him.
I've seen
that car before.
Don't turn around.
They found something
in 1 966.
Something went wrong,
and they waited
30 years
before they sent
another expedition.
But then something else
went wrong.
There was an accident.
4 men died.
One of them was
Isaiah's father.
So before Isaiah's
father dies,
he sends his son a tape
telling him what
really happened.
Tork comes looking
for the tape,
they kill Isaiah to get it.
And then they killed
the man on the boat.
There's got to be
something else
on that tape.
Like what they
really found
up there in Greenland.
They're planning
to go up again.
They've had to wait
until now
for the pack ice to melt
in the Davis Strait.
I know a man...
who knows about boats.
Norsaq Christiansen, dead,
on the Gela Alta glacier,
July 1 993.
Hmm.
It says in the report
that he died
in an explosion,
but I don't think that's
what killed these men.
These are enlargements
I made from the negatives.
You can see what remains
of the liver,
the esophagus, stomach.
This is the heart--
what's left of it.
Smilla?
Do you notice anything
unusual here?
Something's got
into the heart.
But what is it?
This-- This is so gross.
What's it got
to do with us?
Get her out of here.
Darling, why don't you
wait for me outside?
I'll join you later.
But it's disgusting.
What's it got
to do with us?
I'll be with you soon.
Please. Please.
Smilla?
This is the arctic worm.
Drancunculus Borealis.
Prehistoric.
No one has seen pictures
of them before.
Loyen must have
photographed them.
You see, the female worm
entered these men's
vital organs.
The uterus burst.
There were 1 0 million
larvae released.
The men go into toxic shock.
They die on the spot.
But it's very strange.
Parasites don't usually
kill their hosts.
It's very bad manners.
But I thought the worm
was extinct.
I thought so too, Smilla.
But the question is,
what brought them
back to life?
Why are you getting
involved in this?
I told you before...
a child died.
It's my New Year's resolution
to make someone pay.
This friend of yours
who dropped you off.
Is he also involved?
I don't know.
I don't know him
very well.
He has a repair shop
which he never goes to.
His hands
are much too clean.
He lies to me.
I don't know what he does.
Are you in love with him?
I've been trying
to avoid it
all my life,
so now that
it's here,
I just want
to renounce it.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I'm tired of
wondering why it is
that every day
I'm on this earth
I'm in exile.
I'm sorry you're so angry.
I'm sorry
I made you do things.
Is it time for
confession, Moritz?
What things did you
make me do?
I made you leave
your country.
What were you
supposed to do,
leave me there?
I punished you because
your mother was dead.
I'd look at you,
and I'd see her face.
I never loved anyone
the way I loved
your mother.
Benja will be sorry
to hear that.
It's late, Smilla.
I'm going to bed.
All day today I thought
about your hands on me.
Your mouth on my mouth.
This friend of yours, Lander.
What does he do?
He owns the place.
Now, what can I do for you?
I need to know where
the boat is going...
why it's going,
and who's behind it.
The ship you saw, the Kronos,
it's classified ice class.
They spent an incredible
amount of money
getting her ready.
Whatever they're after
has to be very lucrative
for them to recoup
the investment they've made.
But you don't know...
Normally a ship is
chartered with a crew.
But in this situation,
you would prefer
a bare-boat charter--
a ship and nothing else.
Then you find a captain.
He has to be a special
kind of person,
the kind you can take aside,
and over a full glass
tell him that his wages
will be a little
out of the ordinary.
On the other hand,
you need all his tact
and sensitivity.
Where would someone
find such a person?
Right here.
That gentleman over there.
Captain Sigmund Lukas.
A very, very skilled
German seaman.
Knows the North Atlantic
like no one else.
Doesn't drink,
but he gambles.
He no longer has
a home or a family.
And now he's for sale,
if the amount
is big enough.
If he's so broke,
whose money is he
playing with?
Uncle Lander's money, honey.
That's why he's going
to be nice to you.
This is not a game.
If you go on board
that boat,
they'll kill you.
I need to know
what happened to him.
You don't even know
where the boat is going.
Wherever the boat
is going,
I'll find out why
they killed Isaiah.
They've come for you.
Just keep walking.
Don't turn around.
Lander'll be
waiting outside.
Go to your father's house.
Wait there.
I'll meet you there.
Man: Perfect!
Miss Jaspersen?
Miss Jaspersen.
Go.
- Open this door!
- Go!
I need you to help me
get on the Kronos.
What makes you think
I can help?
Just talk to Lukas.
[Laughing]
My life is shit.
But whatever it's worth
I owe to your boyfriend,
so the answer is no.
I'm going whether
you help me or not.
Wait, wait, wait.
You scare me, honey.
Other women,
it's all threat,
and no action.
You, I believe.
You'll go anyway
and get yourself
really fucked.
So give me a call
when you're ready.
Thank you, Lander.
[Police Radio]
O.K., thank you very much.
It's the door
straight on.
Benja?
You don't belong here.
They're going
to take you away.
You can't run away
your whole life.
We'll get you
a good lawyer.
They'll find a way
to kill me,
or I'll just have
an accident.
I was resisting arrest.
I tried to escape.
And you'll spend
your wretched life
knowing you could
have saved me.
Are you going,
or should I get...
Give us a minute.
But you promised me!
Quiet!
She is crazy!
I can't take this anymore!
Will you be quiet?
What do you
want me to do?
Drive your car
to the back
so I can get in,
and lie down
on the floor,
and then cover me.
Lander.
Where are you?
Meet me at the marina.
Thank you, Lander.
I'm coming.
Once you drive off,
I'll send them
after you.
[Gasps]
Benja.
Leave me alone.
[Gagging]
[Gasping Air]
Emergency at the hospital.
Good night.
Thanks for your help.
I wanted peace
and quiet so badly,
wanted my family
around me,
but I never
achieved that.
I don't want to let
you go, Smilla.
I'll take that.
Thank you, Lander.
Change your mind and
come back with me.
I can't do that.
Man: Ooh, sweet thing.
Men: Welcome back,
welcome back.
We've been waiting for you.
Nils Jakkelsen.
Stick with me.
I can do things
for you.
You know what I mean?
[Laughter]
You can start
by getting my bag.
[Laughter]
Man: That's one way to do it.
I'll take you
to the captain.
To your left, upstairs.
Here.
Straight on.
It's in there.
You can go, Jakkelsen.
You're on board
because we needed
a cabin steward.
Your duties include
light cleaning,
and you're responsible
for the ship's laundry.
You can go now.
We have representatives
from the shipping
company with us,
living on
the upper boat deck.
There's no admittance
whatsoever.
If you disobey
this order,
I'll have you locked up.
How about a quick fuck?
Women are crazy
about me.
Hmm.
[Whistling]
[Footsteps]
Smilla QaavigaqJaspersen.
That must be
a Greenlandic middle name.
What's on the upper deck?
Fucked if I know, man.
I've never seen security
like this before.
This whole outfit
is weird.
Even the captain says
he doesn't know
where we're headed.
And the crew.
They're a pile of shit,
and they
stick together.
They are scared,
and they won't tell me why.
And then the passengers
on the upper deck
we never get to see.
Who the fuck are they?
Then there's you, Smilla.
Why'd Lukas
let you on board?
Everyone thinks
you're a cop.
You're spying on me?
Actually, Jakkelsen,
I came for a quick fuck.
But you spoiled it
by talking.
And you're gonna
help me,
you little needle freak.
No way.
I get claustrophobic.
I'm not kidding.
You're not going.
I am.
I get claustrophobic.
Press the button
for the upper deck.
If anyone tries
to send you away,
just refuse to leave.
Give me an hour.
If I'm not back
in a hour,
wake up Lukas.
No. I can't do that, man.
Why not?
He's my father.
That's why I'm on board.
That's why I have the key.
He thinks I'm clean.
You'd do that to me, man?
You'd tell him?
In a second.
Now send me up.
Gentlemen.
What we are planning
to bring back
from our expedition
to Greenland
is a scientific
sensation--
the most valuable
discovery ever made.
An energy-producing
meteorite,
the fragment of a planet
from the beginning
of creation,
back from the origin
of the solar system.
Not only will it multiply
our investment,
but it will give
our company
a very dominating position
in the world.
But there's a drawback.
The stone brought a lethal
prehistoric organism
back to life.
It's a kind of worm.
Some of our men
were killed by this worm
when they were diving
in the melt water
around the meteorite
on our last expedition.
The only survivor is a child,
who, unfortunately,
ran into the water
in an attempt
to reach his father,
one of the divers.
Ever since this incident,
this child has been
kept under observa--
Man: Give me your hand here.
This worm
is always fatal,
but only when it reaches
the inner organs.
It seems that young people
can live with it longer,
presumably because their
immune systems are stronger.
[Doors Closing, Footsteps]
They're out
of champagne.
What did you
see up there?
Enough to nail
those bastards.
[Groans]
I've got her!
No!
[Groans]
[Alarm]
What else could I do?
I lit a cigar
and put it up
to the sensor.
I'm really
fucked now, man.
They know it's me.
Bunch of freaks!
What the hell
did you do
to make them want
to kill you?
They want to kill
both of us.
[P.A. System]
This is the captain.
We're approaching
the Nordic Star platform.
We'll be docked
for about half an hour.
All crew members are confined
to quarters.
No one is to leave
the ship.
I repeat:No one is
to leave the ship.
I've got
to get off now.
Don't look so panicky.
Just stay close to
Jakkelsen the Great.
Ever been to Hong Kong?
They offered me
a modeling contract once.
Let's go there.
You are expressly
refused permission
to leave the ship.
Any crew member attempting
to do so
will be arrested
and taken into custody.
Won't he worry
about you?
I'll send him
a telegram.
Let's get out of here.
How about a quick
fuck before we go?
Once the lights
go out,
give me a head start,
and then follow me.
[Glass Shatters]
Relax, man.
You can make it up
to me in Hong Kong.
Man: Aah!
[Whimpering]
Get up!
We're almost there.
I don't feel well.
It'll be hard to find
a modeling job.
Never look right
at the audience.
You got to look
over their heads.
Proud. Like you
don't give a shit.
Like a fucking star, man.
Like a star.
Yeah, Jakkelsen.
Oil rigging will commence
in 45 minutes.
Please be sure to secure
all your safety clothing
as recommended by
the Ansi safety standards.
Oil rigging will commence
in 45 minutes.
Please be sure to secure
all your safety clothing
as recommended
by the Ansi safety standards.
What are they
paying you?
Is it enough?
The g-government
never pays well enough.
Listen to me!
The government knew
that there was
something big going on.
They didn't know
what it was exactly,
but they knew they
were going again.
They hired me
because I was a diver,
because I was the kind of person
that Tork needed.
I met him:
he trusted me.
He arranged for me to
move into the building
to keep an eye
on the boy.
I didn't even know
that he was sick.
You never loved him!
Of course I loved him!
I just wanted
to protect him,
and for a while,
I thought that I could.
Listen to me.
Listen.
There's not a night
that goes by...
that I don't dream
that I catch him.
I catch him
in my arms...
...before
he hits the ground.
We can start over.
Tork and Loyen
are desperate.
They're under
extreme pressure.
They'll show no mercy.
You can hide
in my cabin,
but only
for a little while.
The ship is approaching
the coast.
You've to get ashore.
Just go inland.
Wait for me.
There's a village
just inside the bay
about 7 miles
to the south.
[Wind Howls]
[Voices]
You see how it's
drawing energy
from some sort of
vacuum in the center?
I knew you'd come.
For people
with resources,
the right events
happen.
They may look
like coincidences,
but they arise
out of necessity.
Incredible,
isn't it?
We can see
inside it.
It's not a real
meteorite.
Meteorites are cold.
This is warm.
Meteorites are dead.
This...is alive.
And why are you doing
all this, Tork?
Why, money.
Fame. More money.
This is the biggest
scientific discovery
of the century.
You can't remove it
and transport it
to a densely populated
part of the world.
Not until you know
exactly what it is.
You could set off
a catastrophe.
Oh, death
is always a waste,
but sometimes
it is the only way
to arouse people.
Bohr participated
in the construction
of the atom bomb
and thought it
would promote peace.
You lack
imagination, Smilla,
which is unforgivable
in a scientist.
What about the boy?
He jumped
into the damn water.
We were forced to take him
along into the cave.
His father collapsed
while he was still
near the surface.
The boy wanted to go to him.
It was Loyen's idea
to keep him under observation.
The worm was not
in his internal organs.
He never even felt it.
[Gunshot]
Aaarrrgh!
He killed my son.
[Beeping Sound]
[Gunshot]
[Drops Bar On Ground]
Tork!
The boy, Tork.
Tell me about
the day he died.
You were waiting
outside his school,
weren't you, Tork?
He's the only child
who walks home alone.
Smilla:
You follow him.
You grab him,
not by his arms,
but by his clothes
so you don't leave
any marks.
But you miscalculate.
He knows you, Tork,
Not from the hospital
where you spent hours
tormenting him,
but from the day
he saw his father die.
It's death itself
he associates with you.
You're guessing.
He gets to his building
and then there's
no escape.
He knows
what's behind him.
he's going to die.
This fear is even stronger
than his fear of heights.
Inside him an engine
is spinning
that will keep turning
until all his strength
is used up.
And you chase him
up to the roof.
Maybe for the first time
it occurs to you
not just to get the tape...
but that it's possible
to eliminate him.
And avoid him
ever telling anyone
what he saw in a cave
on a glacier somewhere
in the Davis Strait.
I didn't mean
to kill him.
I needed the tape.
He panicked,
I shouted,
he turned around,
he didn't see me.
You're lying.
He didn't turn around.
He couldn't hear a thing.
He was deaf.
[Explosion]
[Rumbling]