Captain's log, stardate 41235.25.
Our location, planet Ligon II,
source of a rare vaccine needed
on Federation planet Styris IV.
Starfleet has instructed me
to engage in a friendly visit
and open treaty negotiations
to acquire this medicinal substance.
Standard orbit, sir.
Lieutenant Yar calling
from Cargo Bay 1, sir.
Standing by to beam the Ligonian
welcoming party aboard.
On our way.
You have the helm, Mr. Data.
Cargo 1.
This should be an interesting
experience.
Agreed.
Not only are they closely humanoid,
but their history has remarkable
similarities to ours.
A highly structured society,
and they're exceedingly proud.
They've insisted on using their own
transporter device, sir.
It's their way, lieutenant.
Do they have our coordinates?
They have, sir. Precisely.
And they're standing by for your signal.
This is Captain Picard aboard
the Starfleet vessel Enterprise.
Please do us the honor
of visiting our vessel.
I am Lutan.
Captain Jean-Luc Picard.
Welcome aboard.
These are my officers.
My second in command,
Commander William Riker,
ship's counselor, Deanna Troi,
and my security officer,
Lieutenant Natasha Yar.
A woman?
- Your chief of security?
- Yes, Lutan. That is her expertise.
I am honored to meet your officers.
This is my secondary, Hagon.
A sample of the vaccine.
My duty, Lutan. I'm sorry,
but I'm required to inspect--
Out of my way, woman.
How interesting.
May we prove as surprising to you.
If I may suggest, sir. No apology.
In their view, it would weaken us.
Nothing concealed, captain.
Would you care to accept it?
Unless you care
to examine it further.
Absolutely not.
This vaccine sample is a gift of life
and we are honored at receiving it.
Would you do us the additional honor
now of letting us entertain you?
Yes, yes, please prepare it.
We shall join you shortly.
I ask forgiveness.
They are strange alien things.
You bear no fault.
But the female...
May be exactly what I have needed.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission:
to explore strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go where no one
has gone before.
Lutan, we are aware of many
of your planet's achievements,
and its unique similarity to
an ancient Earth culture we all admire.
On behalf of the Federation,
therefore,
I would like to present this token
of our gratitude and friendship.
From China's Sun Dynasty,
14th century.
- Thirteenth century, sir.
- Ah, yes, indeed.
A most thoughtful gift.
We are pleased.
We of Ligon have been apprehensive
about strangers.
We are not technologically advanced
as you,
yet we possess something
you do not.
A vaccine which has been
found to be an effective antidote
against your dreaded
Achilles fever.
If you respect our customs
and we see that respect,
we will be friends.
And we will make the antidote
available to all who need it.
If you require respect from us,
I am sure that you will see it.
Surrounded by such friendship,
I feel no need for my guards, heh.
I will return shortly.
Prepare to transport me then.
If there is anything else,
any further courtesy...
Would it be possible to see
one of your wondrous holodecks?
We have heard how they are used
to train your officers.
And used for many other things too.
Commander Riker, perhaps you
and Counselor Troi will demonstrate?
Would it be possible for Lieutenant Yar
to do so, captain?
Some demonstration
of defense training?
We've noticed you're intrigued with her
having security responsibilities.
But these things are not at all
unusual with us.
With us, it is the duty of women
only to own the land
and the duty of men to protect
and rule it.
Much the same has happened
in human history too.
I'd like to do it, sir.
As a sign of respect, perhaps.
- Very well.
- This way, please.
Aikido, one.
It won't move again
until my actions activate it.
You can create people
without a soul?
It's not a real person, Lutan.
It has no life.
Everything it does
is controlled by computer.
Who am I?
Do you hear me?
But it will feel real when it hits you.
A force like that cannot possibly come
from an image, Lutan.
Then you will show me, Hagon.
Thank you, lieutenant.
How very enlightening.
Aikido, vanish.
I could create two, even three,
but, really, one is enough.
As you fight with it, it learns,
and before long
it knows exactly how to defeat you.
Even the extraordinary
Lieutenant Yar?
It forces us to keep improving.
Your skill impresses me.
I like you.
Farewell, my new friends
of the noble Enterprise.
Understanding has made friends
of many different people.
We've had a good beginning, Lutan.
May I also extend a personal farewell
to Lieutenant Yar?
In your Federation terms...
Picard to Bridge. Red alert!
Shields up.
Photon torpedoes activated, sir.
What com contact
have we had with them?
With their orbital control station, sir.
Make contact there
and on all hailing frequencies.
This is the Enterprise to Lutan
and the Ligonian government.
You have committed an unfriendly act.
We insist that you reply immediately.
Photon torpedoes ready, sir.
Set them for a display blast
a thousand meters short
of the planet's surface.
- Set.
- Fire.
Do we know the source
of their transporter beam?
Our own transporter people have tried
to trace it, sir, but to no effect.
It reads similar
to early Starfleet efforts,
but uses the Heglenian shift
to convert energy
and matter in different...
Which is actually
not important at this time.
This is Captain Picard of the
Enterprise with a message to Lutan
whom I have so far acknowledged
as a friend.
But you have now committed what
our laws regard as an attack upon us.
Since you have visited our vessel,
you most certainly
know the power of it.
We insist that you reply
to this message.
Opinion, counselor.
Will they injure Lieutenant Yar?
I believe not, sir.
They seem mainly curious.
In the case of Lutan, however,
I did feel other needs.
What kind of needs?
Some sexual attraction
from all the males.
Lieutenant Yar is physically
very attractive.
But with Lutan, I felt something else.
Something more like avarice
or ambition.
- Other comments?
- If I may, sir?
One of the things about them
in the briefing studies
was their respect for patience.
Strongly emphasized.
And you can see it in the precise,
ritualistic way they do things.
I'm worried about
Lieutenant Yar too, sir.
But maybe we should sit
and wait them out.
Stardate 41235.32.
I am concerned.
Over a full day of waiting
with no response from Lutan.
We are now testing whether they are
aware of our sensors probing them.
So far, we believe we have pinpointed
Lutan's government compound.
- The vaccine, sir.
- Yes, doctor?
The vaccine.
I'm a physician, I've seen death.
But not on the scale this could mean.
You were testing
if you can replicate the vaccine.
And we can't.
The sample works fine
when used as an injection,
but it becomes unstable
when we try to replicate it.
You must get the vaccine
from the planet, captain,
as much as you can, immediately.
I'm aware of that, doctor.
You've never had to watch
a patient die from this disease.
That's true.
But I have seen my share of death.
Damn.
Where are the calluses we doctors are
supposed to grow over our feelings?
Perhaps the good ones
never get them.
May I speak to you about my son,
Wesley?
What? Oh, yes. Hmm, all right.
He seems quite interested
in starship operations,
and speaking as a mother,
of course,
he seems quite knowledgeable.
Well, yes, speaking as a mother.
He's on the turbolift.
You'll remember you ordered him
to stay off of the Bridge?
Wesley?
I haven't stepped one foot
on your Bridge, captain.
It's all right, sir,
I'll see that he leaves immediately.
- No.
- No?
Why don't you sit at Ops,
next to Lieutenant La Forge?
' Sir?
Is the whole ship deaf?
Sit down over there, young man.
Temporarily.
Captain, we have more information
from the briefing studies on Ligon.
Oh, excuse me.
Dr. Crusher,
some of this may interest you.
Let's hear the analysis.
It is a highly structured society
in which people live
by strict codes of honor.
For example, what Lutan did
is similar to what certain
American Indians once did
called "counting coup."
That is from an obscure language
known as French.
- Counting coup--
- Mr. Data, the French language,
for centuries on Earth,
represented civilization.
Indeed.
- But surely, sir...
- I suggest you drop it, Mr. Data.
Yes, sir.
Counting coup
could be something as simple
as touching an enemy
with a stick in battle,
or taking something
from him and escaping.
It was considered extremely heroic.
And under these circumstances,
Lutan considers himself heroic,
risking literally everything
in the face of our superior power.
And it fits Lutan's personality profile
as well.
He has an abnormally high need
for achievement.
Self image, to him, is a function
of what he thinks he's achieved.
Those who set their standards too high
can kill to meet them.
- Why Tasha?
- As a Starfleet security officer,
she may have represented
his riskiest prize.
Transmission from planet surface, sir.
Main viewer on.
- Lutan, what do you want?
- You will display your image, please.
What is required is an image
of Lieutenant Yar, well and--
Are you making demands, captain?
Sir.
According to the Ligon code of honor,
Lutan has done what he set out to do,
achieve recognition
for being daring and bold.
We've studied this
in some depth now, sir.
The proper thing for you to do now
is to ask to get Tasha back.
Ask for her?
Politely, captain.
And now, Lutan,
you have boldly taken Lieutenant Yar
from us and we ask that...
...you now please return her.
Then come visit us, captain,
and we shall return her to you.
Commander.
Commander?
- That's quite formal.
- So is this request, sir.
Uh, we believe it would be preferable
if the captain led this away party.
Agreed, sir.
Their customs concerning guests
make it much preferable.
And I'm very much against that idea.
Lutan is clearly a liar and devious.
Counselor Troi has admitted that
she believes he's capable of killing.
It is my duty to keep
the captain from danger, sir.
Except that Ligonian custom
makes it clear
that a visiting leader
becomes an honored guest.
Not us,
not second in command, him.
And the custom requires that Lutan
should die rather than violate that.
Yes, it seems reasonable,
put that way.
But I warn you, if you get hurt,
I'll put you on report, captain.
Welcome to my Centerplace,
Captain Picard.
Consider yourselves
my honored guests.
Every hospitality
will be accorded you.
This is my First One, Yareena.
Lutan is a fortunate man.
- You've met Counselor Troi.
- Yes.
As on your vessel,
you have only to name
whatever courtesy we can provide.
Then, sir, the courtesy of seeing
Lieutenant Yar.
Lieutenant Yar
will be returned to you tonight
at a banquet
I have arranged in your honor.
I'd like to see her now.
Bring Lieutenant Yar.
I find it odd, captain,
that a man of your experience
has such difficulty
in understanding ordinary politeness.
Such as the politeness of saying
"please" before abducting someone?
The expression "please" is used only
when requesting the person back.
Yours is a different world.
With clear and simple ways
deeply rooted in our culture.
If you are willing to ask for
Lieutenant Yar's return tonight,
in front of all, honor will be satisfied.
One can see
the importance of honor here, sir.
Honor is everything.
Have you been treated well,
lieutenant?
Fine, captain. But they're showing
some signs of wear.
There isn't any need to be concerned,
captain. She's being well cared for.
My ship's company and I are certain
of your gentle wisdom in that.
Heh, for a moment,
I thought I heard a threat implied,
but that would be foolishness.
Heh, something
to be carefully avoided, I agree.
The festivities for her return to you
are in preparation.
- Shall we retire until then?
- Until tonight, Lutan.
Lutan, you have granted us hospitality
and the safety of your Centerplace.
The gifts you give us are rare
and precious. We thank you.
And now, according to the customs
of your ancestors,
whom we honor and respect,
I am here in peace to ask
for the return of Lieutenant Yar.
Well spoken.
There are those among my equals
in this gathering
who were wary of my approaching
the Federation.
I am proud to have taken this first step
toward a treaty,
and proud that we have something
of great value to offer you,
a priceless, life-giving vaccine.
The abduction I have done
according to our custom for all to see.
Your conduct in this matter has been
beyond exemplary, Captain Picard.
But now that the moment has come,
I find that I cannot part with her.
You speak of a code of honor.
What you are saying now, according to
our custom, is called an act of war.
This is not an act of war, but of love.
I want Lieutenant Yar
to become my First One.
I challenge your right
of supersedence!
No woman has challenged
supersedence for over 200 years.
The right is mine and I will have it.
Natasha Yar, I challenge you.
- A struggle to the death.
- No.
The challenge
is unequivocally refused.
Then you shall have no treaty,
no vaccine and no Lieutenant Yar!
Ship's log,
First Officer Riker reporting.
We have been informed of the
challenge to Lieutenant Yar,
and are maintaining combat readiness
around the clock.
We are probing Lutan's compound
deeply with our sensors now,
still unnoticed.
Captain. Deanna.
Did you have any idea, lieutenant,
that Lutan was suddenly
going to announce
that he wanted you
for his First One?
No, sir.
- Tell me what you know about this.
- Nothing, sir.
But it was a thrill.
Lutan is such a basic male image
and having him say he wants you...
Yes, of course it made me feel
good when he...
Troi, I'm your friend
and you tricked me.
Only so you'd think about it
completely and clearly.
We're all being manipulated,
lieutenant. Myself, most of all.
How simple all this would be
without the Prime Directive.
That thought had passed
through my mind, counselor.
What is this message from
Starbase 14?
It's showing the infection rates,
percentage illness increases.
The plague on Styris IV
has flared up out of control.
They're estimating deaths
in the millions, sir.
Captain Picard, come in.
I know I can win.
Not that I'd take her life, of course.
But I'd be glad to embarrass her.
The idea of accusing me of taking...
The plague?
If anything,
even worse than we'd heard.
Which means they desperately
need the vaccine, sir.
And I know I can win this challenge.
You have nothing to prove here,
lieutenant.
But the vaccine is important
in this case, sir.
Counselor, you're the last person
I'd expect to argue
in favor of accepting the challenge.
Betazoid blood is also practical,
captain.
The odds are very good she'd defeat
Lutan's wife easily,
and you would win
all the bargaining points you need.
The odds are.
You have pointed out yourself, we are
all at risk every day of every mission.
I'll want some explanation
from Lutan.
Lutan, why are you so obsessed
with this Lieutenant Yar?
Surely Yareena is more desirable.
Certainly she can offer you
much more.
She owns many things, many lands.
It's a great pity you began by abducting
my security officer, Lutan,
because I should tell you I do admire
the hospitality you offer here.
I am in the grip of forces
you do not understand.
Some of it I do understand.
She is a rather lovely female.
Ha, ha, you surprise me, captain.
What do you know of needs
and feelings?
Nothing. Well, almost nothing,
in my position as ship's captain.
I see.
But it puzzles me,
if you feel like that for Tasha,
why have you challenged her
to a fight to the death?
Heh, not I. Yareena.
I am merely a spectator.
Ah, but you are also a man
of great importance and wealth.
Great importance, perhaps,
but he do--
I see.
You too understand
the proper value of women.
We understand
that they are highly pleasant things.
But after all, unimportant,
except for the land they own.
You are a truly clever person, Lutan.
You stand to lose nothing,
either way the challenge goes.
Heh, a code of honor protects one,
captain, like a magic cloak.
I will order Lieutenant Yar to fight.
And may your cloak
bring you all you deserve.
Come in.
Why that razor, my friend?
Why not the one I adjusted
to perfect efficiency?
Shaving is a human art form, Data.
Technological perfection
can shave too close.
Puzzling.
How can anything be too efficient?
Thousands of things are too efficient,
Data. At least for humans.
We always come back
to the human equation.
Exactly.
- Have you continued to work on it?
- Constantly, my friend.
Particularly the humor.
A man goes to a store
to buy some kidneys.
Oh, no.
He says to the shopkeeper,
"I'd like a pound of kiddillies, please."
The shopkeeper says,
"You mean kidneys, don't you?"
The man says,
"I said kiddillies, diddle I?"
It's too old.
And you didn't tell it very well.
How do you know
when something is funny?
It's not explainable. You just do.
Perhaps it is you, Geordi.
Includling the kiddillies,
I've told 662 jokes
and you have not...
"Includling the kiddillies."
Now, see, that's funny. Ha-ha-ha.
It was not meant as a joke.
The tongue slipped.
Oh, boy.
Riker to Commander Data,
Lieutenant La Forge.
Report to the Transporter Room
for Away Party duty.
First officer to captain.
Ready with the away personnel.
Lock in on this location.
Transporter locked in, sir.
Energize.
You've both seen the message
about the plague?
And how badly the vaccine is needed.
Yes, sir.
We need to know as much as possible
about Ligonian armaments.
Data, especially important is an
analysis of their combat capabilities.
Geordi, concentrate on their
cutting edges, wherever applicable,
durability, composition,
weaknesses of material.
- Aye, sir.
- From any particular point of view, sir?
From the perspective of Lieutenant Yar
using them in combat
with Lutan's wife.
Most interesting.
Could this be human joke
number 663?
Negative, Data.
That's a captain's order.
Which makes it important to know
which of these weapons
are to be used.
And that won't be known
until combat begins.
You're right, Data.
It does sound like a joke.
With the power of the Enterprise,
we could overwhelm this place easily
just take what we want.
I may not understand
human humor, sir,
but I am
a Starﬂeet Academy graduate.
Which means, of course...
Understanding
the Prime Directive, sir.
And that is, ironically,
what this is about.
By our standards, the customs here,
their code of honor,
is the same kind of pompous,
strutting charades
that endangered our own species
a few centuries ago.
We evolved out of it because no one
tried to impose their own set of...
I'm sorry, this is becoming a speech.
You're the captain, sir.
- You're entitled.
- Hmm.
I'm not entitled to ramble on about
something everyone knows. Carry on.
Ship's log,
Commander William Riker reporting.
Continuing our appraisal
of Ligonian technology,
the captain has made it clear
he wants Lieutenant Yar
beamed immediately to safety
if her life should become endangered,
and I fervently hope the rules
of that contest make it possible.
Riker to transporter chief.
Do we have our people
on sensors yet?
Their general area, sir.
Visual on-screen now.
As you see,
we're still doing some fine tuning.
I've agreed to this meeting,
but I see no point to it.
You've accepted the challenge
and there's nothing further to say.
I think you should know that there
is no physical training anywhere
that matches Starfleet,
especially its security people.
And you should know that even
though these contests are rare,
we have a tradition of making
ourselves capable of them.
Yareena, my acceptance
had nothing to do with Lutan.
It has everything to do with Lutan!
Lutan wants you to be his First One.
Impossible, Yareena.
I am a career Starfleet officer.
How could you not love him?
Every woman loves him.
I fight for the vaccine.
That's the truth.
The truth is I will kill you if I can.
And believe me, I can.
There's nothing else to say.
In my world,
it's a greater honor to refuse.
You are on our world!
Captain, I'm your counselor.
You brought me with you to Ligon
to be of help.
Then help me, please.
What is a way out of this?
- With the vaccine?
- Mm-hm.
None.
The weapons in that room, captain,
are surprisingly flexible,
durable and deadly.
And light, as if they were made
for women to use.
Hmm, some of them
still have traces of blood and poison.
- Poison?
- Hmm.
Alkaloid base. Lethal.
What about those lengths of metal
in the yard outside?
Uncertain, sir.
However, joined together they would
make a rectangle or square
enclosing 121 square meters.
If put end-to-end vertically, they would
make a pole 44 meters high.
- Or two of 22.
- Thank you, Data.
You're welcome, sir.
She won't budge. She loves him.
Without reservation.
- And she thinks I love him too.
- Most interesting.
- Do you?
- Of course I don't, Data.
As Troi pointed out to me, I'm attracted
to him, but that's entirely different.
Riker to captain.
Go ahead, Riker. We're alone.
We're fine tuned enough
to see your hosts gathering
in the open area outside, sir.
Three of them are heading
for your location.
Thank you, Number One.
Lieutenant, do you still feel
that you want to go through
with this challenge?
- Do you judge your condition good?
- I judge it excellent, sir.
Your weapons, Lieutenant Yar.
You may choose your size.
Tasha, don't touch
the spines. They're poisoned.
If you're not careful,
you could kill yourself.
These I understand.
First Officer's log, supplemental.
Captain Picard,
faced with a critical need
for a vaccine produced
on this planet,
has permitted Lieutenant Natasha Yar
to engage in a fight to the death.
I have yet to understand
his reasoning or his plan.
Care to lend a hand? Sit at Ops.
Was I seen leaving?
They've got eyes only for the program.
Captain Picard wanted no risk of our
communication being overheard.
You are to proceed now
as he indicated.
Captain's orders too.
Did the Captain understand
what you and Geordi reported
about these weapons?
They're razor-sharp,
split-second lethal...
I'm here to brief you
on what he plans.
- Any last minute instructions, sir?
- Stay alive.
We'll hope to do the rest.
I speak for Lutan.
The rules are known.
Let combat continue
until there is a victor.
It will not be interrupted.
Combatants, hold your positions.
Return the weapon.
Careful, Yareena!
Move.
We're too late. She's growing cold.
Sorry, that clashes
with my instructions.
Oh, no, no, no.
Exactly what do you find unfair,
Lutan?
They fought to the death,
you saw the final blow.
- You know the effects of your poison.
- But what of your Lieutenant Yar?
- She is to become my First One now.
- I certainly won't stop her
if she cares to claim that honor.
Remember, you have all Yareena's
wealth and lands, Lutan.
At least all has not been lost.
Riker to captain.
Picard here.
Since you've
fulfilled your agreement, captain,
can we now beam
the vaccine aboard?
- Ah, yes, of course.
- No problem, Number One.
Send down a medical team.
And to complete our business here,
we are locked on to you.
Five to beam up. Energize.
Welcome back, captain.
You're wanted in the lounge.
This way, gentlemen.
She is not dead!
There was no death combat.
You violated our agreement.
There will be no treaty. No vaccine.
The challenge was carried out.
She died, Lutan.
There was no challenge. She lives!
I am a physician and saw her die.
If you doubt this poison,
why don't you test it on yourself?
Lutan, we can provide you
with records of her death
and how Dr. Crusher
brought her back.
And at the instant of death,
Lutan, a mating agreement dissolves.
But this is witchcraft, Yareena.
To discard a mate in this manner--
Is less painful than the one
you selected for me.
Yareena, no.
Even as I battled, Hagon,
I heard you calling out for me.
Yareena, be my First One.
All my land and all my goods,
all I have is yours to rule.
How sad for you.
You've lost everything.
- I have my honor.
- It's such a waste.
Do you want him?
No.
There would be complications.
Then I will have you
as my Number Two.
Take your place, accordingly.
Well, as you see, captain,
you may excel in technology,
but not in civilized behavior.
What?
Wesley.
Yeah, Wesley, he's been
manning that station for me. I forgot.
Well, thanks again for manning one
of our Bridge stations, Wesley.
We'll see, uh, that you have
another chance.
Yes, sir.
So, what's the delay, Number One?
Why aren't we warping out of here?
Set course for Styris IV, warp 3.
- Course laid in for Styris IV, sir.
- Engage.