Captain's log, stardate 41263. 1.
We have rendezvoused
with the USS Fearless
from which a Starfleet
propulsion expert and his assistant
are beaming over to conduct tests
on the Enterprise's
warp drive engines.
They have completed
similar adjustments
on two other Starfleet vessels.
I don't understand your concern,
Number One.
They're not authorized
to make any alterations in our engines.
According to Starfleet's report,
they will simply run tests
on different ways
of entering warp speed
and different intermix formulas.
- Where's the harm in that?
- It's the specs Kosinski sent us.
- In my opinion, sir, they're gibberish.
- Gibberish?
Mr. Data, would you explain?
Sir, we put Mr. Kosinski's specs
into the computer
and ran a controlled test on them.
There was no improvement
in engine performance.
Then how do you explain
Starfleet's report
that the same tests on the USS Ajax,
and on the Fearless over there,
resulted in a measurable
increase in propulsion?
Our engines are new, sir.
Top condition.
The tests on those older ships
may have simply been to straighten out
some inefficiency.
Bridge from transporter chief.
Two from USS Fearless
are ready to beam over.
Stand by for Mr. Riker, chief.
He's on his way.
Aye, sir.
Since you're concerned
about these tests.
Yes, sir.
Captain, if I may,
I'll ask Counselor Troi
to look these visitors over.
Very good.
Welcome aboard, Mr. Kosinski.
I'm the first officer,
Commander William Riker.
- And this is--
- Where is the captain, please?
He's engaged in other duties, sir.
A ship's engines should be
the concern of a ship's captain.
They are, sir.
Which is why they have made
their first officer directly responsible
for an engine's conditions
and performance.
Guided, of course,
by one of our chief engineers.
Lieutenant Commander Argyle,
in this case.
A pleasure to meet you, sir.
I appreciated receiving the specs.
To which you have
no end of questions.
Aye, I have.
- And you, sir, are listed as--
- As Mr. Kosinski's assistant.
Uh, my actual name
is unpronounceable by humans.
You're from Tau Alpha C.
That's very distant.
All approved and described
in the Starfleet communications.
Now, I would like to set up
in the engine room immediately.
I'll have our chief engineer
show you to his engine room.
No need.
I know my way around starships.
One thing that Kosinski isn't hiding?
His bad disposition.
Agreed.
Also, he's arrogant, overbearing,
self-important
and very sure of himself
and his ability.
- And the other one, his assistant?
- He's the puzzle.
With most life forms,
I can usually feel something.
I may not be able to understand
or interpret it
but I feel something,
if only a presence.
With him, nothing. Empty space.
It's as though he isn't even here.
Something about this concerns me.
I don't know what.
I can point to no reason, yet.
But stay concerned, please.
The safety of the Enterprise
may be entrusted to these two.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission:
to explore strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go where no one
has gone before.
Inform the Bridge I shall begin
my first test in precisely 15 minutes.
- Why is this child here?
- He's working on a school project.
Before you begin,
there are some questions.
First, tell us how you arrived--
In order to save myself time,
let me ask those questions for you.
You received the information
which Starfleet provided,
you fed it into your computer
as precisely as humanly possible,
then you did a controlled test.
And then, to your astonishment,
nothing happened.
So you said, "What's going on?
This doesn't work. Kosinski is a fraud."
You see, I have had this conversation
on other Starfleet vessels before.
They didn't understand it,
why should you?
Hmm. Surely you're not saying
it's unexplainable.
I'm saying I'm not a teacher.
Nor do I wish to become one.
I have neither the inclination,
nor the time.
You have all the time you need.
I don't think you understand.
This has already been approved
by Starfleet Command.
But it hasn't been approved
by the chief engineer or by me.
- I didn't know that was necessary.
- Now you do.
Perhaps I should speak
to Captain Picard.
If you like. It won't change anything.
- How basic shall I be?
- I'll leave that to you.
Would you get on
the auxiliary panel, please?
In order to save time, my assistant
is going to lay in my base formulas
more rapidly than any human being
possibly could, even myself.
So here then, in the simplest
possible terms, is what I do.
Now, this warp drive system
has been tuned
only in the grossest possible sense,
at least, according to my standards.
What I do is specific. Thank you.
Now, how to say...
Well, sufficient to say for now that
these symbols and their relation...
Something troubles you in the way
this is configured?
However,
those of you who are sufficient in...
How about it now?
Yes.
But shouldn't these be connected?
Here?
And here.
Now will it do
what Kosinski says it will?
It has a chance.
It might work better this way.
Yes.
View with me this screen
as we consider the following.
Now, is this merely mechanics
or is it nature
that we deal with in all of this?
And what else than nature
are the elementals of space and time?
You are trained in the system,
you are-- You go in a straight line.
Confident, yes,
perhaps even innovative
in a minimalist sort of way,
but what I do here
is not the end of the process.
It is the beginning.
So, what do I do?
Go back to the Fearless,
which I left with a more efficient
warp drive system than I found?
Or do you cast off your ignorance
and allow me to continue?
Can anything he's proposing
damage our system?
- How could it'? It's meaningless.
- Then we should let him try it.
What do you mean, let him try it?
Don't talk about me in the third person
as if I'm not standing right here.
Yes, we might as well let him try it.
"We might as well let him try it."
You are too generous.
Boy. Boy. Don't play with that.
Captain, Main Engineering
is ready to proceed.
Engineering, this is the Bridge.
It's your call.
Do this one just like the last time.
Nothing changes.
Commander, I'll make my
preliminary adjustments at warp 1.5
and complete them
as we achieve warp 4.
Engineering to Bridge,
did you copy that?
Affirmative, Number One.
- You ready?
- We are.
La Forge, set in warp 1.5.
Warp 1.5, sir.
Engage.
All right, here we go.
What are you doing?
Captain, we're passing warp 10.
- What is our velocity?
- It's off the scale, sir.
Reverse engines.
Captain, no one has ever
reversed engines at this velocity.
Because no one has gone this fast.
Reverse engines.
- All stop.
- Reading all stop, sir.
- Position?
- Calculating it, sir.
Data, what do you read over there?
- A malfunction, I trust.
- Position, Mr. La Forge?
Well, sir,
according to these calculations
we've not only left our own galaxy
but passed through two others,
ending up on
the far side of Triangulum.
- The galaxy known as M33.
- That's not possible.
Data, what distance
have we traveled?
Two million, 700,000 light years, sir.
- I can't accept that.
- You must, sir.
Our comparisons
show it to be completely accurate.
And I calculate
that at maximum warp, sir,
it would take over
300 years to get home.
Captain's log, stardate 41263.2.
This will be a rather unusual log entry,
assuming Starfleet ever receives it.
As I've already informed my crew,
a phenomenal surge of power
during a warp speed experiment
has sent our starship
hurtling out of our own galaxy
and past another,
taking us over 2, 700, 000 light years
in a few minutes.
The message on this has already been
transmitted to Starfleet, sir.
Which traveling subspace,
they should receive in 51 years,
10 months, 9 weeks, 16 days--
- Mr. Data.
- Sir?
Captain Picard, I presume.
We're still trying to determine
what happened.
The truth is, captain,
I made a mistake.
- A wonderful, incredible mistake.
- Just explain what brought us here.
As the power grew,
I applied the energy asymptomatically.
I anticipated some tiling
but it didn't occur.
Now, that was my error,
using the Bessel functions
at the beginning.
What is he saying, Number One?
To tell the truth, sir,
it sounds like nonsense to me.
- But considering-
- Considering
where we are,
you must assume it isn't.
Can I do something to help?
- I can call my mother. She's a doctor.
- No, there's nothing she can do.
I need to rest.
I've been away too long.
What happened to you?
Is it part of what happened to the ship?
Please believe me, I mean no harm
to this vessel or those in it.
Is Mr. Kosinski like he sounds?
- A joke?
- Heh, no, that's too cruel.
He has sensed
some small part of this.
That space and time and thought
aren't the separate things
they appear to be?
I thought the formula you were using
said something like that.
Boy, don't ever say that again.
Especially not at your age,
in a world that's not ready for such...
Such dangerous nonsense.
I've always suspected
that this rate of speed was possible,
of course, but at this level, ha, ha,
HO, never.
We're going to need new definitions,
new parameters.
Perhaps you could call it
the Kosinski Scale.
Why not? Yes, of course.
Since I'm the one who has
made the so-called warp barrier
meaningless.
And, captain,
this must be a special thrill for you.
- Thrill?
- Mm-hm. As an explorer.
In three centuries of space travel,
we've charted just 11 per cent
of our galaxy.
And then we accomplished this.
Yes, but isn't the real point,
can you do it again?
Can you get us home?
Well, of course, I can.
I'll just do what I did before.
Coming, Riker?
Commander Riker
will join you in a moment.
Comment is invited. Counselor?
He's convinced he's right.
I've no doubt of that.
Captain, can you allow a man
who has made one mistake
back into a position
where he may make another?
Captain, what are our options really?
I mean, if this guy can't get us back,
who will?
Captain, we're here.
Why not avail ourselves
of this opportunity for study?
There is a giant protostar
here in the process of forming.
No other vessel
has been out this far.
Spoken like a true
Starfleet graduate.
- It is tempting, eh, Number One?
- Aye, sir, it is.
But as they say, sir,
you're the captain.
I know that if Kosinski
can get us home,
Starfleet can use his technique
to bring back a pure science vessel,
do even more.
Number One, tell Kosinski
to prepare to get us out of here.
Aye, sir.
Do you realize how many
great advancements of mankind
have been tied to speed?
This is a moment in history.
Right here, right now.
And your names
will be forever linked with mine.
Excuse me, Commander Riker.
I don't think he did this.
- I think that it was--
- Not now, Wes.
Standing by, Number One.
Sir, when all this happened,
I was watching his assistant--
I'm sure this is fascinating, Wesley,
and I am looking forward to hearing
all about it, but not right now.
Aye, sir?
- Come on.
- He's too tired.
- Why don't you do it by yourself?
- Yes.
- Why not?
- No.
- I will help.
- As you wish.
I've laid in
the reciprocal course back, captain.
Tell the captain I am ready,
first officer.
We're ready for you
to engage, captain.
- As before, begin at warp 1.5.
- Warp 1.5, sir.
This isn't working.
All stop.
Answering all stop, captain.
According to the instruments, sir,
our speed never exceeded
warp 1.5.
All stopped, sir.
Yes.
But where is this place?
Where none have gone before.
Captain's log, stardate 41263.3.
Instead of returning
to our own galaxy,
the Enterprise has gone forward
to a place in the universe
which is uncharted and unknown.
Our present position puts us at over
a billion light years from our galaxy.
Data, you have the helm.
I'll be in Engineering.
- What is it?
- A Klingon targ.
My Pet.
From home.
But when I was a child.
You're telling me it's a kitty cat?
Yes.
I suppose you could call it that.
You, darling.
What are you doing here?
Now run. This place isn't safe at all.
Tasha, what's wrong?
You look scared to death.
I was...
This is crazy.
I was at the colony where I grew up.
- Being chased by a rape gang.
- Are you all right?
- Mm-hm.
- Well, you're safe now.
Captain, captain.
We need your help.
- What's wrong?
- Don't you see what's following us?
Ensign, what are you doing?
You look tense, Jean-Luc.
Come and have a cup of tea.
- Mama.
- I'll make it good and strong.
The way you like it.
Mama?
We'll have a nice long talk.
This can't be.
- You've been--
- Dead?
But I'm always with you.
You know that.
Yes.
I felt that.
- But why now? Suddenly?
- You mean out here?
At what you say
is the end of the universe?
Or do you see
this as the beginning of it?
We believe it the outer rim.
Mama, do you understand
these things?
Can you tell me where my ship is?
What is this place?
Captain?
- You were reported headed for--
- Just a moment, Number One.
Can I help you, sir?
No.
No, let's help all of us.
General quarters, red alert.
What is it, captain?
Why are we at general quarters?
I had to get everyone's attention.
This seemed to be the quickest way.
This is the captain.
This is not a drill.
It seems that in this place,
the world of the physical universe
and the world of ideas
is somehow intermixed.
What we think
also becomes a reality.
We must, therefore,
I repeat, must
begin controlling our thoughts
We will give you more on this
as our understanding increases.
The Enterprise will stay at full alert
until the crisis is over.
- What did you do?
- It wasn't him, it never was.
- It was his assistant.
- What are you talking about?
Kosinski wasn't the one controlling
the warp experiment.
It was me.
The equations he punched in
were nonsense.
- Just as we thought.
- I honestly thought it was me.
I thought somehow...
Somehow, I was operating
on his level.
It was also my fault, captain.
I should have realized
it wasn't Kosinski.
How could you?
How could any of us?
Wesley did.
If you knew something,
why didn't you say so?
He tried, twice. I didn't listen.
- He's unconscious. Why?
- I'm not certain yet.
He phased, sir.
What does that mean?
Parts of him disappeared
and then came back.
Nobody else was paying attention
to him the first time.
When we saw it this time,
he seemed to be struggling.
Fighting it.
- He's dying.
- He mustn't.
He's the only one
who can get us back.
Realistically,
that doesn't seem possible.
Captain's log, supplemental.
Our position is unknown
and our only chance of returning
to the known universe is a dying alien
who is generally humanoid
but with a physiology sufficiently
different from our own
to create medical problems
in caring for him.
- Cause?
- I don't know.
My equipment doesn't register
his kind of life signs.
I would have to guess
exhaustion, fatigue.
- Is he gonna be all right?
- What is the boy doing here?
Mom, he's my friend.
You may want him here
before we're done.
He seems to have developed some
sort of special attachment to the boy.
My name is Wesley,
Commander Riker.
He knows.
We all know.
- Will he live?
- I'm not sure.
Wake him.
I recommend we let him come around
in his own time.
I don't have that luxury.
Wake him.
He could die
and with him any chance we have.
Doctor, Wes,
we all have other friends
on board this ship.
If we stay here much longer,
we may lose the ability to distinguish
between thought and reality.
Now, regardless of the risk,
wake him, now.
Do you recognize me?
I'm the captain and I need answers.
I'll do my best to provide.
Who are you? Or what?
I am a traveler.
Traveler?
- What is your destination?
- Destination?
Yes.
- What place are you trying to reach?
- Ah, place, no.
There is no specific place
I wish to go.
Then what is the purpose
of your journey?
Curiosity.
- That's not an answer.
- I have certain abilities.
They give me a knowledge
of propulsion.
I've been trading this for passage
on Starfleet vessels.
And allowing Kosinski
to take credit for what you did?
It seemed the sensible way.
Until now.
Captain, I seek only transportation
in order to see and experience
your reality.
I am no threat to you,
your ship or your crew.
He isn't, captain. I know he isn't.
Our reality?
And in order to satisfy this curiosity,
you have brought my ship
and my crew into grave risk.
- I have made some mistakes.
- Some mistakes?
What mistakes could possibly explain
these incredible explosions of velocity?
I don't know if I can put this in terms
you'll understand.
I believe that there may be
a warp speed
that can get us
beyond Galaxy M33.
But there is no velocity
of any magnitude that can possibly
bring us wherever this is.
Is it true what our navigational senses
are telling us. Are we...?
Are we millions of light years
away from where we were?
- Yes.
- But what got us here?
- Thought.
- Thought?
You do understand, don't you,
that thought is the basis
of all reality?
The energy of thought,
to put it in your terms,
is very powerful.
That's not an explanation.
I have the ability to act like a lens
which focuses thought.
That's just, uh, so much nonsense.
You're asking us to believe in magic.
Oh, yes, this could seem like
magic to you.
No.
No. That actually
makes sense to me.
Only the power of thought could
explain what has been happening,
especially out here.
Thought is the essence
of where you are now.
You do understand the danger,
don't you?
Chaos.
What we think is what happens.
It pains me I was so careless,
captain.
My intent was only to observe,
not to cause this.
You should not be here
until your far, far distant future.
Certainly not
until you've learned control.
You are from a different time,
aren't you?
Oh, well, no, not exactly
from another time.
Although,
as you understand the concept,
yes, perhaps
that term fits as well as any.
- And you have this ability, to travel?
- Yes.
And others of your kind
have the same ability?
- Oh, yes.
- Then why,
in all of our history,
is there no record of you
or someone like you
ever having visited us?
What wonderful arrogance.
There is no record because we have
not visited you before.
Why not?
Well, because up until now,
if you'll forgive this,
you've been uninteresting.
It's only now that your life-form merits
serious attention.
I'm sorry.
What's happening?
- He's unconscious again.
- Revive him.
Whatever you need from him,
you better get it soon.
If I may suggest, sir,
our first leap out of our galaxy was,
as he said, a mistake.
Unless
he was distracted by something.
And it weakened him in some way,
resulting in the incredible
leap out here.
Theory.
Do you have any facts that fit this?
- Can you get us back?
- Wait, captain, not so fast.
We have an opportunity here
for scientific discovery.
And we report our observations how?
To whom?
- Can you get us back?
- I will try.
Number One, take him down
to Main Engineering.
- I'll be on the Bridge.
- No.
He's very weak.
The captain is right. We must hurry.
But first, I request a moment
with the captain, alone.
Strange how he seems
to care for you.
He will forget me in time.
Which is as it should be.
It's Wesley
I wanted to speak to you about.
The boy?
It's best you do not repeat
this to the others,
especially not to the mother.
Whatever happens, it is imperative
that it proceed naturally.
I must get my ship back.
Do we have time for this?
Oh, yes.
He and a few like him
are why I travel.
You have it in your power
to encourage him without interfering.
Encourage him in what?
How shall I explain?
Are you familiar with the intricacies
of what is called here music?
Somewhat.
And such musical genius as I saw
in one of your ship's libraries.
One called Mozart,
who as a small child
wrote astonishing symphonies.
A genius who made music
not only to be heard, but seen and felt,
beyond the understanding,
the ability of others.
Wesley is such a person.
Not with music,
but with the equally lovely intricacies
of time, energy, propulsion
and the instruments of this vessel,
which allow all that to be play--
You're right, I must hurry now.
But you're right in something else,
he is just a boy for now.
He should be encouraged,
but told none of this.
We've gotta get back home.
Take him to Main Engineering.
- Yes, sir.
- I'll be on the Bridge.
Yes, sir.
- Put it out!
- How?
Think!
Put the flame out in your thoughts!
Now, get to your station,
and concentrate on your assignment.
Yes, sir.
Captain's log.
Any time entry is meaningless.
We have no choice but to repeat
the same warp experiment,
but with one variation."
A principal part of this warp formula
will be the thoughts
of everyone aboard the Enterprise.
We have no idea exactly
how this works.
We understand only that the Traveler
makes use of this somehow.
And it will be most important
that those aboard
avoid random thoughts
that might change the reality
of what we 're attempting to do.
Do you have any further advice,
counselor?
When you begin the attempt,
there will be stress.
And it's only natural
the crew's concentration will shift.
Plus some genuine fear, captain.
You can't notice
what's happening outside
without feeling some of that.
All decks, all stations.
This is the captain speaking.
All decks,
I must have your full attention.
In a few moments,
as we attempt to warp back home,
it is vital, absolutely vital,
that you center your thoughts
on your duty
or on the welfare of the one called
the Traveler.
Think of giving him
some of your strength.
Now, this is an order.
You must try to do this
And now, attempt to concentrate
completely on your duty of the moment
or on the Traveler,
on his well-being.
Think of
him as someone you care deeply for.
All decks, all stations.
Battle stations.
I will need Kosinski
back on the main computer.
You need me?
Yes.
Helm set in warp 1.5,
retroactive course.
Warp 1.5,
retroactive 261 mark 31, sir.
Bridge to Engineering, stand by.
I feel such an abundance
of well-being on the ship.
It feels like...
Quite wonderful.
Engineering to Bridge, we're ready.
On my order,
Mr. Data, Mr. La Forge,
engage.
It's not happening. It's not enough.
Warp 1.5, sir,
which is what my instruments
have read all along.
And our position reads
exactly what it was
before this sleigh ride began, sir.
Cease red alert.
Sleigh ride?
Or whatever you wanna call it, Data.
I don't have a proper name for it.
- The Traveler is gone, sir.
- Gone?
He's phased,
completely out of existence.
At least out of our existence.
Attention, all decks.
This is to inform you
that with your support,
the Traveler has returned us
to our own galaxy.
However, he has now left us,
wherever he has gone,
we wish him well.
Have the boy sent to the Bridge,
Number One.
Wesley Crusher, report to the Bridge.
On the double.
Our next assignment
is on this heading?
Yes, sir.
Mr. Data, Mr. La Forge,
increase to warp 5, same heading.
- Warp 5, sir.
- On that same heading, sir.
Oh, Wesley, come on the Bridge.
Move.
Commander Riker has told me
how supportive you were
in Engineering. Well done.
Oh, at ease.
- Uh, sit here, in command.
- Captain, it's not allowed.
Your orders.
Oh, that's true.
Well, uh,
I, uh, can't waive them again.
Only commissioned officers?
It's quite all right, sir. I understand.
- Please don't interrupt me, Wesley.
- I'm sorry, sir.
Any commission rank?
Even ensign?
That would give him
authorized access to the Bridge.
Well, then, I'll have
to make him an acting ensign.
Captain's log, stardate 41263.4.
For outstanding performance
in the best Starfleet tradition,
Wesley Crusher
is made acting ensign,
with the duties
and privileges of that rank.
And whether that rank
becomes permanent, Mr. Crusher,
depends on you.
At the earliest opportunity,
your entrance application
for Starfleet Academy
will be tendered.
Until then, you will learn this ship.
Every operation, every function.
Commander Riker,
a duty schedule for Mr. Crusher.
- Heavy on study.
- Aye, sir.
Meanwhile, you can sit here
and learn something.
Sir, shall I send for Dr. Crusher?
Why? Is someone ill?
Or would you rather
tell her about this, Wes?
If you don't mind, sir,
I'd like to sit here for a while.
I'll tell her later.