Captain's log, stardate 41386.4.
We are in pursuit of a starship
of Ferengi design.
Our mission is to intercept
and recover a T-9 energy converter
which the Ferengi stole
from an unmanned monitor post
on Gamma Tauri IV.
A theft which automatic
scanners recorded,
providing us
with the long-awaited opportunity
to make close contact
with a Ferengi vessel.
If we succeed in this chase, it will be
Starfleet's first look at a life form
which, discounting rumor,
we know almost nothing about.
There she is.
Enlarge.
What is their course?
They are now angling
through that solar system, captain.
- Identify.
- Listed as Delphi Ardu, sir.
Eleven planets, unexplored.
- Stay with them, La Forge.
- Aye, sir.
Sensors read a power surge
from their last maneuver, captain.
They are dropping to sub-warp speed.
Reduce to impulse power.
Sensors record fluctuations
in the energy readings from it, captain.
Possibility:
- A malfunction in their engines, sir.
- Breaks my heart.
In visual range, captain.
Fully enlarge.
Hello, stranger.
Very impressive design.
Anything on that design, Data?
Nothing specific, sir.
As you know,
Ferengi technology is estimated
to be generally equal to our own.
But that does not mean
identical, however.
Correct, sir.
We are no doubt advanced
in some areas, they in others.
Showing another power surge, sir.
They are firing on us.
- Damage report.
- Shields holding.
Mostly electromagnetic.
Fusion generator
and batteries down by 30 percent.
Our impulse engines
are surging now.
They're firing again.
Deflector shield power
weakening, captain.
Phasers ready.
Photon torpedoes ready.
- Do we return their fire, sir?
- Negative, Number One.
They're just responding
to our close pursuit.
Fall back a bit, but stay with them.
They are slowing too, sir.
They may be turning to fight.
Open hailing frequen-- Why are we
gaining on them? Don't anticipate.
I'm not, sir. Something's wrong.
Sir, something is dragging us forward.
I read that too.
Lieutenant Yar,
what do your sensors show?
Not certain, sir.
I'm getting very confusing readings.
Captain, this shouldn't be.
Our power systems are failing.
Deflector shield failing.
Phasers going inoperative, captain.
Captain, something
is completely immobilizing us.
Immobilized by the damn Ferengi?
I need more information.
What the hell are they using?
Obviously we've underestimated
their technology, captain.
Considerably.
It appears the Ferengi have us
right where they want us:
In their sights.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission:
to explore strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go where no one
has gone before.
Are you searching all
frequencies? Is there any message?
Negative, sir.
Weapons report, lieutenant.
I have phasers
and torpedoes armed.
But I show insufficient power
to fire them.
Engineering, give me status
on power recovery.
Engineering, come in.
Why aren't they answering?
- La Forge.
- Sir?
- Get me a full report from Engineering.
- Aye, sir.
It's impossible they could be
draining all power from all systems.
Counselor?
I'm sensing nothing from them, sir.
Which could mean they can shield their
thoughts and emotions from others.
Which still makes it our move.
Sir, they may know as little about us
as we do about them.
Except that they know
that they've got us in deep trouble.
If so, then the question becomes
what do they do with that knowledge?
Data, do you have any information
touching this on any file?
None, sir. Only hearsay and third-hand
reports, most of which conflict.
Which reports do not conflict?
That the Ferengi are--
Well, the best description
may be traders.
What kind of traders?
A comparison modern scholars
have drawn from Earth history
likens the Ferengi
to the ocean-going Yankee traders
of 18- and 19-century America, sir.
From the history of my forebears.
Yankee traders.
Who, in this case, sail the galaxy
in search of mercantile
and territorial opportunity.
And are these scholars saying
that the Ferengi may not be unlike us?
Hardly, sir. I believe the analogy refers
to the worst quality of capitalists.
The Ferengi are believed
to conduct their affairs of commerce
on the ancient principle
caveat emptor.
"Let the buyer beware."
Yankee traders.
I like the sound of that.
Well, sir,
I doubt they wear red, white and blue
or look anything like Uncle Sam.
Engineering?
Join La Forge down below
in Engineering, Number One.
Aye, sir.
Without warp capacity,
we're just a floating target.
Uncle who?
What have bright primary colors
got to do with it?
Oh, I understand the allusion.
Colors representing countries at a time
when they competed with each other.
Red, white and blue
for the United States.
Whereas the French more properly
used the same colors
in the order blue, white and red.
And the German nation,
red, black and gold.
The Italians, green, white and red
British--
- That's enough, Data.
- It was you who--
We were discussing the Ferengi.
I wish I had some clue
as to what they will do next.
Given what is now happening
to our ship, sir,
their weapons could be vastly
superior to ours.
Yes, Data,
that is a natural assumption.
Engineering?
- Bottom line, La Forge.
- Ah, it's not good, sir.
Ferengi force field that holds this ship
compensates almost as fast
- as we can increase power.
- Almost?
Well, there's a 0.372 millisecond delay
between the use of our power
and the neutralizing counterforce
of the Ferengis.
See, we push, and they push back
with equal force, sir.
What's our acceleration delay
between slow-reverse impulse
and top warp speed?
Well, that's 0.300 milliseconds.
There's...
Ah, I see where you're going.
We shift down,
then kick hard into warp 9.
Yeah, come back fighting.
Whoo-ee!
- Can we do it, Geordi?
- Ask me after it's done, sir.
I want a slow reverse into drop-off
over five minutes.
We'll show them
what this baby can do, sir.
Give it everything you've got.
Aye, aye, sir.
In a sudden, abrupt power
surge to high warp speed, captain,
we may be able to break loose
from that Ferengi force field.
I wish I knew
what they were thinking over there.
They're wondering
what we're going to do next.
I say fight, sir.
There's nothing shameful
in falling before a superior enemy.
And nothing shameful
in a strategic retreat, either.
All systems ready, captain.
And communication now restored
to Engineering.
Excellent, La Forge.
Now let's, uh, throw them off guard.
Lieutenant Yar,
open hailing frequencies.
Hailing frequencies open, sir.
At least we won't begin
with weakness.
Attention, Ferengi starship.
This is Captain Jean-Luc Picard
of the USS Enterprise.
In the name
of the United Federation of Planets,
I demand that you return
the T-9 energy converter
you removed from Gamma Tauri IV.
Send that in all language forms.
All language forms, sir.
Sometimes, Riker,
the best way to fight is not to be there.
Yes, sir. "He will triumph
who knows when to fight
- and when not to fight."
Hmm.
Glad the Academy is still teaching
the strategies of Sun Tzu.
This delay had better prove out,
La Forge.
Point-300 milliseconds, sir.
Let's blast full power into warp 9.
Ready?
On your command, captain.
On the count of three.
Stand by on phasers.
One. Set warp to nine.
Two.
Divert shield power to main engines.
Three.
Merde.
Shields up.
Captain,
I think you had better see this.
What's wrong?
Someone is reading every file,
every bit of information stored
in the Enterprise memory banks.
They can do that?
And more, perhaps.
Captain, if I may recommend,
with our attention on the Ferengi vessel,
we have ignored the planet.
Data, consult the charts on this planet.
See what we've got on it.
Conference evaluation.
So while we still have some power left,
it's time for difficult decisions.
- Opinions, please.
- I say put all available power
into a full-out combined phaser
and photon torpedo salvo.
Destroy their ability
to sustain this force field, sir.
Yes, hit them hard and hit them fast.
Impractical.
And provocative.
Even assuming that we have
the power to sustain such a tactic.
But, captain,
isn't firing on us an act of war?
The facts are the Ferengis did
fire on us, but we were chasing them.
Since then, all they've done
is search our computers,
trying to learn who and what we are.
- Your point, counselor?
- Let's talk to them.
It's been tried. No response.
But did we tell them anything
they wanted to hear?
La Forge?
Other opinions?
Thank you for your advice.
Will?
I haven't heard your assessment.
I believe we've covered
every available option, captain.
Are there other options
that you wanna analyze?
The only one remaining is the one
that needs no conversation.
- The one we must avoid.
- Sir?
The one that leads
to total annihilation.
- Open hailing frequencies.
- Open, sir.
Attention, Ferengi starship.
This is Captain Picard.
It is obvious that we are in a situation
here which needs resolving.
And we are willing to do
whatever is required,
whatever is necessary.
I would like--
I would request
that you present your terms to us.
Captain's log, stardate 41386. 5.
It is with a heavy heart
that I have offered
to meet whatever reasonable
and necessary terms
are demanded by the Ferengi.
I fear for my people and my vessel
in the event the unknown Ferengi
ask the unreasonable.
How can I oppose
even unreasonable demands?
It's moving, sir.
We ask to surrender
and now they fire on us?
Ready torpedoes, sir? We have
enough power for a few of them.
Ready, but hold on ready.
Open hailing frequencies.
Hailing frequencies open, sir.
Ferengi vessel,
we await your response.
Suggest first strike, sir.
Our shields now only have 63 seconds
of power left before lowering.
If the Ferengi ship's sensors
can read us, sir,
they will be waiting
until we are most vulnerable.
I'm afraid I agree.
They have not responded.
We will wait a bit more,
Number One.
Fifty seconds.
Patience. Patience.
The quicker we can come to terms,
the better, NCC-1701-D.
Who is speaking?
I am Tarr, daimon of the Ferengi.
You wish to discuss surrender,
Captain Picard?
What I said, Daimon Tarr, is--
Unconditional surrender,
I warn you, is totally unacceptable.
We will die to the last one of us
before such dishonor.
Hailing frequencies closed, sir.
Something has seized their ship too.
They're in the same predicament as us.
Launch a sensor probe.
Set it to search for the source
of whatever this something is
that is holding both ships.
Go back to hailing frequency, fast.
And I regret, Daimon Tarr,
that I can no longer negotiate
unless it is conducted visually.
Your complete message
not received, Enterprise.
But visual communication
is against our custom.
And it is against Starfleet orders
to accept a surrender otherwise.
Do you withdraw your surrender?
You give us no choice, Enterprise.
May we have a visual on you
as well?
Agreed, Daimon Tarr.
You should be able to view us now.
Are we on your screen?
Yes.
The ugliness of the human
was not an exaggeration.
I do not know how your twisted alien
culture has paralyzed our vessel,
but I concede your Enterprise
is superior.
We will return
your worthless T-9 device
and we offer the lives
of our second officers
as required by the Ferengi code.
Fortunately Starfleet has no such rules
involving its second officers.
Is this to your satisfaction,
Picard Captain?
Your offer may be inadequate,
but I will discuss it with my staff.
Stand by for further communication.
Matthew, Pola.
You know this area is off limits.
Come on, come on, come on.
Boys will be boys, captain.
Have you launched the probe?
Aye, sir. We should be getting
those readings soon.
Well, if we're not holding the Ferengi
and they're not holding us,
who the hell is?
Well, the probe will give us
some of those answers, sir.
Data, you were going
to show us something?
As requested, captain,
library-computer information
on this planet.
It has been charted only
from long-range scans.
It is class M, but shows no indication
of life forms, sentient or otherwise.
However,
you may find this of interest.
Resolving it into our language.
The center of a huge space federation.
A population of trillions.
Trillions?
I've never heard the word
"Tkon" before.
Understandable.
It has been extinct for 600,000 of our--
Of our years.
These planets were once outposts
of that empire.
Data, what are you doing?
Apologies, captain.
I seem to have reached
an odd functional impasse.
I am, uh, stuck.
Then get unstuck
and continue with the briefing.
Yes, sir.
That is what I am trying to do, sir.
But the solution eludes me.
My hero, ha-ha-ha.
Continue, commander.
Intriguing. It de-Uh--
It describes the Empire as being
highly advanced and powerful,
and capable of actually moving stars.
Stars whose planets
are their defense system?
Correct, sir. Outposts.
The planet below
was possibly one of them.
Excuse
the interruption, but this may be worth it.
We're now receiving a signal
from the probe.
We'll take it here.
Incredible.
- Our mysterious something, captain.
- Hmm.
- It is a force field of some kind.
- Reaching up from the planet surface.
Amazing power.
Data, what does the legend say
about the end of the Tkon Empire?
Their sun went supernova, sir.
Could this planet have escaped that?
This planet may have been
the most distant outpost, sir.
But it shows no life-form readings.
We should take a look at it.
Stand by with an away team.
And if the Ferengi also realize
the force field emanates
from the planet, sir?
Hmm, that's a complication.
Maybe we should ask them
to join us in this.
Team up with the Ferengi, sir'?
We've been ordered
to learn all we can about them.
Do you know a better way?
Data.
Captain's log, supplemental.
In orbit of a mysterious planet
whose unexplained force field
has seized us with a power
almost beyond imagination.
If there is a solution to this,
it almost certainly will involve
cooperation from the Ferengi.
Ship's power drain is critical, captain.
I must now shut down our shields
to maintain life support systems.
Understood.
Open hailing frequencies.
Hailing frequencies open, sir.
Ferengi vessel from Enterprise,
come in.
Your alien images again shock us.
With regard to surrender, Daimon Tarr,
the facts are somewhat different.
Our own probe has already
shown us your trickery, human.
- We withdraw our surrender.
- Agreed.
Perhaps you would agree
to a more productive relationship.
I prefer a more profitable one
human.
Yankee trader.
Explain what means
"Yankee traders."
He heard that.
It recognizes your interest in profit.
Or is that an incorrect assumption?
We seek only what is equitable.
What do you seek?
Why did you begin by attacking us?
We did not attack you.
We gave chase in order to recover
a Federation-owned energy device
- which--
- Which we know is ours.
Your barbarous Federation
placed it on one of our planets.
On the contrary, Gamma Tauri IV is
recognized by all civilized members of--
The Ferengi
are not uncivilized, human.
Are you suggesting otherwise?
All I'm saying
is that you removed something
which clearly did not belong to you.
Are you now calling us thieves?
On the contrary.
I have no wish to discuss issues
of property or territory
while our mutual problem remains.
Like it or not, we are both trapped
by this energy-draining force field
from the planet.
On that matter,
there can be no argument.
I would like to propose a swap.
And what is a swap?
It's a trade, uh, an exchange.
Yes, trade, human.
What do you offer?
We'd tell you
what we know about the planet,
and in trade,
you would give us your information.
Ridiculous. How do we know
you will not withhold information?
We must trust each other, Tarr.
Amusing, human. Trust each other?
I propose that we test this relationship
by cooperating in a joint exploration
of the planet surface.
And what profit is in this,
Picard Captain?
The profit, Daimon Tarr,
of saving all our lives.
We will agree, no doubt foolishly,
but you are warned that
any further trickery on your part
- will be met with no mercy.
- Agreed.
If you join us, we have a well-proven
transporter device--
We have a matter-energy device
of our own.
We will beam a science team of three
to whatever coordinates you propose.
Excellent, we will transmit
the information shortly.
Enterprise out.
Hailing frequencies off.
I would log that agreement
as promising, at least.
I wonder, captain.
I'm not usually one to distrust at first
sight, but this may be an exception.
Especially in view of the fact
that the image he transmitted, sir,
was somehow distorted.
I sensed the same thing, captain.
He's hiding something.
With this power drain, we can't delay.
Now, I'd like some additional help,
in case we run into trouble.
- Can you spare Worf?
- Take him.
And be careful, Number One.
With this power drain,
we may have trouble communicating
- with the Enterprise, sir.
- Understood. Anything else?
Due to this force field, there is
presently no way to beam us back, sir.
- Oh, you had to ask.
- Understood.
Energize.
Tasha? Data?
Geordi?
Worf?
Anybody?
Data?
- What are you doing up there?
- Most intriguing, sir.
I assume a problem of inaccurately
transmitted program coordinates
due to the force field
around the ship, sir.
- Are we alone, sir?
- Unfortunately.
Let's find the others.
What do you make of these?
Crystalline. Mostly inert.
Nothing to write home about.
Excuse me?
Slang, sir.
I did use it correctly, did I not?
They've gotta be around
here somewhere.
- What's that?
- What?
That.
Geordi!
Are you conscious?
Do I look conscious?
- What are you doing?
- I'm resting, sir.
My foot's stuck up there.
I materialized upside-down
above the planet's surface.
Tricorders useless, sir.
Communications gone too.
- Fortunately you did not break--
- Data.
Mm-hm?
Data, who's that?
Who are you?
Captain's log, supplemental.
It is now six hours since our away team
beamed down to the planet surface.
On the Enterprise,
our condition is rapidly worsening.
Ordinarily,
with reserve power alone,
we could maintain life support
for several months,
but the force holding us
has closed down all engines
and is draining
our reserve power too.
It's getting much, much colder, sir.
- How far down is it likely to go?
- A lot.
Even in orbital space,
it will get below minus-200 degrees.
We won't have to worry much
past minus-70 or so.
Feels like that now.
Good, thank you.
- If he moves, kill him.
- Letek.
Has what we've done broken
our agreement with their captain?
We will accuse the humans
- of preparing to ambush us.
- Ah.
It will be our word against theirs.
And who is more trustworthy,
Mordoc?
Uh...
It looks like gold.
Tastes like gold.
It is gold.
Accursed planet!
Nothing compared
to what our captain will do
when he finds out you've broken
our landing party agreement.
What part of the agreement?
You appeared and attacked us.
Are you one of their assassins?
I'm Commander William Riker,
first officer of the USS Enterprise.
You have a lot to learn.
I've got this one!
Careful, commander.
They are much stronger than--
- Let me go!
' Pygmy cretins!
Let me go!
- Kill them.
- Hideous monsters.
No!
Good.
You've heard of phasers.
Now, over there.
Is this a female?
A human female, Letek?
Hmm, then it is true.
You work with your females,
arm them,
and force them to wear clothing.
Sickening.
I've diverted the reserve power
down here to the family decks.
They'll last longest.
Is there anything else
we can do, doctor?
Where's Wesley?
He's in our quarters.
- I was tempted to give him a sedative.
- You shouldn't.
I know, but he's my son. I love him.
He has the right
to meet death awake.
Is that a male perspective?
Rubbish.
Hold it right there.
Stop. Stop.
- Phasers on stun.
- Already set.
What's going on?
What is this?
I believe we can deduce
that these crystalline tree shapes
are actually energy collectors.
Along the same principle as that which
is draining energy from our ships.
But the Ferengi whips were working
when we first arrived.
Which means
something new has happened.
I'm finally beginning to understand
what my eyes have been showing me.
There's patterns of force
everywhere.
This entire planet has been turned
into a power accumulator.
- And these?
- Whole point of this place.
I can see the planet's power
emanating from--
Commander.
Be you barbarians?
Speak.
Who meets the challenge?
Who Will it be?
Him.
You have awakened Portal 63.
Do you petition to enter the Empire?
Who asks the question?
A guardian of the Tkon Empire.
Biped. Excellent.
Why would we petition to enter
an empire that no longer exists?
Why do you attempt this deception?
The empire is forever.
Your empire fell prey to a supernova.
We are forever.
Data, please repeat the file.
It is a matter of record, Portal,
in the Age of Makto,
the central star
of the Tkon Empire destabilized--
There has never been
an Age of Makto.
In fact, there have been many ages
which have come and passed
since Makto.
- This is the Age of Bastu.
- I'm afraid not.
According to the Tkon use of
the galactic motionary startime charts,
after Bastu came Cimi,
Xora, Makto--
Enough. Absurdities.
You must have been asleep, Portal,
for hundreds of thousands of our years.
Deception is the way of the humans.
We Ferengi will gladly
make a petition.
We invite your petition.
Speak.
We wish to offer our services
to serve the Tkon Empire
at no profit.
Return control of our starship to us
and we will happily destroy
the human criminals
and their vessel which attacked us
without provocation.
They came to loot your empire.
But we intercepted them.
You are accused
of deceit and treachery.
Do you give yourself up
for judgment?
Yes.
If you believe these accusations,
then you certainly should act on them.
And there is even more.
We can prove that the humans
are destroyers of legal commerce
and that they selfishly withhold
vital technology from backward worlds.
And necessary
defensive weapons too.
We Ferengi now challenge
this human madness.
I admit, we've withheld modern
technologies from some worlds.
You see? They are demented,
their values are insane.
You cannot believe the business
opportunities they have destroyed.
Proof of their barbarism.
They adorn themselves with gold,
a despicable use of a valuable metal.
And they shamelessly
clothe their females.
Inviting others to unclothe them,
the very depth of perversion.
Paws off, Ferengi.
No female, human or Ferengi,
can order Mordoc around.
Submit.
Just try it, shorty.
At ease, lieutenant.
And we still have more faults.
They should add that Starfleet has
permitted several civilizations to fall.
We have, at times, allowed the strong
and violent to overcome the weak.
They admit their crimes. Hear them.
They admit the evil that they do.
Barbarian.
Yes, you show wisdom.
Barbarians, all.
But this one first.
In the fashion the Empire
has always challenged savages.
No, for battle, come to me!
No! That's an order.
You have a single chance for life.
One only.
What is the answer
to my challenge?
I offer a thought:
"He will triumph who knows
when to fight and when not to fight."
You are being tested, Riker.
What is the answer?
How do you know my name?
Ah.
You are facing fate with composure.
But what is the answer
to my challenge?
Fear is the true enemy.
The only enemy.
Unlike these little ones
who close their minds,
your mind holds interesting thoughts.
"Know your enemy and know yourself,
and you will always be victorious."
Why that thought?
And who is this Sun Tzu you revere?
An old Chinese philosopher
from ancient Earth history.
You must tell me more of this wisdom,
so much like our own.
Gladly, but first our starship.
Can you release it?
It is released.
All power is restored.
Not a moment too soon, Jean.
I mean, captain.
I admit I had my doubts
as your ships battled each other.
In overt acts of belligerence, normally
I would have destroyed all of you.
And your ships.
But something confused me.
Which was?
First you wanted
to destroy each other.
Then you were willing
to assist each other.
What of our vessel?
We knew the same answer.
The truth is,
I gave those words to this human.
What of them?
Shall I destroy them?
Then they would learn nothing.
A most interesting conclusion.
But what if they never learn, Riker?
- Is this a test also?
- Hmm.
In life, one is always tested.
I see them much as we were
several hundred years ago.
But possessing the technology
they now have, they're very dangerous.
Untrue.
We seek friendship with you.
But we can hardly hate
what we once were.
They may grow and learn.
And learn ways to destroy you.
Well, our values require us
to face that possibility.
What of you,
with your empire gone?
The universe exists to me
to create life.
I shall sleep until needed again.
- Compliments, lieutenant.
- Thank you.
Lieutenant Worf.
- You've done well.
- Something to write home about.
"Something to write home about"?
Data, that's very human.
The T-9 energy converter has been
beamed aboard and secured, sir.
The Ferengi complained bitterly,
but one final roar from Portal
convinced them.
I commend your performance,
Number One.
One final request, sir.
Permission to beam a box of Data's
Chinese finger puzzles
over to the Ferengi,
a thank-you for all they tried to do.
Make it so.
Set course, La Forge.