Captain's log, stardate 41209.2.
We are running at warp 7
to rendezvous with the science vessel
SS Tsiolkovsky,
which has been routinely monitoring
the collapse of a red supergiant star
into a white dwarf.
What has brought us here
is a series of strange messages
indicating something has gone wrong
aboard the research vessel.
SS Tsiolkovsky,
repeat your message.
Well, hello, Enterprise. Welcome.
I hope you have a lot of pretty boys
on board,
because I'm willing and waiting.
In fact, we're going to have...
- Boys?
- ...a real blowout here.
Do it, yeah, go ahead.
Whoo! Ha-ha-ha. Do it.
Captain, what we've just heard
is impossible.
Report.
I believe that last sound
was an emergency hatch being blown.
Are you certain?
Yes, of course you are.
Data. Geordi. Tasha.
Sensor scans now reveal
no life signs aboard, captain.
Cover the ship as planned. Move out.
Indications of what humans
would call a wild party?
Yeah.
Their Bridge.
If this thing works,
be sure to record everything.
You were right.
Somebody blew out the hatch.
They were all sucked out into space.
Correction, sir. That's "blown out."
Thank you, Data.
A common mistake, sir.
Commander Riker, Lieutenant Yar.
Location, Engineering. Ten people
here, sir, all frozen. No vital signs.
Frozen? How?
Looks like someone has been playing
with the environmental controls, sir.
Just let all the heat bleed away
into space.
Sir, Lieutenant La Forge
in the crew quarters.
Something in here.
Riker to captain,
I have a report for you, sir.
Picard here.
They're all dead.
Apparently, some of them
were blown out
the emergency hatches.
But there were 80 people on that ship,
Number One.
Yes, sir.
As I said,
all dead.
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
to explore strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go where no one
has gone before.
Captain's log, supplemental.
We are downloading
the research information gathered
on the collapsing star nearby.
I'm concerned
at being in such close orbit,
but the Tsiolkovsky's research records
will no doubt predict the time
of the star's final collapse.
I can't find anything unusual
in any of the tricorder readings
they sent over, captain.
Give me a theory, doctor. Anything.
Madness? Mass hysteria? Delusion?
Any or all, captain.
All right.
Let's bring the away team back.
Set the transporter
to maximum decontamination.
And then full examination
and observation when they're here.
If you were any more perfect, Data,
I'd have to write you up
in a Starfleet medical textbook.
I'm already listed
in several biomechanical texts, doctor.
Yes, of course.
You're next, lieutenant.
Normal, all across.
Except, why are you perspiring,
lieutenant?
I suppose because you have it too hot
in here. What else would it be?
Doesn't sound like you, Geordi.
Heh. Well, maybe it's not,
maybe she threw her voice.
Hey, it's a joke.
Of course.
But I would like to run, uh, one or two
more tests on you, lieutenant.
Sickbay to Bridge.
Picard here. Go ahead, doctor.
I'm confining Lieutenant La Forge
to Sickbay until further notice.
Do we have a problem, doctor?
I don't know yet.
Data, I need help in locating
some library computer information.
Specifics, sir?
All I have is a vague memory
of reading somewhere
about someone taking a shower
in his or her clothing.
Ah. The body Geordi discovered.
Well, I believe
it may have happened before.
To someone, somewhere.
This ought to be easy for someone
written up in biomechanical texts.
About that, sir,
did the doctor believe I was boasting?
Probably.
- This may take some time?
- At least several hours.
But what I said
was a statement of fact.
Perhaps she will look it up.
You can depend on it.
Oh, my God.
Geordi.
Security, Lieutenant La Forge just
left Sickbay while I was in my office.
He doesn't have his communicator.
It is very important that we find him.
Security team alert.
Pick up Lieutenant La Forge.
He just left Sickbay moments ago.
Captain, anything further'?
Affirmative.
Make it a ship-wide search, lieutenant.
It's a model of the same kind
of tractor beam our ship uses,
with a few ideas of my own added.
So that's your science project, huh?
Wes, you're really something.
And since the captain
won't let me on the Bridge,
I use this to imagine I'm there.
Take the helm, Mr. Crusher.
Set a course for 37, mark 180.
Warp 6.
That's the captain's voice.
It's pieced together from words
he's used on the intercom.
With this, I can pretend he's ordering
me to take the Enterprise anywhere.
And listen to this.
Chief engineer, report to the Bridge.
Commander Riker,
report to the Bridge.
- Dr. Crusher, report to the Bridge.
- Ha, ha.
What do you think?
I think the captain's lucky
you're on his side.
But he still won't let me
on the Bridge.
And there's nothing there
I don't understand.
I wish I understood myself that well.
Are you okay?
No. Suddenly I seem
to be burning up inside.
It's so hot in here.
Geordi?
Geordi.
Lieutenant Yar
in the observation lounge,
send a team here now.
- Medical's been worried about you.
- Help me.
Help me to not give in
to the wild things coming into my mind.
- Geordi, my job is security--
- Tasha, please.
All right.
All right. Helping is more important.
- Geordi, how can I help you?
- Help me to see.
Like you do.
But you already see better
than I can.
I see more.
But more isn't better.
- Geordi, please, put these on--
- I wanna see in shallow, dim,
beautiful human ways.
We'll talk about it, Geordi.
Right now
I'm going to take you to Sickbay.
All right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Good.
And then we got him down to Sickbay
so Dr. Crusher could examine him.
He wasn't violent?
No, sir. He was very upset.
He kept talking
about wanting normal vision.
Hmm.
Thank you, lieutenant.
According to our medical readouts,
there's still nothing wrong with him.
He looks like
he's running a temperature,
but every instrument says he's not.
Doctor, every person on that ship
over there died.
Is there any chance that
whatever did it is loose on my ship?
If you mean a disease, sir,
I'd say there's no chance of it.
We used full decontamination,
we examined every team member
very carefully.
The entire crew somehow managed
to kill themselves, doctor.
If it's not a disease,
what else made them do it?
The obvious alternatives
are in the areas of insanity
and severe emotional upset.
Troi, do you feel anything unusual
in the lieutenant?
Security just told me
that he was longing for normal sight.
It's a sudden yearning for that.
Since his records show
no previous mention of that,
the fact that it happened now
could be important.
But all I sense from him
is confusion.
If I didn't know better,
I'd say he was intoxicated.
Our tests would have shown that.
Also any other signs of drugs,
hallucinogens,
or any other contaminants.
Can you provide more information,
sir?
Seeking an instance of someone
showering in his or her clothing is--
I know, it's like looking for a needle
in a haystack.
Why should anyone wish
to expend his time in such a search?
Correction, Data, I should have said
proverbial needle in a haystack.
Ah. A human proverb.
As in folklore, or an historical allusion,
or tribal memories--
Historical. That's it.
I remember I was reading a history
of all the past starships
named Enterprise.
Enterprise history.
Aberrant behavior.
Medical cross-reference.
Captain, I believe we have the
answer to what happened over there.
"The Constitution-class
starship Enterprise,
Captain James T. Kirk
commanding."
Similar conditions.
They were monitoring a planet
that was breaking up,
and not a collapsing star,
as in this case.
But there were the same huge shifts
in gravity.
Which somehow resulted
in complex strings of water molecules
which acquired carbon from the body
and acted-
Acted on the brain like alcohol.
Data, download this information
to Medical immediately.
Aye, sir. Downloading.
Fascinating.
The entire crew going out of control.
Like intoxication, but worse.
Judgment
almost completely impaired.
Until they found this formula,
barely in time.
Picard to Dr. Crusher, come in.
This is Crusher. Go ahead, captain.
You can relax, doctor.
The answer to all of this is feeding
into your medical banks right now,
including a cure.
Are you certain, captain?
Absolutely.
Tasha?
What are you doing?
I need your advice.
That's why I came to your quarters.
- Of course. Anything I can do--
- On clothes.
You always wear
such beautiful clothes off duty.
And your hair always looks so nice.
I wanna change my image.
What do you think about this?
Or--? Or this one?
It's not for you.
Tasha, I feel you're very uncertain.
That you're fighting something.
What is it?
Never mind.
I'll find what I need myself.
Ship's stores will have it.
Tasha? Tasha, wait.
Troi to Captain Picard.
Picard here.
Sir, I think
Tasha's been infected too.
She just left my quarters.
Counselor,
it's not actually an infection.
Yes, sir, it's more like an intoxication.
But whatever it is, she's got it.
Thank you, counselor.
Number One, it seems our Security
chief has the equivalent of a snootful.
Inquiry, sir.
Snootful?
Forget it.
Hey, Mom, look what I can do.
I've been able to widen
and strengthen the beam.
- Just like I told you last night.
- Do me a favor, Wes.
There's something happening
on this ship.
Just to be safe, I'd like you to stay
in our quarters until it's solved.
Sure, Mom. Sure.
Your wish is my command.
Now, Wes.
Okay. But you could be stunting
my emotional growth. You realize that?
Why's it so hot in here, anyway?
Picard to Crusher.
Crusher here.
Have you made a test injection yet?
We're getting indications
that this condition is spreading.
No test yet, captain, but very soon.
Captain, another 41 minutes
will see the information
from the Tsiolkovsky
downloaded to us.
Why so slow?
Slow, sir?
The Tsiolkovsky has been
eight months in accumulating it.
How much danger from that star?
Worst case.
Like a full collapse, sir?
Any stellar material it threw this way,
we could still outrun
on half impulse power.
Picard to Engineering.
Chief engineer, report to the Bridge.
Assistant Chief Engineer Shimoda,
report to Medical.
- Hi, Jim.
- Oh.
Was that the captain
ordering you to Medical?
Which would leave no one
here on duty.
The chief was just summoned
to the Bridge.
What about me?
I could call the chief on the Bridge
if anything happened.
Reporting as ordered, sir.
What?
You ordered me
to report to the Bridge, sir.
I did no such thing.
I want you down in the Engine Room,
just in case we need
to move out of here.
Uh...
Attention, all decks.
Effective immediately,
I have handed over control
of this vessel
to Acting Captain Wesley Crusher.
Acting captain?
Thank you, Captain Picard. Thank you.
And with that order dawns
a brave new day for the Enterprise.
Captain's log, stardate 41209.3.
The strange contaminant
that /ed to the deaths
of the Tsiolkovsky crew
is now aboard the Enterprise,
and our Engineering section
has been commandeered
by young Wesley Crusher.
And henceforth, a dessert course
shall precede and follow every meal,
including breakfast.
- Hurray for the acting captain.
- All right.
I never got as far as Sickbay, Wes.
I feel too good for that.
Incredible. How did you do that?
Hooked my model tractor beam
into ship's power.
Now it's a repulser beam too.
Want in?
I swear to be faithful to you, captain.
Number One, MacDougal,
get that boy out of Engineering.
Sir, I'm getting very strange reports
from all decks.
Such as?
Such as the ship's training division
ordering all officers
to attend a lecture
on metaphysics.
Metaphysics?
Confirmed, sir.
And there was
a rather peculiar limerick
being delivered by someone
in the shuttlecraft bay.
I am not sure I understand it.
There was a young lady from Venus
Whose body was shaped like a--
Captain to Security, come in.
Did I say something wrong?
I don't understand
their humor either.
Ha, ha. Yeah?
Where is my security chief?
Get me Lieutenant Yar.
Keep your britches on--
Captain Picard.
Lieutenant, where are you?
Ha-ha-ha. I'm in my quarters,
and, um, I'm pretty busy
right at the moment,
Jean-Luc.
All right, lieutenant,
you just stay right there.
Data, go to Lieutenant Yar,
take her down to Sickbay.
Yes, sir.
Captain to Security.
I want all your senior supervisors
to report to the Bridge immediately.
Lieutenant Yar?
Here, Data.
You wanted me?
Captain Picard ordered me
to escort you to Sickbay, lieutenant.
Did he say when?
I'm sure he meant now.
So you should get into uniform.
Tsk. But I got out of my uniform
for you, Data.
Do you know how old I was
when I was abandoned?
Chronological age?
No.
- I'm afraid I am not familiar with--
- Five.
Five years old.
But I survived.
I learned how to stay alive,
how to avoid the rape gangs.
I was 15 before I escaped.
I am sorry. I did not know.
And what I want now is gentleness.
And joy.
And love.
From you, Data.
You are fully functional, aren't you?
- Of course, but--
- How fully?
In every way, of course.
I am programmed
in multiple techniques.
- A broad variety of pleasuring.
- Oh.
You jewel.
That's exactly what I hoped.
What have you learned?
Captain, the ship's engines are cut off
from the Bridge.
The assistant chief engineer
has pulled out
the isolinear optical chips
from command.
All the engines are off-line.
Wesley has hooked up some kind
of tractor beam to the ship's power.
He has it aimed at the door.
And we can't get past
to get to the computer.
Can you short out the power?
Yes, I can.
But it's gonna take some time.
Do it.
Bill?
Deanna, what?
So many minds on this ship,
all free.
Released.
Deanna.
I can feel them all.
What they want, what they feel.
It's a side of humans
I never felt before.
Come on. I'm getting you to Sickbay.
Wouldn't you rather be alone with me?
With me in your mind?
The medical records we found
say this works almost instantly.
It's not fair, doc.
I've never seen a rainbow,
a sunset, sunrise.
This is gonna help me?
Help me see like you?
Dr. Crusher?
Deanna needs your help.
The formula from the old Enterprise
didn't work.
- What?
- This water-carbon complex
may induce the same symptoms,
but somehow it's different.
Maybe it's mutated. But I've got
to isolate it in order to analyze it.
- We don't have that kind of time.
- You brought Deanna in?
- Yes, she's infected with it.
- You touched her.
Oh, God, and you touched me.
I've gotta quarantine you.
If I don't get the command computer
back online soon,
none of this, whatever this is,
will matter.
We'll all be dead.
Captain's log, supplemental.
It is no longer an inconvenient,
childish prank.
Young Wesley Crusher,
admittedly a victim
of the Tsiolkovsky infection,
is now in control of my starship.
Wesley? This is Captain Picard.
- Do you see me?
- Yes, sir.
You will now return control
of this vessel
to the Bridge, where it belongs.
At once.
I'm sorry, sir.
Why don't you just tell me
what you want done and I'll do it?
Because ship captains
control their own vessels, young man.
But, sir, you don't do it yourself.
You give the orders,
but somebody else does it.
What's wrong with giving me
the orders to do it?
Captain, getting unusual readings now
from the dwarf star.
Stand by on that for a moment.
Wesley.
Wes.
Are you aware
that you are behaving strangely?
That a kind of infection was brought
over from the Tsiolkovsky
which acts like intoxication?
Are you saying that's why
I feel so hot? So strange?
That's...
That's a very adult bit of reasoning,
Wesley.
So you mean I'm drunk.
I feel strange but also good.
Because...
Because you have lost the capacity
for self-judgment.
Now, alcohol does this, Wesley,
but the contaminant we brought back
from the Tsiolkovsky
does it even more so.
What would you do
if you got your ship back?
Oh, it's very important I do, Wesley.
Because I must immediately
lock a tractor beam
onto the Tsiolkovsky
and tow it out of--
Tractor beams are my specialty,
skipper.
I'll contact you when that's done.
Wesley out.
Wesley?
Conn, where are you headed?
Sir, the star.
It's beginning to collapse.
What the hell is happening
in Engineering?
Lock on.
Lock on, Tsiolkovsky.
- Where's that sonic driver?
- It's over there.
Okay. Let's see if this
cuts out his tractor-beam power.
Come on.
Oh, no. No.
I must find the answer.
I've got to find the answer.
Captain, tractor beam.
We just locked onto the Tsiolkovsky.
Captain to--
Wesley. Wesley Crusher, come in.
Ah, good, Data.
- At least you're functioning.
- Fully, captain.
Data, intoxication
is a human condition.
Your brain is different,
it's not the same as--
We are more alike than unlike,
my dear captain.
I have pores.
Humans have pores.
I have fingerprints.
Humans have fingerprints.
My chemical nutrients
are like your blood.
If you prick me,
do I not leak?
- Doctor--
Captain,
can I see you in your Ready Room?
It's a private matter.
No, actually, it's an urgent one.
But--
Damn it.
Now, doctor--
I believe I've become infected myself,
captain.
Do you know what the infection is?
- Come on, quickly.
- Ha, ha-- Sorry.
It is definitely like alcohol intoxication.
The same lack of good judgment.
For example,
right now I find you extremely,
extremely...
Of course,
we haven't time for that sort of thing.
- What sort of thing?
- Oh, God, would I love to show you.
Doctor, there must be a cure.
Some formula.
Similar to the old one.
Damn it, damn it, captain.
My dear captain.
You owe me something.
You do realize that, don't you?
I'm a woman.
I haven't had the comfort
of a husband, a man.
Not now, doctor.
Please.
- Bridge to Riker. Urgent.
- Riker here.
Sir, regret to inform you
that the captain appears to be infected.
And Data.
Thank you, lieutenant,
I'm on my way.
You'll have to handle this.
Are you saying
you're gonna handle that?
What we're seeing, sir,
is a huge chunk of the star's surface
blown away,
heading for us.
Take us...
Are you all right, sir?
Worf, you do know what to do.
Take us, uh...
- Take us out of here.
- Right.
- Controls are still off-line, sir.
- Override.
Same result, sir.
Wes, come in, please.
Wesley Crusher, this is Riker.
This is urgent. Come in, please.
Engineering, urgent.
We must have ship's power.
These are control chips.
Bridge from Engineering.
The star is still collapsing.
- We're directly in the path--
- I can't help you, Bridge.
Someone here has yanked out
all the control chips.
It was an adult who did it.
Sir, I estimate 14 minutes
until that mass gets here.
No way. I cannot
replace these chips in 14 minutes
Two hours, three, maybe.
Data could assemble them
back faster.
What? What's that?
What's that, Wesley?
Well, they're just simple isolinear
chips, sir. To Data, anyway.
He could shuffle them like cards.
Come on, Data, hurry.
Ship's log, First Officer Riker.
Enterprise will be destroyed
unless it can be moved out of the path
of the star material hurtling toward us.
Our only hope is
for Lieutenant Commander Data,
in the time we have left,
to regain his senses and reconnect
engine power to the Bridge.
- Nice to see you, Wesley.
- Hi, Mr. Data.
No time for courtesy.
Get the control chips back in place.
In the correct order. Now!
It's like a game
of how fast can you do it'?
Ah. A game.
I think I can switch this
to main viewer, sir.
Data, we've eight or nine minutes
at most. Can you finish by then?
No. This will take slightly more time
than we have, sir.
Oh, damn it, no.
I can't afford to get this.
Beverly.
Yes, Jean-Luc?
You will address me as captain.
Captain?
Well, then, my dear captain,
you will address me
as chief medical officer, or doctor.
- I will?
- Ha, ha.
That's true.
I started out by calling you Beverly,
and, of course, naturally, you--
I'm still not thinking straight.
Likewise.
Where the hell was I headed?
If that's something you were going
to test--
Yes, on Geordi. Come here.
See how I reversed the fields on this,
commander?
I made it into a repulser beam.
If we just had one minute more, sir.
If this were a hundred times
more powerful than it is...
Why not try it with the real thing?
Why not reverse fields on this, ma'am,
if we just need an extra minute?
It would take weeks
of laying out new circuits.
Why not just see it in your head?
Yeah.
Come off the main lead,
split off at the force activator,
then...
Then...
If I could just think straight
about this.
I made this a broader-based remedy.
I hope, ha,ha.
But it's still very close to the formula
from the old Enterprise records.
Decades ago. Light years away.
But almost exactly the same conditions
as here.
Wow, what was in that, doctor?
My head's beginning to clear. Ahem.
Come here.
Here. Take this to Engineering.
I'll make up hypos for the others.
Okay, Bev.
We're not gonna make it, captain.
If we only had a minute or so more.
Yes, then reversing power leads,
back through the force activator,
repulser beam hard against
Tsiolkovsky.
Don't you see?
It's giving us a push-off.
The extra time we need.
We're pushing away.
Bridge, engage engines.
Captain, something seemed
to move us aside at the last minute.
Do we owe our thanks
to Commander Data, sir?
Yes, and Wesley may have given us
a few seconds too.
Did he say "Wesley"? The boy?
He said "Wesley."
It's only fair to mention Wesley
in a log entry, sir.
Fair is fair.
And let's credit
his science teacher too.
Congratulations, sir.
To many people.
Data.
I'm only going to tell you this
just once.
It never happened.
I put it to you all.
I think we shall end up
with a fine crew.
If we avoid temptation.
So, Number One,
let's go to our next job.
Aye, sir.
Helm, prepare for warp 3.
Heading 294, mark 37.
Warp 3. Heading 294, mark 37, sir.
Engage.