♪ ♪
[rain pattering]
[crowd shouting
and chanting in German]
[shouting and chanting
continue]
[clattering]
[loud banging, clattering]
[distant siren,
whistles blowing]
♪ 'Cause I'll be leaving
in the... ♪
[doorbell ringing]
- ♪ In the fairest ♪
- [knocking]
♪ Of the seasons ♪
[knocking continues]
MAN:
Oh.
Patricia.
♪ That I'll be leaving ♪
♪ In the fairest
of the seasons ♪
♪ Do I stay or should I go? ♪
So, I have a patient
that is coming in five minutes.
I can ask him
to come back later.
Please.
[Patricia chuckles]
♪ 'Cause I'll be leaving ♪
♪ In the fairest
of the seasons ♪
[continues singing
indistinctly]
♪ That I'll be leaving ♪
♪ In the... ♪
This song, it's stuck
in my head, and it's so loud.
They're going to try
to keep her alive after all.
Markos?
[Patricia panting quietly]
[loud bang outside,
crowd shouting]
[crowd chanting in German]
I have to tell Sara
to get out of there.
She's the only girl
I actually give a damn about.
[curtains closing]
PATRICIA:
If I leave without her,
they may pick her next.
Or Olga.
I should warn Olga, too.
Olga's already
figured out things.
She saw how they groomed me.
[chuckles]
There's more in that building
than what you can see.
[Patricia panting quietly]
They've been underground
since the war.
And you think
they can hear you now?
[eerie voices
whispering indistinctly]
At the beginning,
they gave me things.
Perfect balance, perfect sleep.
Talking with our minds.
But they took my hair.
They took my urine. They...
They took my eyes.
Now she can see me.
♪ 'Cause I'll be leaving ♪
♪ In the fairest
of the seasons ♪
♪ I'll be leaving... ♪
PATRICIA:
Mother Markos.
Oh, she wants
to get inside of me.
I can feel her.
Oh, I thought I wanted it.
[sighs]
I let it happen.
[eerie voices laughing]
[gasping]
[eerie voices laughing,
moaning]
[grunting, panting]
[whimpers softly]
If they find out I was here,
they won't hesitate.
[door opens]
[Patricia gasps, pants]
[door opens and closes]
[speaking German]
[bird squawking]
♪ ♪
- [wheezing quietly]
- [indistinct whispering]
[water splashing gently]
[wheezing continues]
♪ This is what I was thinking ♪
[quiet, indistinct chatter]
♪ About our bodies ♪
[crying]
♪ What they mean ♪
♪ For our salvation ♪
[objects clattering quietly]
♪ Only the clothes that ♪
♪ We stand up in ♪
♪ Just the ground ♪
♪ On which we stand ♪
[banging, creaking]
♪ Is the darkness ♪
♪ Ours to take? ♪
Okay, that's good. That's good.
♪ Bathed in lightning ♪
♪ Bathed in heat ♪
[takes deep breath]
[wheezing continues]
♪ All is well ♪
♪ As long as we keep spinning ♪
♪ Here now ♪
♪ Dancing behind the wall ♪
♪ Hear the old songs ♪
♪ And laughter within ♪
[wheezing continues]
♪ When I arrive, will ♪
- Morning, Pastor.
- ♪ You come and find me? ♪
Did the rain get your clothes
all wet?
No, don't you worry. The girls
just hung that all up.
- ♪ In a crowd ♪
- Two days of rain
is what I just heard
on the radio.
- That'll just about do it.
- Just about.
♪ Be one of them ♪
- [door opens and closes]
- PASTOR: How is she today?
- ♪ Mother wants us ♪
- MAN: Much the same.
♪ Right beside her ♪
♪ No tomorrows ♪
♪ At peace. ♪
[wheezing continues]
[wheezing fades]
[announcement in German
over P.A.]
[chatter in German]
[train screeching in distance]
[train rumbling and screeching]
[quiet chatter]
[objects rattling and banging]
[distant banging]
[panting]
[woman speaking German]
You're Miss Tanner?
Yes. Come in.
[panting quietly]
TANNER:
Nah?
I tried to call you
at your hotel this morning
to ask you
if you could reschedule.
- Why?
- Company business.
It's not a good time
just today.
But here you are.
[sighs]
[taking deep breaths]
[continues breathing deeply]
WOMAN:
And one, and two,
and three, and four,
and five,
and six, and seven,
and eight.
Elbows up. And one...
Come in, Susie.
[Susie clears throat quietly]
Miss Millius and Miss Mandel
are the company's repetiteurs.
SUSIE:
And Veva Blanc?
I was told she would be here.
[chuckling]:
Oh, dear.
You have no formal training
or references.
Your insistence to audition
happened to catch Madame Blanc
on a good day.
But you really shouldn't
be here at all.
Do you understand?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah?
Good.
[speaks German]
Uh...
I prefer dancing without music.
- Danke schoen.
- [laughing]
You can keep time
in your head, yes?
[clears throat quietly]
[sighs]
[lights buzz quietly]
[gasps]
Mm-hmm, and Hypnose.
And here we have...
a line between the elbows.
Face forward.
Perfect, and... Morphus.
And here,
not so close to the face.
More like you're holding
a bird or something.
[inhales sharply]
[panting]
[panting heavily]
♪ ♪
[heavy panting continues]
[panting continues in distance]
[heavy, rapid panting]
♪ ♪
[panting]
[indistinct chatter]
WOMAN: They did it when we
were in morning rehearsal.
They just put her things
in shipping boxes.
WOMAN 2: You don't think she
had to go underground, do you?
WOMAN 1:
I don't care what happened.
I just want her to call.
I'm really worried.
WOMAN:
Fraulein Bannion.
Kommen Sie.
I've just spoken
with Madame Blanc.
Well done, Miss Bannion.
[Susie laughs]
I imagine you will need
to return home
to settle things
and make arrangements
for moving to Berlin.
No. No, no.
I can start right now.
[chuckles]
Good.
This is Miss Boutaher,
our technical director.
Guten Tag.
And this is Miss Vendegast.
- She acts as house mother...
- Hello.
...for our dancers
who reside here.
Where'd you come from?
[clears throat]
Ohio.
[chuckling]
We operate as a sort
of Ruth Bré collective.
As we cannot pay our dancers
a lot of money,
we offer dormitory-style rooms,
rent-free.
You don't... you don't charge
anything at all?
Not a mark.
[chuckles]
In this company,
we fully understand
the importance of a woman's
financial autonomy.
[chuckles]
Normally, it would be full
at this time of year,
but we have had a room open.
Yeah. Patricia's.
Do you know Patricia?
SUSIE:
Mmm...
No, I heard some girls talking
about her in the hall.
- Ah.
- [distant door closes]
Now that you're one of us,
I won't be coy.
Patricia has just left
the company
under sad circumstances.
We think she won't be back,
so there's room if you want.
We'll send you one of our girls
to help you with your luggage.
After lunch.
It's all right for you?
Yes.
It's-it... it's all...
- Yes.
- [laughter]
It's perfect.
♪ ♪
[chuckling]
- [thunder crashes]
- [knocking at door]
Hello. Hi.
I'm sorry I'm late.
- Hi.
- It's the rain.
Whenever it rains in Berlin,
everyone jumps in a cab,
and like an idiot,
I just let ours go.
Hi. I'm Sara.
We're gonna have to take
our chances on the street.
Do you have an umbrella?
Oh, when you weren't here
by 6:00,
I had to take the room
for another night.
Oh. God, Susie, I'm sorry.
Everything was a mess
at the company today.
- [chuckles]
- Why are you smiling?
- I'm sor... I-I...
- [indistinct chatter]
Um, uh, when you said Berlin
a second ago,
you said "everyone in Berlin,"
and I just thought that...
that includes me now.
I live in Berlin.
- Yes. Congrats.
- [chuckles]
I heard you were
a sensation today.
Have you called your
family yet, to tell them?
Miss Blanc came
into my audition.
But she left right after.
- [chuckles]
- She's incredible.
The way she transmits her work,
her energy.
When it shines on you, it's...
"addictive" is the word for it.
She's tough.
She kept the company alive
through the war.
When the Reich just wanted
women to shut off their minds
and keep their uteruses open,
there was Blanc.
Thank you.
La vraie chose.
What?
W-Was that French?
[loud bang, rattling]
[alarm ringing in distance]
[indistinct shouting
in distance]
SARA:
It's a bomb.
I can smell it.
There's a bank that way.
Don't you know
what's happening here?
The hijackers
are negotiating a release
of the Stammheim prisoners
tonight.
The RAF.
Baader-Meinhof.
They kidnapped an executive.
During the war,
he was a Nazi SS, an officer.
Now he runs the German
Employers' Association.
You don't get how awful
that is, do you?
[upbeat music playing
over radio]
[music stops]
[indistinct chatter over radio]
Sorry.
I'm just worried
about my friend.
[alarm ringing]
[panting quietly]
[Vendegast humming a tune]
[continues humming]
[door opens, closes]
♪ ♪
[quiet, indistinct chatter]
[radio broadcast continues]
[indistinct chatter]
[panting]
[chatter in German]
[chatter continues]
[train whirring and rattling]
[chatter]
[buzzing]
[buzzing stops, door opens]
♪ ♪
[inhales deeply]
[quiet chatter]
♪ ♪
[keys jingling]
[birds squawking and tweeting]
[takes deep breath]
SARA: Bedrooms are on
the second floor.
[indistinct chatter
and laughter]
[music playing over radio]
[sighs]
Why don't you try speaking
to me like you love me?
Huh?
For a change.
[sighs]
This is my room.
And here...
is yours.
We're neighbors.
You can knock on the wall
if you ever need anything.
[chatter and laughter
continue in other rooms]
[grunts quietly]
[TV broadcast
playing in German]
[door opens and closes]
BLANC:
Good morning.
- Good morning.
- Hello.
- Hi.
- Good morning. Good morning.
How's your knee? Okay?
It's wonderful you're here.
- Thank you.
- [quiet chatter]
We have some happier
company business today.
We have a new dancer.
This is Susie Bannion,
who's joining us from America.
I was privileged to witness
her audition yesterday.
We are very lucky to have her.
Would you like
to say something, Susie?
Um...
I don't know.
Hello.
[quiet laughter]
I feel like
I'm not even here yet.
I don't know.
You join in
whenever you feel ready,
but there's no rush.
Welcome to our little family.
I'm Susie.
- Hi. Hi.
- [indistinct chatter]
All right,
so for today's rehearsal,
I want to pick up exactly
where we left off with Volk.
I've spoken to Olga,
and she's going to dance
Patricia's part.
And, Sara, I'd like you
to dance Olga's part.
Is everyone happy with that?
- [quiet murmurs of agreement]
- Okay.
Good.
[mid-tempo piano music playing]
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Music off, please.
- One moment.
- [music stops]
Okay, so...
And one, and two, and three.
You pull it from the ground.
All right? Gravity, remember.
And everybody from here,
please.
And Tanner.
One and two and three.
And one, and two, and three.
Und eins, und zwei, und drei.
- Und eins, und zwei, und drei.
- [dancers panting]
Und eins, und zwei, und drei.
Und eins,
und zwei, und drei.
Und eins, und zwei, und drei.
Und eins,
und zwei, und drei.
Und eins, und zwei, und drei.
This is shit.
- Such shit.
- Okay.
Why don't we all break
for ten minutes.
You can't even be bothered
to respect your own lies.
Miss Ivanova!
BLANC:
No, no, no, no, no, it's okay.
Let's face this.
Patricia is gone, Olga.
We don't know where.
If she's gone into hiding,
she wouldn't have told us,
- would she?
- She would have told someone.
We know that she had dealings
with people
who are interested in targets.
And we know
there was another bomb
in Kreuzberg last night.
OLGA:
She wouldn't do that.
[Blanc shushing]
She wanted to live her beliefs.
Who doesn't admire that?
And there's so much to change
in the world.
If she wants to live
in a cellar
filling bottles with petrol,
that's her choice.
And who won't be heartbroken
if she's shot by police?
[sobbing]:
You manipulate everything.
She didn't trust you
because you're hypocrites.
Will you take Olga
to her room, please, Tanner?
[Olga crying]
No, Miss Tanner!
Call Olga a cab.
She's had enough.
And is going to pack her things
and get the fuck out
from this box of rabies!
[Olga sobbing]
[Tanner laughing]
BLANC:
I'm sorry about that.
It's a hot thing we do.
Okay, so... who will dance
the protagonist?
Sonia?
I can't. Not yet.
Caroline?
Very well. We'll manage.
I suggest that we all
take it from the top.
SUSIE:
I'll dance.
I know it.
It's in the documentary.
I-I've seen it a hundred times
at the library.
Sweetheart,
we rehearsed this piece
for ten months
before we performed it.
I've seen it in person, too.
TANNER:
First do it alone, then.
We don't want to put
the others at risk.
The last thing we need
is someone to get kicked
in the ribs.
[chuckles quietly]
All right?
♪ ♪
[mid-tempo piano music plays]
[takes deep breath]
[panting]
Okay, stop. Stop, stop.
- Stop.
- [music stops]
All right.
Clear your head.
I want you to start over.
Have you stretched?
This is no joke.
♪ ♪
[quiet chatter in German]
[distant laughter]
- [door opens]
- [laughter continues]
- [laughter stops]
- Olga.
[muffled, distorted whooshing]
[muffled, distorted whispering]
- [whooshing, whispering stop]
- [laughter resumes]
[sighs, grunts]
[laughter continues]
[exhales]
[sniffs, grunts]
[laughter echoing]
[exhales, sniffs]
[grunting, sniffing]
[laughter echoing]
[panting]
WOMAN:
Olga.
[speaking German]
Come.
[whimpers, sobs]
[sobbing,
speaking indistinctly]
BLANC: Remember, you start
on one with the music,
and if you feel ill
at any time, just stop.
You start here.
And...
[piano music plays]
[rhythmic breathing]
[groans]
[gasps, coughs]
[exhales sharply]
[pained gasping]
[panting rhythmically]
[grunts]
[yells, coughs]
[gasps, grunts]
[pained grunt]
[grunts]
- [crunching]
- [gasps, screams]
[pained gasping]
[panting]
[coughs, wheezes]
Lauter!
[music volume increases]
[groaning]
Bravo. Bravo, Susie.
[pained gasping]
[groans, gasping]
[gasping weakly]
[sobbing]
- [crunching]
- [screams]
[breathing rhythmically]
[agonized screaming]
[gasping]
[breathing rhythmically]
[panting, whimpering]
[screams, whimpers]
[breathing rhythmically]
[pained scream]
[screams]
[pained gasp]
[breathing rhythmically]
- [crunching]
- [gasps]
[panting]
- [coughing]
- [music stops]
[wheezing]
[breathing weakly]
[whimpers]
[panting, whimpering]
It'll pass.
You're not the first dancer
who lost the room.
[inhales deeply]
SUSIE:
I'm not usually dizzy.
An occasional collapse
is a vocational hazard,
I'm afraid.
I-I didn't...
I didn't collapse.
You're on the floor, and that's
not where the dance ends.
[panting]
I was trying not to throw up
in your studio.
Susie, it's fine.
It was wonderful.
Sara, can you take her
to her room, please?
You can rest
for the rest of the day.
[quiet chatter]
- How enlightening.
- WOMAN: Okay, come on, girls.
- [clapping]
- Let's go.
And one, and two, and three.
BLANC:
And...
[clears throat]
[trickling]
[birds chirping]
[panting]
GIRL:
No, Susie.
We have to study America.
I said no.
WOMAN:
Susanna.
[panting]
[humming quietly]
♪ ♪
[wheezing quietly]
[wheezing]
[inhales deeply]
[groans quietly]
[raspy groaning]
[groaning]
[raspy gasp]
[grunts]
[chuckles quietly]
- [grunts]
- [wheezing weakly]
[clunking]
[wheezing weakly]
You don't look better.
Or are you this pale
all the time?
I will leave you.
Good night.
SUSIE:
The Amish split
from the Mennonites
in the 17th century.
They were worried
the Mennonites
were becoming too liberal.
"They"? Not "we"?
You've left religious thinking
behind you, then?
And you're not comfortable
talking about these things.
I don't know why we are.
It's difficult not
to be curious about you.
In two days, you've auditioned,
been accepted
and danced a lead.
How did your journey
towards us begin?
I went to New York.
To the Martha Graham Center.
I saw you there three times.
I went once by bus,
then I hitchhiked
the other two.
That's risky.
Were you punished?
Yeah.
But I felt I had to see you.
What did it feel today
to dance Volkin front
of the one who made it?
No, no.
That's a vain question.
Let me ask you another.
When you were dancing,
what did it feel like...
inside you, inside your body?
It felt like what I think
it must feel like to fuck.
You mean to fuck a man?
No, I...
was thinking of an animal.
[chuckles]
You looked...
I'm going to ask Caroline
to work on your jumps with you.
Yours are nowhere near
good enough yet.
We'll have to build you up.
So that I can dance
the protagonist
when you perform it?
I'll need to see you dance at
this level time and time again.
I can do it.
Olga made Volkseem
like such heavy lifting.
[water running]
She never understood
the heart of Volk.
- [water stops]
- [gasps quietly]
She lacked conviction.
I'm relieved she's gone.
Thank you for your help
with that.
[knocking]
[door opens]
SUSIE [chuckling]:
Madame Blanc...
wants me to dance
the protagonist in Volk.
I didn't think it was
gonna be like this.
She's so kind. [chuckles]
That's wonderful.
Are you all right?
I'm fine. I was just...
I was just thinking about
what Olga said in rehearsal.
About Patricia.
SUSIE [in other room]:
What do you mean?
SARA: She was active
in some political groups.
No one knows where she is,
really.
If she's all right.
Was it true...
what Olga said?
Yes.
Patricia didn't trust
the matrons.
And I never understood why.
If I asked you for a favor
tomorrow, would you do it?
Yes.
- [grunts]
- We might get caught.
Okay.
[heavy breathing]
[heavy breathing continues]
[wheezing]
GIRL [whispering]:
Mother. Mother.
Mother.
Mother. Mother. Mother. Mother.
Mother. Mother.
[shuddering]
WOMAN [whispering]:
Susanna.
[girl screams]
- [heavy breathing]
- [dish clattering]
- [woman speaks German]
- [wheezing]
[heavy breathing]
[woman shouts in German]
[gasping, shrieking]
[dog barking in distance]
[distant barking continues]
[paper rustling]
[sighs]
- Guten Morgen.
Morgen.
Guten Morgen.
WOMAN:
Yeah, I know. It's crazy.
Okay, well, let's meet soon.
- [indistinct chatter]
- [chuckling]
Yeah, no, I'm-I'm... I'm ready.
I'm almost out the door.
Okay. Yeah.
- I'll see you soon.
- Marketa.
- Marketa, come on.
- I'll see you soon.
Come on.
[indistinct chatter]
[whispers]:
Come, come, come.
[door closes]
Are you sure no one's coming?
Oh, I'm sure. Don't worry.
Nobody comes here
during the weekend.
[laughing]
Patricia's isn't here.
SUSIE:
Try looking for Olga's.
SARA:
Olga...
She's not here.
I just need a number.
For her parents or someone
who can tell me for sure
she is or isn't in Berlin.
Hmm. How odd.
[rummaging]
[distant laughter]
[whispers]:
1961.
[distant laughter continues]
1955.
1949.
It's bizarre.
[woman humming quietly]
WOMAN: Here, kitty, kitty,
kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty...
[laughter]
[quiet, indistinct chatter]
[laughter continues]
[raucous laughter]
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty,
kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty...
[laughter continues]
There's nothing.
Come on.
- [door opens]
- [chuckles]
[quiet chatter, laughter]
WOMAN:
Sit down.
BLANC:
This morning,
we turn our instincts inward.
Miss Millius, Miss Mandel,
can you close the mirrors,
please?
Miss Marks, no music.
I want to start work
on a new piece.
A piece about rebirths.
The inevitable pull
that they exert
and our efforts to escape them.
We'll learn it now, but, Susie,
you will improvise freely
at its heart.
I'm interested
in your instincts here.
The piece will be called
Weider OÖffnen.
Open Again.
Allez.
[breathing heavily]
- One, two, three, four.
- [snapping fingers to beat]
One, two,
three, four.
One, two, three, four.
One, two,
three, four.
One, two, three, four.
One, two,
three, four.
[grunts, pants]
One, two, three, four.
One, two,
three, four.
One, two, three, four.
One...
[muffled]:
...two, three, four.
- One, two, three, four.
- [raspy breathing]
One, two, three, four.
- [gasping]
- One, two, three, four.
One, two,
three, four.
One, two, three, four.
One, two,
three, four.
One, two, three, four.
One...
[raspy breathing]
[panting]
SUSIE:
Did something happen?
- Hmm?
- To you, during it?
N-No.
Did you... did you...
Did you feel something there?
Someone?
Or just something.
What made you say that?
I don't know.
- Am I confusing you?
- [chuckling]
No, it's, um...
It's odd. It's the...
It's the sort of thing
Patricia would say.
It's bizarre.
Come on.
Let's get changed,
or Sonia will leave without us.
I've got a dress you can wear.
Double caposhi.
[singing in German]
[laughter, excited chatter]
♪ ♪
WOMAN:
Susie!
[indistinct chatter
and laughter]
Oh, Susie!
[indistinct chatter
and laughter]
[panting]
[shuddering breaths]
[gasps softly]
[object clatters]
[distorted, echoing breaths]
[pants, grunts]
[gasping]
[distorted voices]
[gasps softly]
SARA [whispers]:
Is it true?
[exhales]
[screams]
- [panting, gasping]
- [screaming]
[distorted, muffled chatter]
[distorted shout]
[distorted, gruff groan]
[distorted screams
and echoing voices]
[panting]
[wheezing]
SARA [echoing]:
Is it true?
[indistinct whispering]
I know who I am!
[dancers murmuring quietly]
- [gasps]
- It's all right.
It's okay.
Is she all right?
It's just a nightmare.
The Markos Company special.
I'm surprised
it took this long.
Hey, let me know
if she needs a Valium.
[groans]
[laughter]
She's right. I dreamt
of hairballs in toilets
for three weeks before I got
a decent night of sleep here.
Move over.
SUSIE: I've only ever slept
in bed with my sister.
SARA:
We're sisters now.
♪ ♪
[bubbling]
[teakettle whistling]
[gasps quietly]
♪ ♪
WOMAN:
Herr Klemperer?
[typewriter clacking
and dinging]
WOMAN:
And one, and two, and three.
And one, and two,
and three.
And one, and two, and three.
And one, and two,
and three.
One, and two, and three.
And one, and two, and three.
And one, and two,
and three.
And one, and two, and three.
That's-that's okay.
[indistinct conversations]
Do you want to do the jumps?
Okay.
And...
one, and two, and three.
And one, and two, and three.
No.
Elbows higher.
All right, one moment.
Susie, part of the jump
is muscle,
and that will develop
as you condition,
but you seem to have
an aversion to them,
and I don't quite see why.
Are you so happy
to be stuck to the earth?
[chuckles quietly]
There's a yield
before the push,
which I don't think
you're quite understanding.
Caroline. Could you come and do
a series for us, please?
Thank you.
And now you.
♪ ♪
[panting]
What I really want
is to be on...
on the floor right now, anyway.
[chuckling]:
Well, of course.
That's because you're mistaking
physical weakness
with artistic preference.
And because you're tired.
- [chuckles]
- SUSIE: At this point,
the jumps are opposing
the pull of the structure,
but...
it's soon for that,
don't you think?
[panting]
The floor work is... is keeping
the other dancers pushed down.
So this...
this could echo that...
[panting]
...on-on a slightly higher
point of elevation.
If I stay close
to the ground now
and go straight into the jumps
where you have them later,
then that's more to the point.
The resistance is more...
emphatic.
Right?
I don't know how aware you are
of what times we lived through
here 40 years ago.
Out of which
this piece was made.
We learned at great cost
through those years
the value of the balance
of things.
Every arrow that flies
feels the pull of the earth,
but we must aim upwards.
We need to get you in the air.
[quiet, indistinct chatter]
[dancers gasping, murmuring]
Leave her, leave her,
leave her, leave her, leave...
[choking, shuddering]
[gasping]
[sobbing]
Ja?
[chuckles softly]
WOMAN:
She hit her head hard.
I heard it. I hope...
I am... I'm looking for
a dancer from your company.
Who are you looking for?
You are Sara.
Yes.
May I help you?
I am a friend from Patricia.
SARA: I don't know what
to make of any of this.
I know the kind of thing
she was involved with,
but I can't see how any of this
could be happening
inside the company.
Well, she describes...
something like
a revolutionary organization
in a crisis of leadership.
With Markos very ill...
I live there.
I have friends there.
I don't see any evidence
of this at all.
No one has ever approached me
or any of the other girls,
as far as I know.
Read this.
What is this?
This is Patricia's diary.
Mother Markos.
Mother Meinhof.
The dance rehearsal.
Political action.
These two areas
in Patricia's life
were of equal importance.
This is how
transference happens,
how delusion is made.
Delusion, Sara,
is a lie that tells a truth.
- This says "witches."
- Mmm.
Maybe Patricia's fantasies
about witches,
they are her way of processing
some other form of intrigue.
The company's a family.
There's a lot of love there.
Love and manipulation--
they... they share houses
very often.
They are frequent bedfellows.
Sorry, I don't see this.
Eat.
[dishes clattering nearby]
[quiet chatter]
Only...
maybe the police,
they missed something.
And Patricia,
she did spoke of...
whole hidden areas
of the building.
Actual rooms that are secret.
I don't want
to be disrespectful--
I don't--
but you're asking me,
- and I'm telling you...
- Oh, please.
It's a dance company.
We're not talking
about anything else.
Sara.
Please, only look closer.
Thank you for caring
for Patricia,
but I hope
you don't come again.
[panting quietly]
[door opens]
[door closes]
- Good night.
WOMAN:
Sara, hurry up.
I'm tired. I need the bathroom.
- Good night, Doll.
- Good night.
[music playing,
laughter in distance]
WOMAN:
She hasn't come back yet?
- Maybe she's seeing somebody.
- [laughter]
[indistinct chatter, laughter]
BLANC:
Part of the issue always
is not being able
to see your body in space.
One angle in one mirror
or on film is not enough.
Movement is never mute.
It is a language.
It's a series
of energetic shapes...
- [door opens]
- ...written in the air
like words forming sentences.
Like poems.
Like prayers.
Spells?
When you jump,
it's not the height
but the space beneath you
that matters.
Every leap into the air
must be a coup de foudre.
I don't understand.
A strike of lightning.
A bolt of love, in fact.
That's beautiful.
There are two things
that dance can never be again:
beautiful and cheerful.
Today, we need
to break the nose
of every beautiful thing.
And if you're going
to be a dancer,
you must learn French.
When you dance
the dance of another,
you make yourself
in the image of its creator.
You empty yourself
so that her work can live
within you.
Do you understand?
Yeah.
You're in a company now.
You have to find
your right place.
You have to decide--
what is it you want to be
for this company?
Is it the head?
The spine?
The sex?
The heart?
The hands.
I want to be
this company's hands.
♪ ♪
- [panting]
- Higher.
Higher. Higher.
- [panting continues]
- Higher.
Higher! Higher.
- [grunting, panting]
- Higher.
Higher, higher, higher.
Higher.
Higher. Higher.
Higher. Higher. Higher.
Sometimes I only need
to be told twice.
[chuckles softly]
[all screaming]
[frantic chatter in German]
[distant clattering, footsteps]
[distant footsteps,
muffled chatter]
[distant, muffled chatter]
[footsteps]
[whispering]:
33, 34, 35, 36,
37, 38, 39,
40, 41.
[distant whimper]
57, 58, 59,
60, 61, 62, 63.
65, 64, 63, 62.
23, 22, 21.
Ten, nine, eight,
seven, six.
Two, one.
[firm tap]
[hollow thud]
[clunking]
♪ ♪
[rattling]
[creaking]
♪ ♪
[gasps softly]
[quiet creaking]
[shout, groan nearby]
[yelling nearby]
- [chanting]
- WOMAN: Come with me! Quickly!
[screaming]
[screaming continues, muffled]
- [door opens and closes]
- [rhythmic grunting]
[grunting continues]
KLEMPERER:
Patricia wrote about
"Three Mothers" lost in time,
predating all Christian
invention.
Pre-God. Pre-Devil.
Mother Tenebrarum,
Mother Lachrymarum
and Mother Suspiriorum.
Darkness, Tears and Sighs.
I saw images of that
last night.
In porcelain,
these very fine things.
You can tell they have money.
Patricia said that, uh, Markos
claims to be one of the Three.
But there is dissent
amongst them.
She wrote about "Markosites"
and "Blancites."
In-Internal division.
Madame Blanc's
involved in this?
Do they believe
they're witches?
You can give someone
your delusion, Sara.
That's religion.
That was the Reich.
The Reich had these things.
Insignia.
Esoteric ritual.
These "Mothers," yeah,
they could be
code names for founding members
with metaphoric histories.
I don't know.
But I do know you are living
with dangerous people.
- Patricia could still be in...
- [door closes]
...in there.
[grunts]
- They could be holding her.
- [door opens and closes]
In the building.
Well, I cannot promise
that the authorities
will come back to, uh,
inspect a cabinet
full of porcelain
after all that has happened.
But we can try.
And in the meantime, you must,
uh, take care of yourself.
Perhaps you should leave.
You have somewhere you can go?
I'll figure it out.
And I think you should
put this back.
Or better still,
you leave it here.
Not good for them
to know that you have it.
[rattling]
♪ ♪
[dogs barking, distant chatter]
[whistles blowing in distance]
- [whistling]
- [shouting in German]
[dog barking]
[distant siren blaring]
[quiet chatter]
[speaking German]
[takes deep breath]
[door opens]
[quiet, echoing wheezing]
[wheezing continues]
PRIEST:
Is anyone among you sick?
Let him call for the elders
of the church;
and let them pray over him,
anointing him with oil
in the name of the Lord.
And the prayer of faith
shall save him that is sick,
and the Lord
shall raise him up;
and if he has committed sins...
[whispers]:
My daughter.
...they shall be forgiven him.
My last one.
She's my sin.
She's what I smeared
on the world.
[wheezing]
[crying]
You're making some kind
of deal with them.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
[Sara gasping]
SARA:
How can you know
what they're going
to ask you in return?
Sara, whatever you have
in your mind,
- nothing is wrong.
- [Sara shudders]
You just haven't
seen the bill yet.
Nothing's wrong.
♪ ♪
[quiet, indistinct chatter]
What's the matter with you?
Huh?
You don't be so afraid
about the white, Susie.
They need to see you
from the very back row.
Where is Sara?
She came early in the morning,
did her makeup and left.
[quiet chatter in German]
[chorus vocalizing]
[chorus singing in German]
[quiet, indistinct chatter]
[bell ringing]
MILLIUS:
Girls!
- [claps]
- Vier minuten!
Four minutes!
- [clapping]
Tak, tak.
[quiet chatter continues]
[door creaking open]
[panting]
[quiet chatter]
[dancers whispering
indistinctly]
SARA:
Is it true?
PATRICIA [whispers]:
Sara.
Patricia.
Patricia. Patricia.
- I knew it.
- They'll kill him.
I'm sorry it took me so long.
I'm so sorry.
What did they do to you?
[raspy]:
I wake up here every day.
It's all over now.
I'll get you out.
The performance
is starting upstairs.
Everyone will be looking
the other way.
Get up. Get up.
Patricia!
- Patricia, get up.
- I'm trying.
Get up.
[screams]
[screams] Get it off of me!
Sara!
- [door slams shut]
- [running footsteps]
[wheezing]
- [bell ringing]
- [quiet chatter]
[ringing stops]
[dancers whispering
indistinctly]
[chanting]:
Markos! Markos! Markos! Markos!
[quiet chatter]
[whispers]:
Marketa.
Where is Sara?
Sara?
I don't know.
- Is she upstairs?
- No. I looked.
TANNER: Just dance
as if she's with you.
[grunting, panting]
[wheezing nearby]
PATRICIA [raspy]:
Sara!
[wheezing continues]
[Sara gasping]
TANNER [whispers]:
Go!
[speaking German]
[gasping]
[distant squealing]
[panting]
[shuddering breaths]
♪ ♪
[rapid panting]
[agonized screaming]
♪ ♪
[grunting, gasping]
[screams]
[gasping]
[rhythmic breathing]
[grunts, exhales]
[screaming]
[whimpering]
[agonized scream]
[door opens]
No.
- No.
- Sara, lie still.
- No! [gasping]
- Sara.
Please. Please...
[screams]
No! No!
♪ ♪
[rhythmic breathing]
[rhythmic breathing continues]
♪ ♪
[rhythmic grunting]
[rhythmic breathing
and grunting]
♪ ♪
[rhythmic grunting]
[rhythmic breathing continues]
[panting]
[rhythmic grunting]
[screaming]
- [music stops]
- [people gasping]
[screaming]
Sara!
[Sara panting, wheezing]
[quiet chatter]
[Sara screaming]
[speaks German]
[wheezing, gasping]
[chatter in German]
[Sara continues wheezing
and gasping]
[shuddering breaths]
- [Sara moaning in pain]
- [chatter in German]
- [cracking]
- Good.
- [Sara screams]
- Good. That's good.
[Sara continues wheezing
and gasping]
[gasping quietly]
♪ ♪
- [gasps]
- [wind whistling]
[voices screaming,
whispering indistinctly]
[screaming and whispering stop]
[door opens]
SUSIE [telepathically]:
I'm sorry I went off book.
BLANC [telepathically]:
This can't happen again.
You're only just starting
to understand, Susie.
We brought Sara back upstairs
to try to complete
the performance in time,
but then you derailed it.
SUSIE:
Did I hurt those people?
BLANC:
Not this time.
They saw a dance.
That's all.
SUSIE:
It's all a mess, isn't it?
The one out there.
[spoken aloud]:
The one in here.
The one that's coming.
Why is everyone
so ready to think
the worst is over?
[telepathically]: I could
explain everything to you.
I think it would be wrong,
though.
[gasps quietly]
♪ ♪
One, two, three, four.
- One, two, three, four.
- [panting]
One, two, three, four.
- One, two, three, four.
- ♪ Open again ♪
One, two, three, four.
One, two,
three, four.
♪ We breathe again ♪
♪ Upon the other shore ♪
♪ Washed out ♪
♪ We live again ♪
♪ We're demons, all of us ♪
♪ We're open ♪
♪ Just say it ♪
♪ Just say the magic words. ♪
♪ ♪
Herr Doktor.
[laughter, indistinct chatter]
[cheering, applause,
indistinct chatter]
[speaking French]
[panting]
[grunting]
♪ ♪
[grunts]
[quiet, indistinct chatter]
[waiter speaking French]
[song playing in French]
[festive shouting, laughter]
[festive chatter]
[song continues playing
in French]
[panting quietly]
♪ ♪
[chuckling]
[Anke whimpers]
♪ ♪
[laughter]
[singing in German]
[singing continues]
[laughter]
[singing and laughter fade]
♪ ♪
[panting quietly]
[gasping]
[shrieking]
[growling, shrieking]
[shrieking laughter]
[echoing footsteps]
[distorted, distant screams]
♪ ♪
[heavy breathing]
[distorted, distant screams
continue]
♪ ♪
[rhythmic breathing]
[wheezing, rhythmic breathing]
[whimpering]
[sobbing, moaning]
[gasping]
[pained whimpering]
[rhythmic breathing continues]
[Klemperer whimpering]
[intense, rhythmic
breathing and moaning]
I'm ready, Madame.
[cackling]
[rhythmic breathing continues]
[choral singing]
[sobbing]
You look afraid.
[laughs]
She's afraid for you.
[rhythmic breathing
and grunting]
[choral singing continues]
[hissing, chattering]
[straining, raspy]:
There will be nothing of you
left inside.
Only space for me.
I came here for this.
[rhythmic grunting
and breathing continue]
You've all waited long enough.
Ah!
It is happening.
It is happening!
[cackling]
[choral singing continues]
[rhythmic grunting
and moaning continue]
[choral singing continues]
[shrieks]
Do you come here willingly?
Hmm?
Huh?
You must have no doubts, Susie.
If you do, I can take you back.
I can take all of this
from your head.
You can forget everything.
[wheezing laughter]
I want this to be pure.
[straining, raspy]:
We all know what you want.
[straining grunt]
This isn't vanity.
This isn't...
art!
There is something wrong here.
Can you not feel it?
This is not right.
We have to stop this now.
We have been on
two sides of this
for too long now.
MATRONS [chanting]:
Markos! Markos! Markos!
Markos! Markos!
- Markos! Markos!
- [shrieking]
Markos! Markos! Markos!
Markos! Markos!
[squishing, crunching]
[wheezing]
[deep, gasping breaths]
If you accept me,
you must put down
the woman who bore you.
Think of that false mother now.
[labored breathing]
- [wheezing]
- MARKOS: Reject her.
Expel her.
You have the only mother
you need here.
Death to any other mother.
Say it.
[screams]
Death to any other mother.
[matrons shrieking]
[whimpering]
[shrieking continues]
[taking deep breaths]
Who are you?
For whom were you anointed?
Which of the Three Mothers?
Mother...
[wheezing, whimpering]
Mother Suspiriorum.
I am she.
[wheezing, whimpering]
[gasping]
[choking, gasping]
[matrons shrieking]
[deep growl]
[shrieking continues]
Markos.
[crunching, squishing]
[shrieking continues]
Markos!
[panting]
[shrieking]
[moans softly]
[groaning]
[sobbing]
[gasping, sobbing]
[panting]
Markos!
Markos.
[panting]
[echoing]:
Death to any other mother.
Markos.
♪ ♪
Markos!
♪ Come under my wings ♪
♪ Little bird ♪
♪ Come under ♪
Markos!
♪ My wings ♪
♪ Little bird ♪
♪ Come under my wings... ♪
Markos!
♪ Unmade ♪
♪ I swear
that there's nothing ♪
♪ Up my sleeve ♪
[distorted voices
hissing and screaming]
♪ Bring it back again ♪
[voices growing louder]
♪ I swear there's nothing... ♪
[whispering]:
I am the Mother.
[distorted voices screaming
and groaning]
♪ ♪
What do you ask?
To die.
♪ Broken pieces ♪
PATRICIA:
Mother.
Mother, we're so tired.
♪ Unmade ♪
[sobbing, moaning]
What do you ask?
To die.
I want to die.
♪ I swear there's nothing... ♪
Sweet girl.
What do you ask?
Die.
♪ Come under my wings ♪
- ♪ Under my wings. ♪
- SUSIE: Yes.
Dance. Dance.
Keep dancing.
It's beautiful.
[echoing deep breaths]
[echoing gasps]
[gasping]
[quiet chatter in German]
Yeah. Okay.
Good. Good.
[sighs]
[singing in German]
[gasping, panting]
[grunting]
[panting]
[gasping, whimpering]
[frightened moaning]
[whimpering]
[birds cawing]
[panting]
- [yawns]
- My God, what a night.
I definitely drank
too much wine.
[speaking French]
- Bonjour.
[chatter continues in French]
- Guten Morgen.
- Morning.
Good morning.
- [grunting]
- [humming a tune]
[whimpering]
[gasping weakly]
[gasps, grunts]
[quiet chatter in distance]
[quiet, shuddering breaths]
♪ ♪
[door opens]
I regret what my daughters
did to you.
I wasn't in a position
to prevent it.
I believe you deserve
to know the truth.
Your wife did try
to make it south
to Teplice.
She was apprehended
by border guards
in the woods
just outside of Glashuütte.
She was then taken
to Theresienstadt camp.
She lived there for 20 days.
On the 11th of November, 1943,
the commandant of the camp,
a man named Burger...
...ordered all 40,000
detained there
stand outside in the cold
for a census.
Hours and hours passed.
Some hundreds died of exposure.
Your wife had two women
with her as she died.
Women she had befriended,
who made her feel
that she was not alone.
Her final thoughts...
were of a birthday
when you took her
to a concert as a surprise.
Chopin and Brahms.
[whimpering, sobbing]
It was the first time
you held her hand.
She was cold when she died.
But she wasn't afraid.
She was thinking only of you.
[Klemperer sobbing softly]
Of Anke Meier...
...of Patricia Hingle...
...of Sara Simms...
...of Susanna Bannion,
of all the women
of your undoing...
...every memory will vanish.
They will melt away in the sun
and be gone.
[gasping, choking]
[dish shatters]
- Herr Doktor.
- [gasping continues]
Herr Doktor.
[shuddering]
[taking deep breaths]
- Ja?
- Ja.
[train approaching]
[humming a tune]
[quiet, indistinct chatter]
[speaking German]
[young girl singing in German]
[chatter continues in German]
♪ ♪
♪ This is what I was thinking ♪
♪ About our bodies ♪
♪ What they mean ♪
♪ For our salvation ♪
♪ Only the clothes that ♪
♪ We stand up in ♪
♪ Just the ground ♪
♪ On which we stand ♪
♪ Is the darkness ♪
♪ Ours to take? ♪
♪ Bathed in lightning ♪
♪ Bathed in heat ♪
♪ All is well ♪
♪ As long as we keep spinning ♪
♪ Here now ♪
♪ Dancing behind the wall ♪
♪ Hear the old songs ♪
♪ And laughter within ♪
♪ All forgiven ♪
♪ Always or never be true ♪
♪ When I arrive, will ♪
♪ You come and find me? ♪
♪ In a crowd ♪
♪ Be one of them ♪
♪ Mother wants us ♪
♪ Right beside her ♪
♪ No tomorrows ♪
♪ At peace. ♪
♪ ♪