(Woman) Hey, Rose.
Hey, Dorothy.
(Shuffling)
(Thump and groan)
I'm gonna go over there.
We're waitin'.
(Birds)
Alvin.
Alvin Straight!
Rose left a couple of hours ago.
Did you hear me hollerin' for
Rose? I wasn't lookin' for Rose.
- I haven't seen Alvin today.
- Did I ask?
Straight, you're late!
(Mutters)
Alvin!
- Come in, Bud.
- What the... Alvin?!
(Door creaks)
Where the hell are you?
I can't see a thing.
Over here, Bud. Watch your step.
What the hell's going on?
What are you doin'
layin' on the floor? You nuts?
Supposed to be down
at Davmar's one hour ago.
What's going on?
Oh, my God!
(Alvin) Hey, Dorothy.
What's the number for 911?
- No, Dorothy.
- What you doin'?
I'll call the bar
and tell 'em we're not comin'.
Are you crazy?
We have a stricken man here.
Are you stricken, Alvin?
Put the phone down!
Dad, what's all the yellin'?
Wh-what... uh,
have you done to my dad?
Oh, for cry eye!
Dad?
Are you OK, Dad?
I just need a little help
gettin' up, honey.
(Car rattles)
(Engine revs severely)
(Bumps)
I'm goin' to Davmar's.
I'll be right back.
OK, Bud.
I'm not goin'.
Dad.
You promised me, Dad.
OK, Mr Straight,
put this robe on.
Just bring me the doctor.
(Door opens and closes)
(Rose stammers) You like birds.
I build... uh, birdhouses...
uh, for bluebirds.
Oh, that's nice.
Yeah, it's Pete... uh,
Pete sells my...
uh, birdhouses...
at the Ace Hardware.
- I'll look for them next time.
- Yeah?
No operation.
This morning you fall and can't
get up, that's your hips, Alvin.
And you'll need a walker now.
No walker.
Fine, a second cane, then.
You say you're having
trouble seeing.
That could be
a diabetes-related problem.
I'd like to run some tests.
No tests and no X-rays.
Well, I see and hear
that you smoke.
My guess is you're in the early
stages of emphysema.
And Alvin,
you have circulation problems
and I'm worried
about your diet.
If you don't
make some changes quickly,
there will be
some serious consequences.
It... has a... a red roof.
Another pretty one, Rose.
I want to... uh,
paint the... uh, next one blue.
That's a good idea.
What... uh, did the doctor say?
He said
I was gonna live to be 100.
I think I'll go
and mow the lawn.
Uh, I can... uh,
cut it for you, Dad.
I got it, sweetheart.
(Tries ignition again)
God darn!
No, we'll...
we won't be mowin' today.
Storm's comin' in.
Yeah.
(Thunderclap)
I love a lightnin' storm.
Uh, me too, Dad.
(Phone)
(Rose) Hello?
This is... is Rose.
Yeah... Yeah... Uh-huh.
Oh, no...
When?
OK... right... right...
I'll tell him.
Yeah... OK... Bye.
Uh, that was... Bobby.
Uncle Lyle... had a...
...a stroke.
(Severe thunderclap)
Dad?
No, Bobby,
he... he didn't say much.
Uh, they've both...
uh, been so...
uh, stubborn.
No, no,
it was longer, I remember.
It was... uh, July, uh, 7th,
19... 88, uh, Bobby.
I always... remember the dates.
Yeah.
I don't know... uh,
what he'll do.
(Alvin) Rose, darlin'?
Rose?
I'm gonna go back on the road.
I've gotta go see Lyle.
But, Dad...
How are you?
Well, I... haven't quite
got that figured yet.
One, your eyes are bad.
That's why you don't...
uh, drive your car.
Uh, two, Uncle Lyle...
uh, lives in... uh, Wisconsin,
which is... uh, 317 miles away.
You would have to... uh,
stay all night... in Des Moines.
Then there's no...
uh, bus... to Zion.
Three, your... uh, hips are bad.
You can hardly... uh, stand...
for two minutes... And
when you... uh, do stand up...
this... is the sound you make...
when you... stand.
(Moans)
Uh, four, uh,
you are... uh, 73 years old...
You were... uh, born
when, uh, Calvin... uh, Coolidge
was president... of America.
Uh, you are...
uh, 73 years old, Dad.
And... I cannot drive you there.
Rose, darlin', I'm not dead yet.
Uh, what are we...
uh, building, Dad?
Havin' a party?
Oh, jeez...
I love... uh, parties.
Oh, me too.
And so... where's it at?
Where's what at?
Your... uh, party.
I'm not havin' a party.
I thought
YOU were havin' a party.
I am?
Well, yeah.
Look at all that Braunschweiger.
Oh, yeah,
it's a lot of Braunschweiger.
It's... uh, for my dad,
uh, for his... his trip.
Uh, my dad...
he's going to... uh, Wisconsin.
I... asked him how
he's... uh, going to get there...
Uh... but he...
uh, won't say nothing.
Wisconsin?
That is a real party state.
Yeah.
I... uh, hate...
uh, Braun... uh... schweiger.
Yeah.
Alvin, you've got three
five-gallon cans there.
15 gallons of gas.
What do you need
so much gas for, Alvin?
Sig, you're one nosey
son of a gun.
(Man sniggers)
You got that right.
- I wanna buy that.
- What?
The grabber.
Oh, jeez, Alvin.
- That's MY grabber, Alvin.
- Well?
Oh, jeez, Alvin. I don't...
I... I do have two of them...
I think five dollars is right.
That's a darn good grabber,
Alvin.
- I... I...
- Well?
They're hard to come by, Alvin.
It's gonna take me two months
to get another one on order.
Jeez, Alvin, ten dollars.
Ring her up.
(Sighs)
What do you need
that grabber for, Alvin?
Grabbin'.
(Motor starts)
Oh, jeez, Dad.
(Rumbling)
Listen to that
old grain elevator.
It's... uh, harvest time.
Uh, that... uh, trailer is too
h-heavy for... for that.
It's a lawn mower.
You're going to...
...drive a... a lawn mower
to another state?
Rosie, I've...
I've gotta go see Lyle.
And I... I've gotta make
this trip on my own.
I know you understand.
I guess so.
Look up at the sky, Rosie.
The sky is sure full
of stars tonight.
Crimenetto, it's Alvin
and he's driving his lawn mower.
Alvin! What are you settin' out
to do here?
For cry eye, Alvin!
Alvin, you're gonna get blown
right off the road,
that's what I'm afraid!
He'll never make it
past The Grotto.
(Truck horn)
(Crickets)
(Ignition turns over)
(Turns over a second time)
(Turns over again and dies)
(Vehicle approaching)
I'm havin'
a little engine trouble.
What the heck is that
you're driving there?
It's a Rehds. Could you
give me a lift into town?
Yeah, to The Grotto. This
is the Sun Ray Tour. Get in.
- I'll get you help there.
- I'd appreciate that.
(Chattering from bus)
My Edward loved
his riding mower.
Hey, come here, hurry. Hurry up.
Poor Alvin.
So the man... in a... pick-up,
he brought my dad back.
Ohh... mm, I must've been
at the beauty shop.
What kinda pick-up?
(Door creaks)
A Ford.
But what's your dad doin'
with that gun?
I don't know.
(Fires)
(Fires again)
I gave you that old Rehds
last time, right?
That you did.
- You tradin' in that Rehds now?
- No, I don't believe I will.
Pete told me you used that rider
in a real interestin' way.
- You still plannin' to do that?
- Yeah, Tom.
I know not to talk you out of
somethin' you set your mind to,
but Alvin, you've always
struck me as smart.
Well, that's appreciated.
Until now.
(Both laugh)
(Alvin) What year?
(Salesman) '66.
Kohler engine.
We've used it for parts
but I always replace them.
The guts are good.
It's got the old transmission.
Nothing fancy.
- Is it a good machine?
- It's good.
Tom, I got $325.
That's a fact.
Sounds good to me, Alvin.
Let's go settle up with Alice.
One more thing,
sometime you can find out
about these old machines,
if you know who run 'em.
- Do you know who owned it?
- You bet... Me.
All right.
(Fire roaring
and crickets rattling)
(Honks horn)
(Crickets)
(Fire crackling)
I couldn't get a ride.
Are you hungry?
Whaddaya got?
Weeners.
Weeners?
Weeners. Wanna try one?
Here's a good stick for you.
What a hunk ofjunk.
Eat your dinner, missy.
So... how long you been
out on the road?
Well, I been travellin'
most of my life.
Where you from?
Laurens.
Got a wife back there? Kids?
My wife, Francis delivered
14 babies. Seven of 'em made it.
My daughter,
Rose lives with me.
Francis died in '81.
Where's your family?
Are you runnin' away?
(Sighs softly)
How far along are ya?
Five months.
(Owl hoots)
Well, I'm headin'
to see my brother Lyle.
Huh?
I said I'm goin' to see
my brother Lyle in Mount Zion.
- Where's that?
- Wisconsin.
- Oh...
- Just across the state line.
Cheddar Heads.
(Both chuckle)
Aren't those the dumbest things
you ever seen somebody
stick on their head?
I hear that's
a real party place - Wisconsin.
Guess I'll never
get to find out.
There's a blanket
in the trailer.
Why don't you go get it?
My family hates me.
They'll really hate me
when they find out.
You didn't tell 'em?
No. No one knows.
Not even my boyfriend.
Well, they may be mad,
but I don't think they're
mad enough to wanna lose you
or your little problem.
I don't know about that.
Well, of course, neither do I,
but a warm bed and a roof
sounds a might better
than eatin' a hot dog on a stick
with an old geezer that's
travellin' on a lawn mower.
My daughter Rose is...
Some people call her
a little bit slow but she's not.
She's got a mind
like a bear trap for facts.
She keeps everything
organised around the house.
She was a real good mom.
She had four kids.
One night, somebody else
was watchin' the kids
and there was a fire.
Her second boy
got burned real bad.
Rose had nothin'
to do with it but, ah...
...on account of the way Rose is,
the State figured
she wasn't competent
to take care of them kids
and they took 'em all
away from her.
There isn't a day goes by that
she don't pine for them kids.
(Fire crackling)
When my kids were real little,
I used to play a game with 'em.
I'd give each one
of 'em a stick and -
one for each one of 'em -
then I'd say "you break that."
'Course they could, real easy.
Then I'd say "tie them sticks in
a bundle and try to break that".
'Course they couldn't.
Then I'd say "that bundle...
...that's family."
Why don't you sleep
in the trailer?
This chair's just fine
for me tonight.
No, I'll be fine
sleepin' out here.
Lookin' at the stars
helps me think.
Well...
Thank you.
(Birds)
(Hum of lawn mower)
(Distant thunder)
(Big thunderclap)
Woo!
What the?
What the hell?
Hey, how're you doin'?
Doin' good.
(Hum of lawn mower)
(Cheers and applause)
Hey, Irene.
You don't think about
gettin' old when you're young.
You shouldn't.
Must be something good
about gettin' old.
Well, I can't imagine anything
good about being blind and lame
at the same time, but... still
at my age, I've seen about all
that life has to dish out.
I know to separate the wheat
from the chaff and let
the small stuff fall away.
Let's go, man.
So, ah... what's the worst part
about being old, Alvin?
The worst part of being old is
rememberin' when you was young.
(Hum of lawn mower)
(Roar of big engines)
(Car horn)
(Car skids)
(Crash)
(Motor dies)
(Wind whistles)
Can I help you, lady?
No, you can't help me.
No one can help me.
I've tried driving with my
lights on, sounding my horn!
I scream, I roll the window down
and bang on the door
and play Public Enemy real loud!
I've prayed to St Francis
of Assisi, St Christopher too!
What the heck! I've tried
everything and still every week
I hit at least one deer!
I have hit 13 deer in seven
weeks driving down this road!
And I HAVE to drive
down this road every day,
40 miles to work and back.
I HAVE to drive to work
and I HAVE to drive home!
Where do they come from?
Oh... he's dead.
And I LOVE deer.
(Car screams away)
Well, they sure picked the right
place to practise a burn on.
(Hums "Taps")
(Man) That Rumelthanger place
was an eyesore.
(Motor clicks)
(Chugging)
(Bigger click)
What do you suppose?
(Woman) Is that a lawn mower?
(Thundering motor)
(Breathes deeply)
(Man) Mister, you OK?
Jeez, mister, you're lucky
she didn't roll on you.
I guess the belt broke.
(Man) I wouldn't be surprised.
You don't have brakes
on that trailer, right?
I worked for John Deere
for 30 years,
you shouldn't be hauling a rig
behind a mower.
At least not down
a hill like that.
I'm Danny Riordan.
Alvin Straight.
Alvin, let's get you
and this rig off the road
and see what the damage is.
Let's get this off the road.
Sure you're OK?
(Birds)
OK.
You OK? Everything all right?
I'm going back to the exercise.
Thanks. Appreciate it.
(Sighs)
Well... let's
take a look at this mower.
- This is what '65, '66?
- '66.
Well... tell you right now,
Alvin,
you won't be going
anywhere tonight.
Aside from your, ah,
drive belt being busted,
you got transmission problems.
- Where you headed?
- Mount Zion.
Mount Zion, Wisconsin?
Past Prairie du Chien?
That's 60 more miles of hills.
That's across the Mississippi.
(Danny)
What's in Mount Zion, Alvin?
My brother lives there.
- Why didn't you take your car?
- I'm not licensed.
- (Woman) Couldn't he visit?
- He's had a bad stroke.
Where are you coming from?
Back a piece.
(Danny) West Union?
- Hawkeye?
- Nope.
Well, not New Hampton?
You haven't come that far.
You've come a long ways,
haven't you?
Yeah, I have. Laurens, Iowa.
(Woman) Laurens?!
That's west of The Grotto. How
long have you been on the road?
What's the date?
October eighth.
Five weeks. I left Laurens
on the fifth of September.
You been bunkin' in that?
That's my rollin' home.
Where you been settin' up camp?
In the fields. I pull off.
I don't travel at night.
Haven't you been scared,
being alone?
There are weird people
everywhere.
Well, ma'am, I fought
in the trenches in World War II.
Why should I be scared
of an Iowa cornfield?
Well, um...
till we get
this mower fixed...
why don't you... ah,
bivouac in our yard here?
There's a bathroom
in the garage you can use.
Well, that's
awful generous of you
and I'm sure my machine here
is agreeable to that too.
Sure wanna thank you folks
for helping me today.
There's a lot of rain forecast.
Sure don't want to get stuck
in that trailer.
I... I do a little woodwork.
I thought you'd like a few fish.
My daughter does woodwork.
She makes birdhouses.
(Both) Oh, that's nice.
- You finished there?
- I believe I am.
(Fly buzzing)
- I'm in need of a phone.
- Sure. Come in.
I wanna tell my daughter
about my recent travels.
Sure. Come in.
If it's all the same with you,
do you have a cordless phone?
- Door's wide open, come...
- I can call from out here.
Here you go. You're welcome
to sit in the kitchen.
We can leave, if you're
lookin' for privacy.
Out here's fine.
Is the area code still 712 here?
No, Alvin.
That hill rolled you into 319.
You need to dial one
and your area code.
712, thank you.
'Hello? '
Rose?
Dad? Dad...
Uh, I'm... so glad to hear you.
It's gonna cost him a bundle
to fix that mower.
I don't think
he's got that kinda money.
I wouldn't drive
that thing to Excelsior.
It's a lawn mower,
for God's sake.
Uh, your social security cheque?
Ah... it's here, Dad.
Rose, can you send me my cheque?
Uh, yeah.
He's damn lucky
he made it down that hill.
- He could've died easily.
- Yeah.
He's none too strong.
See how he has to walk
with the canes?
OK, Dad.
(Chuckles)
I... I...
OK, OK, Dad, OK.
I... I have a pencil, Dad.
The hills just get worse
the closer you get
to the Mississippi.
Go ahead and drive him, honey.
Mount Zion can't
be half a day. It's fine.
You're a good man,
Danny Riordan.
And that's why I married you,
despite what my mother said.
Now, shoo!
Dad?
I miss you, Dad.
I love you, Rosie.
'I love you too, Dad.'
Uh, bye, Dad.
Bye... Dad.
(Tone)
Ahem.
(Door creaks)
(Footsteps)
What are you cookin'
there, Alvin?
Oh, I'm makin'
my Mexican coffee.
Ah. Mind if I join you?
Get you a chair...
that iron one there.
You'll be a guest
in your own back yard.
Amm, I talked to the Olsen
twins, and, ah... they estimate
it'll cost around 250 dollars
to get your mower fixed.
Well, that's twice
what it oughta be,
I guess it's cos
they're twins, huh?
(Both laugh)
I'd be happy to drive you the
rest of the way to Mount Zion.
Be a nice Sunday drive.
We enjoy crossin' the river,
especially now
with the trees in colour.
Well, I appreciate that, but...
...I wanna finish this one
my own way.
Try this.
Thank you.
Well, you know, Alvin,
there's a lotta hills
bigger than Clairmont's
between here and Zion.
Even if you get that mower
runnin' again,
it may still break down.
Well, you're a kind man
talkin' to a stubborn man.
I still wanna finish this
the way I started.
No, no...
Hi, Verlyn.
- How the heck you doin'?
- Fine.
Wonderful.
He's there.
Well... they gave you
a plate of her brownies.
(Laughs) Yeah.
How's that for timing?
Janet makes the best brownies...
(Both) in Lafayette county.
She won prizes every year
at the county fair.
- Mmm... help yourself.
- Thank you.
Mmm... I've been doin' errands
and I'm heading for a beer.
I thought you'd like
to join me.
Well, I don't drink
any more, but...
I'm always up for a change
of scenery.
Well, come on.
Well, I'm ridin' a little higher
and a little faster.
Except when you came down
that hill.
(Both laugh)
I picked up a mournful taste
for liquor in France.
When I came back,
I couldn't drink enough of it.
I wasn't worth a stick
of stove wood... I was mean.
A preacher helped me
put some distance
between me and the bottle.
And he helped me see...
the reason I was drinkin', I was
seein' all them things here,
that I'd seen over there.
♪ Though things may look very
dark, your dream is not... ♪
Lots of men came back
drinkin' hard.
Well... everyone
tryin' to forget.
I can see it
in a man right away.
Yup.
♪ The rainbow,
you will suddenly... ♪
There was one time...
when we just...
Were waiting for
the first warm meal in ten days.
We... thought
we'd seen the worst.
We hadn't had
much trouble from the air.
I was on the rise...
with the quartermaster,
workin' on more coffee
for me and my buddies.
(Sobbing) A stray Fokker
came over the treetops...
and dropped
an incendiary on the mess tent.
(Sounds of war)
All my buddies...
The Kraut banked right in front
of me on that hill...
and now I can...
see the... Swastika.
That is one thing
that I can't shake loose...
All my buddies faces
are still young.
And the thing is, the more years
I have, the more they've lost.
(Sobbing quietly)
And it's not always buddies
faces that I see,
sometime they're German faces.
Near the end we were shootin'
moon-faced boys.
I was a sniper.
Where I grew up, you learned
how to shoot to hunt food.
They'd post me up front.
Darn near ahead of the lines.
And I'd sit... forever.
It's an amazing thing what you
can see while you're sittin'.
I'd look for the officers, the
radio guys or artillery spotter.
Sometime I'd spot
a gun nest by the smoke
and I'd fire into it.
Sometime it was just
a movement in the woods.
We had a scout,
a little fella...
name of Kotz.
He was a Polish boy
from Milwaukee.
He'd always take recon
and he was darn good at it.
We went by his word and he saved
our skin many a time.
He was a little fella...
We'd broken
out of the hedgerows...
We were makin'
a run across the open
and we come upon a woods.
We started drawin' fire.
I took my usual position...
and I saw somethin' movin',
real slow like.
I waited ten minutes,
it moved again and I shot.
The movement stopped.
The next day
we found Kotz... head shot.
He'd been workin'
his way back toward our lines.
Everyone in the unit thought
a German sniper had taken him...
Everyone, all these years.
Everyone but me.
Ha ha!
See, Harald... brainiac...
Got the mower assembly free with
this here little old wrench...
You said it wouldn't work.
I'd say it worked
pretty good. Wouldn't you?
So help me slide her out.
We can get settled up.
(Harald snarls)
Uh... I got parts and labour
that add up to $247.80.
Well, I'd say that's a little
heavy for light work.
Don't you think?
I've got an old man's eyes,
but, ah...
I'm noticin' some new tyre here.
Well, now... ah,
we got those off a resell,
but the treads are good!
Well, friend, are you chargin'
me for good or for new?
Ahhhh... Thorvald?
Ahh... we can make
an adjustment there.
Well, I think the adjustment
should be about thirty dollars.
Is that what
your pencil's sayin'?
And, ah... about the labour...
I appreciate that you boys have
done some real time on this...
of course, a man's gotta ask
when he's workin' with twins -
especially a bickerin' pair -
how much workin' was fightin'?
(Danny) He got that right.
(Both) Shut up, Danny.
If I was to judge by this joyous
affair I saw today,
I would calculate maybe 20
per cent taken off the labour.
Anything else, mister?
Well, I'm not from these parts,
but where I come from,
I would say that that was a
little rich for Iowa oil.
Take the oil, no charge.
Well, that's a splendid offer
and I do appreciate it.
What's the tally?
Ah... ahhh...
Hundred and eighty even?
Done. (Chuckles)
Thanks to you boys, I'm gonna
get this rig back on the road.
I've drove it all the way across
Iowa and I'm hopin' it holds on
till I get to Wisconsin.
My brother lives there.
I haven't seen him
in ten years.
There's no one
knows your life better
than a brother
that's near your age.
He knows who and what you are
better than anyone on Earth.
My brother and I said some...
unforgivable things
the last time we met, but, I'm
tryin' to put that behind me.
And this trip is a hard
swallow... of my pride,
I just hope I'm not too late.
A brother's a brother.
Well...
Guess I'll be turnin' in.
I'll, ah... see you in the
morning, then, before you go.
I'm gonna leave awful early.
I wanna thank you for your
kindness to a stranger.
It's been a genuine pleasure
havin' you here, Alvin.
Write to us, sometime.
I will.
(Lawn mower starts up)
(Passing truck)
I noticed your campfire.
I brought you some dinner...
Mashed potatoes, meat loaf.
Well, thank you kindly.
I've had my dinner,
but would you
join me for a while?
Sure.
Thank you.
I hope you don't
mind me trespassin'.
Oh, no, not at all.
Made a fine choice.
You're camped next to
one of the oldest cemeteries
in the Midwest.
French Catholic trappers.
- The Marquette party.
- Two of his men.
I couldn't help but notice
the rather unusual
mode of transport.
Well, you're not the first
person to notice that, Padre.
My eyes are bad. I can't drive.
I don't like someone else
drivin' the bus,
and I need to get
to my brother's.
Fair enough.
Where is he?
Well, he's so close,
I can practically feel him.
Mount Zion.
What's his name?
Lyle Straight.
Is he that fella that came in
with a stroke some weeks ago?
Do you know him?
I work at the hospital
in Boscobel.
I remember him comin' in.
Caught my attention
because... he lives in my parish.
Well, he's a Baptist.
Oh, I believe he told me that.
Told me a few things,
matter of fact,
but he didn't
mention having a brother.
Well, neither one of us has had
a brother for quite some time.
So, you saw him?
Is he all right?
I only saw him that once and
I haven't heard anything more.
Well, Lyle and I grew up
as close as brothers could be.
We were raised on a farm
in Moorhead, Minnesota.
We worked hard. My mom and dad
darn near killed themselves
tryin' to make that farm work.
And me and Lyle would
make games out of our chores.
We'd dream up somethin'
about racin' and wagerin'
do anything to keep
our mind off the cold.
Lord, it was cold.
He and I used
to sleep out in the yard
every summer night,
if it wasn't pourin'.
Nine months of winter,
we couldn't get enough summer.
We'd bunk down
when the sun went down.
We'd talk to each other
until we went to sleep.
We'd talk about the stars
and whether there might be
somebody else like us
out in space,
places we wanted to go and...
it made
our trials seem smaller.
Yeah, we pretty much talked
each other through growin' up.
Oh, whatever happened
between you two?
Story as old as the Bible.
Cain and Abel.
Anger, vanity.
You mix that together
with liquor, and...
you've got two brothers who
haven't spoken in ten years.
Well, whatever it was
that made me and Lyle so mad...
don't matter any more.
I wanna make peace.
I wanna sit with him,
look up at the stars...
like we used to do...
so long ago.
Well, sir...
I say "Amen" to that.
(Fire crackles)
(Hum of lawn mower)
Howdy.
I haven't had a drink
in a lot of years.
Now I'm gonna have me a beer.
What flavour?
What does
a Miller's Lite taste like?
There you go.
- How's it taste?
- It's good.
- Keep the change.
- Thank you.
It's an interesting rig you got
outside. Get up the hill OK?
That hill and 200 more
just like it.
How far did ya come?
From Iowa.
I'm headed
for Lyle Straight's place.
Iowa! My God,
you must be thirsty.
(Cough)
(Scraping)
(Sighs)
Another beer?
This will do me fine.
I wonder could you point me
to Lyle's place?
I haven't seen him
in an awful long time.
Well, you just... ah,
cross 61 here, on "W",
Take "W" on down to Weed Road
and then on to Remington Road.
(Barman) On your right
will be Lyle's place.
If he's there that is.
(Motor clicks)
(Chugs)
(Squeaks)
(Motor dies)
(Motor hissing)
(Turns off engine)
How you doin'?
Not too good.
This thing's just tired.
Is there anything
I can do to help you?
Well, I don't know.
It just quit on me.
Why don't you try her again?
(Motor turns over and ignites)
I'm headin'
to Lyle Straight's place.
(Tractor engine
starts with a roar)
Lyle!
Lyle?
(Lyle) Alvin?
(Husky voice) Sit down, Alvin.
Did you ride that thing all
the way out here to see me?
I did, Lyle.
Subtitles by
European Captioning Institute