John Gotti, life in prison...
...no chance of parole.
We've seen prosecutions in Florida
and elsewhere of top Mob figures.
What are you doing?
Put that back.
[BOXING MATCH COMMENTARY]
What's the situation on the ground
today, right now, in the Mob?
BRAUN:
Confusion...
...instability...
...vacuum at the top.
ANNOUNCER: What caused it?
Your sister's ass.
BRAUN:
- policy over two decades...
...to behead the crime families.
ANNOUNCER:
But wasn't it, at least in part...
...a disregard
within the Mob itself...
...of the rules that served
the old dons so well?
- If the shoe fits.
BRAUN: No doubt.
Sil. Cheer me up, babe.
Just when I thought I was out,
they pull me back in.
Is that Pacino or is that Pacino?
Spitting image.
ANNOUNCER: Vincent Rizzo.
RIZZO: Yes.
ANNOUNCER:
Former soldier in the Genovese family.
Government witness
turned best-selling author.
Do you agree with U.S. Attorney Braun?
The party's over.
- He is a wiseguy. Elaborate.
RIZZO: It's not like it was.
- Cloning.
- Mexicans are huge in that.
- Fascinating.
- Because they work as parking valets.
RIZZO:
Do I mean that organized crime...
...will go the way of the dodo bird?
[BRAUN CONTINUES TALKING]
- What the fuck are you talking about?
- Mexicans.
- What about them?
- Cell phones.
I'm not talking
about cloning cell phones.
I'm talking about fucking sheep!
Science.
I tell my kids,
"Only God can make a life."
A guy here asks, "What if they had
cloned Princess Di?"
But you know, the heydey?
You know, the Golden Age...
...or whatever, of the Mob?
That's gone.
And that's never coming back.
They have only themselves to blame.
They pay this chiacchierone
by the word?
Drug trafficking.
- Oh!
RIZZO: I think it ruined everything.
You're looking at a mandatory
35 to life in prison.
Guys started to rat
so they could avoid prosecution.
What's going on
with that Princess Di?
Do you think the royal family
had her whacked?
Last time I take a limo in Paris.
Like you were ever in Paris.
I went for a blowjob.
Your mother was working the bonbon
concession at the Eiffel Tower.
You hear what I told him?
"I went over for a blowjob.
Your mother was working
at the Eiffel Tower."
I got a list of people
I wouldn't want cloned.
The mayor of New York, that's
the guy least likely to get cloned.
So the code of silence, the omertá,
or whatever, just went by the boards.
You're always gonna have
organized crime. Always.
As long as the human being
has certain appetites...
...for gambling, pornography
or whatever.
Someone's always gonna surface
to serve these needs. Always.
Just when I thought I was out,
they pull me back in.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
- You got DVD players?
- Don't hurt me.
Only people who get hurt
are the jerk-offs.
Now step down, nice and easy.
He's got the DVD players.
Quick and painless.
Not to hurt you.
You gotta tie me up.
- You gonna be a jerk-off?
- My boss'll think I'm in on it.
We look like we want a merit badge?
We travel with rope?
I've got some in the cab.
Please, I need this job.
Okay, get the rope.
I don't know who gave the route,
but there's no way I'd go unscathed...
...without being fired.
- You want to be scathed?
So it looks like I didn't
give up without a struggle.
- Oh!
- That's cool. Thank you.
That's enough.
No, wait.
Oh!
Ow! That's good!
- Scathed?
- Scathed.
CHRIS:
He's scathed.
Mr. Miller, my science teacher,
he got his car stolen.
You're kidding.
From where? His house?
Mm-mm. His parking spot at school.
A Saturn. He only had it a year.
MEADOW:
The security people are a joke.
Did you hear what A.J. just said?
Mr. Miller's car got stolen.
Refresh my memory. Who is he?
He's your son's science teacher.
[TONY SINGS]
You're up early.
He just bought that car a year ago.
So? Insurance will pay.
They don't give full value.
These poor teachers,
they don't make a lot.
So he can work his summer vacation.
You could help find it.
I thought I told you I changed my name
from LoJack to Soprano.
Laugh. I'd pee in my pants.
Pussy's got the body shop.
He couldn't ask?
MEADOW:
I'm late.
- What are you getting in science?
- D-plus.
- See what I can do.
- That's not what I meant.
He's gotta work for his grades.
[TONY SINGS]
[TONY CONTINUES SINGING]
I'm going back to bed.
- Bye, Dad.
- See you later.
[SPEAKS ITALIAN]
Here, eat this.
CHRIS:
Technology comes to the Bing!
SILVIO:
Hey, where you been?
SILVIO: Come on.
CHRIS: Let's go.
TONY: Hey, is the load here?
PAULIE: Yeah.
[PHONE RINGS]
If Serge calls, I'll be back.
These new phones, hold, conference,
sometimes I get confused.
How complicated is it?
Answer the phone, take the message.
Voice mail only comes on
if you let it ring.
Jesus Christ, Georgie.
I hear there's not as many titles
as on laser.
There's more coming.
My internist said the picture's
not that different.
But the sound...
Way improved.
Good. Nothing beats popping up some
corn and listening to Men in Black.
- Fuck it!
- It's the damn wires, that's all!
I'll hook it up.
I used to be an installer.
Why can't you be nice to Brendan?
We discussed that.
I was gonna come looking.
It's the guy.
It's Serge?
I'll take it over there.
Serge?
Press "hold" when you transfer a call.
I'm sorry, Tony.
Now he's not gonna call back.
Brendan's a good earner, T.
This jack was his plan.
He's a good kid,
but I don't like meth.
Fuck, I gotta call my mother.
- Hello?
- Hello, Ma?
Oh, look who calls.
- How you doing?
- I was wondering when you'd call.
You can stop wondering now.
This is it, I'm calling you.
I called yesterday.
You were supposed to call me back.
I phoned your house.
Some operator answered. I couldn't
understand a word she was saying.
That's not an operator,
that's an answering machine.
Oh, fancy, fancy.
Here, let me turn the heat off
under these mushrooms.
You and Mom are like peas in a pod.
She can't master the phone,
but she's 70. What's your excuse?
What is she doing now?
Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God.
- Ma!
Ma!
Hey, Ma!
- Oh, my God!
- Ma!
Where is she?
- Who is this?
- It's Anthony!
The mushrooms, they're on fire!
Get the fire extinguisher
under the sink!
Oh, my God!
The wall's getting all black!
Ma, hang up and call 911.
The guy's on the second line.
- Aren't you coming over?
- You press "hold," goddamn it.
I can't, I'm 40 minutes away.
You hang up and you call 911.
Leave the house.
Look at how I live!
Ma, hang up and call 911.
My mother's got a fire in the kitchen.
- Oh, my God.
- She's calling 911. Go there.
- I'm on my way.
- Thank you, baby. I know you're busy.
Serge, Serge.
I can't talk now.
I gotta go to an outside line.
All right. I'll call you back.
Is your mom okay?
Shit cannot go on like this.
Hey, T. Hey, T.
This teacher, his car,
you got a plate number?
Call my wife.
- Have a nice day.
- Thanks.
No problem.
Ma.
I wish you'd let me
get somebody to help you.
- You shouldn't be alone.
- Help me what?
- With the housework.
- I have my ways.
A stranger could care less
about doing it right.
Can I tell you something though, Ma?
You need company.
Don't start with that nursing-home
business again.
This is not a nursing home.
It is a retirement community.
You want me to make you pastina?
Something in your stomach?
Ma, now, I've told Tony...
...and I've told you many times.
You can come live with us.
I know when I'm not wanted!
I invited you to share my home.
If you want me to beg, that's different.
Leave this place
that my husband and I shared?
Well, change can be a positive.
He was a saint.
That son of mine, is he
still having those fits?
They're not fits, Ma.
They're anxiety attacks.
You know, he's on medication.
What BMW's charging us for paint?
O trippa di zia.
- It's been that way for six months.
- When was I last here?
Hey.
We maybe caught a break.
Watchung Avenue said some guys brought
a Saturn trying to load it for parts.
Are you saying this car's for Tony
and leave it all in one piece?
Yeah, sure.
It's for the kid's teacher.
My guy said one of those goofballs
had a uniform on from Buttfucks.
Whatever, the coffee shop.
I guess the guy works there.
Watchung and what?
I'm fucking Rockford here.
CASHIER: Decaf cappuccino Primo, non-fat
Magnifico, double espresso regulare.
I'll take you here.
I think I'll have an espresso.
Paul, you want anything?
They got any just coffee?
Our café du jour
is New Zealand Peaberry.
Madonna. Whatever.
That's $4.20. Pick up there.
One medium du jour,
one single espresso.
Here, keep it.
Honey, let me ask you.
My wife was in the body shop around
the corner the other day.
The guy in front of her leaves
and she sees he dropped...
...his money clip.
But he was already gone.
We'd like to give it back.
She said he was wearing
a uniform like that there.
Real black hair.
Tall? Little earring.
These stores are everywhere.
Yeah, tell me about it.
Fucking Italian people.
How'd we miss out on this?
- What?
- Fucking espresso, cappuccino.
We invent it and these
cocksuckers are getting rich.
Isn't it amazing?
It's not just money.
It's a pride thing.
All our food, pizza,
calzone, buffalo mozzarella...
...olive oil.
These fucks had nothing.
They ate puzzi before
we gave them our cuisine.
But this, this is the worst.
This espresso shit.
Take it easy.
She finally agreed
to have somebody come in days.
Carmela called an agency, and they
sent over this Trinidadian woman.
But no matter what I do,
I feel guilty.
Why?
The real reason is,
I can't let her live with us.
That doesn't seem practical,
given her personality.
Well, it's my wife.
She won't allow it.
Where are your sisters in this?
They cut it off with her long ago.
No way she's bunking with them.
So you're carrying all this guilt
when your mother is clearly someone...
...who has difficulty maintaining
any relationship.
But she's my mother.
You're supposed to take care of your
mother. She's a little old lady.
Not to you.
She's very powerful.
Bullshit.
You accord this "little old lady"...
...an almost mystical ability
to wreak havoc.
Let me tell you. You definitely
don't want to get her started.
There are some people who are not
ideal candidates for parenthood.
Come on. She's an old sweetie-pie.
What were some of the good
experiences you remember as a child?
The loving warm ones?
One time we were down at the shore.
About '68, '69, the whole family.
My father, he tripped and fell down
the stairs, and we were all laughing.
The whole family was laughing.
My mother was laughing.
Any other loving experiences?
Hey, she's a good woman.
She put food on the table every night.
I'm the ungrateful fuck.
I come here, complain about her...
...and I let my wife exclude her
from my home.
[DOORBELL CHIMES]
Hey, Ma!
- You Perrilyn?
- Yes.
Tony Soprano.
Ah.
TONY: How you doing?
PERRILYN: I'm fine.
Oh, Livia, your son is here!
And isn't he a handsome thing.
And look what he brought.
All right, listen.
Let's get one thing straight.
In the hours you're here taking care
of my mother, no ganja. Okay?
Hey, Ma, fiori.
I'm not dead, unfortunately for some.
The tall ones are delphiniums.
You know, Frankie Valli
when he visits Jersey?
This is the florist he uses.
Aren't they beautiful?
Want me to put them on the table?
You make sure the bottom
of the vase isn't wet.
Mr. Tony, would you like
some tea or something?
Coke, thanks.
So how's it going today?
She's stealing.
Who?
That ditsoon, who.
That beautiful plate Aunt Settimia
took from that restaurant in Rome.
It's gone.
I don't know.
She seems like a nice person.
She doesn't fool me for a second.
[PERRILYN HUMMING]
You sure she stole it?
You didn't give it
to one of the relatives?
You keep forcing your possessions
on people, thinking you're gonna die.
I wish it was tomorrow.
And she's so forward too.
Who does she think she is?
She's happy, Ma. She's singing.
Anthony, I don't want her around here.
I can manage somehow.
No, I'm not giving in
to you this time.
She stays.
[LIVIA SIGHS]
Your uncle called here
looking for you.
Uncle Jun?
He sounded agitated.
JUNIOR: Jackie, tell them to leave
Comley trucking alone.
Didn't know it was a Comley truck.
For 21 fucking years, Comley's put
food on my table, protection money.
- Chris didn't know going in.
- Bullshit.
Want my DVD?
You can watch Grumpy Old Men.
- You gonna be a fucking funny boy now?
JACKIE: Hey!
You Sopranos.
You hope you and your uncle can settle,
not be invited to a fucking sit-down.
You got a crew of cowards
you don't control.
Here we go.
You got a ruling?
The kids make restitution to Junior.
Done. It's done.
Christopher Moltisanti's
a fucking loose...
You get him out of a sick bed?
Hey, fuck that shit.
Giacomino, how you feeling?
I may be acting boss while your old
man's a guest of the government...
...but I wish somebody'd tell
my bowels. They don't obey.
Ah, the fucking chemo.
Maybe I should name a successor.
This day and age?
Who wants the fucking job?
Your mom tells me you got
a girl coming in to help.
That's good.
All right, I gotta go.
I'll see you soon.
TONY:
We okay?
All right.
The smoke he hires for his own mother.
Hey, Mikey, how's the boy?
- What boy?
- The one you sleep with.
Oh.
I'm just kidding.
How's Jun treating you?
We're covering our nut. Your nephew
retarded? Likes to play with trucks?
What if Jerry Lewis heard
you talking like that?
No, that's muscular dystrophy, Tony.
Too bad they don't have a telethon
for fuckface-itis. They find a cure?
I'm just kidding you.
Come on, you're a good sport.
You all right?
- Yeah.
- You all right?
- I'll see you later.
SERVER: Double cappuccino suprema.
CASHIER: Double cappuccino suprema.
Thanks. Excuse me.
A guy fitting the description
does work in this branch.
His name is Edguardo Arnaz.
Him and his gay lover both work here.
And I got the address.
- Paulie, are you listening to me?
- Yeah.
Again with the rape of the culture.
Can we go find these Spice Girls
and get this over with?
SERVER:
Two small café du jours.
That's it!
What happened?
Beats me.
Did you say something to her?
I know how to talk to people.
These blacks.
Who knows what they'll
take the wrong way.
So she's gone!
RADIO ANNOUNCER: Traffic and weather
on this Tuesday morning.
HEATHER: There's a delay as you
get out of the Lincoln Tunnel.
About a 25-minute delay if you're
approaching near Deer Route 3.
The queue beginning just before
the Bergen Viaduct.
TONY: You had orders. Why didn't you
pay his restitution?
BRENDAN: Restitution, okay. But you
know how much your uncle wants? $15.
You got the wrong truck,
that's what happened.
I didn't notice you rushing
to give back your fucking DVD player.
I'm enjoying it very much.
I screened The Bank Dick last night.
"Did you warble, my little wren?"
I'm not gonna pay it.
- Oh, yeah?
- I'm serious.
Serious is what happens
if you don't pay, by me.
In my thoughts, I use the technique
of positive visualization.
How come I always feel undermined?
By what I did on the Triborough Towers
alone, I should've been made. Boom!
Hmm.
I'm fucking serious, Tony.
The books are closed.
Did you talk to Jackie about me?
They're not accepting
any new members, okay?
You know, you got a reputation
for immaturity...
...and it's not helping, not paying
the tributes the acting boss demands.
Acting boss, my ass.
Everybody knows you really run things
since Jackie became the "chemo-sabi."
Open the fucking door.
Open the fucking door!
BRENDAN:
Ow. Oh.
[DOOR SLAMS]
All right.
All right. Fuck it.
But 15 grand is too much!
I'll tell you what.
You give me the 15K,
I'll talk to Uncle Junior...
...and maybe I can get it
to around 10.
One more thing.
You leave Comley Trucking and every
other item that belongs to Jun...
...including his hemorrhoid doughnut,
the fuck alone. Got it?
Yeah.
"Did you warble, my little wren?"
What will his commission will be?
Two, three grand. Ten to Junior.
We're lucky we net 500 bucks
from the whole thing.
Ah!
ARNAZ:
Who is it?
What?
Mr. Arnaz?
What do you want?
You seen a schoolteacher's
Saturn around here?
Come here!
Anybody else here, Desi?
JEROME: Eddie, I'm ready.
- Yep.
Here comes Lucy.
JEROME: Those people at the airport
shuttle are always late.
ARNAZ: Uh!
- Eddie!
You boys drove off in the wrong car.
We ain't saying shit
until there's an attorney.
Well, go ahead. Make a statement.
I got fucking Johnny Cochran here!
PUSSY:
You boys put a crimp in my week.
- Ah, mannaggia!
PUSSY: Get over there.
PAULIE:
Hey, Puss, here's the fucking set.
Look.
PUSSY:
Fucking car's been chopped. Useless.
That's not it.
Then why is that car inside there?
That Dodge?
Why is that motherfucker wearing the
fucking plate number I had all week?
- I don't know.
- Here's what's gonna happen.
The two of youse are climbing over that
fence and shagging those plates.
But the razor wire.
Then one of you stays with us while
the other goes and gets another Saturn.
[TONY SIGHS]
- On the lookout for ducks?
- Know the old man pretty good.
Don't look so sad. Remember how
pissed you were about the pool filter?
They were special, them coming here,
huh? Don't you think?
I wasn't into it.
What time's Grandma getting here?
She had to drive
Fanny to the doctor's.
Then she is picking up my parents
and they're coming here.
They're each bringing
some antipasto.
I complain about my mother,
about how she just sits at home...
...and feels sorry for herself.
But she's always ready to drive those
friends of hers that can't drive.
I'm proud of her. It gives me hope.
FANNY:
It's getting chilly out here.
Make plenty of noise
before you open the front door.
You never know who's in there.
There's my Star-Ledger. Thanks.
Oh, this street,
another pain in the ass.
She broke her wrist
on the steering column.
A minor concussion.
What about the other woman?
Hip.
[WINCES]
We were at the hospital till 2 a.m...
...talking to her doctor
and the staff gerontoligist.
They say she shouldn't
live alone anymore.
She can't manage the telephone.
Yet you say she's healthy and alert.
Like a bull.
Why?
I'm just thinking.
I know there are other doctors there,
but you know from your own life...
...that depression can cause
accidents, poor performance or worse.
So, what are you saying?
Unconsciously she tried
to whack her friend?
It's interesting that you would even
take that from what I said.
Either way, she could need a change
in her living situation...
...be around more people.
We were looking at Green Grove.
It's a beautiful facility.
It's more like a hotel
at Cap d'Antibes.
Yeah.
- But to her it's a nursing home.
- She needs to see the distinction.
That, in fact, she's embarking
on a rewarding chapter.
I know seniors who are inspired
and inspiring.
CHRIS:
You're not forgetting us, buddy?
Ladies.
Hey, Kenny Portugal said
to say hello.
Oh, yeah. Kenny.
The fuck is with this cocksucker?
BOUNCER:
Back up! Mr. Scorsese, good evening.
CHRIS:
Whoa! Wow!
Marty!
Kundun! I liked it.
So my boy at Comley...
...said there's a load
of Italian suits.
Those unload fast.
Mario'll take the whole load.
He says shipment moves
Thursday at 6 a.m.
Give me one good reason
I should not jack this truck.
It's Junior's own fault. He gives us
no choice except to do it again.
Taking that outrageous tribute.
He shits on our heads, we're
supposed to say thanks for the hat.
I'm getting nowhere playing
by the rules. Fuck Tony.
"The books are closed." Blow me.
That's some true shit.
They're not confirming any
new made guys. How come?
Fucking chaos. Nobody knows
who's running things anymore.
Guys don't know who to make payments
up the ladder to in some cases.
I'm talking about the year 2000.
The millennium.
Where do we go from here?
TONY:
Oh.
Ma, this Virginia ham...
Go on, get yourself some more.
No, I'm full.
It's good, though.
You never let me feed you.
So getting back
to what we were talking about.
- You want that lamp?
- Lie down.
That lamp, that's real ormolu. You
know what that's worth when it's new?
We're fixed good lamp-wise, thank you.
Take it and take the Barcalounger.
Somebody's gotta take
this stuff before I die.
Otherwise there's gonna be
a lot of stuff here...
...that the junkman's gonna
have to cart off to the dump.
Mom, you're not gonna die. Your
stuff won't be hauled off to the dump.
Plan for the future. The most rewarding
chapter of your life's coming up.
- You know my good jewelry?
- The stuff Dad gave you.
Some of those pieces came right
out of Cartier's window.
Listen, Carm doesn't want it.
Not now.
We want you to live long and wear your
sparklers to grandkids' graduations.
I gave it all
to your cousin Josephine.
The fuck?
The good jewelry?
She always admired it.
They don't have much.
You gave her Cartier rings,
and you give me a vibrating chair?
Your wife never showed
any interest in my jewels.
She never complimented me
on any of it, as I remember.
Before you do more damage to yourself
or your grandchildrens' inheritance...
...you'll stop living alone.
I'm not going to that nursing home.
Green Grove is a retirement community!
It's like a hotel at Captain Teeb's!
Who's he?
A captain who owns luxury hotels
or something.
I talked to Mrs. DiCaprio, and she's
got a corner suite available.
It's available. It'll go fast.
Of course it's available.
Somebody died!
You gotta stop with this black poison
cloud all the time. I can't take it!
Oh, poor you!
I got problems at work,
problems at home.
I got a friend diagnosed with cancer.
Most parents would be grateful
if their children did this!
I'm not going to that place.
I will go to court and get power
of attorney and place you there.
Then kill me now.
Go on, go into the ham...
...and take the carving knife
and stab me here.
Here! Now please, it would hurt me
less than what you just said.
I know seniors that are inspired!
[LIVIA CRIES]
Yo, money, we said we'd meet out
front, and you're not even dressed!
I'm taking a pass.
What? It's Italian suits, Christopher.
There was a time when being with
Tony's crew was all I ever dreamed of.
So what am I doing?
This is some fucking note here.
Don't wake her up.
Come on, it's 5:15.
Maybe one reason things are so fucked
in the organization these days...
...is guys running off not listening
to middle management.
"Fuck Tony." That's a quote.
We have to stick together.
Why be in a crew?
Why be a gangster?
Hey, coach?
Suck my dick.
Yeah.
Yo! Hey! Yo!
We need some help over here!
Okay, let's be very cool, yo!
Get down out of the cab!
You heard the motherfucker.
I'm a friend of Billy's.
Your friend on the inside.
Yeah, cool. "Increase the peace,"
that's our motto.
- I'm gonna take my lunch, okay?
- Yeah, whatever. Come on.
GANGSTER: Hold up, man.
You can't drive a Fisher Price.
What's with the gun pointed sideways?
Get out! Come on, get down!
You drive, I'll direct you.
[GUN GOES OFF]
Jesus!
Control your shit, fool!
Fuck, I'm fucked! Fuck!
Fuck!
Fuck! Junior-fucking-Soprano's
gonna go ape-shit. Fuck!
You excited about coming
to live with us, hon?
You will be. Trust me.
Look, Ma, here's your stuff.
- Wow, they made good time.
TONY: Yeah.
You got your own bed and your dresser.
You know, when my grandmother
went to live... elsewhere...
...they weren't allowed
personal effects.
All right, Ma, sign right here.
[PHONE BEEPS]
BONNIE:
Yes?
Mr. Soprano, do you have
an Uncle Junior?
He tracked me down here?
Line two? Here you go.
I'll call him back.
He'll return the call. He did?
It's urgent. She said he sounded
upset. He'll call back.
Livia, did you ever hear the old
Italian saying? My aunt used to go:
"Col tempo la foglia
di gelso diventa seta."
What's that mean, Bonnie?
Time and patience change
the mulberry leaf to silk.
You gonna be all right?
Yeah, sure.
Thanks for all your help.
I'll make us a nice lunch.
I've got some fantastic
prosciutto in there.
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello?
Yeah. It's Christopher.
Yeah.
I've been calling for hours.
Call me on an outside line.
[PHONE RINGS]
T, don't get mad.
There's been a little shit.
- I had nothing to do with it...
- Spit it out!
Brendan hit Comley again.
He what?
- And the driver, you know...
- No, I don't know.
He caught some friendly fire
or something and he's gone.
Oh, fuck!
What do we do, T?
Brendan didn't fence the load.
He's thinking it was Mario
who dimed us to Junior last time.
Fuck!
[SIGHS]
SILVIO:
Hey, Ton.
Sorry you have to wreck
your Saturday like this.
TONY:
You boys. You boys, I'll tell you.
It's beautiful stuff, though.
- Ton, I'm so sorry.
- Shut up.
Just so you realize I had
nothing to do with this.
- Ton, that's true. He stood home.
- Shut up.
Stood home?
Did you do anything to stop it?
Did you offer any guidance?
What do we mean when we say
leadership, hm?
Part of it's the crank. But I'm
going into detox, swear on my mother.
Brendan, shut the fuck up.
You want to get me clipped?
What are we gonna do?
You're gonna put these suits back
in the truck and give them back.
Fuck!
Then call my uncle
and tell him it's done.
What about the dead guy?
Prod him with a stick.
Light a candle to St. Anthony.
But I think you're fucked.
Ton...
...what if this didn't go back?
Would it be a problem?
I don't see you assholes putting
that rack, and that rack...
...and this rack here
back in the truck.
Just when I thought I was out,
they pull me back in.
Hmm!
MR. MILLER:
Hey, Mr. Miller, your car is back.
My wife dropped me off
and there it was, in my parking spot.
My Uncle Pussy
helped my dad locate it.
Uncle Pussy?
He's in the car business.
I don't know what to say to your
dad, I mean, thanks of course.
It's nice and clean too.
Whoa, different keys!
It's probably too much to hope my
papers are still inside the trunk.
WOMAN:
It's a different color.
MR. MILLER:
Whoa. Ooh.
My dad's a hero.
[SNIFFS]
[CLEARS THROAT]
MELFI: Did you actually lose
consciousness like with the ducks?
No.
Just a shortness of breath and
the white spots in my field of vision.
Improvement.
Because I'm sad to put my mother away?
Sad is good. Unconscious isn't.
She'll be in very good hands.
You've done the best for her.
She won't speak to me.
That is sad.
But whose choice is that?
Somehow that doesn't make it
any better.
Can you admit to yourself that yes,
you're sad...
...but you're angry and full of rage?
I'm sad.
It's hard to admit that...
...you may have feelings of hatred
towards your mother, isn't it?
You're out of your tree.
Listen carefully.
Of course you love her.
What I'm trying to say is, own
the anger instead of displacing it.
Otherwise it defines your life.
It needs to be acknowledged.
It's a good thing time is up.
I don't want to talk to you anymore.
"Hate your mother."
[DANCE MUSIC PLAYING]
Shit.
A what do you call it? A menu.
Press two if you know
your party's extension.
Is that an operator
or an answering machine?
Let's see. Hello? Hello?
Hello?
Press zero. Hello?
Hello? Hello?
GEORGIE:
Ooh.