(Flies buzzing)
(Echoing laughter)
(Ghostly voices keening)
Woman: ♪ I sent you 20 letters
from Paris last year ♪
♪ Well, you've been
gone six months ♪
♪ And I got the fear ♪
♪ After all the songs that
we've sung together ♪
♪ After all the sweet
and all the stormy... ♪
(Ghostly moaning)
♪ If I knew where you were ♪
♪ Well, I would surely
inform you that... ♪
♪ But every night don't you
sleep on your right? ♪
♪ Don't you... ♪
Hey, Ash, where are we?
Well, we just crossed
the Tennessee border.
- Which would put us...
- Yeah?
Which would put us...
"fight"
- here.
- (Tires screeching)
(Honking)
Turn!
- (Horn blaring)
- (Screaming)
(Sighs)
What the hell was that? Are
you trying to kill us?
Hey, don't blame me. It's
your steering wheel.
The damn thing jerked
right out of my hand.
I can't understand it.
I had this thing in for
a tune-up yesterday
and they said they'd
go over everything.
You'd better take it back 'cause
the damn thing don't work.
The only thing that does
work is this lousy horn.
(Honking)
Aw, go to hell! I'm
not honking at you.
Jesus Christ.
Woman: Hey, Scotty, what's
this place like anyway?
Well, the guy that's renting
it says it's an old place...
A little rundown, but it's
right up in the mountains.
And the best part is
we get it so cheap.
Yeah, why are we
getting it so cheap?
Well, I don't know. Might
be in real bad shape.
You mean nobody's
seen this place yet?
Scott: Well, not yet.
- Well, it might not be that bad.
- No.
- Actually, it might be kinda nice.
- Yeah.
It's probably a real pit.
Hey, I think this is
where we get off.
Woman: This is the bridge
we're gonna cross?
Scott: Jesus Christ, the whole
thing's falling apart on us.
Ash: Don't let the
noise fool you, girls.
This thing is solid as a rock.
(Woman screams)
(Scott laughing)
(Distant thumping)
(Thumping grows louder)
(Thumping)
(Thumping stops)
It's supposed to be
one of these on here.
(Creaking)
- Come on.
- Hey.
Hey hey.
- Huh!
- (Laughs)
(Crickets chirping)
(Ticking)
(Chimes)
(Chiming)
- Demon: Join us.
- (Banging)
Join us.
(Whimpering)
(Banging)
(Grinding)
(Whispering) Dead
bodies in the cellar.
- Dead bodies in the cellar.
- Will you stop it?
I would like very much
to make a toast here
for all this evening.
"That sounds a" right.
Uh, as a Greek friend
of mine once said...
He said, "...I'"
- (Woman giggles)
- Ash: No, okay okay okay.
"Nis nis..."
tu tu tu...
"tu-tar-im."
- Woman: Which means?
- "Party down!" Yeah!
(Clangs)
(Water dripping)
What is this?
Whatever it is, it's
still down there.
I don't like cellars.
Let's just close it up.
It's probably just some animal.
An animal? An animal.
That is the stupidest
thing I ever heard of.
Jesus Christ.
Well, there's
something down there.
Well, maybe it is
just some animal.
Yeah, you're probably right.
It's probably just some animal.
Here, Cheryl. Why don't you go
down and check to make sure?
Scotty, I'm not
going down there.
Okay okay, you cowards. I'll go.
Be careful.
Back in a minute.
(Water dripping)
Hey... hey, Scotty,
you find anything?
Scotty?
Scot“
He's just kidding around.
- Isn't he?
- Scotty!
Scot“
Linda, get me a flashlight.
That's the only one
we brought up.
Then get the lantern.
(Water dripping)
Scotty?
(Wood clatters)
(Creaking)
Boo! (Laughing)
Hey, come here. I want
to show you something.
Look at all this stuff.
(Clicks)
I bet this still shoots.
Probably does.
Oh! God.
Oh God.
Look at this.
This kind of looks like
your old girlfriend.
Come on, let's take
this stuff upstairs.
I'll grab the recorder and
you get everything else.
(Thunderclaps)
Scott: This guy was a
real turd, you know?
Everybody hated him.
Like you kind of, right?
Yeah, just like me. I'm
gonna break your face.
Scott: Also, he was into
this Western stuff.
He makes all these
little models...
Okay, shh.
Listen to this.
This is the tape I
found downstairs.
(Thunder rumbling)
Man: It has been a
number of years
since I began excavating
the ruins of Ca'n Dar
with a group of my colleagues.
Now my wife and I have
retreated to a small cabin
in the solitude of
these mountains.
Here I continued my
research undisturbed
by the myriad distractions
of modern civilization
and far from the
groves of Academe.
I believe I have made
a significant find
in the Ca'n Darian ruins:
a volume of ancient
Sumerian burial practices
and funerary incantations.
It is entitled
"Naturan Demanto.“"
Roughly translated...
"Book of the Dead."
The book is bound in human flesh
and inked in human blood.
(Thunderclap)
It deals with demons,
demon resurrection
and those forces which
roam the forest
and dark bowers of man's domain.
- (Thunderclap)
- The first few pages
warn that these
enduring creatures
may lie dormant but
are never truly dead.
They may be recalled
to active life
through the incantations
presented in this book.
It is through recitation
of these passages
that the demons are given
license to possess the living.
(Thunder booming)
Hey, what'd you do that for?
It was just getting good.
I just don't wanna hear
it anymore, that's all.
(Eerie vocals)
Ash: Scott, come on.
Leave her alone, man.
Hey, come on. I just wanna
hear the rest of it.
No big deal.
(Man chanting in Sumerian)
(Sumerian continues)
Kanda.
Shut it off.
Shut it off!
- Shut it off!
- (Thunder booms)
- (Screams)
- Oh my God!
- (Crying)
- Cheryl.
- Where are you going?
- I can't believe this.
Scott, you knew
not to play that.
I mean, come on, you knew
it was upsetting her.
You just don't know when you're
taking something too far.
Hey, don't give me that.
You were playing it too.
You could have shut it off.
I mean, big deal. She's nuts.
I mean, it's just a joke.
- Come on.
- (Glass shatters)
Jesus Christ, she acts like she's
three years old or something.
(Thunder booming)
Listen, why don't we stay up for
a while and listen to the storm?
All right, yeah.
But let me check on Cheryl
first to make sure she's okay.
Okay.
Oh, stealing from
the blind, huh?
It's for you.
Ash, how sweet of you.
- Would you put it on?
- Oh sure.
I was gonna give it to you
before we came up here,
but things got so hectic.
This is really the first
chance we've had to be alone.
Take a look.
Oh, Ash, it's beautiful.
I really love it.
I'll never take it off.
(Demonic voices)
(Demonic growling)
Demon: Join us.
Is anybody out there?
(Wolf howling)
I know someone's out there.
I heard you. I heard
you in the cellar.
(Fluttering, screeching)
- (Branches cracking)
- (Creature growling)
(Growling continues)
(Growling intensifies)
(Screams)
Demons: Join us.
(Screaming)
(Grunting, screaming)
(Whimpering, grunting)
- (Trees cracking)
- (Ghostly howling)
(Whimpering, screaming)
(Cries out)
(Screaming)
Help! (Screaming)
Ashley!
Help!
Oh, the keys.
(Grunting)
Help!
(Screams)
(Demons shouting)
Ash: What the hell happened to you?
What's the matter with you?
Did something in the
woods do this to you?
No, it was the woods themselves.
They're alive, Ashley.
The trees, they're alive.
Ash, why don't I take her in the
back room so she can lie down?
I'm not lying down!
I wanna get out of here.
I wanna leave this
place right now.
- Right now, Ashley.
- Scott: Wait a minute.
I sure as hell am not
leaving anyplace tonight.
- Cheryl.
Look, there's nothing out there.
Trees do not attack people.
Ashley, will you drive
me into town or not?
What, right now?
Yeah. Look, sure sure,
I'll take you into town,
but just listen to
what you're saying.
I don't care how it sounds.
I wanna get out of
this place right now.
Okay, you can stay
somewhere in town tonight.
(Engine chugging)
Come on, come on, come on.
(Sighs)
(Engine chugging)
I know it's not gonna start.
It's not gonna let us leave.
(Engine starts)
(Wood creaking)
Why are you stopping?
Wait here a minute.
(Creaking continues)
Do you see something?
Where are you going?
Ashley?
Oh oh!
(Screaming)
(Crying)
- It's not gonna let us go.
- What?
It's not gonna let us go.
I told you!
I told you, it's not
gonna let us go.
Why won't you listen to me?
(Crying)
No! No!
Man: I know now that my
wife has become host
to a Ca'n Darian demon.
I fear that the only way to stop
those possessed by the
spirits of the book
is through the act of
bodily dismemberment.
I would leave now to
avoid this horror,
but for myself I...
I have seen the dark shadows
moving in the woods
and I have no doubt that whatever I
have resurrected through this book
is sure to come calling for me.
Okay, let me think. Um...
it's a seven.
- What suit?
- Um, diamonds.
No no no, wait. Um, hearts.
Oh my God! Seven of
hearts, you're right.
Linda: Hey, Ash, I
guessed the card right.
Yeah, truly amazing, Linda.
I don't know, I don't
know, but I think
it's really some sort of
extra sense or something.
- You know, like ESP?
- Okay, try this.
- Okay, um, it's a seven.
- I don't believe it!
(Stuttering) Of spades...
queen of spades.
Cheryl: Four of hearts,
eight of spades...
(Agitated) two of spades,
jack of diamonds, jack of clubs!
- (Roars)
- (Women scream)
(Demonic voice) Why have
you disturbed our sleep,
awakened us from our
ancient slumber?
You will die like the
others before you.
One by one we will take you.
(Growling)
- (Thuds)
- (Gasps)
What happened to her?
Did you see her eyes?
Ash, I'm scared.
What's wrong with her?
(Screaming)
Cheryl, stop it!
(Grunts)
Join us. Join...
(Cheryl grunting, snarling)
(Panting)
(Snarling subsides)
(Cheryl snarling)
(Door opens)
Scott: Ash, I think we
ought to get out of here.
Yeah.
We still have a few more
hours before morning.
Shelly: I don't think
I can wait that long.
You have to. We all have to.
And then in the morning
we'll get in the car
and we'll take the bridge.
- And...
- (Cheryl continues snarling)
Why does she keep making
those horrible noises?
Ash: I don't know!
What about her eyes?
For God's sake, what
happened to her eyes?
(Growling, laughing
maniacally)
(Demon growling)
Everything's gonna be all right.
Scotty, I... I think there's
something out there.
Go to bed and get
some sleep, okay?
(Demon groaning)
(Groaning intensifies)
(Screaming)
(Wolves howling in distance)
(Wood clatters)
Scott: Shelly?
CWT-“Tm
- (Scott screaming)
- (Shelly screeching)
Cheryl: No!
Don't burn her! Get her out!
No no no.
(Demonic voice) Thank you.
I don't know what
I would have done
if I had remained
on those hot coals,
burning my pretty flesh.
You have pretty skin.
- Give it to us!
- (Choking)
(Hissing, shouting)
Join us. Join us.
Join us.
(Shouting)
(Shrieking)
(Cracks)
(Hissing)
(Screaming)
(Shrieking)
(Shrieking continues)
(Shrieking stops)
(Moaning)
(Growls)
(Growling)
(Roaring)
Hit her.
Hit her!
Hit it!
Cheryl: No no no!
No no! You love her.
(Shelly screaming)
Cheryl: No, you love her.
Don't do it!
(Panting)
(Squishing)
Scott?
Yeah?
What is... what are we gonna do?
We're gonna bury her.
You can't bury Shelly.
She's a... She's a
friend of ours.
Ash, she's dead.
Shelly's dead.
We gotta bury her now.
(Squishing)
(Wind whipping)
(Thunderclap)
(Demon moaning)
Linda's still sleeping.
- I think once her leg's...
- I'm getting out of here.
Scott, we can't take Linda
anywhere with her leg like that.
We don't even know if there is any
other way back besides the bridge.
Well, maybe there's a
hiking trail or an old road
or some other way
around the cliff.
I mean, there's gotta be another
way besides the bridge.
Listen to me.
Linda cannot walk with
her leg like that.
She can't even stand up.
Well, then we'll leave her here
until we can send somebody back.
What are you, crazy?
- Scott...
- Look, I'm gettin' out.
I don't care what
happens to her.
She's your girlfriend.
You take care of her.
I'm getting the hell
out of here right now.
Cheryl: Soon all of
you will be like me
and then we will lock
you up in the cellar.
(Cackling)
- Ahh!
- Ash!
- Oh my God.
- Help me.
Yes yes.
(Giggling)
Ash.
(Groaning)
Scotty, you're gonna be okay.
You're gonna be just
fine, you'll see.
- (Metal clangs)
- (Shelly cackling)
Ash, it's not gonna
let us leave.
Cheryl... Cheryl was right.
- We're all gonna die here.
- No, we're not gonna die.
"We're all gonna die, a" of us!
No, we're not gonna die.
We're not gonna die! We're
gonna get outta here.
Now listen to me, Scotty.
Is there a way
around the bridge?
- Scotty!
- (Groaning)
Listen to me, please.
For God's sake!
- Scott!
- (Grunts)
- Come on.
- Ash...
Ash, I don't wanna die.
You're not gonna leave
me, are you, Ash?
- An you?
- (Mocking) "I don't wanna die."
"You're not gonna leave
me here, are you?"
"Are you, Ash?" (Laughing)
Scotty, now come on! Listen
to me, for God's sake.
Is there a way
around the bridge?
There's a way... the trail.
But the trees, Ash,
they know.
Don't you see, Ash?
They're alive.
- (Women giggling)
- Ahhh!
(Laughing)
Ash: Shut up. Shut up, Linda!
(Shrieking laughter continues)
Shut up!
(Continues laughing)
Kill her. Kill her.
Kill her if you can, lover boy.
God forgive me, Linda.
(Continues laughing)
Oh, Ash... help me, please.
(Shotgun clatters)
Ash.
Help me, please, Ash.
Oh, Ash, please don't let
them take me away again.
- Please.
- No, I won't.
- I won't, I promise.
(Cheryl in normal voice) Ashley.
Ashley, help me.
Let me out of here.
Ashley? Ash, help me.
Let me out of here. I'm...
I'm all right now.
I'm all right now, Ashley.
I'm all right.
Unlock this chain
and let me out.
Cheryl?
(Demonic voice) I'm
all right now, Ashley.
(Laughing)
Come unlock the chain
and let me out.
I'm all right now.
It's your sister Cheryl.
Oh, you bastards.
Why are you torturing
me like this?
- Why?!
- (Llnda giggling)
(Thunderclap)
Shut up.
♪ We're gonna get you ♪
♪ Not another peep ♪
♪ Time to go to sleep ♪
♪ We're... ♪
(Cackling)
Useless! Useless!
In time we'll come for him
and then we'll come for you!
(Yelling)
(Linda panting)
Here. Here.
Now the sun will be
up in an hour or so
and we can all get out
of here together...
You, me, Linda, Shelly.
Oh no, not Shelly.
She...
We'll all be going
home together.
Wouldn't you like
to be going home?
Bet you'd like that,
wouldn't you?
Scott?
(Cheryl cackling)
(Wolf howling)
(Shrieking)
- Ahh!
- (Cackling)
(Shrieking)
(Laughing)
(Yelling)
(Growling)
Join us.
Join us!
(Shouting)
(Gurgling)
(Panting)
(Raspy breathing)
(Squeaking)
(Buzzing)
(Buzzing stops)
(Crying) Oh, Linda.
(Snarling)
- (Wailing)
- Ahh!
No! Ahh!
(Screaming)
- Eyah!
- (Cackling)
Oh! (Cackling continues)
Come to me.
Yah!
Ahh ahh ahh!
(Cooing)
Come on, get off.
(Screaming)
(Linda moaning)
(Wailing)
(Door creaking)
(Soft thumping)
(Thumping continues)
(Thumping)
- (Roaring)
- Ahh ahh!
(Gunshot)
- (Roars)
- Ash: Oh God.
The door.
(Grunting)
(Thunder rolling)
(Cheryl shouting, whimpering)
The back door.
Shells... where did I
see that box of shells?
(Liquid dripping)
(Gasping)
Ow! Ahh!
(Panting)
('20$ jazz music playing)
(Coughing)
Linda's voice: ♪ We're
gonna get you ♪
- J“ We're gonna get you. J“
- Ash's voice: Shut up, Linda!
- Scott's voice: We're all gonna die.
- Ash's voice: Shut up.
- Scott: All of us.
- Shut up!
Linda's voice: Ash,
how sweet of you.
Ash's voice: God
forgive me, Linda.
Man's voice: through the act
of bodily dismemberment.
- Scott's voice: Hit her.
- Linda's voice: I really love it.
- I'll never take it off.
Scott's voice: Hit it!
(Electrical crackling)
(Music distorting)
(Record slows, stops)
(Clock ticking)
(Chiming Westminster quarters)
(Loud chiming, clanging)
- (Stone clatters)
- (Gasps)
(Heart beating)
(Door creaking)
(Panting)
Ahh ahh!
(Screaming)
(Heartbeats quicken)
(Roaring)
(Wind howling)
(Wood creaking)
Oh God...
There. (Muttering)
Come on, come on.
Why are you torturing
me like this?
(Footsteps)
(Clopping)
(Clock ticking)
Linda.
(Ticking stops)
(Screaming)
Cheryl: Join us!
Join us!
(Shouting)
- (Growling)
- (Gun clatters)
(Shouting)
(Screaming)
(Blood gushing)
(Roaring)
Must die.
(Grunting, crying out)
(Demons screaming)
(Screaming fades)
(Bones cracking)
(Grunting)
No.
(Moaning)
(Moaning fades)
(Squishing)
(Soft groaning)
(Roaring)
Ahh! Oh God!
(Flies buzzing)
(Snorting, gurgling)
Demon: Join us.
Join us. (Snarls)
(Fading) Join us.
(Birds chirping)
(Ticking)
(Crickets chirping)
(Demonic growling)
(Wood banging)
(Screaming)
('20$ jazz music playing)
(Music distorts)
- (Music stops)
- (Wind howling)
(Flies buzzing)