[Waves Lapping, Faint]
[Man Whispers] Brother.
Mother.
It was they who led me to your door.
[Bird Squawking]
♪♪ [Choir Singing. ; Dirge]
[Woman] The nuns taught us
there are two ways through life-
the way of nature...
and the way of grace.
You have to choose which
one you'll follow.
Grace doesn't try to please itself.
Accepts being slighted,
forgotten, disliked.
Accepts insults and injuries.
Ooh!
[Child Chattering, Faint]
Nature only wants to please itself.
- Bless, O Lord, this food to our use-
- Get others to please it too.
[Father]
...your loving and faithful service.
Likes to lord it over them.
[Father] Bless these boys.
[Woman] To have its own way.
It finds reasons to be unhappy...
when all the world is
shining around it...
when love is smiling
through all things.
They taught us that no one
who loves the way of grace...
ever comes to a bad end.
[Woman] I will be true to you.
Whatever comes.
♪♪ [Choir Fades]
[Sobs] Oh, God!
[Engine Roaring]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Engine Roaring Fades]
[Bell Tolls]
- [Child Chattering, Faint]
- [Mother Whispers] My son.
[Quiet Sob]
I just want to die...
to be with him.
[Older Man]
He's in God's hands now.
[Mother]
He was in God's hands the whole time.
Wasn't he?
My hope.
My God.
"I shall fear no evil-
fear no evil, for you are with me. "
What did you gain?
"Be not far from me,
for trouble is near."
[Father]
Okay, go on now. We're all right.
We're all right.
Thank you. Thank you.
- Sure, you have your memories of him, and, uh-
- [Mother Crying Quietly]
You're gonna have to be strong now and...
I know the pain will...
It will pass in time, you know?
It might seem... hard, my saying that...
but it's true.
[Whispers] I don't want it to.
Life goes on.
People pass along.
Nothing stays the same.
You've still got the other two.
- [Quiet Sob]
- The Lord gives, and the Lord takes away...
and...
that's the way he is.
He sends flies to wounds...
that he should heal.
[Woman Screams, Faint]
[Father] I never got a chance
to tell him how sorry I was.
One night he...
punched him- himself in the face
for no reason.
He was sitting next to me at the piano...
and I criticized the way
he turned the pages.
I made him feel shame.
My shame.
[Whispers] That poor boy.
That poor boy.
[Man] How did you come to me?
In what shape?
What disguise?
I see the child that I was.
[Birds Chirping]
[Children Shouting, Faint]
- I see my brother.
- [Water Running]
True.
Kind.
He died when he was 19.
- [Clanging, Faint]
- [People Chattering, Walking]
Just check this- this one against this.
She wants to get back together,
but... that chapter's closed...
story's been told.
What are you gonna do?
Experiment.
When you're young,
it's all about your career.
You don't understand anything.
I just feel like I'm bumping into walls.
I didn't know how to do her hair.
[Mechanical Beeping]
Hey, Dad.
I'm sorry I said what I said. L...
Yeah. Yeah, I think about him every day.
I just shouldn't have said what
I did, and I'm sorry.
No, it's just, oh, this day.
[Father] What are you thinkin'?
[Son] I know- I know
you did everything you could.
[Son's Colleague] And only two of those
were turned down by the client.
One of them...
[Waves Lapping]
[Son] How did I lose you?
Wandered?
Forgot you?
[Wind Whistling]
[Waves Crashing]
[Young Boy] Find me.
[Son] How did she bear it?
Mother.
[Mother Screams]
[Mother Whispering]
Was I false to you?
[Mother] Lord.
Why?
Where were you?
[Mother Whispering]
Did you know?
Who are we to you?
Answer me.
[Rumbling]
[Explosions]
[Mother] We cry to you.
My soul.
My son.
Hear us.
[Loud Hissing]
[Gurgling]
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Ocean Waves Roaring]
[Mother] Light of my life.
I search for you.
My hope.
My child.
[Bell Tolls]
[Son]
You spoke to me through her.
You spoke with me from the sky.
The trees.
Before I knew I loved you...
believed in you.
[Insects Chirping]
When did you first touch my heart?
[Faint Murmuring]
[Crying, Faint]
♪♪ [Mother Singing, Faint]
[Man]
And manfully to fight under his banner...
against sin, the world and the devil.
We had the commander over for dinner.
This little devil bit
him right on the ankle.
[Son] Mama!
Me!
[Clanging]
[Whispers] Rhinoceros.
Two alligator.
Two alligators.
- Kangaroo.
Jump.
[Gentle Ocean Waves]
- [Boy Chattering]
- Mmm.
[Baby Cooing]
Ah!
- [Crying]
- Sweetheart.
- Shh! Please.
- [Whining]
I know. No!
No!
[Clattering]
[Kissee]
It's mine!
You found me.
You'll be grown before that tree is tall.
[Son As Child]
Blue. Far.
You.
[Barking]
Are you afraid?
Come here.
Come here. All right. Now, come back here, Son.
Stay out of there.
That's the Spencers' yard. Okay?
You see this line? Let's not cross it.
Do you understand?
Hmm? Do you understand?
You see this line? Lookit here. Look here.
Okay. Now, come back here, Son.
Come on back.
Stay out of there.
[Giggling]
"'Now, my dears, '
said old Mrs. Rabbit one morning..."
'you may go into the fields
or down the lane...
but don't go into Mr.
McGregor's garden. ;
Father had an accident there. "'.
That's where God lives.
Good night. We'll see ya in five years.
[Both Laughing]
You want to eat a grasshopper?
I found a dinosaur bone!
Oh!
- Is that a rock?
- No.
Ah.
[Laughs] Hey!
[Mother] Boys!
Come home!
Boys!
[Boy Shouting, Indistinct]
[Laughing, Chattering]
You're a "potleak" now!
- You're filthy!
- [Shouts, Indistinct]
[Laughs]
Bless this food to our use and us to
your loving and faithful service...
and make us ever mindful
of those who are in need.
Amen.
♪♪ [Record Player. ; Classical]
Can you pass the butter, please?
- "Can you pass the butter, please, sir?"
- Sir.
What'd you do today?
- Went to school.
- After that?
What about the yard?
Did you put the runners in like I asked?
Yeah.
Yes, sir.
[Father]
Well, it didn't look like it.
- Hmm?
- Yes.
Mr. Reese liked Jack's book report...
- [Father] What is that, sweetheart?
- And wanted him to make a model.
You know this?
♪♪ [Orchestra. ; Dramatic]
Brahms.
Son?
Sir?
Reach me my lighter.
Haven't you forgotten somethin'?
Do you love your father?
Yes, sir.
[Mother]
"... against the Panther...
and they went off
to look for Kaa the Rock Python.
They found him stretched out
on a warm ledge in the afternoon sun...
"admiring his beautiful new coat."
Who do you love the most?
I love you all three the same.
Tell us a story from
before we can remember.
[Mother]
Went for a ride in a plane once.
It was a graduation present.
[Young Jack Whispers] Mother.
Make me good.
Brave.
- ♪♪ [Humming]
- [Gasps]
[Shouts]
Aah! Aah!
[Youngest Brother]
Can it happen to anyone?
Shh.
[Young Jack]
Nobody talks about it.
Help me not to sass my dad.
Help me not to get dogs in fights.
Help me be thankful for
everything I've got.
[Young Jack] Where do you live?
Help me not to tell lies.
[Whispering]
Are you watching me?
[Chattering, Shouting]
I want to know what you are.
I want to see what you see.
♪♪ [Organ]
- [Father] Come here, youl
- [Boys Shouting]
- Come here. Come here, you!
- [Laughing]
That funny?
[Door Slams]
You're gonna stand there, and you're
gonna close this door quietly 50 times.
Count it out.
Three, four...
five, six...
seven, eight-
You can't just yank off the top.
You gotta get it by the root.
- [Father] Your mother's naive.
- Whoa!
It takes fierce will to
get ahead in this world.
If you're good,
people take advantage of you.
Every one of these top executives-
you know how they got where they are?
- Floated right down the middle of the river.
- [Laughing]
Don't let anyone tell you
there's anything you can't do.
Don't do like I did. Promise me that.
I dreamed of being a great musician.
I let myself get sidetracked.
If you're lookin' for somethin' to happen,
that was it.
That was life. You lived it.
[Man] Job imagined
he might build his nest on high...
that the integrity of his behavior
would protect him against misfortune.
And his friends thought,
mistakenly...
that the Lord could only
have punished him...
because secretly he'd done something wrong.
But no.
Misfortune befalls the good as well.
We can't protect ourselves against it.
We can't protect our children.
We can't say to ourselves,
"Even if I'm not happy...
I'm going to make sure they are."
We run before the wind.
We think that it will carry us forever.
It will not.
We vanish as a cloud.
We wither as the autumn grass...
and, like a tree, are rooted up.
Is there some fraud
in the scheme of the universe?
Is there nothing which is deathless...
nothing which does not pass away?
We cannot stay where we are.
We must journey forth.
We must find that which is
greater than fortune or fate.
Nothing can bring us peace but that.
Is the body of the wise
man or the just...
exempt from any pain...
from any disquietude...
from the deformity
that might blight its beauty...
from the weakness
that might destroy its health?
Do you trust in God?
Job, too, was close to the Lord.
Are your friends and
children your security?
There is no hiding place
in all the world...
where trouble may not find you.
No one knows
when sorrow might visit his house...
any more than Job did.
The very moment everything
was taken away from Job...
he knew it was the Lord
who'd taken it away.
He turned from the
passing shows of time.
He sought that which is eternal.
Does he alone see God's hand
who sees that he gives?
Or does not, also, the
one see God's hand-
- [Father] I'm your man.
- Who sees that he takes away?
Or does he alone see God...
who sees God turn his
face towards him?
Does not, also, he see God...
who sees God turn his back?
That's a friend of mine.
He owns half the real estate in town.
Frank Johnson.
He started out as a barber.
- But he built something big.
- [Laughing]
Now you'd think he's the fourth person
of the holy Trinity.
They never talk about their money.
Wrong people go hungry...
die.
Wrong people get loved.
The world lives by trickery.
If you want to succeed,
you can't be too good.
Hey there, young fellas.
How's it going today?
Do y'all want some barbecue?
[Father]
How about a pound of brisket?
You're like this, right? Okay?
Come on. You act like you're scared.
- You act like you're in trouble.
You don't wanna fight. - Nah.
You don't want any trouble.
The minute you see him blink, crack him, okay?
- Okay.
- Okay? Come on. Three quarters.
Cover. You're gonna cover, right?
Okay. Hit it. Come on.
Nice. Nice. Harder. Nice.
That's a good right. Let's see your left.
That's the most important thing, okay?
You come in this way?
You come in this way? You keep the guard up.
Hit me! Come on, hit me.
Come on! Come on, Jack!
Hit me. Hit me. Hit me. Come on. Come on.
Here. Here it is. Here it is.
Hit it. Come on, Son! Come on! Son.
Left. What are you doing?
Dust yourself off.
Left. Don't leave your tongue out.
You're gonna lose it.
Left. Left.
Right. Right.
Left. Harder. Harder. Harder!
Come on, hit me. Hit me.
Come on, Son. Hit it. Give me something.
Show me what you got.
Come on. Go on.
[Father] One meal.
[Murmurs]
[Chuckling]
Leave the table.
You too?
- You gonna continue to defy me?
- No, sir.
You interrupted me. I wasn't done yet.
Am I finished?
May I?
- [Grunts]
- Thank you, Your Majesty.
♪♪ [Piano]
♪♪ [Guitar]
[Young Jack Whispering]
Makes up stories.
Original words.
- [Laughing]
- [Shouts]
He says, "Don't put
your elbows on the table."
Are you ready?
[Young Jack] He does.
Insults people.
- Doesn't care.
- [Shouts]
[Father]
I remember when you were born.
They wouldn't let me come home.
The navy said an officer must be present
for the laying of the keel...
but... not at the launching.
- [Shouting, Chattering]
- [Bell Clanging]
[Man]
The next word is "volcano."
The next word is "socket."
Please pass your answers to each other.
We're gonna grade each other's papers now.
[Laughing]
[Teacher]
No interruptions, please.
[Laughing Continues]
Come on. Get your pencil out.
After logs go to the paper mill...
♪♪ [Piano]
[Children Shouting]
[Whistle Blowing]
Taylor! Taylor, sweetheart!
Honey! Honey!
Let me go!
[Boys Laughing]
- [Screams]
- [Gasps]
[Young Jack] Was he bad?
[Children Shouting In Distance]
[Youngest Brother]
Will you die too?
[Middle Brother]
You're not that old yet, Mom.
[Young Jack] Where were you?
You let a boy die.
You'll let anything happen.
I can't see!
[Young Jack]
Why should I be good...
if you aren't?
Thank you.
Too close.
Edges.
Why's this bare here, hmm?
- Grass won't grow under the trees.
- Does at the Kimballs'.
- They have a yardman.
- They have money.
Course, he inherited it.
I don't want to hear one more word out
of you, not till this is finished.
Hmm?
[Sniffles]
Cropping that too close.
You're gonna have to keep that watered.
Not high enough.
[Whispers, Kissee]
[Boys Laughing]
Toscanini...
once recorded a piece 65 times.
You know what he said when he finished?
"It could be better."
Think about it.
Twenty-seven patents your father has.
It means ownership.
Ownership of ideas.
You gotta sew 'em up.
Get 'em by the nuts-
- We'll get 'em next time.
- Pardon my French.
[Father] We'll be rich.
You make yourself what you are.
You have control of
your own destiny.
You can't say, "I can't."
You say, "I'm having trouble.
I'm not done yet."
You can't say, "I can't."
[Young Jack]
Why does he hurt us?
Our father.
[Youngest Brother]
Come on, Dix. Come on!
Ah, yeah. Get it! Get it!
Give your father a kiss.
♪♪ [Piano]
- ♪♪ [Warped]
- [Father Chattering, Indistinct]
[Young Jack] He lies.
- Pretends.
- Can you do something for me?
You promise you'll do it
without having to ask what it is?
Just have the confidence
that what your father asks of you is right?
Yes, sir.
For the next half hour, will you not speak
unless you have something important to say?
What'd you do today,
my fine feathered friend?
Sit on the front two inches of your chair.
Better for your posture.
I read that in the paper.
Did you actually buy this from Mr.
Ledbetter?
Don't explain. Just nod- yes or no.
- Hmm?
- No.
Be quiet.
What did you say?
Please.
- [Jack] Leave him alone!
- Come here!
[Mother] Honey!
- [Record Player Needle Scratches]
- Leave him alone!
Come here! Get back. Come here.
Get up there!
[Slamming Furniture]
You turned my own kids against me.
You undermine everything I do.
- How do you like-
- Stop...
Stop it.
Stop it! Stop. Stop it.
[Sobs]
Stop it.
Stop. Stop.
[Sniff ling, Crying]
[Sprinkler Whirring, Hissing]
Where's Dad?
He's gone on a trip.
- [Footsteps Running]
- [Boys Laugh]
♪♪ [Piano]
Whoo!
[Mother Yelps] No!
[Shouting, Laughing]
Open the door!
[Boys Shouting, Indistinct]
- Get her!
- No!
[Mother] Help each other.
Do not slam that screen door!
Love everyone.
- Every leaf.
- [Water Trickling]
- Every ray of light.
- [Laughing]
[Frog Croaking]
Forgive.
[Dog Barking In Distance]
This is my house!
You're allowed to live here!
You are allowed to live here!
Get out of my way!
[Mother] No!
[Father] Shut up!
[Shouts, Indistinct]
[Wind Chimes Tinkling]
[Boy, Faint]
I got it, I got it, I got it!
[Boys Chattering, Shouting]
- Boom! Boom! Boom, boom!
- Boom, boom!
- Watch out!
- Go!
- [All Shouting]
[Boy Laughs]
[Firecracker Pops]
[Boys Shouting]
One, two, three!
I say let's bust 'em.
- Yeah!
[Shouting, Laughing]
Yeah!
[Boy] We found a frog!
Let's go set it off with a skyrocket!
[Boy #2] He's getting away!
Get back! Get back!
[Sparks Crackling]
Did it go to the moon?
[Boy Laughs]
Where is he?
Here he is.
It was an experiment!
[Young Jack] Liar.
Never do it again.
Promise?
You gonna tell Dad?
[Boy]
They're just trying to scare you.
[Boy] Keep you ignorant.
[Young Jack]
Things you got to learn.
How can we know stuff until we look?
- [Boys Chattering]
- [Dog Barking]
[Hammer Clicks]
They say you can't try stuff?
They do.
What do you need to be afraid of?
You're afraid.
I see it.
[Boy #2]
Right here! Right here!
[Sprinkler Whirring, Hissing]
- [Car Door Closes]
- [Engine Starts]
[Car Departing]
[Floorboards Creaking]
[Bird Chirping Softly]
[Panting]
[Dog Barking In Distance]
[Girl Laughs, Mutters]
I can't talk to you.
[Thunder Rumbling]
Don't look at me.
[Sniffles]
[Young Jack]
What have I started?
What have I done?
[Lightbulb Hissing]
[Door Closes]
Stick it in there.
I trust you.
[Lmitates Buzz]
- [Middle Brother] You tired?
- [Jack] Nol
I never get tired!
- Did this morning.
- No, I was just pretending.
- Gonna call me a liar?
- No.
I don't want to fight.
Afraid to?
No, I just don't wanna.
If I was to say you're scared,
would you call me a liar?
No.
[Jack]
Then you're scared, aren't you?
[Grunting, Laughing]
Aha!
Quit it.
Come here.
[Footsteps]
[Mother] Come here!
No!
I'm not gonna do everything you tell me to.
I'm gonna do what I want.
What do you know?
You let him run all over you.
[Young Jack]
How do I get back...
where they are?
[Horn Honks]
- How are you, Son?
- Good.
This one's heavy.
You're gonna need two hands for that one.
Whoa.
Careful now. You know what that...
- Chinese?
- Know what that- That's Chinese.
That's very good. Yes, it is.
Your father went all around the world,
all the way to China.
That's Pan Am airlines.
That's what your father flew on.
The entire bathrooms are stainless steel,
even the washbasin.
- [Giggles]
- I feel confident the deal's going through.
If not, they can forget it.
I'll tell them all to go to hell.
- That's from Germany.
- How do you use them?
[Father] See that?
Put that down, Son.
Can Cayler come over?
Is your family not good enough for you?
[Door Closes]
- [Patrons Chattering]
- Hope it's not gonna take as long as last time.
Al dente.
[Father] Subjective point of view.
You know the difference?
"Subjective" means it comes from your mind.
Can't be proven by other people.
- Mwah.
- [Laughs]
So- Here you go.
Mm, mm, oop, oop, oop.
[Laughs]
- Good to see you again.
- Okay.
Let's go, boys.
Come on.
There are things you can't do?
Well, there are things I can't do either.
You are not to call me "Dad."
You will call me "Father."
- But-
- But- Don't interrupt!
- But you do.
- Don't interrupt!
It's your house.
You can kick me out whenever you want to.
♪♪ [Piano]
You'd like to kill me.
- [Father] No-
- [Young Jack] Dad.
Why was he born?
♪♪ [Fades]
[Insects Chirping]
[Tools Clattering]
[Young Jack Whispering]
Please, God, kill him.
Let him die.
Get him out of here.
She only loves me!
[Man] Def end, O Lord, this thy child
with thy heavenly grace...
that he may continue thine forever...
and daily increase
in thy holy spirit more and more...
until he come unto thy everlasting kingdom.
Amen.
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Spokes Clicking]
I see something.
[Gunshot]
- [Pellet Clatters]
- [Rifle Cocks]
[Gunshot]
Put your finger over it.
Like that.
Come on.
- [Gunshot]
- [No Audio]
[Brother Sobbing]
[Young Jack Whispering]
What I want to do, I can't do.
I do what I hate.
You can hit me if you want.
[Jack] I'm sorry.
You're my brother.
[Young Jack]
What was it you showed me?
I didn't know how to name you then.
But I see it was you.
Always you were calling me.
[Father] I wanted to be
loved because I was great.
A big man.
I'm nothin'.
Look... at the glory around us.
Trees and birds.
I lived in shame.
I dishonored it all
and didn't notice the glory.
I'm a foolish man.
They're closing the plant.
They gave me a choice.
No job...
or a transfer to a job nobody wants.
[Young Jack Whispering] Father.
[Father]
I never missed a day of work.
[Young Jack Whispering] Mother.
[Father] I tithed every Sunday.
[Young Jack Whispering]
Always you wrestle inside me.
Always you will.
You know, Jack,
all I ever wanted for you was...
to make you strong and...
and grow up and be your own boss.
Maybe I've been tough on you.
I'm not proud of that.
I'm as bad as you are.
I'm more like you than her.
You boys are about all I've done in life.
Otherwise I've drawn zilch.
You're all I have.
You're all I want to have.
My sweet boy.
- [Sniff ling]
- [Train Whistle Blows In Distance]
[Crying]
[Children Chattering In Distance]
[Bird Squawking]
You just gonna stand there
like a bump on a log?
Go on.
[Clattering]
Come on.
[Mother]
The only way to be happy is to love.
Unless you love...
your life will flash by.
Do good to them.
Wonder.
Hope.
[Beeping]
[Beeping Fades]
[Adult Jack] Brother.
Keep us...
guide us...
till the end of time.
[Young Jack] Follow me.
[Waves Crashing]
[Seagulls Squawking]
I give him to you.
I give you my son.
[Elevator Beeping]
[Traffic Sounds]
[Chirping]
[Waves Lapping]
[Animals, Insects Chirping]
[Creature Sounds Fade]