It's an impressive collection.
You have some very rare editions here.
Are you sure you
wanna sell them all?
They're no use to
Father, not anymore.
Not since he's been this way.
His library was his whole world.
Now it's just a painful memory.
WOMAN:
Unbearably painful.
I understand.
Well, at a rough preliminary estimate,
you have a collection here...
...worth around $600,000.
Six hundred thousand?
Yes, or thereabouts.
I've picked out one or two volumes
that merit special attention.
This Persiles, for
example, is important.
I'd hang on to that.
It will never depreciate.
It's a good investment.
- Valuable?
- Very valuable.
As for this Hypnerotomachia Di
Poliphili by Colonna, Venice 1545...
...I'm sure I could
find you a buyer.
But I wouldn't let the rest
go for less than $500,000...
...under any circumstances.
It may take a month
to place them.
In the meantime, I advise
you to be patient.
- A month?
- Yes, a month or two.
It depends on how much
of a hurry you're in.
You see, more hurry, less money.
- Of course.
- Well, that's my advice anyway.
I'm sure you wouldn't
want to rush things...
...but please feel free to
consult another expert.
If you have any questions,
you know where to reach me.
Incidentally, this four-volume edition
of Don Quixote is quite nice...
...but not
particularly valuable.
Now, I could take it
off your hands...
...right away.
How much were you thinking of?
I couldn't go more
than 4000, 4200, tops.
MAN:
Fine.
- You here?
- Hello, Witkin.
You didn't waste much time.
There's a small fortune
in there, help yourself.
You're a vulture, Corso.
A vulture.
Who isn't, in our business?
You'd stoop to anything.
For a Quixote by Ybarra?
You bet I would.
Unscrupulous. Thoroughly
unscrupulous.
Happy hunting.
(WHISTLES)
I just got off
the phone with Witkin.
He's spitting blood.
Really?
What's his problem?
He said you're a double-dealing,
money-grubbing bastard.
Thought he had that
deal sewed up.
He said you queered his pitch.
Well, he should've been
quicker off the mark.
May I?
Sure. And he said your
evaluation was way over the top.
Got those people
coming out in a rash.
Now they're asking twice
what those books are worth.
(CORSO CHUCKLES)
Let's face it, you screwed him.
- That's what it's called.
- Yes.
He also said that you
snatched the Don Qui-
Ybarra, Don Quixote, 1780.
All four volumes.
Son of a bitch.
Fantastic.
Fantastic. You are the best.
That client of yours, the Swiss, you
think he'd still be interested in this?
I have Witkin on my ass. I told him
I had no part of this operation.
Except 10 percent.
20 percent. The Swiss
was my client.
- No deal.
- Fifteen, for my children's sake.
- You don't have any children.
- I'm still young, give me time.
Ten.
Hey, man, how you doing?
How about a couple of bucks?
CORSO:
Not today. Not today.
Hey.
(MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
And earlier, in 1580, in De La
Demonomanie Des Sorciers...
...by the Frenchman, Jean Bodin.
Bodin was probably the first to
attempt to establish a system...
...if the term 'system' may be
applied to the Middle Ages...
...for classifying the
contemporary perceptions of evil.
In Bodin, we find one of the first
definitions of the word 'witch. '
And I quote,
"A witch is a person who, though
cognizant of the laws of God..."
"...endeavors to act through the
medium of a pact with the devil."
To assist them in their work,
many witches kept familiars.
That is to say, creatures
such as cats or toads...
...in which supernatural spirits
or demons were thought to reside.
For those of you ladies and gentlemen
who wish to delve more deeply...
...into the controversial
subject of witchcraft...
...a great deal of relevant information
may be found in the following works,
Nicolas Remes'
Demonolatria Libri...
...and Compendium Maleficarum
by Francesco Maria Guazzo.
I see you were stimulated by
my little talk, Mr. Corso.
- Did I snore?
- Well, it's nice of you to ask.
No. Not that I noticed.
Shall we go?
Don't you sleep nights?
- Like a baby.
- Strange.
I'd have bet a brace
of Gutenberg Bibles...
...you spend half the night
with your eyes peeled.
You're one of those lean,
hungry, restless types...
...that put the wind
up Julius Caesar.
Men who stab their
friends in the back.
Not, I suspect, that you have
many friends, do you, Mr. Corso?
Your kind seldom does.
That makes two of us.
You're right, of course.
Your friendships don't
concern me in the least.
Our relations have always been strictly
commercial and that's the way I like it.
The professional and the personal
should be mutually exclusive.
Listen, I came here to do some
business, not shoot the breeze.
If you wanna expound your
personal philosophies...
...write another book.
- You don't like me, do you?
- I don't have to like you.
You're a client
and you pay well.
You're privileged, Mr. Corso.
Very few people ever
set foot in here.
This is my private collection.
Some bibliophiles specialize
in gothic novels...
...others in books of hours.
All my own rare editions
have the same protagonist.
The devil.
- May I take a look?
- Yes.
It's why I brought you here.
(BEEPING)
Beautiful, aren't they?
The soft sheen, the
superb gilding.
Not to mention the centuries
of wisdom they contain.
I know people who would kill
for a collection like this.
The Ars Diavoli.
You'll never see as many books on the
subject anywhere else in the world.
They're the rarest, the
choicest editions in existence.
It's taken me a lifetime
to assemble them.
Only the supreme
masterpiece was missing.
Come.
The Nine Gates of
the Kingdom of Shadows.
- You're familiar with it?
- Yes.
Venice, 1666.
The author and printer, Aristide Torchia,
was burned by the holy Inquisition...
...together with all his works.
Only three copies survived.
One.
Catalog lists three copies
surviving in private ownership,
- Fargas, Kessler and Telfer.
- It's true.
You know your business, but
you're mistaken nonetheless.
According to my own research,
only one is authentic.
Well, three are known.
That's the trouble.
Where'd you get it?
I bought it from Telfer.
- Telfer?
- Yes, he finally sold it to me.
The day before he
killed himself.
It's good timing.
(BALKAN READS LATIN
TEXT IN BOOK)
- Silence is golden.
- Precisely.
Ever heard of the Delomelanicon?
I've heard of it, yes.
It's a myth, isn't it?
A book reputed to have been
written by Satan himself.
No myth.
That book existed.
Torchia actually acquired it.
The engravings you are now
admiring were adapted...
...by Torchia from
the Delomelanicon.
They form a kind
of satanic riddle.
Correctly interpreted with the
aid of the original text...
...and sufficient
inside information...
...they're reputed to conjure up
the prince of darkness in person.
You don't say.
Are you a religious man,
Mr. Corso?
I mean, do you believe
in the supernatural?
I believe in my percentage.
Don't you get dizzy
standing there?
What is it that you
want from me, Balkan?
I want you to go to
Europe and investigate.
The other two copies are
in Portugal and France.
I want you to find some way
of comparing them with mine.
Every page, every engraving,
the binding, everything.
I'm convinced only one is authentic.
I wanna know which.
That could be an expensive trip.
That's to get you started.
Spend what you need.
What if I find that
your copy's a forgery?
It's quite possible.
Really?
It doesn't appear to be.
- Even the paper sounds kosher.
- Even so.
- There's something wrong.
- You mean the devil won't show up?
If all three copies turn out to be bogus
or incomplete your work will be done.
If, on the other hand, one of
them turns out to be genuine...
...I'll finance you further.
I want you to get it for me,
at all costs, never mind how.
- "Never mind how" sounds illegal.
- Wouldn't be the first time...
...you've done
something illegal.
- Not that illegal.
- Hence the size of the check.
Do a good job, I'll double it.
Gotta be something wrong with it if
you're letting it out of your hands.
I have the utmost faith in you,
Mr. Corso.
Nothing more reliable than a man whose
loyalty can be bought for hard cash.
Good morning, I'm Dean Corso.
I'm terribly sorry to disturb
you at a time like this.
It would be very helpful, ma'am, if
you could tell me what you know...
...about this book.
- Isn't this one of my husband's books?
- Right.
It was in his collection until very
recently. He sold it to a client of mine.
I'm trying to authenticate it.
He sold it, you say?
Strange. This was one of his
most treasured possessions.
- He never mentioned the sale?
- No.
It's news to me.
Who bought it?
A private collector.
May I know his name?
I'm afraid that's confidential.
I suppose he has a bill of sale?
- No problem there.
- Is this your job?
Authenticating rare books?
And tracking them down, yes.
You're a book detective.
Kind of.
Do you recall when and where
your husband acquired this book?
In Spain.
We were vacationing at Toledo.
Andrew got very excited.
He paid a great deal
of money for it.
He was a fanatical collector.
So I gather.
I'll show you.
CORSO:
It's impressive.
Andrew used to
spend many hours in here.
Too many.
Did he ever try it out?
I don't understand.
The book.
Did he ever use it to perform
some kind of ritual...
...intended to produce
a supernatural effect?
Are you serious?
Yes, absolutely.
Andrew was a trifle eccentric,
Mr. Corso...
...but he wasn't insane.
It's true he'd been acting...
...strangely those last few days.
He shut himself up in here.
He seldom emerged
except for meals.
That morning, I was awoken...
...by the screams of the maid.
He'd hanged himself.
(SIGHS)
Whatever he was up to...
...I certainly can't see him chanting
mumbo jumbo or trying to raise the dead.
The devil, Mrs. Telfer.
This book is designed
to raise the devil.
(CORSO READING LATIN
TEXT IN BOOK)
Thus let the light shine.
Son of a bitch.
Where did you get this?
CORSO:
Balkan.
Wants me to research it.
Balkan owns a Nine Gates?
Recently acquired from the
late lamented Andrew Telfer.
BERNIE:
Trust Balkan.
What does he need you for? I don't
suppose he plans to sell it.
He wants me to compare it with
the two surviving copies...
...which are in
Portugal and France.
- So I'm off to Europe.
- Compare it?
Yeah. Only one of three's
authentic, he says.
Well, this looks genuine enough.
Christ, it's gotta
be worth a million.
- Take care of it.
- That's why I'm here.
I need you to stash it for me.
- Because I'm starting to see things.
- Like what?
Uninvited visitors,
unfamiliar faces.
I don't trust anyone,
not even Balkan.
Come to think of it, I'm
not even sure I trust you.
You know I wouldn't screw you
unless there was a good reason.
Money, women, business. Other
than that, you can relax.
- I'll pick it up on my way to the airport.
- Sure.
These engravings are terrific.
CORSO:
Or horrific, whichever.
Sensational. Absolutely
sensational.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
- May I come in?
- Mm-hm.
Please, sit down.
- I've come to talk business.
- Mm-hm.
Yesterday, when you came to
see me about that book...
...I was too surprised to
react as I should've done.
I mean, it really was one
of Andrew's favorites.
So you said.
I'd like to get it back.
- That could be a problem.
- Not necessarily. It all depends.
- On what?
- On you.
I don't understand, Mrs. Telfer.
The book is not mine to dispose of.
You work for money, I take it?
- What else?
- I have a great deal of money.
- I'm very happy for you.
- You could stage a theft.
I imagine your client
is well insured.
- I'm a professional, ma'am.
- A professional mercenary.
- Mercenaries work for the highest bidder.
- I make a living.
I could throw in a bonus.
- This has happened before someplace.
- I know. In the movies.
And she had an automatic
in her stocking.
LIANA:
No automatic.
- Would you like a drink?
- Why not?
Okay, where is it?
Where's what?
Don't fuck with me.
I thought I already did.
(CORSO SCREAMING)
Wait. No, no,
wait, wait, wait.
Take it easy. Wait.
Ah!
CORSO:
(PHONE RINGING)
(ON RECORDING)
You have reached Bernie's Rare Books.
Please leave your
message after the beep.
(BEEP)
Bernie, you there?
Pick up.
Bernie.
Give me a minute,
I won't be long.
- You can take me on to Kennedy.
- No problem, sir.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
Bernie?
(WHISTLES)
Bernie.
Oh, Jesus.
Jesus Christ.
Bernie.
DRIVER:
No problem?
Stop.
- Stop at that phone booth. Pull over.
- No problem, sir.
He isn't available
at this time. May I know who's calling?
- Dean Corso.
- Would you like to leave a message?
No. I have to talk
with him at once.
Oh, I'm afraid he's in transit.
Give me your number, I'll have him
return when he checks with us.
No. I am at a phone booth.
It's an emergency.
I have to speak
with him right now.
Right now, do you hear me?
Right now.
One moment.
- Jesus Christ.
- Are you there, Mr. Corso?
- Yes.
- I'll patch you through.
Mr. Corso,
what have you got for me?
- More than I bargained for.
- What do you mean?
I mean I quit. I wanna return the book.
Where are you?
I'm disappointed in you,
Mr. Corso.
You never let me down before.
Well, this is different.
- You remember Bernie Ornstein?
- Ornstein?
- Yeah.
- The dealer?
I gave him your book to stash for
me, and now he's dead. Murdered.
Because of the book?
What else?
Well, I never said it would be easy.
If it's a question of money...
It isn't the money. I want out.
This matter means a great
deal to me, Mr. Corso.
I'm not an ungenerous
man, you know that.
Proceed as arranged and you can
tack another zero onto your fee.
Final call for
passengers traveling to Paris...
Hey, where are you, Balkan?
Balkan?
(WOMAN & BOY SPEAKING SPANISH)
- Buenas tardes.
- Do you speak English?
- Yes, I do.
I would like to get
your opinion on this.
(MAN COUGHING)
What a habit for a bookbinder.
The Nine Gates, superb edition.
Very rare. The Telfer copy.
Yes. You used to own it, right?
- We used to, yes.
- Sold it.
We sold it when the
opportunity presented itself.
- It was too good to-
- Too good to miss.
- An excellent sale.
- An excellent buy.
- Impeccable condition.
- Impeccable.
- Are you the present owner?
- No. A client of mine.
I would never have believed she
would part with it, never.
- She?
- Mrs. Telfer.
Uh-huh.
I understood that it was
Mr. Telfer that had bought it.
He paid for it.
It was Mrs. Telfer
who made him buy it.
- He didn't seem particularly...
- Interested.
An exceptional specimen.
- Do you think it could be a forgery?
- Forgery?
- You hear that, Pablo?
- I took you for a professional.
- You speak too lightly of forgeries.
- Far too lightly.
Forging a book is
very expensive.
Paper of the period, right inks.
Too expensive to be profitable.
- Still, it can be done.
- Of course.
Requires a great skill,
but, yes, it can be done.
Do you think that could
be the case here?
What makes you ask?
My client wishes to satisfy himself
on the book's authenticity.
His name is Balkan. Boris
Balkan of New York.
- All books have a destiny of their own.
- And a life of their own.
Mr. Balkan is a celebrated collector.
He's no fool.
He must know this
book is authentic.
- We know it.
- So must he.
- We had this book for years.
- Many years.
And ample opportunity
to study it thoroughly.
The printing, the binding
are magnificent examples...
...of 17th century
Venetian craftsmanship.
Finest rag paper, resistant
to the passage of time.
None of your modern wood pulp.
Watermarks, ink, typefaces.
If this is a forgery, or a copy
with missing pages restored...
...it's the work of a master.
- A master.
- Yes.
Have you studied the engravings?
They seem to have some
underlying significance.
But of course.
Here, for example.
This one could be
interpreted as a warning.
"Venture too far," it seems to say, "and
danger will descend on you from above."
These type of books often
contain little puzzles.
Especially in the case of such
an illustrious collaborator.
Collaborator?
You could not have proceeded very
far in your research, señor.
Here, look close.
Now, you see? Only six of
the nine engravings...
...were signed by
Aristide Torchia.
CORSO:
Yes. And the other three?
PABLO:
This is one of them.
"LCF."
- Who's LCF?
- Think.
Lucifer?
Very perceptive of you, señor.
Torchia was burned alive
because he wrote this book...
...in collaboration
with someone else.
Come on. You can't
honestly believe-
The man who wrote this book did
so in alliance with the devil...
...and went to the stake for it.
Even hell has its heroes, señor.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(CLANGING)
I've seen you before.
- Have you?
- Yes.
Are you traveling in this car?
- The next one.
- The sleeper.
I travel on the cheap.
You're a student?
Something like that.
- I like trains.
- Trains I'm on?
Just trains.
What's your name?
Guess.
- Green eyes.
- That'll do.
- What's yours?
- Corso.
Strange name.
Italian. It means "run."
You don't look like
a runner to me.
More the quiet type.
Well, give my regards to Balkan.
- Tell him I'm doing my best.
- Balkan?
CORSO:
Never mind.
GIRL:
See you around.
Maybe.
CORSO:
I wouldn't be surprised.
(BELL RINGING)
Sí?
Yes, Dean Corso, Mr. Fargas.
Corso? Oh, yes. Please, come in.
Thank you.
Please.
Home, sweet home.
You won't say no to a
brandy, I take it?
CORSO:
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
What handsome glasses.
They're the only
ones I have left.
Thanks.
- Must've been a beautiful place.
- It was.
But old families are like
ancient civilizations...
...they wither and die.
There they are, 834 our of them.
A pity you didn't see
them in better times.
I used to have 5000.
But these are the survivors.
So this is the
Fargas collection?
Not quite as I imagined
it, I must say.
C'est la vie, my friend.
But I keep them in perfect condition.
Safe from damp, light, heat, rats.
I dust and air them every day.
These are the occult.
What do you think?
- Not bad.
- Not bad indeed.
At least 10 of them are
extremely rare. Here.
Plancy's Dictionnaire Infernal.
First edition, 1844.
Leonardo Fioravanti's
Compendio de Secreti, 1571.
And there it is.
In perfect condition.
It has traveled the world for
three and a half centuries...
...yet it might've been
printed yesterday.
Is it in order? I mean, you haven't
detected anything unusual?
Unusual? No. The text is
complete, the engravings too.
Nine, plus the title page,
just as the catalog states...
...just like Kessler in Paris
and Telfer in New York.
Yes. It isn't the
Telfer anymore.
Telfer killed himself.
But he sold his copy
to Boris Balkan first.
Balkan.
If he sets his heart on a
book, no price is too high.
Not that I would
ever sell this one.
Not at any price.
It's...
It's strange that he
should've sent you here...
...if he already had...
You have it here?
May I see it?
Superb.
Beautiful.
Identical.
Two of the only three
to escape the flames...
...reunited for the first
time in over three centuries.
Yes.
Look at this slight
imperfection here.
The damaged S.
The same type, the
same impression.
Incredible.
You see, if it weren't for
this slight discoloration...
...on the back of your copy,
no one could tell them apart.
If you don't mind, I'd like to stay for
a while and examine them in detail.
What are you looking for,
Mr. Corso?
I'm not quite sure.
Some books are dangerous.
Not to be opened with impunity.
That's very true.
I'll be damned.
(PHONE RINGING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hello again.
- You didn't say you were bound for Sintra.
- Neither did you.
- What are you doing here?
- Reading.
- I can see that.
- And bumping into people.
Unexpectedly.
Yes. Unexpectedly is right.
Are you on a business trip?
Is that why you always
carry that thing around?
- Is this part of your course?
- My course?
Winning friends and
influencing people.
- You said you were a student.
- Did I?
So I am. In a way.
I like books.
Do you?
- Have you been traveling long?
- A while.
I don't suppose you ever
travel by motorbike.
Excuse me, senhor.
(SPEAKING PORTUGUESE)
CORSO:
For me? You're sure?
The phone, sir.
- Yes?
- Mr. Corso?
My God. How'd you find me?
Made any progress?
Progress? Yeah, you
could call it that.
Well?
I can't talk here, I'm in the lobby.
Let me call you back. Where are you?
Never mind that. Get them to
transfer it to your room, I'll wait.
All right.
Senhor, pardon me. Could you
send this up to my room, please?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
(PHONE RINGING)
- Still there?
- Yes.
All right.
I've examined the Fargas copy.
It's authentic enough, at
least it looks that way.
It's like yours, but
there are discrepancies.
Discrepancies?
The engravings, they're
not identical.
It's, like, keys in
different hands...
...doorways open in one copy
and bricked up in the other.
- And there's another thing.
- Yes.
Yes, go on.
Ones that differ aren't signed "Torchia.
" They're signed "LCF."
- Still there?
- LCF?
Listen, where are you, anyway?
I must have that copy,
Mr. Corso.
Get it for me.
The old man wouldn't sell it to
save his life. He said as much.
Did he?
Hello?
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(KNOCKING)
Just a minute.
Yeah.
- What time is it?
- Early, but you have to go.
- Go? Go where?
- The Fargas place.
I've already seen Fargas.
I think you should
see him again.
What is this, some kind of practical joke?
Who are you?
- What do you know about Fargas?
- Get dressed. I'll wait for you outside.
(BELL RINGING)
Don't bother.
He isn't there.
Oh, really? Then where is he?
Over there.
God almighty.
Wanna get inside?
I had thought about it, yes.
You wait here.
Shit.
Well? Did you find it?
You know, it's come to my attention
that you know too goddamn much.
- Why do you keep following me around?
- You're wasting time asking questions.
Better get out of here. There's a
flight from Lisbon to Paris at noon.
- We should just make it.
- What's with the "we"?
There are two of
us, aren't there?
What happened back there?
The old man caught someone
stealing, I guess.
- What do you guess happened to him?
- He drowned.
- With a little help from who?
- He's dead. Who cares?
I do.
I could easily wind
up the same way.
Not with me around
to look after you.
Oh, I see. You're my
guardian angel then.
If you say so.
- Someone's playing a game with me.
- Of course. You're a part of it.
And you're getting to like it.
(WOMAN SPEAKING FRENCH ON PA)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
- Hello, Gruber.
- Hello, Mr. Corso.
Delighted to see you again.
We don't have any vacancies...
...but I'm sure I'll be
able to organize something.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
(DOOR BUZZES)
CORSO:
Good afternoon.
I'm Dean Corso. I have an
appointment with Baroness Kessler.
This way.
You have 30 minutes.
- Yes?
- Monsieur Corso.
Oh, yes, Mr. Corso. Come in.
- I've heard a great deal about you.
- Oh.
- Nothing good, I hope.
- You hope right. Merci, Simone.
Well, I'm reassured, baroness,
because in my trade...
...to be spoken well of can
be professionally disastrous.
- My God.
- Yes, there it is.
The Kessler collection.
I know your catalog
almost by heart.
Strange we haven't met before.
Your name is a byword among
dealers and collectors.
But I imagine you know your own
reputation better than I do.
Yes, well, it does keep the wolf
from the door, so to speak.
Sorry, were you in the
middle of something?
My latest work, The Devil, History
and Myth, a kind of biography.
It will be published
early next year.
- Why the devil?
- I saw him one day.
I was 15 years old and I saw
him as plain as I see you now.
It was love at first sight.
You know, 300 years ago, you'd
have been burned at the stake...
- ...for saying something like that.
- I wouldn't have said it.
Nor would I have made a
million by writing about it.
Yeah.
What is it you wish to discuss,
Mr. Corso?
There's a book in your collection
I'd like to examine, if possible.
The Nine Gates of the
Kingdom of Shadows?
The Nine Gates.
An interesting work.
Everyone's been asking
me about it lately.
- Is that so?
- Follow me.
Do you truly believe
in the devil, baroness?
Enough to devote my
life and my library to him.
Not to mention many
years of work.
Don't you?
Almost.
This book demands a
certain amount of faith.
I'm afraid my faith is in
short supply these days.
I know this work extremely well.
I've studied it for years.
Do you have any doubts
about its authenticity?
- None whatsoever.
- You're sure?
My knowledge of this
book is profound.
- I wrote a biography of its author.
- Yes, I've read it.
Aristide Torchia, The Devil's Apprentice.
Excellent work.
A courageous man.
He died for the sake of
this very book in 1667.
While studying the black arts in
Prague, he acquired a copy...
...of the dread Delomelanicon.
This is Torchia's adaptation of that work
which was written by Lucifer himself.
After they burned him at the stake,
a secret society was founded...
...to perpetuate its memory
and preserve its secrets.
The Order of the Silver Serpent.
- A sect?
- A kind of witches' coven.
For centuries, they have met
to read from this book...
...and worship the
prince of darkness.
Today, they have degenerated
into a social club...
...for bored millionaires and
celebrities who use its meetings...
...as an excuse to indulge
their jaded sexual appetites.
I, myself, belonged
to the order.
Years ago, but time is
too precious at my age.
Besides, my orgy days are over.
I told them to go to the devil.
(KESSLER CHUCKLES)
You mean it's all
about sex or...?
Of course not.
They are under the illusion that
they owe their money and success...
...to membership in the order.
Do they still meet?
Every year on the anniversary
of Torchia's death.
They'll be meeting
very soon now.
- And you say they read from this book.
- Not this one.
I took mine back when Liana Telfer
acquired the one in Toledo.
Victor Fargas is a nonbeliever.
He's always refused to participate, so
naturally, they use the Telfer copy.
Not that it has ever worked.
- Did Andrew Telfer ever take part?
- Telfer?
No, no.
That creature, Liana,
married him for his money.
She comes of an old and
aristocratic French family...
...the Saint Martins, but
they were penniless...
...so Liana used his dollars
to restore her chateau...
...and buy The Nine Gates.
If he ever finds out what his wife
gets up to at these gatherings...
...he'll probably kill himself.
Funny you should say that, baroness,
he hanged himself last week.
Who, exactly, are you
working for, Mr. Corso?
My client's name is irrelevant, baroness.
I'm simply trying to authenticate his copy.
The one that Telfer sold
him before he died.
How stupid of me. I
should have guessed.
You've outstayed your welcome,
Mr. Corso.
I was hoping to examine
your copy in detail.
Certainly not.
Tell your client, who can
only be Boris Balkan...
...to come and examine
it himself, if he dares.
Tell him not to send any more
wolves in sheep's clothing.
Now, kindly leave.
I'm sorry if I
have troubled you.
Thank you very much
for your time.
You don't know what you're getting
yourself into, Mr. Corso.
Get out, before it's too late.
I'm afraid it already
is, baroness.
Good day.
(PHONE RINGS)
(SIMONE SPEAKING FRENCH)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
They're broken.
You should be more careful.
- I need a favor, Gruber.
- Certainly, Mr. Corso.
Liana Telfer.
Maiden name de Saint Martin,
40ish, brunette, dishy.
Probably accompanied by...
...a black gentleman with closely cropped
platinum blond hair and a mustache.
I wanna know if they're
staying at some hotel here.
- Take a little time.
- Yes, of course.
Start with the five-stars,
that's your best bet.
- Very well, sir.
- All right.
Are you feeling all right?
I've felt better, Gruber.
Thanks.
Let me know if you locate them.
Put this against the
back of your neck.
You were really great
down there by the river.
I haven't thanked you for that.
All right, look.
I think it's about time you
told me what's going on here.
- Someone's after your book.
- No kidding.
And you, where do
you fit into it?
(PHONE RINGING)
Yeah?
WOMAN:
There's a call for you.
May I take it in
reception, please?
All right, I'll be right down.
- Yes?
- Anything new?
Oh, his master's voice again.
No, not much aside
from the fact...
...that someone's tried to take
my life a couple of times.
- Oh, yes. Fargas has been murdered.
- Oh.
Murdered? How do you know?
I saw him. And his copy.
Or what was left of it, anyway.
Someone had snatched the engravings
and tried to burn the rest.
- What do you make of it?
- That's tragic. It's tragic.
What about Baroness Kessler?
How did you get on today?
- Where exactly are you?
- What about her copy?
No. Why do I get
the impression...
...that you've been down
my neck the entire time?
You're an investment of mine, Mr. Corso.
I'm merely looking after it.
The old woman swears her
copy's authentic...
...but I didn't get a chance
to examine it closely.
She threw me out as soon as she guessed
that you were behind my visit.
You aren't exactly in her good
books, if you know what I mean.
- You must see her again.
- What, are you kidding?
- Have you seen her secretary?
- Try the lunch break.
Hello?
(MAN SNORING)
(BELL RINGING)
Do you have a photocopy
machine back there?
Oh, yes, monsieur.
- May I use it?
- Of course, monsieur.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
(ON INTERCOM)
Oui.
Yes. Hello, baroness, it's me,
the wolf in sheep's clothing.
I thought I made myself
quite clear, Mr. Corso.
Well, I've got something
for you, baroness.
A kind of peace offering.
Will you allow me
to give it to you?
Please?
(DOOR BUZZES)
CORSO:
First, let me apologize.
I should've told you right away
that I'm working for Boris Balkan.
It was foolish of me to think that I could
deceive someone as astute as yourself.
- So please forgive me.
- Flattery will get you nowhere, Mr. Corso.
Get on with it.
Right.
These...
...are for you.
What is this?
What is this supposed to be?
You said that your knowledge of
The Nine Gates was extensive...
...but did you ever compare
your copy with the other two?
No.
- Why?
- Well, you should.
These are copies of the
engravings in Balkan's book.
You'll find that some of
them differ from yours.
Differ?
So you question my book's
authenticity, do you?
If that's your peace offering,
you can take it and go.
My Nine Gates is
absolutely genuine.
I don't dispute that, baroness.
In my opinion, all three
copies are genuine.
But the fact remains,
they display variations.
Variations?
If that were true, it
would be a revelation.
What makes you so sure?
I've already compared these
with the Fargas engravings.
And in his book...
...the keys were
in the other hand.
Here, the doorway
wasn't bricked up.
And in this one...
...the man was hanging
by the other leg.
- Well?
- Well, what?
CORSO:
Look closely, baroness.
The turrets.
Three in yours...
...four in Balkan's.
Amazing.
I'm convinced there'll be a
third one in here somewhere.
Three variations in three
copies makes nine.
Coincidence, or something more?
Maybe Torchia hid the secret of the
Ninth Gate in three books, not one.
I must admit I'm impressed.
This puts an entirely different
complexion on the matter.
You have my permission to
investigate further, Mr. Corso.
Take as long as you need.
My permission did not
extend to that, Mr. Corso.
Nobody smokes in my library.
(THUMP)
(GROANING)
(BANGING)
CORSO:
Baroness?
Baroness.
(SIREN WAILING)
Excuse me, there's something
missing from my room.
Has anyone been up
there while I was out?
Only your wife, monsieur.
My wife? I don't have a wife.
(PHONE RINGS)
Excuse me, monsieur.
(MAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
For you, sir.
(PHONE RINGS)
- Yes?
- What news?
News?
Let me see.
Well...
Yes, the good news is that I got
to examine the old woman's book...
...and three of her
engravings were signed "LCF."
The bad news is that someone strangled her
and made a bonfire of her collection.
- Now, that's tragic, wouldn't you say?
- You took the words out my mouth.
Yes. It's the Fargas
story all over again.
I'm of the mind that they
tore out the engravings...
...before they
torched the place.
That makes two sets they've got.
And my copy?
Well, I learned my
lesson, fortunately.
I don't carry it around
with me anymore.
Otherwise, it might've
gone up in smoke.
Excellent. Good thinking.
Well, with two copies gone...
...that seems to conclude
your assignment.
It only remains for you
to return my book.
I'm staying at the Ritz. You can
pick up your check at the same time.
Shall we say in half an hour?
There's more bad news.
- I don't have it.
- You don't have it?
Someone lifted it from my room.
Listen to me very carefully,
Mr. Corso.
I think you may already
have some idea...
...of the lengths to which I am
prepared to go when I want something.
Unless you recover my property
in double-quick time...
...you'll discover just
how far that can be.
(PHONE HANGS UP)
- Where is it?
- Where's what?
The book, where is it?
Would I be here if I took it?
You should know better by now.
I must apologize for my young
colleague, Mr. Corso...
...that was unpardonable of him.
Is that her?
No, monsieur.
She was tall, dark hair,
very chic, very elegant.
Which reminds me, sir, I have
the information you wanted.
The lady and gentleman
you mentioned...
...they are staying at the
Plaza Athénée Hotel...
...Suite 209, 211.
Thank you very much, Gruber.
I owe you one.
I need a taxi, quick.
(GRUBER SPEAKING FRENCH)
Send this to Mr. Balkan at the Ritz.
That's B-A-L-K-A-N.
- Fax it, immediately.
- Certainly, sir.
Always a pleasure
to be of service.
You coming?
Monsieur.
What do you plan to
do if you see them?
Probably hide behind you.
(PEOPLE SPEAKING FRENCH)
Whoa, that's them. That's them.
We should grab a taxi
before they take off.
Let's go.
They're going.
(HORN HONKING)
Coming?
Couldn't you pick something
less conspicuous?
Don't be so picky.
Some people would give their
eyeteeth for a ride in this.
Listen, we can't sit on their tail
forever, they're bound to smell a rat.
How do I look?
You look ridiculous.
Sit tight.
(HORN HONKING)
Take your pick.
No, you.
- You know everything.
- If you say so.
We lost them.
Well, not at this speed.
Must've gone the other way.
You mean, I don't know
everything after all?
Turn around.
30ish, brunette, dishy.
- What was her name again?
- Telfer. Liana Telfer.
No, her maiden name.
- Saint Martin.
- Look.
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANT)
(CHURCH BELL RINGING)
CORSO:
Monsier.
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
The chateau, I knew it.
Merci.
Keep going.
GIRL:
See them anywhere?
CORSO:
No.
- Sorry to intrude on you like this.
- What are you doing here?
I just dropped by to pick up
the book you stole from my room.
- That book is mine.
- We've been through this before.
My husband gave it to me.
- Well...
- It wasn't his to sell.
Sold it to get back at you.
What happened?
- Catch you with that albino?
- How dare you?
CORSO:
Keep an eye on her.
LIANA:
Don't.
CORSO:
Be careful. She bites.
Hi.
Don't move.
Either one of you.
Get the book.
Don't kill them up here,
you'll make a mess.
Take them downstairs.
You, go first.
And you.
Down.
Open the door.
Watch out.
I didn't know you had it in you.
(SPEAKING IN LATIN)
(CROWD CHANTING IN LATIN)
(LIANA SPEAKING IN LATIN)
You stay here and cover me.
I'm going down.
(LIANA SPEAKING IN LATIN)
(CROWD CHANTING IN LATIN)
MAN:
Who's that?
Mumbo jumbo,
mumbo jumbo, mumbo jumbo.
Look around you, all of you.
What do you see?
A bunch of buffoons,
in fancy dress.
Think the prince of darkness would
actually deign to manifest himself...
...before the likes of you? He
never has, and he never will.
Never.
You read from his book...
...but you have no conception
of its true power.
I, alone, have
grasped its secret.
I, alone, have fathomed the
master's grand design.
I, alone, am worthy to enjoy
the fruits of that discovery.
Absolute power to
determine my own destiny.
You're insane, Boris.
Give it back to me.
You, Liana de Saint Martin...
...you're even guiltier than the
rest of this pathetic rabble.
You have at least some idea of what
this book can do in the right hands.
Yet, you lend yourself to
these farcical proceedings...
...these orgies of aging flesh
conducted in the master's name.
You're a charlatan.
LIANA:
Ah!
Don't, Corso. Don't.
(CRACK)
Let it be.
Boo!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
- What is it with you?
- He just murdered someone in public.
You're off the hook...
...for the other killings.
- You should be grateful.
- I'm ecstatic.
You're out of a job. It's over.
What more do you want?
You know what.
Not taking me for a ride?
- You were working for him all along.
- Funny, I thought you were.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Shit.
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
- Madame.
- Oui.
(CORSO SPEAKING FRENCH)
(WOMAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
(MAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SHEEP BAAING)
BALKAN:
Yes.
That's it.
Precisely.
All is in readiness.
One...
...four...
...three, six, seven...
...five, eight, two, nine.
The enigma is solved at last.
To travel in silence...
...by a long and
circuitous route...
...to brave the arrows of misfortune
and fear neither noose, nor fire.
To play the greatest of all games
and win, foregoing no expense...
...is to mock the vicissitudes of
fate and gain at last the key...
...that will unlock...
...the ninth gate.
Corso.
What were you
expecting, an apparition?
You're not wanted here,
Mr. Corso. Leave.
I'm the only apparition
you'll see tonight.
You'll find a check waiting
at my New York office.
Payment in full.
You killed for those.
- They're worth more than money.
- Infinitely more.
But they happen to be mine.
Not yours.
You know something, Corso?
In spite of our differences...
...I have a soft spot for you.
- I'm touched.
- We have something in common.
We share the same passion.
You've developed the same
obsession, haven't you?
Unfortunately for you, only one
of us is destined to fulfill it.
You're out of your depth.
Kindly go.
I'm not leaving
here empty-handed.
Don't even think about it.
Stand aside.
I credited you
with more finesse.
- You heard me. Stand back.
- Put that away, it's not your style.
(GRUNTING)
It seems you've found your
proper niche at last.
I like that.
Now...
...you can watch.
I'm entering
uncharted territory.
Taking the road that leads
to equality with God.
Ooh.
You can't come with me.
I must travel alone,
but you may look on...
...and marvel.
- That's very kind of you.
- Indeed it is.
There have been men who
have been burned alive...
...or disemboweled for
just a glimpse...
...of what you are
about to witness.
I give you my
allegiance, master.
I pledge myself to
you, body and soul.
Let me fear neither noose,
nor fire, nor poison.
Erase me from the
book of life...
...inscribe me in the
black book of death.
Admit me to the ninth gate.
Let it be so.
Let it be so now.
Yes.
I feel the power surge through
me like an electric current...
...rendering me capable of
any feat of mind or body.
I'm invulnerable.
I'm invincible.
(LAUGHING)
I could float on air, I
could walk on water.
Behold.
I plunge my hands in fire.
I feel no heat.
That's just great.
Give us another one.
(SPEAKING LATIN)
(BALKAN SPEAKING LATIN)
It's miraculous.
(LAUGHS)
I feel nothing. Nothing at all.
(LAUGHING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(GUNSHOT)
Is that it?
Is the game over?
For Balkan, yes.
Not for you.
Why didn't it work for Balkan?
The ninth engraving
was a forgery.
Where's the real one?
I want it.
You're running low on gas.
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
(CORSO SPEAKING SPANISH)
Pepe Lopez.
Ricardo Herrera.
Do you speak English?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)