1
00:00:45,671 --> 00:00:48,606
<i>[Waves Lapping, Faint]</i>

2
00:01:16,902 --> 00:01:18,529
<i>[Man Whispers]</i> <i>Brother.</i>

3
00:01:24,343 --> 00:01:25,970
<i>Mother.</i>

4
00:01:31,316 --> 00:01:34,012
<i>It was they who led me to your door.</i>

5
00:01:35,620 --> 00:01:37,588
<i>[Bird Squawking]</i>

6
00:01:45,530 --> 00:01:50,263
<i>♪♪ [Choir Singing. ; Dirge]</i>

7
00:02:04,383 --> 00:02:07,511
<i>[Woman] The nuns taught us</i>
<i>there are two ways through life-</i>

8
00:02:09,254 --> 00:02:11,950
<i>the way of nature...</i>

9
00:02:12,057 --> 00:02:14,218
<i>and the way of grace.</i>

10
00:02:15,327 --> 00:02:17,795
<i>You have to choose which
one you'll follow.</i>

11
00:02:30,609 --> 00:02:32,804
<i>Grace doesn't try to please itself.</i>

12
00:02:35,680 --> 00:02:39,980
<i>Accepts being slighted,
forgotten, disliked.</i>

13
00:02:44,189 --> 00:02:47,158
<i>Accepts insults and injuries.</i>

14
00:02:58,670 --> 00:03:00,137
Ooh!

15
00:03:02,007 --> 00:03:03,975
[Child Chattering, Faint]

16
00:03:05,710 --> 00:03:08,804
<i>Nature only wants to please itself.</i>

17
00:03:08,914 --> 00:03:13,044
- Bless, O Lord, this food to our use-
- <i>Get others to please it too.</i>

18
00:03:13,151 --> 00:03:14,778
[Father]
...your loving and faithful service.

19
00:03:14,886 --> 00:03:16,615
<i>Likes to lord it over them.</i>

20
00:03:16,721 --> 00:03:18,621
<i>[Father]</i> <i>Bless these boys.</i>

21
00:03:18,723 --> 00:03:21,191
<i>[Woman]</i> <i>To have its own way.</i>

22
00:03:25,664 --> 00:03:28,224
<i>It finds reasons to be unhappy...</i>

23
00:03:28,333 --> 00:03:31,598
<i>when all the world is
shining around it...</i>

24
00:03:32,671 --> 00:03:35,469
<i>when love is smiling
through all things.</i>

25
00:03:50,789 --> 00:03:54,520
<i>They taught us that no one</i>
<i>who loves the way of grace...</i>

26
00:03:54,626 --> 00:03:57,288
<i>ever comes to a bad end.</i>

27
00:04:04,870 --> 00:04:07,031
<i>[Woman]</i> <i>I will be true to you.</i>

28
00:04:09,040 --> 00:04:10,371
<i>Whatever comes.</i>

29
00:04:33,265 --> 00:04:35,233
<i>♪♪ [Choir Fades]</i>

30
00:05:00,559 --> 00:05:01,856
[Sobs] Oh, God!

31
00:05:01,960 --> 00:05:04,087
[Engine Roaring]

32
00:05:05,497 --> 00:05:07,397
[No Audible Dialogue]

33
00:05:33,792 --> 00:05:35,316
[Engine Roaring Fades]

34
00:05:51,343 --> 00:05:53,243
<i>[Bell Tolls]</i>

35
00:06:31,750 --> 00:06:33,718
- [Child Chattering, Faint]
- <i>[Mother Whispers] My son.</i>

36
00:06:41,660 --> 00:06:45,027
[Quiet Sob]
I just want to die...

37
00:06:45,130 --> 00:06:47,098
<i>to be with him.</i>

38
00:07:27,305 --> 00:07:30,240
<i>[Older Man]</i>
<i>He's in God's hands now.</i>

39
00:07:36,014 --> 00:07:38,881
[Mother]
He was in God's hands the whole time.

40
00:07:41,653 --> 00:07:43,518
<i>Wasn't he?</i>

41
00:07:47,659 --> 00:07:49,559
<i>My hope.</i>

42
00:07:54,332 --> 00:07:55,959
<i>My God.</i>

43
00:08:02,574 --> 00:08:04,667
<i>"I shall fear no evil-</i>

44
00:08:06,344 --> 00:08:08,744
<i>fear no evil, for you are with me. "</i>

45
00:08:08,847 --> 00:08:10,781
<i>What did you gain?</i>

46
00:08:10,882 --> 00:08:13,146
<i>"Be not far from me,
for trouble is near."</i>

47
00:08:13,251 --> 00:08:15,446
[Father]
Okay, go on now. We're all right.

48
00:08:18,389 --> 00:08:20,482
We're all right.

49
00:08:29,334 --> 00:08:31,427
Thank you. Thank you.

50
00:08:36,374 --> 00:08:40,367
- Sure, you have your memories of him, and, uh-
- [Mother Crying Quietly]

51
00:08:40,478 --> 00:08:42,571
You're gonna have to be strong now and...

52
00:08:45,850 --> 00:08:48,614
I know the pain will...

53
00:08:48,720 --> 00:08:50,585
It will pass in time, you know?

54
00:08:50,688 --> 00:08:53,350
It might seem... hard, my saying that...

55
00:08:53,458 --> 00:08:54,982
but it's true.

56
00:08:55,093 --> 00:08:57,061
[Whispers] I don't want it to.

57
00:08:59,697 --> 00:09:01,597
Life goes on.

58
00:09:03,601 --> 00:09:05,501
People pass along.

59
00:09:07,272 --> 00:09:09,638
Nothing stays the same.

60
00:09:12,844 --> 00:09:15,210
You've still got the other two.

61
00:09:21,386 --> 00:09:23,911
- [Quiet Sob]
- The Lord gives, and the Lord takes away...

62
00:09:24,022 --> 00:09:26,115
and...

63
00:09:26,224 --> 00:09:28,192
that's the way he is.

64
00:09:34,365 --> 00:09:36,629
He sends flies to wounds...

65
00:09:36,734 --> 00:09:38,861
that he should heal.

66
00:09:38,970 --> 00:09:41,495
<i>[Woman Screams, Faint]</i>

67
00:09:55,920 --> 00:09:59,048
<i>[Father] I never got a chance</i>
<i>to tell him how sorry I was.</i>

68
00:10:05,463 --> 00:10:07,363
One night he...

69
00:10:09,334 --> 00:10:13,031
punched him- himself in the face
for no reason.

70
00:10:20,378 --> 00:10:22,346
He was sitting next to me at the piano...

71
00:10:22,447 --> 00:10:25,075
and I criticized the way
he turned the pages.

72
00:10:43,134 --> 00:10:45,466
I made him feel shame.

73
00:10:47,138 --> 00:10:48,765
My shame.

74
00:10:53,745 --> 00:10:56,509
[Whispers] That poor boy.

75
00:10:56,614 --> 00:10:58,514
That poor boy.

76
00:11:28,146 --> 00:11:30,273
<i>[Man]</i> <i>How did you come to me?</i>

77
00:11:37,221 --> 00:11:39,416
<i>In what shape?</i>

78
00:11:43,895 --> 00:11:45,624
<i>What disguise?</i>

79
00:13:09,480 --> 00:13:11,448
<i>I see the child that I was.</i>

80
00:13:11,549 --> 00:13:14,211
[Birds Chirping]

81
00:13:19,190 --> 00:13:20,987
[Children Shouting, Faint]

82
00:13:21,092 --> 00:13:23,560
- <i>I see my brother.</i>
- <i>[Water Running]</i>

83
00:13:26,464 --> 00:13:28,091
<i>True.</i>

84
00:13:30,535 --> 00:13:31,661
<i>Kind.</i>

85
00:13:39,110 --> 00:13:41,635
<i>He died when he was 19.</i>

86
00:13:49,120 --> 00:13:52,055
- [Clanging, Faint]
- [People Chattering, Walking]

87
00:14:14,278 --> 00:14:17,475
Just check this- this one against this.

88
00:14:17,582 --> 00:14:21,450
She wants to get back together,
but... that chapter's closed...

89
00:14:21,552 --> 00:14:23,452
story's been told.

90
00:14:24,655 --> 00:14:26,623
What are you gonna do?

91
00:14:28,059 --> 00:14:29,686
<i>Experiment.</i>

92
00:14:33,364 --> 00:14:35,958
When you're young,
it's all about your career.

93
00:14:36,834 --> 00:14:39,064
You don't understand anything.

94
00:14:46,944 --> 00:14:50,311
I just feel like I'm bumping into walls.

95
00:15:03,027 --> 00:15:05,723
I didn't know how to do her hair.

96
00:15:24,248 --> 00:15:26,682
<i>[Mechanical Beeping]</i>

97
00:15:26,784 --> 00:15:30,550
Hey, Dad.
I'm sorry I said what I said. L...

98
00:15:37,261 --> 00:15:39,661
Yeah. Yeah, I think about him every day.

99
00:15:39,764 --> 00:15:43,325
<i>I just shouldn't have said what
I did,</i> <i>and I'm sorry.</i>

100
00:15:47,138 --> 00:15:49,971
<i>No, it's just, oh, this day.</i>

101
00:15:52,009 --> 00:15:53,704
<i>[Father]</i> <i>What are you thinkin'?</i>

102
00:15:53,811 --> 00:15:56,143
<i>[Son] I know- I know</i>
<i>you did everything you could.</i>

103
00:15:56,247 --> 00:15:59,341
[Son's Colleague] And only two of those
were turned down by the client.

104
00:15:59,450 --> 00:16:01,077
One of them...

105
00:16:05,990 --> 00:16:09,016
<i>[Waves Lapping]</i>

106
00:16:21,038 --> 00:16:23,165
<i>[Son]</i> <i>How did I lose you?</i>

107
00:16:30,381 --> 00:16:32,008
<i>Wandered?</i>

108
00:16:36,587 --> 00:16:38,248
<i>Forgot you?</i>

109
00:16:53,204 --> 00:16:56,196
<i>[Wind Whistling]</i>

110
00:17:27,204 --> 00:17:28,432
<i>[Waves Crashing]</i>

111
00:17:37,948 --> 00:17:39,848
<i>[Young Boy]</i> <i>Find me.</i>

112
00:18:04,675 --> 00:18:06,643
<i>[Son]</i> <i>How did she bear it?</i>

113
00:18:16,454 --> 00:18:18,081
<i>Mother.</i>

114
00:18:20,124 --> 00:18:22,251
<i>[Mother Screams]</i>

115
00:18:55,726 --> 00:18:57,921
<i>[Mother Whispering]</i>
<i>Was I false to you?</i>

116
00:19:44,675 --> 00:19:46,302
<i>[Mother]</i> <i>Lord.</i>

117
00:19:53,651 --> 00:19:55,278
<i>Why?</i>

118
00:20:02,960 --> 00:20:04,951
<i>Where were you?</i>

119
00:21:06,524 --> 00:21:08,651
<i>[Mother Whispering]</i>
<i>Did you know?</i>

120
00:21:24,608 --> 00:21:26,576
<i>Who are we to you?</i>

121
00:21:46,263 --> 00:21:48,231
<i>Answer me.</i>

122
00:21:52,303 --> 00:21:55,500
<i>[Rumbling]</i>

123
00:24:41,371 --> 00:24:44,340
[Explosions]

124
00:25:59,183 --> 00:26:01,276
<i>[Mother]</i> <i>We cry to you.</i>

125
00:26:07,825 --> 00:26:09,622
<i>My soul.</i>

126
00:26:18,335 --> 00:26:19,962
<i>My son.</i>

127
00:26:28,378 --> 00:26:30,005
<i>Hear us.</i>

128
00:27:16,526 --> 00:27:19,120
[Loud Hissing]

129
00:27:24,401 --> 00:27:26,733
[Gurgling]

130
00:28:12,883 --> 00:28:15,181
<i>[Thunder Rumbling]</i>

131
00:30:32,189 --> 00:30:36,319
<i>[Ocean Waves Roaring]</i>

132
00:34:34,531 --> 00:34:36,726
<i>[Mother]</i> <i>Light of my life.</i>

133
00:34:40,003 --> 00:34:42,130
<i>I search for you.</i>

134
00:34:46,609 --> 00:34:48,236
<i>My hope.</i>

135
00:34:58,755 --> 00:35:00,689
<i>My child.</i>

136
00:36:06,723 --> 00:36:09,521
<i>[Bell Tolls]</i>

137
00:36:20,370 --> 00:36:22,497
<i>[Son]</i>
<i>You spoke to me through her.</i>

138
00:36:26,309 --> 00:36:28,834
<i>You spoke with me from the sky.</i>

139
00:36:30,847 --> 00:36:32,474
<i>The trees.</i>

140
00:36:37,420 --> 00:36:39,752
<i>Before I knew I loved you...</i>

141
00:36:42,192 --> 00:36:44,160
<i>believed in you.</i>

142
00:36:52,869 --> 00:36:54,837
[Insects Chirping]

143
00:37:02,579 --> 00:37:05,275
<i>When did you first touch my heart?</i>

144
00:38:36,105 --> 00:38:38,164
[Faint Murmuring]

145
00:38:55,658 --> 00:38:58,593
[Crying, Faint]

146
00:39:35,498 --> 00:39:38,296
<i>♪♪ [Mother Singing, Faint]</i>

147
00:39:40,103 --> 00:39:42,333
[Man]
And manfully to fight under his banner...

148
00:39:42,438 --> 00:39:44,906
against sin, the world and the devil.

149
00:40:25,815 --> 00:40:28,147
We had the commander over for dinner.

150
00:40:28,251 --> 00:40:30,719
This little devil bit
him right on the ankle.

151
00:40:48,971 --> 00:40:50,871
[Son] Mama!

152
00:41:02,618 --> 00:41:03,846
Me!

153
00:41:50,867 --> 00:41:53,199
[Clanging]

154
00:42:11,187 --> 00:42:13,178
[Whispers] Rhinoceros.

155
00:42:13,289 --> 00:42:14,984
Two alligator.

156
00:42:15,091 --> 00:42:16,888
Two alligators.

157
00:42:21,497 --> 00:42:25,024
- Kangaroo.
- Kangaroo.

158
00:42:35,578 --> 00:42:36,806
<i>Jump.</i>

159
00:42:48,891 --> 00:42:52,349
<i>[Gentle Ocean Waves]</i>

160
00:43:04,073 --> 00:43:06,871
- [Boy Chattering]
- Mmm.

161
00:43:10,613 --> 00:43:12,513
[Baby Cooing]

162
00:43:27,797 --> 00:43:29,560
Ah!

163
00:43:40,610 --> 00:43:44,239
- [Crying]
- Sweetheart.

164
00:43:45,681 --> 00:43:48,741
- Shh! Please.
- [Whining]

165
00:43:50,486 --> 00:43:52,920
I know. No!

166
00:43:53,022 --> 00:43:54,819
No!

167
00:44:04,166 --> 00:44:05,827
[Clattering]

168
00:44:08,638 --> 00:44:10,105
[Kissee]

169
00:44:19,215 --> 00:44:21,342
It's mine!

170
00:44:24,854 --> 00:44:26,515
You found me.

171
00:45:02,792 --> 00:45:05,886
You'll be grown before that tree is tall.

172
00:45:10,266 --> 00:45:12,359
<i>[Son As Child]</i>
<i>Blue. Far.</i>

173
00:45:15,171 --> 00:45:17,264
<i>You.</i>

174
00:45:22,511 --> 00:45:26,914
[Barking]

175
00:45:29,452 --> 00:45:30,919
Are you afraid?

176
00:45:33,189 --> 00:45:34,816
Come here.

177
00:46:28,010 --> 00:46:31,036
Come here. All right. Now, come back here, Son.
Stay out of there.

178
00:46:31,147 --> 00:46:32,944
That's the Spencers' yard. Okay?

179
00:46:33,049 --> 00:46:37,315
You see this line? Let's not cross it.
Do you understand?

180
00:46:37,420 --> 00:46:40,150
Hmm? Do you understand?

181
00:46:40,256 --> 00:46:42,986
You see this line? Lookit here. Look here.

182
00:46:44,860 --> 00:46:47,328
Okay. Now, come back here, Son.
Come on back.

183
00:46:54,537 --> 00:46:56,164
Stay out of there.

184
00:47:09,552 --> 00:47:11,747
[Giggling]

185
00:47:13,089 --> 00:47:16,581
"'Now, my dears, '
said old Mrs. Rabbit one morning..."

186
00:47:16,692 --> 00:47:19,024
'you may go into the fields
or down the lane...

187
00:47:20,229 --> 00:47:22,663
<i>but don't go into Mr.
McGregor's garden. ;</i>

188
00:47:23,699 --> 00:47:25,792
<i>Father had an accident there. "'.</i>

189
00:47:32,475 --> 00:47:35,137
That's where God lives.

190
00:48:01,971 --> 00:48:06,340
Good night. We'll see ya in five years.

191
00:49:00,329 --> 00:49:02,490
[Both Laughing]

192
00:49:02,598 --> 00:49:05,089
You want to eat a grasshopper?

193
00:49:05,201 --> 00:49:07,669
I found a dinosaur bone!

194
00:49:07,770 --> 00:49:09,067
Oh!

195
00:49:09,171 --> 00:49:11,071
- Is that a rock?
- No.

196
00:49:16,612 --> 00:49:17,909
Ah.

197
00:49:20,683 --> 00:49:22,310
[Laughs] Hey!

198
00:49:36,298 --> 00:49:37,925
[Mother] Boys!

199
00:49:38,968 --> 00:49:40,265
Come home!

200
00:49:44,907 --> 00:49:46,534
Boys!

201
00:49:54,383 --> 00:49:56,681
Come home!

202
00:49:58,520 --> 00:50:00,886
[Boy Shouting, Indistinct]

203
00:50:00,990 --> 00:50:03,959
[Laughing, Chattering]

204
00:50:09,131 --> 00:50:11,361
You're a "potleak" now!

205
00:50:11,467 --> 00:50:14,163
- You're filthy!
- [Shouts, Indistinct]

206
00:50:14,270 --> 00:50:16,170
[Laughs]

207
00:50:19,308 --> 00:50:24,143
Bless this food to our use and us to
your loving and faithful service...

208
00:50:24,246 --> 00:50:27,773
and make us ever mindful
of those who are in need.

209
00:50:27,883 --> 00:50:29,510
Amen.

210
00:50:29,618 --> 00:50:33,349
<i>♪♪ [Record Player. ; Classical]</i>

211
00:50:36,659 --> 00:50:39,594
Can you pass the butter, please?

212
00:50:39,695 --> 00:50:42,425
- "Can you pass the butter, please, sir?"
- Sir.

213
00:50:44,333 --> 00:50:46,062
What'd you do today?

214
00:50:47,102 --> 00:50:49,434
- Went to school.
- After that?

215
00:50:50,906 --> 00:50:54,706
What about the yard?
Did you put the runners in like I asked?

216
00:50:56,478 --> 00:50:57,945
Yeah.

217
00:50:58,047 --> 00:50:59,674
Yes, sir.

218
00:51:01,450 --> 00:51:03,748
[Father]
Well, it didn't look like it.

219
00:51:19,535 --> 00:51:21,162
- Hmm?
- Yes.

220
00:51:34,416 --> 00:51:36,384
Mr. Reese liked Jack's book report...

221
00:51:36,485 --> 00:51:38,817
- [Father] What is that, sweetheart?
- And wanted him to make a model.

222
00:51:39,888 --> 00:51:41,913
You know this?

223
00:51:43,459 --> 00:51:48,226
<i>♪♪ [Orchestra. ; Dramatic]</i>

224
00:51:51,367 --> 00:51:53,460
Brahms.

225
00:52:05,447 --> 00:52:07,005
<i>Son?</i>

226
00:52:07,116 --> 00:52:08,413
Sir?

227
00:52:09,585 --> 00:52:11,883
Reach me my lighter.

228
00:52:19,395 --> 00:52:21,363
Haven't you forgotten somethin'?

229
00:52:46,388 --> 00:52:48,356
Do you love your father?

230
00:52:49,525 --> 00:52:51,152
Yes, sir.

231
00:52:53,228 --> 00:52:55,753
<i>[Mother]</i>
<i>"... against the Panther...</i>

232
00:52:55,864 --> 00:52:59,459
and they went off
to look for Kaa the Rock Python.

233
00:53:02,004 --> 00:53:06,839
They found him stretched out
on a warm ledge in the afternoon sun...

234
00:53:06,942 --> 00:53:09,433
"admiring his beautiful new coat."

235
00:53:19,154 --> 00:53:21,122
Who do you love the most?

236
00:53:26,495 --> 00:53:28,929
I love you all three the same.

237
00:53:30,666 --> 00:53:33,635
Tell us a story from
before we can remember.

238
00:53:37,506 --> 00:53:39,474
[Mother]
Went for a ride in a plane once.

239
00:53:43,245 --> 00:53:45,543
<i>It was a graduation present.</i>

240
00:54:01,063 --> 00:54:02,690
<i>[Young Jack Whispers]</i> <i>Mother.</i>

241
00:54:11,406 --> 00:54:13,306
<i>Make me good.</i>

242
00:54:20,849 --> 00:54:22,476
<i>Brave.</i>

243
00:55:36,258 --> 00:55:39,056
- ♪♪ [Humming]
- [Gasps]

244
00:55:42,030 --> 00:55:45,193
[Shouts]
Aah! Aah!

245
00:57:21,730 --> 00:57:24,062
<i>[Youngest Brother]</i>
<i>Can it happen to anyone?</i>

246
00:57:25,100 --> 00:57:26,727
Shh.

247
00:57:30,706 --> 00:57:32,833
<i>[Young Jack]</i>
<i>Nobody talks about it.</i>

248
00:57:37,245 --> 00:57:39,008
<i>Help me not to sass my dad.</i>

249
00:57:41,583 --> 00:57:44,677
Help me not to get dogs in fights.

250
00:57:58,934 --> 00:58:01,903
Help me be thankful for
everything I've got.

251
00:58:04,039 --> 00:58:06,166
<i>[Young Jack]</i> <i>Where do you live?</i>

252
00:58:07,209 --> 00:58:09,006
Help me not to tell lies.

253
00:58:16,752 --> 00:58:19,050
<i>[Whispering]</i>
<i>Are you watching me?</i>

254
00:58:19,154 --> 00:58:23,056
[Chattering, Shouting]

255
00:58:29,030 --> 00:58:31,157
<i>I want to know what you are.</i>

256
00:58:37,839 --> 00:58:40,364
<i>I want to see what you see.</i>

257
00:58:57,061 --> 00:59:00,462
<i>♪♪ [Organ]</i>

258
00:59:33,264 --> 00:59:35,562
- <i>[Father] Come here, youl</i>
- <i>[Boys Shouting]</i>

259
00:59:35,666 --> 00:59:38,658
- Come here. Come here, you!
- [Laughing]

260
00:59:40,704 --> 00:59:42,467
That funny?

261
00:59:44,542 --> 00:59:46,772
[Door Slams]

262
00:59:48,646 --> 00:59:52,309
You're gonna stand there, and you're
gonna close this door quietly 50 times.

263
00:59:53,751 --> 00:59:56,242
Count it out.

264
00:59:56,353 --> 00:59:59,413
Three, four...

265
00:59:59,523 --> 01:00:02,321
<i>five, six...</i>

266
01:00:02,426 --> 01:00:05,088
<i>seven, eight-</i>

267
01:00:05,196 --> 01:00:08,688
You can't just yank off the top.
You gotta get it by the root.

268
01:00:16,507 --> 01:00:18,475
- <i>[Father] Your mother's naive.</i>
- Whoa!

269
01:00:18,576 --> 01:00:21,374
<i>It takes fierce will to
get ahead in this world.</i>

270
01:00:23,013 --> 01:00:25,641
<i>If you're good,</i>
<i>people take advantage of you.</i>

271
01:00:32,056 --> 01:00:35,492
<i>Every one of these top executives-</i>
<i>you know how they got where they are?</i>

272
01:00:35,593 --> 01:00:39,154
- <i>Floated right down the middle of the river.</i>
- [Laughing]

273
01:00:40,564 --> 01:00:44,000
<i>Don't let anyone tell you</i>
<i>there's anything you can't do.</i>

274
01:00:45,836 --> 01:00:48,805
Don't do like I did. Promise me that.

275
01:00:50,875 --> 01:00:52,843
I dreamed of being a great musician.

276
01:00:53,878 --> 01:00:57,314
I let myself get sidetracked.

277
01:00:57,414 --> 01:01:00,110
If you're lookin' for somethin' to happen,
that was it.

278
01:01:00,217 --> 01:01:01,912
That was life. You lived it.

279
01:01:18,802 --> 01:01:22,898
<i>[Man] Job imagined</i>
<i>he might build his nest on high...</i>

280
01:01:23,007 --> 01:01:27,740
<i>that the integrity of his behavior</i>
<i>would protect him against misfortune.</i>

281
01:01:27,845 --> 01:01:29,745
<i>And his friends thought,
mistakenly...</i>

282
01:01:29,847 --> 01:01:32,577
that the Lord could only
have punished him...

283
01:01:32,683 --> 01:01:36,278
because secretly he'd done something wrong.

284
01:01:36,387 --> 01:01:37,877
But no.

285
01:01:37,988 --> 01:01:41,515
Misfortune befalls the good as well.

286
01:01:41,625 --> 01:01:43,786
We can't protect ourselves against it.

287
01:01:43,894 --> 01:01:46,362
We can't protect our children.

288
01:01:46,463 --> 01:01:49,296
We can't say to ourselves,
"Even if I'm not happy...

289
01:01:49,400 --> 01:01:52,130
I'm going to make sure they are."

290
01:01:52,236 --> 01:01:54,136
We run before the wind.

291
01:01:54,238 --> 01:01:56,968
We think that it will carry us forever.

292
01:01:57,074 --> 01:01:58,598
It will not.

293
01:01:58,709 --> 01:02:00,540
We vanish as a cloud.

294
01:02:00,644 --> 01:02:02,908
We wither as the autumn grass...

295
01:02:03,013 --> 01:02:06,278
and, like a tree, are rooted up.

296
01:02:08,419 --> 01:02:11,650
Is there some fraud
in the scheme of the universe?

297
01:02:11,755 --> 01:02:14,121
Is there nothing which is deathless...

298
01:02:14,224 --> 01:02:17,125
nothing which does not pass away?

299
01:02:19,263 --> 01:02:21,458
<i>We cannot stay where we are.</i>

300
01:02:21,565 --> 01:02:23,829
<i>We must journey forth.</i>

301
01:02:23,934 --> 01:02:28,371
<i>We must find that</i> <i>which is
greater than fortune or fate.</i>

302
01:02:29,406 --> 01:02:32,569
<i>Nothing can bring us peace but that.</i>

303
01:02:33,677 --> 01:02:36,840
<i>Is the body of the wise
man or the just...</i>

304
01:02:36,947 --> 01:02:38,847
<i>exempt from any pain...</i>

305
01:02:38,949 --> 01:02:41,042
<i>from any disquietude...</i>

306
01:02:41,151 --> 01:02:43,881
<i>from the deformity</i>
<i>that might blight its beauty...</i>

307
01:02:43,988 --> 01:02:47,116
<i>from the weakness</i>
<i>that might destroy its health?</i>

308
01:02:49,226 --> 01:02:52,059
<i>Do you trust in God?</i>

309
01:02:52,162 --> 01:02:55,893
<i>Job, too, was close to the Lord.</i>

310
01:02:56,000 --> 01:02:58,662
<i>Are your friends and
children your security?</i>

311
01:03:00,204 --> 01:03:02,434
<i>There is no hiding place
in all the world...</i>

312
01:03:02,539 --> 01:03:04,803
<i>where trouble may not find you.</i>

313
01:03:04,908 --> 01:03:07,672
<i>No one knows</i>
<i>when sorrow might visit his house...</i>

314
01:03:07,778 --> 01:03:10,872
<i>any more than Job did.</i>

315
01:03:10,981 --> 01:03:14,109
<i>The very moment everything</i>
<i>was taken away from Job...</i>

316
01:03:14,218 --> 01:03:17,346
<i>he knew it was the Lord
who'd taken it away.</i>

317
01:03:19,590 --> 01:03:22,582
<i>He turned from the
passing shows of time.</i>

318
01:03:22,693 --> 01:03:25,127
<i>He sought that which is eternal.</i>

319
01:03:26,563 --> 01:03:30,897
<i>Does he alone see God's hand</i>
<i>who sees that he gives?</i>

320
01:03:31,001 --> 01:03:33,026
<i>Or does not, also, the
one see God's hand-</i>

321
01:03:33,137 --> 01:03:36,629
- [Father] I'm your man.
- <i>Who sees that he takes away?</i>

322
01:03:36,740 --> 01:03:39,208
<i>Or does he alone see God...</i>

323
01:03:39,309 --> 01:03:41,470
<i>who sees God turn his
face towards him?</i>

324
01:03:43,480 --> 01:03:47,041
<i>Does not, also, he see God...</i>

325
01:03:47,151 --> 01:03:48,778
<i>who sees God turn his back?</i>

326
01:03:48,886 --> 01:03:51,719
That's a friend of mine.
He owns half the real estate in town.

327
01:03:53,924 --> 01:03:55,551
Frank Johnson.

328
01:03:56,593 --> 01:03:59,562
He started out as a barber.

329
01:04:00,831 --> 01:04:04,392
- But he built something big.
- [Laughing]

330
01:04:04,501 --> 01:04:07,561
Now you'd think he's the fourth person
of the holy Trinity.

331
01:04:09,706 --> 01:04:12,231
They never talk about their money.

332
01:04:15,145 --> 01:04:17,113
Wrong people go hungry...

333
01:04:18,749 --> 01:04:20,341
die.

334
01:04:22,453 --> 01:04:25,388
Wrong people get loved.

335
01:04:27,224 --> 01:04:29,215
The world lives by trickery.

336
01:04:32,096 --> 01:04:35,065
If you want to succeed,
you can't be too good.

337
01:04:42,606 --> 01:04:45,575
Hey there, young fellas.
How's it going today?

338
01:04:46,643 --> 01:04:48,611
Do y'all want some barbecue?

339
01:04:50,781 --> 01:04:52,976
[Father]
How about a pound of brisket?

340
01:05:20,410 --> 01:05:23,504
You're like this, right? Okay?
Come on. You act like you're scared.

341
01:05:23,614 --> 01:05:25,809
- You act like you're in trouble.
You don't wanna fight. - Nah.

342
01:05:25,916 --> 01:05:28,976
You don't want any trouble.
The minute you see him blink, crack him, okay?

343
01:05:29,086 --> 01:05:31,350
- Okay.
- Okay? Come on. Three quarters.

344
01:05:31,455 --> 01:05:34,481
Cover. You're gonna cover, right?
Okay. Hit it. Come on.

345
01:05:34,591 --> 01:05:37,822
Nice. Nice. Harder. Nice.
That's a good right. Let's see your left.

346
01:05:37,928 --> 01:05:40,522
That's the most important thing, okay?
You come in this way?

347
01:05:40,631 --> 01:05:43,464
You come in this way? You keep the guard up.
Hit me! Come on, hit me.

348
01:05:43,567 --> 01:05:48,004
Come on! Come on, Jack!
Hit me. Hit me. Hit me. Come on. Come on.

349
01:05:48,105 --> 01:05:51,370
Here. Here it is. Here it is.
Hit it. Come on, Son! Come on! Son.

350
01:05:51,475 --> 01:05:53,875
Left. What are you doing?

351
01:05:57,548 --> 01:06:00,381
Dust yourself off.

352
01:06:00,484 --> 01:06:03,942
Left. Don't leave your tongue out.
You're gonna lose it.

353
01:06:04,054 --> 01:06:06,079
Left. Left.

354
01:06:06,190 --> 01:06:07,919
Right. Right.

355
01:06:08,025 --> 01:06:11,483
Left. Harder. Harder. Harder!

356
01:06:11,595 --> 01:06:13,756
Come on, hit me. Hit me.

357
01:06:13,864 --> 01:06:16,526
Come on, Son. Hit it. Give me something.

358
01:06:16,633 --> 01:06:18,601
Show me what you got.

359
01:06:20,204 --> 01:06:22,195
Come on. Go on.

360
01:06:27,945 --> 01:06:29,572
[Father] One meal.

361
01:06:33,383 --> 01:06:35,010
[Murmurs]

362
01:06:42,326 --> 01:06:44,726
[Chuckling]

363
01:06:44,828 --> 01:06:46,728
Leave the table.

364
01:06:52,636 --> 01:06:54,263
You too?

365
01:06:55,939 --> 01:06:57,930
- You gonna continue to defy me?
- No, sir.

366
01:06:58,041 --> 01:07:01,067
You interrupted me. I wasn't done yet.

367
01:07:04,114 --> 01:07:05,877
Am I finished?

368
01:07:06,917 --> 01:07:08,544
May I?

369
01:07:09,720 --> 01:07:12,382
- [Grunts]
- Thank you, Your Majesty.

370
01:07:15,359 --> 01:07:20,194
<i>♪♪ [Piano]</i>

371
01:07:28,639 --> 01:07:31,608
♪♪ [Guitar]

372
01:08:08,912 --> 01:08:11,039
<i>[Young Jack Whispering]</i>
<i>Makes up stories.</i>

373
01:08:14,151 --> 01:08:16,051
<i>Original words.</i>

374
01:08:21,692 --> 01:08:24,024
- [Laughing]
- [Shouts]

375
01:08:24,127 --> 01:08:27,187
<i>He says,</i> <i>"Don't put
your elbows on the table."</i>

376
01:08:27,297 --> 01:08:29,094
Are you ready?

377
01:08:29,199 --> 01:08:31,099
<i>[Young Jack]</i> <i>He does.</i>

378
01:08:34,604 --> 01:08:36,504
<i>Insults people.</i>

379
01:08:37,974 --> 01:08:39,601
- <i>Doesn't care.</i>
- [Shouts]

380
01:08:39,710 --> 01:08:42,008
<i>[Father]</i>
<i>I remember when you were born.</i>

381
01:08:47,150 --> 01:08:49,118
They wouldn't let me come home.

382
01:08:50,887 --> 01:08:54,323
The navy said an officer must be present
for the laying of the keel...

383
01:08:54,424 --> 01:08:58,383
but... not at the launching.

384
01:09:28,792 --> 01:09:31,955
- [Shouting, Chattering]
- [Bell Clanging]

385
01:09:42,472 --> 01:09:44,702
[Man]
The next word is "volcano."

386
01:09:55,285 --> 01:09:57,276
The next word is "socket."

387
01:10:03,360 --> 01:10:07,160
Please pass your answers to each other.
We're gonna grade each other's papers now.

388
01:10:09,866 --> 01:10:12,892
[Laughing]

389
01:10:13,003 --> 01:10:14,903
[Teacher]
No interruptions, please.

390
01:10:15,005 --> 01:10:16,597
[Laughing Continues]

391
01:10:16,706 --> 01:10:19,174
Come on. Get your pencil out.

392
01:10:24,147 --> 01:10:26,615
After logs go to the paper mill...

393
01:10:29,820 --> 01:10:33,449
<i>♪♪ [Piano]</i>

394
01:11:05,055 --> 01:11:07,421
[Children Shouting]

395
01:11:26,009 --> 01:11:28,978
[Whistle Blowing]

396
01:11:39,823 --> 01:11:43,418
Taylor! Taylor, sweetheart!

397
01:11:43,527 --> 01:11:45,825
Honey! Honey!

398
01:11:52,736 --> 01:11:54,135
Let me go!

399
01:12:45,055 --> 01:12:47,353
<i>[Boys Laughing]</i>

400
01:13:01,104 --> 01:13:02,833
- [Screams]
- [Gasps]

401
01:13:14,184 --> 01:13:15,981
<i>[Young Jack]</i> <i>Was he bad?</i>

402
01:13:16,086 --> 01:13:19,055
[Children Shouting In Distance]

403
01:13:25,595 --> 01:13:28,063
[Youngest Brother]
Will you die too?

404
01:13:30,900 --> 01:13:33,391
<i>[Middle Brother]</i>
<i>You're not that old yet, Mom.</i>

405
01:13:51,121 --> 01:13:52,918
<i>[Young Jack]</i> <i>Where were you?</i>

406
01:14:05,135 --> 01:14:07,035
<i>You let a boy die.</i>

407
01:14:14,044 --> 01:14:16,512
<i>You'll let anything happen.</i>

408
01:14:29,793 --> 01:14:31,317
I can't see!

409
01:14:31,428 --> 01:14:33,225
I can't see!

410
01:14:36,933 --> 01:14:38,833
<i>[Young Jack]</i>
<i>Why should I be good...</i>

411
01:14:42,872 --> 01:14:45,500
<i>if you aren't?</i>

412
01:15:34,457 --> 01:15:36,084
Thank you.

413
01:15:50,807 --> 01:15:53,367
Too close.

414
01:15:53,476 --> 01:15:55,444
Edges.

415
01:15:55,545 --> 01:15:58,036
Why's this bare here, hmm?

416
01:15:58,148 --> 01:16:01,447
- Grass won't grow under the trees.
- Does at the Kimballs'.

417
01:16:01,551 --> 01:16:04,645
- They have a yardman.
- They have money.

418
01:16:04,754 --> 01:16:06,722
Course, he inherited it.

419
01:16:08,758 --> 01:16:12,159
I don't want to hear one more word out
of you, not till this is finished.

420
01:16:23,973 --> 01:16:25,531
Hmm?

421
01:16:26,576 --> 01:16:28,043
[Sniffles]

422
01:16:29,612 --> 01:16:31,170
Hmm?

423
01:16:53,069 --> 01:16:54,696
Cropping that too close.

424
01:16:54,804 --> 01:16:56,465
You're gonna have to keep that watered.

425
01:17:03,913 --> 01:17:05,813
Not high enough.

426
01:17:05,915 --> 01:17:07,883
[Whispers, Kissee]

427
01:17:11,621 --> 01:17:13,521
[Boys Laughing]

428
01:17:24,100 --> 01:17:25,965
Toscanini...

429
01:17:26,069 --> 01:17:28,264
once recorded a piece 65 times.

430
01:17:28,371 --> 01:17:30,771
You know what he said when he finished?

431
01:17:30,874 --> 01:17:32,899
"It could be better."

432
01:17:34,410 --> 01:17:36,037
Think about it.

433
01:17:38,615 --> 01:17:41,083
Twenty-seven patents your father has.

434
01:17:42,652 --> 01:17:45,553
<i>It means ownership.
Ownership of ideas.</i>

435
01:17:47,156 --> 01:17:49,420
<i>You gotta sew 'em up.
Get 'em by the nuts-</i>

436
01:17:49,525 --> 01:17:52,050
- We'll get 'em next time.
- <i>Pardon my French.</i>

437
01:17:52,161 --> 01:17:53,856
<i>[Father]</i> <i>We'll be rich.</i>

438
01:17:57,000 --> 01:17:59,468
<i>You make yourself what you are.</i>

439
01:18:03,072 --> 01:18:05,870
<i>You have control of
your own destiny.</i>

440
01:18:08,978 --> 01:18:10,946
<i>You can't say, "I can't."</i>

441
01:18:12,115 --> 01:18:14,015
<i>You say, "I'm having trouble.</i>

442
01:18:15,285 --> 01:18:17,014
I'm not done yet."

443
01:18:18,821 --> 01:18:21,255
<i>You can't say, "I can't."</i>

444
01:18:55,158 --> 01:18:57,353
<i>[Young Jack]</i>
<i>Why does he hurt us?</i>

445
01:18:59,696 --> 01:19:01,323
<i>Our father.</i>

446
01:19:07,303 --> 01:19:09,134
[Youngest Brother]
Come on, Dix. Come on!

447
01:19:09,238 --> 01:19:10,569
Ah, yeah. Get it! Get it!

448
01:19:24,854 --> 01:19:26,879
Give your father a kiss.

449
01:19:45,341 --> 01:19:47,809
<i>♪♪ [Piano]</i>

450
01:20:03,559 --> 01:20:06,027
- <i>♪♪ [Warped]</i>
- <i>[Father Chattering, Indistinct]</i>

451
01:20:06,129 --> 01:20:07,687
<i>[Young Jack]</i> <i>He lies.</i>

452
01:20:11,401 --> 01:20:13,699
- <i>Pretends.</i>
- Can you do something for me?

453
01:20:13,803 --> 01:20:16,237
You promise you'll do it
without having to ask what it is?

454
01:20:16,339 --> 01:20:18,967
Just have the confidence
that what your father asks of you is right?

455
01:20:19,075 --> 01:20:20,838
Yes, sir.

456
01:20:20,943 --> 01:20:25,642
For the next half hour, will you not speak
unless you have something important to say?

457
01:20:31,087 --> 01:20:33,555
What'd you do today,
my fine feathered friend?

458
01:20:35,425 --> 01:20:39,794
Sit on the front two inches of your chair.
Better for your posture.

459
01:20:39,896 --> 01:20:41,864
I read that in the paper.

460
01:20:45,001 --> 01:20:48,368
Did you actually buy this from Mr.
Ledbetter?

461
01:20:48,471 --> 01:20:51,099
Don't explain. Just nod- yes or no.

462
01:20:52,375 --> 01:20:54,002
- Hmm?
- No.

463
01:20:56,546 --> 01:20:57,843
Be quiet.

464
01:21:00,883 --> 01:21:02,851
What did you say?

465
01:21:05,655 --> 01:21:07,282
Please.

466
01:21:07,390 --> 01:21:09,017
- [Jack] Leave him alone!
- Come here!

467
01:21:09,125 --> 01:21:11,286
[Mother] Honey!

468
01:21:11,394 --> 01:21:14,852
- [Record Player Needle Scratches]
- Leave him alone!

469
01:21:18,201 --> 01:21:20,567
Come here! Get back. Come here.

470
01:21:24,907 --> 01:21:26,807
Get up there!

471
01:21:32,682 --> 01:21:35,310
[Slamming Furniture]

472
01:22:23,032 --> 01:22:24,761
You turned my own kids against me.

473
01:22:26,469 --> 01:22:28,403
You undermine everything I do.

474
01:22:37,680 --> 01:22:39,272
- How do you like-
- Stop...

475
01:22:40,116 --> 01:22:41,413
Stop it.

476
01:22:41,517 --> 01:22:44,645
Stop it! Stop. Stop it.

477
01:22:46,055 --> 01:22:47,989
[Sobs]

478
01:22:48,758 --> 01:22:50,089
Stop it.

479
01:22:53,029 --> 01:22:54,496
Stop it.

480
01:23:00,036 --> 01:23:02,163
Stop. Stop.

481
01:23:36,939 --> 01:23:39,908
[Sniff ling, Crying]

482
01:23:40,009 --> 01:23:42,204
[Sprinkler Whirring, Hissing]

483
01:25:01,290 --> 01:25:03,155
Where's Dad?

484
01:25:03,259 --> 01:25:05,318
He's gone on a trip.

485
01:25:07,596 --> 01:25:10,690
- [Footsteps Running]
- [Boys Laugh]

486
01:25:10,800 --> 01:25:13,769
<i>♪♪ [Piano]</i>

487
01:25:14,570 --> 01:25:16,470
Whoo!

488
01:25:17,039 --> 01:25:18,506
Whoo!

489
01:25:24,847 --> 01:25:26,314
[Mother Yelps] No!

490
01:25:32,054 --> 01:25:34,147
[Shouting, Laughing]

491
01:25:35,991 --> 01:25:37,856
Open the door!

492
01:25:46,302 --> 01:25:48,896
[Boys Shouting, Indistinct]

493
01:25:49,004 --> 01:25:50,471
- Get her!
- No!

494
01:25:50,573 --> 01:25:52,063
<i>[Mother]</i> <i>Help each other.</i>

495
01:25:53,409 --> 01:25:56,344
Do not slam that screen door!

496
01:25:58,147 --> 01:26:00,945
<i>Love everyone.</i>

497
01:26:02,952 --> 01:26:04,852
- <i>Every leaf.</i>
- <i>[Water Trickling]</i>

498
01:26:06,522 --> 01:26:09,047
- <i>Every ray of light.</i>
- [Laughing]

499
01:26:12,762 --> 01:26:14,855
[Frog Croaking]

500
01:26:16,632 --> 01:26:18,497
<i>Forgive.</i>

501
01:26:35,451 --> 01:26:38,352
[Dog Barking In Distance]

502
01:26:45,995 --> 01:26:47,895
This is my house!

503
01:26:47,997 --> 01:26:49,726
You're allowed to live here!

504
01:26:49,832 --> 01:26:51,959
You are allowed to live here!

505
01:26:53,669 --> 01:26:55,466
Get out of my way!

506
01:26:55,571 --> 01:26:57,334
[Mother] No!

507
01:26:57,440 --> 01:26:59,237
[Father] Shut up!

508
01:27:01,444 --> 01:27:03,207
[Shouts, Indistinct]

509
01:27:09,351 --> 01:27:11,751
[Wind Chimes Tinkling]

510
01:27:13,656 --> 01:27:16,591
[Boy, Faint]
I got it, I got it, I got it!

511
01:27:49,658 --> 01:27:52,320
[Boys Chattering, Shouting]

512
01:27:54,063 --> 01:27:56,691
- Boom! Boom! Boom, boom!
- Boom, boom!

513
01:27:56,799 --> 01:27:58,460
- Watch out!
- Watch out!

514
01:27:58,567 --> 01:28:00,933
- Go!
- [All Shouting]

515
01:28:01,670 --> 01:28:02,864
[Boy Laughs]

516
01:28:02,972 --> 01:28:04,496
[Firecracker Pops]

517
01:28:07,109 --> 01:28:09,771
[Boys Shouting]
One, two, three!

518
01:28:17,987 --> 01:28:19,648
I say let's bust 'em.

519
01:28:32,601 --> 01:28:34,159
- Yeah!
- Yeah!

520
01:28:38,307 --> 01:28:41,572
[Shouting, Laughing]

521
01:28:43,746 --> 01:28:44,940
Yeah!

522
01:28:46,081 --> 01:28:47,343
[Boy] We found a frog!

523
01:28:48,984 --> 01:28:50,747
Let's go set it off with a skyrocket!

524
01:28:50,853 --> 01:28:52,343
[Boy #2] He's getting away!

525
01:28:54,290 --> 01:28:56,224
Get back! Get back!

526
01:29:01,764 --> 01:29:03,322
[Sparks Crackling]

527
01:29:03,432 --> 01:29:05,263
Did it go to the moon?

528
01:29:05,367 --> 01:29:07,130
[Boy Laughs]

529
01:29:08,103 --> 01:29:09,661
Where is he?

530
01:29:09,772 --> 01:29:11,399
Here he is.

531
01:29:13,375 --> 01:29:15,400
It was an experiment!

532
01:29:19,615 --> 01:29:20,912
<i>[Young Jack]</i> <i>Liar.</i>

533
01:29:23,085 --> 01:29:24,882
Never do it again.

534
01:29:25,955 --> 01:29:27,422
Promise?

535
01:29:30,893 --> 01:29:33,225
You gonna tell Dad?

536
01:29:33,329 --> 01:29:36,423
<i>[Boy]</i>
<i>They're just trying to scare you.</i>

537
01:29:39,134 --> 01:29:40,863
[Boy] Keep you ignorant.

538
01:29:45,107 --> 01:29:46,734
<i>[Young Jack]</i>
<i>Things you got to learn.</i>

539
01:29:50,913 --> 01:29:53,006
<i>How can we know stuff until we look?</i>

540
01:29:54,516 --> 01:29:57,781
- [Boys Chattering]
- [Dog Barking]

541
01:30:07,529 --> 01:30:08,996
[Hammer Clicks]

542
01:30:11,533 --> 01:30:14,832
They say you can't try stuff?
They do.

543
01:30:19,108 --> 01:30:20,666
What do you need to be afraid of?

544
01:30:24,446 --> 01:30:26,038
You're afraid.

545
01:30:27,750 --> 01:30:28,944
I see it.

546
01:30:29,051 --> 01:30:31,611
[Boy #2]
Right here! Right here!

547
01:30:31,854 --> 01:30:34,982
[Sprinkler Whirring, Hissing]

548
01:31:01,817 --> 01:31:03,546
- [Car Door Closes]
- [Engine Starts]

549
01:31:06,822 --> 01:31:08,312
[Car Departing]

550
01:32:03,212 --> 01:32:06,875
[Floorboards Creaking]

551
01:32:46,555 --> 01:32:48,716
[Bird Chirping Softly]

552
01:34:10,172 --> 01:34:12,470
[Panting]

553
01:34:18,213 --> 01:34:19,680
[Dog Barking In Distance]

554
01:34:43,672 --> 01:34:46,140
[Girl Laughs, Mutters]

555
01:35:56,278 --> 01:35:58,439
I can't talk to you.

556
01:36:04,486 --> 01:36:07,455
<i>[Thunder Rumbling]</i>

557
01:36:07,556 --> 01:36:09,888
Don't look at me.
[Sniffles]

558
01:36:57,539 --> 01:36:59,006
<i>[Young Jack]</i>
<i>What have I started?</i>

559
01:37:03,111 --> 01:37:04,874
<i>What have I done?</i>

560
01:37:06,014 --> 01:37:07,982
[Lightbulb Hissing]

561
01:37:19,795 --> 01:37:21,262
[Door Closes]

562
01:37:35,510 --> 01:37:37,205
Stick it in there.

563
01:38:16,685 --> 01:38:18,312
I trust you.

564
01:38:23,091 --> 01:38:24,558
[Lmitates Buzz]

565
01:38:33,902 --> 01:38:36,234
- <i>[Middle Brother] You tired?</i>
- <i>[Jack] Nol</i>

566
01:38:36,338 --> 01:38:38,704
I never get tired!

567
01:38:38,807 --> 01:38:41,207
- Did this morning.
- No, I was just pretending.

568
01:38:42,244 --> 01:38:44,371
- Gonna call me a liar?
- No.

569
01:38:44,479 --> 01:38:46,379
I don't want to fight.

570
01:38:46,481 --> 01:38:48,540
Afraid to?

571
01:38:48,650 --> 01:38:50,447
No, I just don't wanna.

572
01:38:52,287 --> 01:38:54,983
If I was to say you're scared,
would you call me a liar?

573
01:38:55,090 --> 01:38:56,182
No.

574
01:38:57,459 --> 01:38:59,427
<i>[Jack]</i>
<i>Then you're scared, aren't you?</i>

575
01:39:03,365 --> 01:39:06,425
[Grunting, Laughing]

576
01:39:08,670 --> 01:39:10,501
Aha!

577
01:39:10,605 --> 01:39:12,232
Quit it.

578
01:39:14,743 --> 01:39:16,074
Come here.

579
01:39:44,039 --> 01:39:46,234
[Footsteps]

580
01:40:00,255 --> 01:40:01,882
[Mother] Come here!

581
01:40:04,492 --> 01:40:06,016
No!

582
01:40:09,097 --> 01:40:11,497
I'm not gonna do everything you tell me to.

583
01:40:12,801 --> 01:40:15,031
I'm gonna do what I want.

584
01:40:18,573 --> 01:40:21,235
What do you know?
You let him run all over you.

585
01:41:11,993 --> 01:41:13,927
<i>[Young Jack]</i>
<i>How do I get back...</i>

586
01:41:19,434 --> 01:41:21,026
<i>where they are?</i>

587
01:41:34,816 --> 01:41:36,078
<i>[Horn Honks]</i>

588
01:41:44,192 --> 01:41:46,160
- How are you, Son?
- Good.

589
01:41:55,870 --> 01:41:58,771
This one's heavy.
You're gonna need two hands for that one.

590
01:42:06,114 --> 01:42:07,581
Whoa.

591
01:42:08,616 --> 01:42:10,777
Careful now. You know what that...

592
01:42:10,885 --> 01:42:12,546
- Chinese?
- Know what that- That's Chinese.

593
01:42:12,654 --> 01:42:14,622
That's very good. Yes, it is.

594
01:42:16,324 --> 01:42:19,191
Your father went all around the world,
all the way to China.

595
01:42:19,294 --> 01:42:21,159
That's Pan Am airlines.

596
01:42:21,262 --> 01:42:23,127
That's what your father flew on.

597
01:42:23,231 --> 01:42:26,166
The entire bathrooms are stainless steel,
even the washbasin.

598
01:42:26,267 --> 01:42:29,566
- [Giggles]
- I feel confident the deal's going through.

599
01:42:29,671 --> 01:42:32,504
If not, they can forget it.
I'll tell them all to go to hell.

600
01:42:32,607 --> 01:42:34,700
- That's from Germany.
- How do you use them?

601
01:42:34,809 --> 01:42:36,208
[Father] See that?

602
01:42:39,414 --> 01:42:41,245
Put that down, Son.

603
01:42:41,349 --> 01:42:43,681
Can Cayler come over?

604
01:42:43,785 --> 01:42:46,185
Is your family not good enough for you?

605
01:42:49,524 --> 01:42:50,582
[Door Closes]

606
01:42:52,360 --> 01:42:56,262
- <i>[Patrons Chattering]</i>
- Hope it's not gonna take as long as last time.

607
01:42:56,364 --> 01:42:57,831
Al dente.

608
01:43:01,202 --> 01:43:03,534
[Father] Subjective point of view.
You know the difference?

609
01:43:03,638 --> 01:43:06,698
"Subjective" means it comes from your mind.
Can't be proven by other people.

610
01:43:06,808 --> 01:43:08,867
- Mwah.
- [Laughs]

611
01:43:08,977 --> 01:43:10,444
So- Here you go.

612
01:43:10,545 --> 01:43:12,240
Mm, mm, oop, oop, oop.

613
01:43:13,515 --> 01:43:15,039
[Laughs]

614
01:43:15,150 --> 01:43:17,311
- Good to see you again.
- Okay.

615
01:43:17,419 --> 01:43:19,478
Let's go, boys.

616
01:43:19,587 --> 01:43:20,884
Come on.

617
01:43:22,223 --> 01:43:24,191
There are things you can't do?

618
01:43:24,292 --> 01:43:26,226
Well, there are things I can't do either.

619
01:43:27,829 --> 01:43:29,956
You are not to call me "Dad."
You will call me "Father."

620
01:43:30,064 --> 01:43:31,725
- But-
- But- Don't interrupt!

621
01:43:31,833 --> 01:43:33,733
- But you do.
- Don't interrupt!

622
01:43:39,774 --> 01:43:41,241
It's your house.

623
01:43:41,342 --> 01:43:43,537
You can kick me out whenever you want to.

624
01:43:43,645 --> 01:43:46,978
<i>♪♪ [Piano]</i>

625
01:43:49,184 --> 01:43:51,209
You'd like to kill me.

626
01:44:10,305 --> 01:44:12,102
- [Father] No-
- <i>[Young Jack] Dad.</i>

627
01:44:16,611 --> 01:44:18,602
Why was he born?

628
01:44:50,512 --> 01:44:52,980
<i>♪♪ [Fades]</i>

629
01:44:54,849 --> 01:44:56,908
<i>[Insects Chirping]</i>

630
01:44:57,018 --> 01:44:59,452
[Tools Clattering]

631
01:45:44,165 --> 01:45:46,633
<i>[Young Jack Whispering]</i>
<i>Please, God, kill him.</i>

632
01:45:51,005 --> 01:45:52,996
<i>Let him die.</i>

633
01:45:57,645 --> 01:45:59,408
<i>Get him out of here.</i>

634
01:46:21,169 --> 01:46:23,069
She only loves me!

635
01:46:34,716 --> 01:46:38,675
<i>[Man] Def end, O Lord, this thy child</i>
<i>with thy heavenly grace...</i>

636
01:46:38,786 --> 01:46:41,778
that he may continue thine forever...

637
01:46:41,889 --> 01:46:45,757
and daily increase
in thy holy spirit more and more...

638
01:46:45,860 --> 01:46:49,819
until he come unto thy everlasting kingdom.

639
01:46:49,931 --> 01:46:51,228
<i>Amen.</i>

640
01:46:54,168 --> 01:46:57,103
<i>[Thunder Rumbling]</i>

641
01:47:08,983 --> 01:47:11,144
[Spokes Clicking]

642
01:47:32,140 --> 01:47:33,767
I see something.

643
01:47:39,080 --> 01:47:40,206
[Gunshot]

644
01:48:00,001 --> 01:48:01,059
[Gunshot]

645
01:48:07,775 --> 01:48:10,243
- [Pellet Clatters]
- [Rifle Cocks]

646
01:48:13,681 --> 01:48:15,012
[Gunshot]

647
01:48:24,759 --> 01:48:26,420
Put your finger over it.

648
01:48:28,629 --> 01:48:29,926
Like that.

649
01:48:32,166 --> 01:48:33,394
Come on.

650
01:48:42,376 --> 01:48:43,741
- [Gunshot]
- [No Audio]

651
01:49:15,109 --> 01:49:18,601
[Brother Sobbing]

652
01:49:30,825 --> 01:49:33,521
<i>[Young Jack Whispering]</i>
<i>What I want to do, I can't do.</i>

653
01:49:39,233 --> 01:49:41,098
<i>I do what I hate.</i>

654
01:50:42,530 --> 01:50:44,225
You can hit me if you want.

655
01:51:02,350 --> 01:51:03,681
[Jack] I'm sorry.

656
01:51:07,221 --> 01:51:09,018
You're my brother.

657
01:51:53,167 --> 01:51:55,294
<i>[Young Jack]</i>
<i>What was it you showed me?</i>

658
01:52:04,445 --> 01:52:07,312
<i>I didn't know how to name you then.</i>

659
01:52:11,819 --> 01:52:13,878
<i>But I see it was you.</i>

660
01:52:19,694 --> 01:52:21,787
<i>Always you were calling me.</i>

661
01:54:11,472 --> 01:54:14,771
<i>[Father]</i> <i>I wanted to be
loved because I was great.</i>

662
01:54:17,278 --> 01:54:19,269
<i>A big man.</i>

663
01:54:21,849 --> 01:54:23,316
<i>I'm nothin'.</i>

664
01:54:27,221 --> 01:54:30,122
<i>Look... at the glory around us.</i>

665
01:54:33,327 --> 01:54:35,795
<i>Trees and birds.</i>

666
01:54:39,333 --> 01:54:40,857
<i>I lived in shame.</i>

667
01:54:44,705 --> 01:54:47,765
<i>I dishonored it all</i>
<i>and didn't notice the glory.</i>

668
01:54:53,848 --> 01:54:55,645
<i>I'm a foolish man.</i>

669
01:55:00,855 --> 01:55:02,823
They're closing the plant.

670
01:55:06,894 --> 01:55:09,385
They gave me a choice.

671
01:55:11,799 --> 01:55:13,562
No job...

672
01:55:16,370 --> 01:55:19,669
or a transfer to a job nobody wants.

673
01:55:28,649 --> 01:55:30,310
<i>[Young Jack Whispering]</i> <i>Father.</i>

674
01:55:32,686 --> 01:55:35,553
<i>[Father]</i>
<i>I never missed a day of work.</i>

675
01:55:35,656 --> 01:55:37,624
<i>[Young Jack Whispering]</i> <i>Mother.</i>

676
01:55:37,725 --> 01:55:40,285
<i>[Father]</i> <i>I tithed every Sunday.</i>

677
01:55:43,898 --> 01:55:46,890
<i>[Young Jack Whispering]</i>
<i>Always you wrestle inside me.</i>

678
01:55:51,906 --> 01:55:53,874
<i>Always you will.</i>

679
01:55:54,875 --> 01:56:00,108
You know, Jack,
all I ever wanted for you was...

680
01:56:00,214 --> 01:56:03,012
to make you strong and...

681
01:56:03,117 --> 01:56:05,176
and grow up and be your own boss.

682
01:56:08,622 --> 01:56:10,749
Maybe I've been tough on you.

683
01:56:12,660 --> 01:56:14,685
I'm not proud of that.

684
01:56:16,997 --> 01:56:18,988
I'm as bad as you are.

685
01:56:21,569 --> 01:56:24,197
I'm more like you than her.

686
01:56:32,813 --> 01:56:36,044
You boys are about all I've done in life.
Otherwise I've drawn zilch.

687
01:56:44,825 --> 01:56:47,259
You're all I have.
You're all I want to have.

688
01:56:55,269 --> 01:56:57,169
My sweet boy.

689
01:57:45,319 --> 01:57:47,981
- [Sniff ling]
- [Train Whistle Blows In Distance]

690
01:58:04,772 --> 01:58:08,731
[Crying]

691
01:58:26,627 --> 01:58:30,620
[Children Chattering In Distance]

692
01:58:30,731 --> 01:58:33,666
[Bird Squawking]

693
01:59:04,031 --> 01:59:06,556
You just gonna stand there
like a bump on a log?

694
01:59:10,871 --> 01:59:12,338
Go on.

695
01:59:14,274 --> 01:59:16,834
[Clattering]

696
01:59:16,944 --> 01:59:18,411
Come on.

697
02:00:18,172 --> 02:00:20,800
<i>[Mother]</i>
<i>The only way to be happy is to love.</i>

698
02:00:25,179 --> 02:00:27,010
<i>Unless you love...</i>

699
02:00:29,016 --> 02:00:30,984
<i>your life will flash by.</i>

700
02:00:42,196 --> 02:00:44,164
<i>Do good to them.</i>

701
02:00:48,969 --> 02:00:50,402
<i>Wonder.</i>

702
02:00:55,209 --> 02:00:56,676
<i>Hope.</i>

703
02:01:29,076 --> 02:01:31,806
<i>[Beeping]</i>

704
02:01:40,320 --> 02:01:42,481
<i>[Beeping Fades]</i>

705
02:01:48,829 --> 02:01:50,660
<i>[Adult Jack]</i> <i>Brother.</i>

706
02:02:40,847 --> 02:02:43,111
<i>Keep us...</i>

707
02:02:50,691 --> 02:02:52,386
<i>guide us...</i>

708
02:03:01,969 --> 02:03:04,199
<i>till the end of time.</i>

709
02:03:46,847 --> 02:03:48,747
<i>[Young Jack]</i> <i>Follow me.</i>

710
02:04:55,015 --> 02:04:57,483
<i>[Waves Crashing]</i>

711
02:06:44,558 --> 02:06:46,617
[Seagulls Squawking]

712
02:10:53,606 --> 02:10:55,267
I give him to you.

713
02:10:59,979 --> 02:11:01,674
I give you my son.

714
02:11:49,129 --> 02:11:50,096
<i>[Elevator Beeping]</i>

715
02:12:01,908 --> 02:12:03,899
[Traffic Sounds]

716
02:12:12,785 --> 02:12:14,753
<i>[Chirping]</i>

717
02:12:34,274 --> 02:12:36,799
<i>[Waves Lapping]</i>

718
02:12:59,299 --> 02:13:02,530
<i>[Animals, Insects Chirping]</i>

719
02:13:46,512 --> 02:13:49,481
<i>[Creature Sounds Fade]</i>
