Gone fishing.
The lonesome foghorn blows.
Oh, dear.
Lucy, this is Pete Martell.
Lucy, put Harry on the horn.
Sheriff, it's Pete
Martell up at the mill.
I'm going to transfer it to the
phone on the table by the red chair.
The red chair against the wall.
The little table with the lamp on
it, the lamp we moved from the corner.
The black phone, not the brown phone.
- Morning, Pete. Harry.
- She's dead.
Wrapped in plastic.
Hold on a second, Pete.
Where?
You stay right there. I'm on my way.
Better get Dr Hayward. Tell him
to meet up at the Packard mill.
Roust Andy out of bed. Tell
him to get up there now.
- What is it?
- We've got a body up there.
Lucy, not a word about this to
anyone till you hear from me.
It's over here.
- You want forensics first?
- No, she's been in the water.
We'd better take some pictures.
- Who is she?
- Andy, the pictures.
- Sorry.
- Then we'll turn her over.
Same thing as last year
in Mr Blodgett's barn.
- Give me the camera.
- Sorry.
Is this going to happen every damn time?
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Why don't you go up to the coroner's
van and bring back that stretcher?
OK. Sorry.
Harry, let's roll her over.
Good Lord, Laura!
Laura Palmer.
Laura, sweetheart, I'm not
going to tell you again.
Yes, I am.
For goodness' sake.
Laura, now means now.
Laura, honey, are you downstairs?
- Hello.
- Beth, it's Sarah.
I just went up to wake Laura and
she's not here. Is she with Bobby?
She could be. He goes running at 5:00
am and then he goes to football practice.
Can you find out? Can you
reach him? I'll call the school.
I've got the number of
the field office here.
Thanks, Beth.
I wonder if she went out with
Leland? He had an early meeting.
I'm sure that's it. Either
that or she's with Bobby.
Sure. I'll call up to the hotel. Thanks.
No, Bobby hasn't shown
up for practice yet today.
As a matter of fact, he's been late
every day this week, Mrs Palmer.
And last week. Maybe
even the week before.
- Are they ready to sign?
- You're not going to mention
that we haven't yet acquired
access to the Packard land?
Sorry.
We have solid information
that the Packard sawmill is going
to go belly up within a year.
We'll be able to get it for
a song. One verse, no chorus.
Now...
let's get out there and get those
cheese eaters where they live.
Benjamin.
...a clean, wholesome
environment, much like your own.
With a quality of life
to rival the very best
that this country has to offer.
That is what the Ghostwood
Country Club and Estates will be.
When I first spoke to Sven,
he was naturally very concerned
about the quality of air here.
If you'll permit me, Sven, to repeat
what you said this morning after your run:
"My air sacks have never felt so good!"
Your wife's on the phone
again. She said it's urgent.
Excuse me a moment,
gentlemen. I'll be right back.
Make it snappy.
So...
...here in Twin Peaks,
health and industry go hand in hand.
- I'll transfer you to the house phone.
- Thank you.
- Sarah, what is it?
- Is Laura with you?
- No, why?
- She didn't go with you this morning?
No. Honey, what's wrong?
What's this all about?
- She wasn't here this morning.
- She's probably with Bobby.
- I can't find Bobby.
- There you are. That's it.
Let's not worry. They're
probably together.
She would have left me a
note. She would have told me.
Honey, take it easy, please.
- I'm looking for Leland Palmer.
- He's right over there on the phone.
Sheriff Truman.
What? Who? What did you say?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
Leland, please. What is it? Tell me.
- Leland...
- Is this about Laura?
I'm afraid it is.
Leland, tell me.
My baby!
We're ready to go with the contracts.
Leland, what's wrong?
My daughter's dead.
What kept you, Heidi?
- I couldn't get my car started. -
Too busy jump-starting the old man?
I thought you Germans
were always on time.
I thought the only time you cared
about, Bobby, was making time.
- You heading out, Shelly?
- Yeah, I'm heading home.
I'm going to practice. I
can drop you on the way.
That would be great, thanks.
Here's a tune for you, gals.
Norma...
...l'll see you in my dreams.
Not if I see you first.
Don't do anything I wouldn't do.
- I think she knows about us.
- Norma?
Fat chance. I think she's
hot to try for you herself.
It's happy hour in France.
Come on, cowboy. Light your fire.
Right, just a little
pick-me-up before homeroom.
I thought I was your
little pick-me-up.
Baby, you are more like
a three-stage rocket.
A pocket rocket.
And what stage are we in now?
Are you sure that your old
man is still on the road?
Yes, he called me last night from Butte.
That's a long way away and he
ain't got a phone in his truck.
Quit worrying and start
screwing, Mr Touchdown.
Butte!
Back up!
I'll call you later.
Leland, I'm so sorry.
17 years old.
- Lee, I hate to put you through this.
- No, I have to see her.
I have to see what was
done to my little girl.
My baby!
That's my little girl.
- God!
- Let's get out of here.
- Have you seen Laura?
- No, not yet.
Nice day for a picnic.
Bobby Briggs, they're looking for you.
- Who is?
- Sheriff is.
Well, here I am in school.
Hey, Snake.
- Something's up.
- Where?
- You think I'm kidding?
- What, me worried?
Bobby, you're wanted in the office.
- Who wants me in the office?
- Right now, young man.
Watch out.
- Terry Franklin?
- Here.
- Martha Grimes?
- Donna Hayward?
- Here.
- Audrey Horne?
James Hurley?
Excuse me. Room 106?
Is there a Bobby Briggs
in this classroom?
No, he's in 107. 107.
- Could I speak to you for a moment?
- Certainly.
...making the announcement.
Thank you for your time.
There'll be an announcement
from the Principal.
I told you.
I got up early like I always do.
I went running like I always do.
I had breakfast at the RR
and I didn't go to practice
because I didn't feel like it.
Why not, Bobby? Were you
upset about something?
You want to tell us about it?
Look, you guys, what did
I do? What's going on?
Mr Wolchezk, there's
rumours all over school.
Maybe it's best if
they heard it from you.
Mr Wolchezk, why don't you go
ahead and make that announcement?
- Now?
- Now's the time.
Excuse me.
What is it, Sheriff? What's going on?
Bobby, you look at me.
Your girlfriend Laura
Palmer's been killed.
She was found just after dawn.
She was with you last night. You weren't
where you should have been this morning.
Have these fellows
advised you of your rights?
Yes, but I didn't know why.
- Laura's dead?
- Yes.
Did you understand your rights
as they were explained to you?
You think I killed her?
Bobby, you can phone your parents
and they can arrange for a lawyer
to be with you when we talk again.
Andy, take Bobby out to make his call.
I loved her.
And she loved me.
Because I wasn't at football practice
I killed my girlfriend? You are crazy!
You get off me.
Bobby, we're going to
talk about this later.
May I have your attention,
please. This is Principal Wolchezk.
I am deeply saddened to have to tell you
that early this morning your
classmate Laura Palmer was found dead.
This is a terrible moment for all of us.
For all of us who knew her.
Her friends, her family.
It is very important
that we all try to help each
other through this difficult time.
The police have asked
me to ask each of you
if you have any information
about Laura's activities
after school yesterday
or yesterday evening,
please come forward.
I am dismissing all classes for the day,
but before we leave I would
like to ask each of you
to join me in a moment
of silence for Laura
and her dear memory.
You can talk to her now, Harry.
Do you know what time it was when
you last saw Laura, Mrs Palmer?
- What time?
- Yes.
It would have been about nine.
Yes, nine o'clock...
...pm.
She came home from Bobby's
and she was going up the stairs.
Those stairs...right there.
- Who's upstairs?
- Your husband and one of my men.
I can tell from the
sounds that it isn't her.
Her diary.
Do you know where the
key to this is, sir?
- Do you have to take that?
- We'll return it as soon as possible.
Did she say anything to you?
No.
She said goodnight.
And I said, "Goodnight.
"Goodnight, sweetheart."
Mrs Palmer, can you remember...
Did she make or receive any phone calls?
I heard her phone ring once.
- About what time was that?
- I don't know who it was.
Harry.
That was Lucy. Got a call from a guy
who works at the mill, Janek Pulaski.
Says his daughter didn't
come home last night
and she didn't show up
at school today, either.
Two by fours, four by eights.
Did you hear me? You can't
do that to my workers.
Don't walk away from me. Come back here.
You're not going anywhere. You're
not going to tell anybody anything.
Catherine,
I'm sorry if this offends you,
but I'm the owner of this sawmill.
You don't knowthe first thing about
this mill. That's why I'm running it.
I've never taken this authority
before, but maybe I should have.
- You're not shutting us down. -
Catherine, I have the final say-so.
- Peter, push the plug.
- Pete, don't you dare.
Catherine, please.
Shorty, tell the boys to pull the plug.
That's right.
May I have your attention.
This is Josie Packard.
I have decided that in light of what
has happened, all work here will stop.
Bitch!
This morning, as you know, the
body of Miss Laura Palmer...
- What's your name?
- Fred Truax e.
You're fired.
Just now your co-worker and
a friend, Mr Janek Pulaski,
has learned that his daughter,
one of Laura's schoolmates,
is missing since last night.
Today all work here will
stop. The mill will shut down.
Perhaps you can spend the
day with your families.
Thank you all for your attention.
What the hell?
Laura's dead.
Yeah, I heard.
She was the one.
Buy you a coffee?
Can't do it.
If you see Donna, could
you give this to her?
Ed!
They said those drapes
would be ready by 10:00.
I want those drapes up by nightfall.
Diane, 11:30 am, February 24th.
I'm entering the town of Twin Peaks.
Five miles south of the Canadian
border, 12 miles west of the state line.
I've never seen so
many trees in my life.
As WC Fields would say, "I'd
rather be here than Philadelphia."
54 degrees on a slightly overcast
day. Weatherman said rain.
If you get paid for being wrong
60% of the time, it'd beat working!
Mileage is 79,345. Gauge is on reserve.
Got to tank up when I get into town.
Remind me to tell you how much that is.
Lunch was $6 and 31 cents
at the Lamplighter Inn.
That's on Highway 2, near Lewis Fork.
That was a tuna fish sandwich, slice
of cherry pie and a cup of coffee.
Damn good food! If you ever get up
here, that cherry pie is worth a stop.
Looks like I'll be meeting up with a...
Sheriff Harry S Truman.
Shouldn't be too hard to remember.
He'll be at the Calhoun
Memorial Hospital.
Guess we'll take a look at that girl
who crawled down off the mountain.
I'm sure the sheriff can recommend
a clean, reasonably priced motel.
That's what I need: a clean
place, reasonably priced.
Diane, I almost forgot.
I've got to find out what trees
these are. They're really something.
- Agent Cooper?
- Yes.
- Sheriff Harry S Truman.
- Dale Cooper, FBI.
- Pleasure.
- Good to meet you.
- Have any trouble finding the place?
- No, no. Fine.
Came out over Highway 2 near Lewis Fork.
Stopped at the Lamplighter Inn.
Had a slice of cherry pie. Incredible.
I'll tell you, we're sure
glad to have the FBI here.
Kind of lucky in a way that Ronnette
stepped out across the state line.
- Whole town's badly shaken up.
- Sure, it's a nice quiet place.
Sheriff, let me stop
you for just a second.
There's a fewthings
we've got to get straight.
It's best to talk about this up front.
When the Bureau gets called
in, the Bureau's in charge.
You'll be working for me.
Sometimes local law enforcement
has a problem with that.
We're glad to have you here.
Sheriff, what kind of fantastic
trees have you got growing round here?
- Big, majestic...
- Douglas firs.
Douglas firs?
Can someone get me a copy of the
coroner's report on the dead girl?
The autopsy hasn't been done yet,
but I'll take you down to the
morgue when we're finished here.
Fine.
Dr Shelvy, this is FBI Agent Cooper.
- Glad to know you.
- Doctor. How's the girl?
She's in shock, suffering from exposure.
- Can I see her?
- All right, this way.
- Was she raped?
- Several times.
- One perpetrator?
- We're waiting for the results.
Is there any connection
to the dead girl?
Same high school. As far as we
know, they hardly knew each other.
No connection.
I'd like to question her.
This girl doesn't even know
where she is or if she is.
What exactly are you saying?
We need a CAT scan and we're
not equipped for that here.
My opinion? She may
have neurological damage.
She's not responsive at all.
I'd like to examine her fingers.
All right.
- They've already scraped for particles.
- That's not what I'm looking for.
There's nothing here, not a thing.
Don't go there.
Ronnie?
Ronnette?
Pull the fish out of
the water, big mouth.
He's got a big mouth
that starts talking to me.
Harry!
Dr Jacoby.
- Terrible, terrible tragedy.
- Yes.
This is Special Agent Dale Cooper.
- Gary Cooper?
- Agent Cooper.
- Agent? FBI.
- Right.
Dr Lawrence Jacoby, Agent Cooper.
Laura was a patient of mine.
You're going to the morgue.
Do you mind if I join you?
Yes, I do. Why would you want to?
Sort of against procedure, Doctor.
No offence. I thought
I could be of some help.
- You still could be...at another time.
- I understand completely.
By the way...
Laura's...Laura's parents.
They didn't know that she was seeing me.
That guy's a psychiatrist?
I have to apologise again
for the fluorescent lights.
- I think it's a bad transformer.
- That's quite all right.
Agent Cooper, we scraped those
nails when we brought her in.
There it is. There it
is. My God, here it is!
- What?
- Would you leave us, please?
- Jim.
- Would you leave us alone, please?
Certainly.
I need something to grab onto this with.
Diane, I'm at the Twin Peaks County
Morgue with the body of the victim.
Laura Palmer.
Diane, it's the same thing.
- I told you we'd see this again.
- What have you got there?
Ring finger, under the nail.
Let's see what he left us.
It's an 'R'.
Diane, give this to Albert
and his team. Don't go to Sam.
Albert has a bit more on the ball.
OK, Cooper, are you going to let
me in on what's going on here?
Sheriff, we've got a lot to talk about.
- Hi, Ed.
- Hey, Donna.
I'm so sorry.
- Have you seen James yet?
- He came by.
- Is he OK?
- No.
Do you know where he went? I've
already been to the Roadhouse.
I don't know, honey. He
told me to give you this.
What the hell are you doing? I've
been looking all over for you.
Bobby's in a lot of
trouble. He's my best friend.
We're going to the police
station to be with him.
Don't tell me where I ought to be!
Second, Laura was my best friend.
- Get in the car.
- Muffle it, junior.
- Mind your own business.
- You're on my lot, friend.
Ed, I'm not your friend.
Donna, you get to the
Sheriff's right now.
I sure know howto pick them.
You waiting for those
drapes to hang themselves?
I know howto pick them, too.
If James comes around, will you
tell him I'm looking for him?
You bet.
And Donna, you take it easy.
That's the videotape we just saw,
the one we found in Laura's bedroom.
At a certain point, I'm going to
want to showthis to the boyfriend.
You say when.
- Did you complete your forensics?
- You bet. All done.
- No key yet?
- We're still looking.
Why not?
Diane, I've just opened
Laura Palmer's diary.
This is the last entry,
dated February 23rd.
It reads: "Asparagus for
dinner again. I hate asparagus.
"Does this mean I'll never grow
up?" And then she's written:
"Nervous about meeting 'J' tonight."
That's the letter 'J', Diane.
And that is the last entry.
That's something to get started on.
- Yeah, that's one out of 26.
- One out of 26.
Diane, I've just turned
back 18 days to day one.
Taped to the page is a plastic
envelope containing a white residue
and a key to a safety deposit box.
Sheriff, we have to very
carefully remove this key.
We're going to run this envelope.
My bet is it will test
positive for cocaine.
- That's impossible.
- You ever been surprised before?
Mr Cooper, you didn't know Laura Palmer.
Let's get a court order to
open the safety deposit box
and maybe we'll both find out
a fewthings about Laura Palmer.
Diane, I'm holding a small
box of chocolate bunnies.
- Lucy.
- Andy, is that you?
Tell Harry we found
where... it happened.
Where Ronnette and Laura
were taken and tortured.
Tell Harry...
...I didn't cry.
Andy, are you OK? Sweetie?
But, Lucy...
...it's so horrible.
Andy, sweetie.
My God.
Bobby, you have been advised of your
constitutional rights. Am I correct?
Yes.
- Bobby, did you kill Laura Palmer?
- No!
She was studying at your house
until about 9:30 last night?
- Yeah.
- Bobby.
Yes, sir.
- Did she drive herself home?
- Yes.
You two had a big fight
last week, didn't you?
So what? If I had a fight with
her, if I sang songs with her,
if I went skipping rope with
her, what difference does it make?
I didn't kill her.
Bobby, here's howthis works:
we ask the questions and you
answer the questions that we ask,
briefly and to the point.
Did you shoot this video, Bobby?
If you didn't, then who did?
Did you know Laura was
seeing someone else?
That's what you fought about last week.
Look at these pictures.
Look how happy she is.
- You ever do cocaine with Laura, Bobby?
- I don't do drugs.
Excuse me, what are you
charging my client with?
That's right.
You're a football
player, aren't you, Bobby?
If you knew who she was seeing...
...tell us.
- Ask Donna, she was with her.
- I'm asking you.
Come on, Bobby, give me a name.
Here's a hint: first initial 'J'.
No...
...she wouldn't do that to me.
You didn't love her anyway.
Let him go.
Julie, the Norwegians are signing
the contract at four o'clock.
When Mr Horne returns,
make sure they do not hear
about Laura Palmer's death.
That will blowthe whole
deal. Got it? Thank you.
OK, Bob. OK, Bob.
Julie, what would happen
if I pulled this out?
You wouldn't.
Audrey, look what you've done!
Did they scoff the whole smorgasbord?
- Audrey, don't go in there.
- I'm hungry.
Don't go in there!
Excuse me, is there something
wrong, young pretty girl?
They found my friend Laura...
lying face down on a rocky beach,
completely naked.
She'd been murdered.
- Hey, buddy.
- Snake. We're out of here, man.
Just a sec. Donna's still in there.
- You straightened her out yet?
- I don't know what's up with her.
Forget her. I've got it
figured. Laura and her.
That cop mentioned something
about the letter 'J'.
We're looking at some freaking biker
and some freaking biker is going
to get his head busted open.
What's his name? We'll
finish this quick.
Come outside.
Robert, I'll be home this evening
if you need a sympathetic ear.
I don't need any damn
sympathetic anything.
I have no idea what's going on here.
Let's just go home.
So you were on a picnic,
just the two of you?
Way up in the mountains,
not another souI around?
Is there some law
against having a picnic?
Donna, this is interesting to me.
With just two of you out there,
I can't figure out
howthese pictures got taken.
That's easy.
There was this...
hiker that came along, a woman hiker.
She had a backpack and...
...we asked her to take
the pictures for us.
What was her name?
I don't think we asked her. I forgot.
Donna, who are you protecting?
Nobody, that's really what happened.
Does this person's name
start with the letter 'J'?
- She didn't tell us her name.
- Donna, this is serious business.
More serious than Laura falling in love
with someone other than her boyfriend.
Much more serious.
Agent Cooper, the Sheriff's
ready to roll up to the site
and I've got something
else for you here.
You can come on in.
I know Laura was your best friend.
You've been through a lot
today. We're finished for now.
Go ahead, Lucy. Tell Agent
Cooper what you heard.
After Bobby was taken back to his cell,
his parents were standing
by the door with his lawyer.
Bobby was released and he came
out and saw his friend Mike,
who was down by the water
cooler, which is near my desk.
I pretended to be typing, but I was
typing what Mike and Bobby were saying.
They didn't say exactly who
it was they were talking about,
but anyway here's what they were saying.
They said the person we're
looking for is a biker.
Looks like a hog to me.
- Holy smoke.
- Holy smoke!
The Norwegians are leaving!
The Norwegians are gone.
Everyone here has gone. Not good.
You are throwing away the
investment opportunity of a lifetime.
- Better that than throw a lifetime away.
- You stay out of this!
Sheriff.
Diane, it's 4:10 pm at
the scene of the crime.
Here's something we haven't seen before:
a mound of dirt, a foot
and a half in diameter.
On the top is a gold
necklace with a gold heart.
Correction: half a gold heart.
At the base of the mound of
dirt is a torn piece of newsprint
written with the words,
which appear to be in blood,
"Fire walk with me".
Sheriff, you and I have got to find out
who's got the other half of that heart.
Mrs Horne?
It might help if you
talked to Johnny yourself.
So you think it might help?
You can tell Johnny one more time
that Laura isn't coming this
afternoon to work with him.
Or tomorrow afternoon or any afternoon.
What is so difficult to
understand about that?
It fell down.
I knew Laura. She was always so nice.
When was the last time she came in?
I couldn't tell you exactly.
We have so many box es.
- You don't keep records?
- We have plenty of paperwork.
How long has she had this box?
I'd say about six months.
I could check for you.
Would you, please? And close
the door on the way out.
"Flesh World".
Man!
There's over 10,000 dollars here.
That's a lot of girl scout cookies.
Here's a page that's marked.
There's your connection:
Ronnette Pulaski.
I can't believe it.
...the law enforcement officials
emerging from an abandoned railway car...
Shelly, would you turn
the television off?
Why, Leo? I want to see this.
Shelly, turn it off.
...escaped her captor
and fled to safety,
remains hospitalised
in critical condition...
Shelly, sit down here a
minute and help me out.
What kind of cigarettes do you smoke?
Whatever's around.
No, you don't. You smoke these.
What are these doing here?
I pick up different packs from the
diner all the time, me and Norma.
Two things, Shelly.
When I come home, this house
should be clean and I mean clean.
You smoke one brand of
cigarettes from now on.
If I ever see two brands
of cigarettes again,
I'm going to snap your neck like a twig.
You have nothing to worry
about with me, darling.
That's right.
Big Ed's Gas Farm. Ed speaking.
I'm sorry. I know I promised
not to call you there,
but I have to see you.
- I hurt so bad.
- It's OK.
Why don't I meet you at
the Roadhouse around 9:30?
Thank you, Ed. I'll see you tonight.
All right, sweetheart.
- I think I saw a cottontail rabbit.
- Must have been a snowshoe rabbit.
Snowshoe? Snowshoe rabbit?
Who's the babe?
That is one of the most beautiful
women in the state. Mrs Packard.
Packard Sawmill?
- Where's Mr Packard?
- Died in a boating accident.
Andrew Packard practically built this
town. Brought her over from Hong Kong.
Left her everything, which
didn't exactly please his sister.
That's her, the original deep freeze.
Who's the glad-handing dandy?
Benjamin Horne, local
big-wig. He owns half the town.
He's not after her. He's after her land.
- Who's the lady with the log?
- We call her the Log Lady.
Ladies and gentlemen, if I
could have your attention.
Is this thing on?
- Is this thing on?
- Hang on, Dwayne.
Thank you, Mayor Milford.
Agent Cooper.
Thank you, Sheriff.
Ladies and gentlemen, FBI
Special Agent Dale Cooper.
One year ago, in a town in the
south-west corner of this state,
the body of a young girl
named Teresa Banks was found.
She had no family. No one
came forward to claim her body.
It wasn't even news...until today.
There are irrefutable similarities,
which I cannot discuss,
that lead us to conclude
Laura Palmer was the second
and Ronnette Pulaski would have been
the third victim of the same killer.
There is a chance the person
who committed these crimes
is someone from this town,
possibly even someone you know.
It is vitally important that
this not turn into a witch hunt.
I would suggest a temporary curfew
for those under eighteen years of age.
Keeping your kids off the
streets now may teach them caution
that may protect them in
the days and weeks to come.
I will remind you that these
crimes occurred at night.
When I left the house,
Sarah was sleeping.
Leland made it through the day somehow.
I'm not sure I could have done the same.
Poor dear, poor Sarah.
Eileen, the brutality...the
madness of it.
I know.
They're not releasing many
details. Wisely, I suppose.
At the scene where it happened,
no one else knows this,
they found part of a necklace,
half of a golden heart.
It was Laura's.
They know this because she was wearing
it in a video of a picnic they found.
I'm telling you this because
Donna was in the video with her.
She won't tell them who shot
it or who else was with them,
but they think the killer may
have the other half of the heart.
Donna, which do you like better?
"The blossom of the evening"
or "The full flower of the evening"?
Listen to me, this is serious.
This is serious, too.
I'm going out the window and
I need you to cover for me.
Don't you know there's a curfew?
They announced it on the radio.
I know, Einstein. That's why
I need you to cover for me.
I suppose this will include a
phone conversation with Mike,
Mr Bonehead Boyfriend?
No, this is about Laura
and it's really serious.
Check.
Thank you.
- I'll need to borrow your bike.
- Then, pump some air in the back tyre.
Yeah. Harriet, don't
forget to brush your teeth.
Actually,
now that some time has passed,
I like "The full
blossom of the evening".
Hey, Snake.
Don't take any oink
oink off that pretty pig.
Don't you worry about that.
Hi, Doctor Hayward. I'd
like to talk to Donna.
Donna's upstairs getting
ready for bed, Mike.
You're not drinking
and driving, are you?
We're all pretty broken up
about what happened today, sir.
Besides, Bobby's doing
most of the driving.
I'll see if she wants to come down.
Would you mind waiting out here, please?
The best-laid plans of mice and men.
Snake, let's go!
Where's your sister?
Dad, I'm going to tell it to you and
I'm going to tell it to you straight.
Harriet!
See that window?
Later.
- Donna's not here.
- You mean she snuck out?
Mike, maybe you have an idea
where she might have gone.
Oh, we'll find her. Don't
you worry about that.
Roadhouse.
Let's go!
Sheriff, I've got a call
for you from Dr Hayward.
I explained that you're on
a stake-out at the Roadhouse,
but he still would very
much like to talk to you.
Patch him through.
I'm going to patch him
through to you now, Sheriff.
I'm patching you
through now, Dr Hayward.
Harry, my daughter Donna
snuck out of the house.
I don't know where she's gone.
Doc, you rest easy now. I'm going
to put out an all points for her.
- We'll keep our eyes peeled.
- Thanks, Harry.
You betcha.
- Lucy, you take care of that all points now.
- All right, Sheriff.
- Of course Donna snuck out.
- Meaning what?
How else is she going
to lead us to that biker?
So all afternoon I've
been hanging drapes.
- Drapes?
- Drapes.
Lots of them.
You know how I feel about you, Ed.
Don't do it for me, do it for yourself.
- It's Tammy Wynette time, darling.
- Yeah?
- What about you and Hank?
- I told you.
- I'm going to leave Hank.
- Before or after he gets parole?
I love you, Ed. I'll do
what's best for both of us.
When your sweetheart's husband's
in the joint for manslaughter,
the word "parole" has
a nasty ring to it.
You know why I'm whittling?
OK, I'll bite again.
Why are you whittling?
That's what you do in a town
where a yellow light still
means slow down, not speed up.
Mike and Bobby.
There's liable to be a
little trouble this evening.
Scottie, Mutt and Jeff just crawled in.
Oh, what a wonderful world!
Looks like sooner than later.
- Why don't you whistle for a little backup?
- I see which way the wind's blowing.
Lucy, get us a backup unit at the
Roadhouse right away. Make that two.
And call Dr Hayward. Tell him we've
found his daughter and she's fine.
All right, Sheriff.
Donna!
Why are you sneaking around?
Everybody's looking for you.
Get your hands off me. Leave me alone!
Get your hands off me!
- Get your hands off me. Let go of me.
- No!
That's enough!
You heard him. Let me go!
Like that, Mr Monkey Wrench?
You guys got it covered? Don't
worry, I'll take you to James.
Joey Paulsen. That's a 'J'.
No, he's taking her to somebody else.
You want me to follow them
at a discreet distance?
Harry, you're all right.
Hold on!
- Do you think they spotted us?
- Give me a doughnut.
Well, Harry, I think we lost them.
Man, smell those trees!
Smell those Douglas firs.
I think I hear them.
- What's down there?
- An old logging road.
The only access is five miles
back at the Packard mill.
I told Doc Hayward his daughter was OK.
My fault, Harry.
- Thanks, Joe.
- Good luck, James.
James, they're looking for you.
I'm going to talk to them,
but I think they're going to lock me up.
Why?
I don't have an alibi for
last night. I was with her.
- James, what happened last night?
- It was kinda like a nightmare.
- Donna, she was a different person.
- What are you saying?
I'm telling you, there were
things she was involved with,
things she let herself get pulled into,
things she thought you'd hate her for.
She said, "There are things about me..."
She said, "Even Donna doesn't know me."
I knew her. I knew her
better than she thought I did.
Donna, she said something
about a guy getting killed.
- Who?
- She didn't say.
But she said Bobby told
her that he killed this guy.
Oh, my God.
This is why I had to see you.
It all makes some kind of terrible sense
that she died, that someone killed her.
I don't know. I can't explain it.
I didn't know whether to
believe any of this last night.
I mean, half the time she
wasn't making any sense.
I couldn't calm her down. I
could hardly keep her on the bike.
We came to the light
at Sparkwood and 21,
and she... she put her
hands around my neck
and she screamed she loved me.
I looked into her eyes. They were clear.
It was like she was Laura again.
She was so sad. She
sounded so desperate.
Then she ran off. I
let her go and she died.
It's OK.
It's not your fault, James.
James. It's all right, James.
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry.
I changed my mind. I'm not sorry.
James.
Oh, James. Those are sirens.
I've got to go to the
police. I don't have an alibi.
After she left I just rode around.
The necklace you gave
Laura with the golden heart.
- You have to give me the other half.
- Why?
They found the half where she was killed
and think the killer has the other half.
If you go there with the
necklace and no alibi...
- What about you?
- I'll get rid of it.
- No.
- We'll hide it.
- All right. We'll bury it.
- OK.
- Right here.
I'll take you home.
- What goes around comes around.
- Round and round.
That's not Joey, that's James Hurley.
James, stand away from the
bike. Stand away from the girl.
- Put your hands behind your head.
- He didn't do anything!
She's probably right.
James. He didn't do anything.
Lucy, get an arrest form ready.
Doc, I'm releasing her to you,
but I want her back for
questioning in the morning.
- All right, Harry.
- Andy, Hawk.
Put James back in number four.
James.
It's gonna be all right.
You!
We'll check on you later.
Good night, officers.
I'm sorry, Dad.
Donna, after what happened today,
I'm sure you understand what you put
your mother and me through tonight.
But I know you wouldn't have done
it unless you had a good reason.
We also have another problem
facing us, young lady.
Where's your sister's bicycle?
I left it at the Roadhouse.
We'll have to go get it.
I understand you promised Harriet
you'd put some air in the back tyre.
Yes, I did.
We're so thankful to
have a daughter like you.
A policeman's dream!
Yup, Lucy sets it up for us every night.
Is everything OK?
There's extra jelly doughnuts for Agent
Cooper and there's some extra decaf.
You know, Andy's been drinking
so much caffeinated coffee lately.
Thank you, Lucy. You can go back
to work now and no listening.
Sheriff, that reminds me.
Can you recommend a good,
inexpensive hotel or motel?
It doesn't have to be fancy.
I can get you a good rate
up at the Great Northern.
I think I'm going to
be here for some time.
These motels promise you a good rate,
but when you get there
it's a different story.
All I need is a bed, a
bathroom, a telephone,
and sometimes a television, in the
event I get a chance to knock off early.
I can get you a good rate
up at the Great Northern.
Sold.
Well, tomorrow comes early.
Diane, it's 12:28 am.
I'll be staying locally at
the Great Northern Hotel.
Sheriff's getting me a rate.
When you least expect it.
Hello, Sheriff.
Hey, Jo.
I understand you wanted
to see the Sheriff up here.
Yes, I did.
Right over here.
He's here again.
Let's get together and talk about it.
All right.
It must have happened about
this time 24 hours ago.
I'm afraid.