Diane, 7:15 am. I'll be heading for
the Sheriff's after breakfast.
From there we'll be going on
to Laura Palmer's funeral.
Good morning, Colonel Cooper.
Just Agent, Audrey. Special Agent.
Special Agent.
Would you care to join me
for breakfast?
I'm in a hurry.
- For what?
Audrey, that perfume you're wearing
is incredible.
Do you really think so?
- Yes, I do. Please, have a seat.
And would you write your name down
for me? Here.
OK.
Audrey, there's something
you'd like to tell me.
There is?
You slipped this note underneath
my door the night before last.
I did?
I wanted to help you. For Laura.
You said you and Laura
weren't exactly friends.
We weren't friends, but I
understood her better than the rest.
What is "One-Eyed Jacks?"
- It's a place up north.
Men go there.
- What about women?
Women... you know, work there.
Did Laura work there?
I don't know. Laura worked
at my father's department store.
Horne's?
- He named it after himself.
Where at Horne's department store?
At the perfume counter.
So did Ronnette Pulaski.
- Really?
The rightward slant in your handwriting
indicates a romantic nature.
A heart that yearns. Be careful.
I do?
I'm gonna have to ask you
to leave now. Police business.
Thank you for talking to me.
Trudy, two more coffees, please.
Harry, Lucy...
It is an absolutely beautiful morning.
Griddlecakes, melted butter, maple
syrup, lightly heated, slice of ham.
Nothing beats the taste sensation
when maple syrup collides with ham.
Griddlecakes, slice of ham.
Who killed Laura Palmer?
Let me tell you about the dream
I had last night.
Tibet?
- No.
You were there. Lucy, so were you.
Harry, my dream is a code
waiting to be broken.
Break the code, solve the crime.
"Break the code, solve the crime."
In my dream, Sarah Palmer
has a vision of her daughter's killer.
Deputy Hawk sketched his picture.
I got a phone call from
a one-armed man named Mike.
The killer's name was Bob.
- Mike and Bobby?
No, it's a different Mike
and a different Bob.
They lived above
a convenience store.
They had a tattoo,
"Fire, walk with me".
Mike couldn't stand the killing
any more, so he cut off his arm.
Bob vowed to kill again,
so Mike shot him.
Do you know
where dreams come from?
Not specifically.
- No.
Acetylcholine neurons fire
high-voltage impulses into the forebrain.
These impulses become pictures,
the pictures become dreams, but...
no one knows why we choose
these particular pictures.
So what was the end of this dream?
Suddenly, it was 25 years later.
I was old, sitting in a red room.
There was a midget in a red suit
and a beautiful woman.
The midget told me that my favourite
gum was coming back into style,
and didn't his cousin look exactly
like Laura Palmer, which she did.
What cousin?
- The beautiful woman.
She's filled with secrets.
Sometimes her arms bend back.
Where she's from,
the birds sing a pretty song
and there's always music in the air.
The midget did a dance.
Laura kissed me and she whispered
the name of the killer in my ear.
Who was it?
- I don't remember.
Damn!
- Damn!
Harry, our job is simple:
break the code, solve the crime.
Yeah?
Sheriff, I'm at the morgue
and there's a big fight going on.
Youhang on, I'll be right there.
That was Andy.
There's a fight over at the morgue.
Albert.
You're the most cold-blooded man
I've ever seen.
I've never known such little regard for
human frailty. Have you no compassion?
I've got compassion running out of
my nose. I'm the Sultan of Sentiment.
Doctor Hayward,
I have travelled thousands of miles
and apparently several centuries
to this forgotten sinkhole
to perform a series of tests.
I do not ask you to understand
these tests. I'm not cruel.
I just ask you to get out,
so I can finish my work!
We are here to conduct
Laura Palmer's body to the cemetery.
If you think we're gonna leave
without her, you are crazy!
All right, all right, all right!
Mr Rosenfield, please.
Leland Palmer couldn't be
with us today,
but I know I speak for everyone,
the Palmer family included,
when I say that we appreciate and
understand the value of your work.
But, as their representative,
I must insist
that we consider the feelings
of the Palmer family as well.
Mr Horne, I realise that your position
in this fair community
pretty well guarantees venality,
insincerity
and a rather irritating method
of expressing yourself.
Stupidity, however,
is not a necessarily inherent trait.
Therefore, please listen closely.
You can have a funeral any old time.
You dig a hole, you plant a coffin.
I, however, cannot perform
these tests next year,
next month, next week or tomorrow.
I must perform them now.
I've got a lot of cutting
and pasting to do, so please,
why don't you return to your
porch rockers and resume whittling?
That does it. I'm taking charge of
the body and you don't touch Laura...
What the hell
do you think you're doing?!
Gentlemen.
- What's going on?
Thank God!
This old fool is obstructing
a criminal investigation. Cuff him!
He won't release Laura's body
for the funeral. He's not human.
What's the hold-up?
- Please, Cooper.
I do not suffer fools gladly,
and fools with badges, never.
I want no interference
from this hulking boob. Is that clear?
I've had just about enough
of your insults.
Oh, yeah?
Well, I've had about enough of
morons and half-wits,
dolts, dunces,
dullards and dumbbells.
And you chowderhead yokel,
you blithering hayseed,
you've had enough of me?
Yes, I have.
That's nice. How appropriate.
Wait in the car, Harry.
The old rustic sucker punch, huh?
A hail of bullets would be nice.
That's enough.
The sheriff didn't mean anything.
He hit me.
- Well, I'm sure he meant to do that.
Albert, release this girl's body
to her family immediately.
I want your test results by noon.
Those are orders.
Thank you, Agent Cooper.
Invitation to love
Starring Martin Hadley as Chet...
Selena Swift as Emerald and Jade...
Evan St Vincent as Jared Lancaster...
and Jason Denbo as Montana.
My darling daughter Jade... and Emerald.
Because of my financial difficulties,
I have decided to end it all tonight.
I hope you can find the strength to
go on without me. Your loving father...
Uncle Leland?
Madeleine?
Jade, what a surprise.
Maddy? Is it you?
Uncle Leland...
I am so sorry.
I'm sure Hank appreciates
your unwavering devotion.
Your husband has been
a model prisoner,
an inspiration to guard
and inmate alike.
He greets the day with a smile
and confounds adversity
with a kind word.
Hank's parole hearing
is scheduled for tomorrow.
Barring unforeseen circumstance,
with your full support
before the board,
he could be released
shortly thereafter.
Any questions?
No.
Will you help find the job that Hank
needs to effect successful parole?
Yes.
- How exactly?
I own the RR Mr Mooney.
You're quite a girl, Norma.
I'll bet you get all kinds of Romeos
in here begging for favours.
How do you keep them
from your door?
I usually tell them I have
a homicidally jealous husband
who's doing 3-5 for manslaughter.
But he expects to be a productive
member of society real soon.
That should conclude our session
for today, Mrs Jennings.
Look at that!
Ducks on the lake!
So fill me in on Leo Johnson.
Leo's one of those guys
you keep your eye on.
So far, we haven't caught him
with his paws in the cookie jar.
Morning, Leo.
Who the hell is he?
This is Special Agent Cooper, FBI.
We'd like to ask you
a couple of questions.
So ask.
"Leo". Is that short for "Leonard"?
That's a question?
Did you know Laura Palmer?
- No.
How well did you know her?
- I said I didn't.
You're lying.
I knew who she was, all right?
Everybody did.
Do youhave a criminal record?
- Nothing. Youcan look it up.
Illegal U-turn, April 1986.
Drunk and disorderly,
November 1987.
September '88, aggravated assault,
charges dropped.
I paid my debt to society.
Where were you the night of Laura
Palmer's murder? Around midnight?
On the road. I called my wife Shelly
from Butte, Montana.
She'll confirm this?
- If you ask her.
Robert?
This may be a good time
for a brief discussion.
You want to talk about cigarettes?
Today?
No, but put it out. It's a filthy habit,
especially for a varsity athlete.
I've attended my share of funerals.
Too many.
Any time a man dies in war,
he dies too soon.
Laura died too soon as well.
Yeah, she did.
But we have a responsibility
to the dead, Robert.
Responsibility is the linchpin
of our society.
Each man responsible
for his own actions,
each action contributing
to the greater good.
What's the good of putting someone
in the ground?
That's man's way of achieving closure.
In ceremony begins understanding
and the will to carry on
without those we must leave behind.
In your life, you must learn, you
will learn, to carry on without them.
Great.
I realise you experience
an ongoing disinclination
to enter fully into
meaningful exchange.
This leads to stalemate
and a desire on my part to force
certain wisdom upon you.
This isn't necessarily a bad thing,
sometimes it's
the best course available.
Son, don't be afraid.
We'll all be there together.
Afraid of what?
- Well, the funeral.
I'm not afraid of any damn funeral.
Afraid?
I can hardly wait.
Afraid?!
I'm gonna turn it upside down!
Everybody ready?
Deputy Hawk.
Agent Cooper, there's no sign
of the man with one arm.
Keep trying.
He's out there somewhere.
If anyone can find him, Hawk can.
He's a tracker?
- The best.
OK, Albert.
What have you got?
Enough forensic spadework
to save your butt
and get mine out of
this godforsaken burg.
What have you got?
OK, first of all, contents of envelope
found in Palmer diary: cocaine.
Toxicology results also positive.
Newsflash: the little lady had a habit.
We've got fibres of twine embedded
in her wrists and upper arms.
Two different kinds of twine.
Fibres of twine found in railroad car
matched the sample from her wrist.
The same twine was used
to bind the Pulaski girl.
Conclusion: she was tied up twice, at
different locations, the night she died.
Once here, once here. Like this.
"Sometimes my arms bend back."
We found traces of pumice in
standing water outside the railroad car.
Soap, industrial strength.
I found identical particles on Laura's
neck. It's not her home-use brand.
My conclusion:
the killer washed his hands
and then leaned in for a kiss.
Like this.
Good Lord...
Distinctive wounds found
on Laura's neck and shoulder
appear to be claw marks,
bites of some kind.
An animal?
Look, it's trying to think.
Finally, a small plastic fragment
from her stomach,
partially dissolved by digestive acids.
I'm taking it back for reconstruction,
as the local facilities give
new meaning to the word "primitive".
I note with some interest
what appears to be the letter "J".
Good work, Albert.
A couple more days, who knows
what I might have found?
Sheriff? It's time.
Excuse us. We have got
a funeral to get to.
Cooper, may I have
a word with you alone?
There's also a report concerning
the physical assault on me this morning.
I think you'll find it's quite accurate.
Requires your signature.
Albert, I'm not going to sign this.
What?
Albert, I hope you can hear me. I've
only been in Twin Peaks a short time.
But in that time I have seen decency,
honour and dignity.
Murder is not a faceless event here.
It is not a statistic
to be tallied up at the end of the day.
Laura Palmer's death has affected
every man, woman and child
because life has meaning here,
every life.
That's a way of living I thought
had vanished, but it hasn't.
It's right here in Twin Peaks.
Sounds like you've been snacking
on some of the local mushrooms.
With your behaviour
towards these good people,
you're lucky
I do not file a report
that could bury youso deep in
Washington you'd never see the sun.
Diane, it's 12:27 pm.
Look into my pension plan options
on outside real estate investment.
I may purchase a piece of property
at what I assume
will be a very reasonable price.
Love me?
You bet.
This a new one?
Yes.
Isn't it beautiful?
How do I look?
Well, you look fine, Nadine.
- Oh, Ed!
Last night was wonderful.
Oh, my darling Ed,
you came back to me.
Now I feel like we're
really together again.
In high school,
I used to watch Norma and you
at those football games.
She was so pretty.
You made such a handsome couple.
But I knew...
even though...
I was just...
a little nobody...
just a little brown mouse...
I always knew inside...
once you got to know me...
we'd be together forever.
That's not your bike, is it, Ed?
It's James.
James who?
We don't want to be late. Ready?
- I'm not going.
It's Laura, James.
I can't. I just can't.
- James!
I don't care what the doctor says.
If you keep indulging him,
he is never going to change.
I don't think we should discuss this
while Johnny is here.
Johnny doesn't know what day it is.
- We have to be patient, Ben.
You be patient. I have waited 20 years
for some sign of intelligent life.
I'm clear about this, Sylvia.
I have my limits.
Don't I know it?
Fine, let's all spray venom
in my general direction.
You take it with no problem.
- Taking it is a speciality of the house.
Sylvia, I'm gonna make it
extremely simple for you.
We can't take Johnny to the funeral
in that ridiculous getup.
Then let the great Doctor Jacoby
see what he can do.
You do it then.
Am I going to have to call
Doctor Jacoby
every damn time I have
a problem with Johnny?
Thank God. All right, let's everyone
just get into the car.
I am the Resurrection and the Life.
He that believeth in me,
though he were dead,
yet shall he live.
And whosoever liveth
and believeth in me
shall never die.
For none of us liveth to himself
and no man dieth to himself.
For, if we live, we live unto the Lord
and, if we die, we die unto the Lord.
Whether we live, therefore, or we die,
we are the Lord's.
Blessed be the dead
who die in the Lord.
Even so saith the Spirit,
for they rest from their labours.
The Lord be with thee.
Let us pray.
O, God, entrust this child Laura
to Thy never-failing care and love
and bring us all
to Thy heavenly kingdom
through the same, Thy son,
Jesus Christ, our Lord,
who liveth and reigneth with Thee,
and the Holy Spirit,
one God, now and forever. Amen.
I baptised Laura Palmer.
I instructed her in Sunday school.
And l, like the rest of you, came to
love her with that special love
that we reserve for the headstrong
and the bold.
Laura was bright.
She was beautiful, she was charming.
But most of all Laura was,
I think, impatient.
She was impatient for her life
to begin,
for the world to finally catch up
to her dreams and ambitions.
Laura used to say that I talk too much.
I'll not make that mistake today.
Just let it be said that I loved her
and I will miss her
the rest of my days.
Amen!
Thank you, Johnny.
What are you looking at?
What are you waiting for?
You make me sick.
You damn hypocrites make me sick!
Everybody knew she was in trouble,
but we didn't do anything.
All you good people...
You wanna know who killed Laura?
You did!
We all did.
And pretty words aren't gonna bring
her back, man, so save your prayers.
She would've laughed at them
anyway.
You are dead, man! You're dead!
That's enough, Bobby. That's enough!
You are dead!
Get off me!
You are dead, man. Dead!
You are dead, man. God... Dead!
Get off me!
Ah, my baby. Laura!
Laura! Laura!
Lee, hang on.
The whole thing has gone haywire.
Don't ruin this, too!
My baby!
Laura!
Here's the father
and this is his daughter in the coffin.
I'm telling you, Harry,
he's just not gonna figure this out.
Ed, that's a bet I'll take. For the check.
He's right on time.
Harry, careful who you trust.
He's just not one of us.
Cooper, take a seat.
Harry, I got your note.
Hawk. Big Ed.
How would you like
some fresh huckleberry pie?
I would love a slice of pie.
Norma, slice of huckleberry pie, heated.
Vanilla ice cream, coffee.
- Coming right up.
Big Ed, how long have you been
in love with Norma?
Ed, looks like pie and coffee's on you.
What did you call me in for
besides the highlights of the menu?
You'd better tell him.
Somebody's running drugs into
Twin Peaks from across the border.
We've tried for six months to set up a bust,
top to bottom. Nobody walks.
Who's targeted?
- Jacques Renault.
Bartender at the Roadhouse.
We figure him for the middle man.
Ed's been doing some undercover.
The night you got into town,
he was staking Renault out.
We think Renault slipped him
a mickey.
Felt like being hit with a log splitter.
I didn't know you were a deputy.
- He's not.
It's a little outside your jurisdiction.
Somebody's selling drugs
to high school kids.
That's everybody's jurisdiction.
I call Ed in when I need him.
He's not the only one I called.
Thanks, Norma.
- Enjoy.
This must be where pies go
when they die.
OK, Harry, would you please tell me
why you really called me in here?
Go along with me on this,
even if it sounds a little weird.
I'm with you.
- Twin Peaks is different.
A long way from the world.
You've noticed that.
Yes, I have.
- That's exactly the way we like it.
But there's a back end to that
that's kind of different, too.
Maybe that's the price we pay
for the good things.
What would that be?
- There's a sort of evil out there.
Something very, very strange
in these old woods.
Call it what you want.
A darkness. A presence.
It takes many forms,
but it's been out there for as long
as anyone can remember.
We've always been here to fight it.
- We?
Men before us. Men before them.
More after we're gone.
- A secret society.
Why don't we take Agent Cooper
for a little ride?
Where to?
- The Bookhouse.
This is where we get together.
Going on 20 years now.
- "We" meaning...?
The Bookhouse Boys.
Coffee's free.
- Like the sound of that.
Cooper, you know James.
Agent Cooper.
- James.
This is Joey Paulson.
- Joey.
Who's this?
- Bernard Renault, Jacques' brother.
Janitor at the Roadhouse.
Bernard came across the border this
morning with an ounce of cocaine.
Thought we'd ask him
a few questions.
Did you sell drugs to Laura Palmer?
- I don't sell drugs.
How much does Jacques pay you
to be the mule?
Jacques don't pay me nothing.
I'm no mule.
So that ounce was for personal use?
- That's right.
I guess you don't get much sleep
at night, Bernie.
Your brother didn't come to work
the last few days. Where's he been?
I don't know.
He got personal business.
Who else is he dealing with?
- Why don't you ask him?
He'll be back tonight. Any minute.
To work at the Roadhouse?
- He's the bartender, isn't he?
Bernard, we've got you tied up
in a chair.
You're mixed up with your brother
in a wide variety of felonies.
Why in the world would you tell us
where and when to find him?
Yeah?
- Leo, it's Jacques.
What's up?
- The light. The bust light's on.
Bernard's in trouble.
- You sure?
I saw it, man. You gotta get me
out of here, Leo. Border run.
Where are you?
- Phone booth by the Cash & Carry.
And I don't like waiting, man.
- Shut up. I'm on my way.
Hi.
Where are you going?
- You don't need to know.
Josie? Josie, what's wrong?
Nothing.
Nothing?
God, you're beautiful.
Josie, there is something wrong.
What is it? I want you to tell me.
Something horrible is going
to happen.
They want to hurt me. I know it.
- Who? Who wants to hurt you?
Catherine.
Catherine and Benjamin Horne.
What makes you think so?
I heard Catherine on the phone
saying I'd never suspect.
Just like with Andrew's death.
Andrew's death was an accident.
- Was it?
Catherine keeps
the mill account books in her safe.
Two books, different numbers.
Andrew built this years ago.
I don't think Catherine knows
that I know it's here.
Why do you think they have
two sets of books?
The usual reasons would be something
to do with stealing. Maybe worse.
There were two. I saw them.
You believe me, don't you?
- Of course I do.
There's nothing unusual in this one.
- There were two.
I swear, there were two.
Have... have you seen my tackle box?
The next time you and the merry
widow want to take a peak in my safe,
don't go to so much trouble.
Be a man about it, Pete.
Ask me to my face.
Maybe I'll check the truck.
Dr Jacoby?
I didn't see you at the funeral today.
I'm a terrible person, Agent Cooper.
I pretend that I'm not.
But I am.
Oh, I sit and listen to their problems.
Day after day.
These people think of me
as their friend.
Truth is, I really don't care.
I thought nothing,
no one could ever reach me again.
Laura changed all that.
I couldn't come today.
I just couldn't.
I hope she understands.
I hope she forgives me.
You think it's possible?
You think somebody killed Andrew?
I don't know.
I believe what they want is
to take the mill away from me.
For Benjamin to have the land.
If it was true with Andrew...
you think they'll kill me too?
Think they would?
Josie...
Nothing is gonna happen to you.
Not now, not ever.
Not while I'm around.
Do you believe in the soul?
Several.
More than one?
- Blackfoot legend.
Waking souls that give life
to the mind and the body.
A dream soul that wanders.
Dream souls...
Where do they wander?
- Faraway places.
The Land of the Dead.
Is that where Laura is?
Laura is in the ground, Agent Cooper.
That's the only thing I'm sure of.
To Laura.
Godspeed.
Will you dance with me?
- Sorry.
Please?
Dance with me? Please?
Dance with me.
- Leave us alone.
Dance with me, please.
Please.
Somebody dance with me.
Mr Palmer?
- Leland.
Let's take you home.
Home...
Home. Home.