Audrey, you're a high school girl.
I'm an agent of the FBI.
So do you want me to leave or what?
What I want and what I need
are two different things, Audrey.
When a man joins the Bureau he takes
an oath to uphold certain values.
Values that he's sworn to live by.
This is wrong, Audrey.
We both know it.
But don't you like me?
- I like you very much.
You're beautiful, intelligent, desirable.
Everything a man wants in his life.
But what you need right now,
more than anything, is a friend.
Someone who will listen.
Friends, huh?
I'm gonna go and get us two malts
and some fries.
Then tell me all your troubles.
- That could take all night.
The night is young.
Now, I'm gonna get the food,
and you're gonna get dressed.
I can't tell you all my secrets.
- Secrets are dangerous things.
Do you have any?
- No.
Laura had a lot of secrets.
Finding those out is my job.
Good morning, Officer Brennan.
I sure wish you would stop calling me
Officer Brennan.
Officer Andy, this is peak activity time
at the station switchboard.
So it's really not convenient
for me to talk right now.
Twin Peaks Sheriff's Station,
may I help you?
One moment, please.
Doctor Stanicek? Yes, it's me.
Oh.
Uh-huh.
Well...
thank you, Doctor.
No, I'm fine.
Bye.
Morning, Lucy.
I heard you were out sick.
I'm much better today, thanks.
Good.
I found it: "Gracula religiosa.
"Commonly known as the hill mynah.
"Native to Southeast Asia,
Indonesia.
"Feeds on fruit mainly,
some invertebrates.
"Its ability to mimic the human voice
is amazing."
Yeah, well, so far we haven't heard
a peep. Hey, Waldo, what's up?
It says here that mimicry
is a kind of play with the mynah.
But this one's in a weakened condition.
Starved, dehydrated.
I'd say he's feeling anything
but playful.
Here you go, little fella.
You want to feed him, Agent Cooper?
- I don't like birds.
When do you think
he'll start talking?
According to the book, his urge to
mimic should return with his health.
If it does, then we got a witness.
- Well, we better keep feeding him.
You got any apples?
- Yeah. There's some in the fridge.
These grapes are on the edge.
- These came in from your office.
Forensics confirms Jacques
had three guests to his cabin:
Laura Palmer, Ronnette Pulaski
and Leo Johnson.
That was the only exposed negative
on the roll of film. Look familiar?
That's our Waldo.
- No, Harry, the girl.
That's Laura.
Well, now we know who and when.
We don't know why.
Voice activated, Harry.
When the bird talks,
maybe we'll get some answers.
This matches the fragment
found in Laura's stomach.
A chip from One-Eyed Jacks.
- Renault deals in the casino.
A little fieldwork is in order.
- Jacks is over the border.
Well, I know that, Harry.
That's why I was thinking this would
be a job for the Bookhouse Boys.
Better call Hawk on that one.
Shelly!
Bobby Briggs.
Come on, lover-boy. Leo's waiting.
I called, but your dad answered.
- Bobby's here, baby. Bobby's here.
I shot him, Bobby.
I know I did.
He just screamed and screamed.
He sounded like an animal.
You what?
Slow down, Shelly. Talk to me.
He's out there, I know he is.
He's gonna kill me.
Bobby, he's gonna kill me.
- Shelly!
Start over. Go real slow.
Leo came home late last night.
He was all beat up.
He had blood all over him.
I told him I was never ever
gonna let him hurt me again.
But he came at me.
So I pulled the trigger.
I shot him, Bobby.
What am I gonna do?
Where am I gonna hide?
Shelly, Leo Johnson is history.
Understand?
I'm taking care of you from now on.
I'm gonna deal with Leo.
I'm gonna deal with James.
Bobby's gonna deal with everything.
Birdseed? No, this bird eats fruit.
The sheriff says it's a witness.
No, not just because it saw something,
because it talks. It needs to eat...
What's up, Doc?
Just a few words before I go to sleep.
I feel like I'm gonna dream tonight.
Big bad ones, you know?
The kind you like.
It's easier talking into the recorder.
I guess I feel I can say anything.
All my secrets.
The naked ones.
I know you like those, Doc.
I know you like me, too.
That'll be my little secret, OK?
Just like your coconut.
Why is it so easy to make men like me?
And I don't even have to try
very hard.
Or maybe...
...if it was harder...
This one's empty.
February 23rd.
The night Laura died.
The tape's not in there.
- He must still have it.
She died, he never returned it.
- Do you think Dr Jacoby killed her?
We're gonna find that tape. Tonight.
Where?
- Jacoby's office.
What if he's there?
- We'll get him out.
How?
Maybe he gets a phone call.
From Laura.
What's up, Doc?
Just a few words before I go to sleep.
I feel like I'm gonna dream tonight.
Here, try this.
It smells like a florist.
This won't do.
I want something more fruity.
Fruity?
- As in fruit.
Jenny, could I see you in my office
in five minutes?
I'm not making myself clear.
I want to make a statement.
Maybe you should try hanging it
around your neck.
It's a perfume,
it's a fashion accessory.
Two statements for the price of one.
I don't appreciate your attitude.
Well, thank you for shopping
at Horne's Department Store.
I'm going to the girls' room.
- OK.
There's a real bad accident outside.
It sounded like a bus or something.
Come right this way, Jenny.
I have something really special
to talk about today.
Come right in.
My, my, you look lovely.
Sit, sit.
- Thank you, Mr Battis.
This is for you, Jenny.
A reward for a job well done.
It's a unicorn.
Ancient symbol of purity.
Tamed only by the young at heart.
Wow, a unicorn.
Have a good time at the club?
- I had a great time, Mr Battis.
They were pleased with you
as well, I must say.
They'd like you to continue.
Believe me, not many girls qualify.
Really?
- Yes.
Now the variety of work is completely
up to you. Hostess, cocktail waitress.
Or, if you are chosen,
hospitality girl.
What's that?
Hospitality girls escort
important guests, VIPs.
It's a lucrative opportunity, Jenny.
Attending to wealthy men
in need of a little company.
That sounds cool.
As long as they're wealthy.
Jenny, your attitude will take you
far in this life.
Call this number, ask for Black Rose.
Why don't we go to Eveningwear
and find you something elegant?
Elegant sounds great, Mr Battis.
Elegant.
How do you feel about rose?
Ronnette Pulaski.
In prison, you remember faces
from home.
Even people you barely knew
seem like friends.
It's something to hang on to.
- Must've been hard on you.
I paid my debt, that's what counts.
You were a really big help around here.
I wanna thank you
for getting Norma through.
You're welcome, Hank.
It's no problem.
She told me in her letters how much
it meant, how much Pete helped.
Pete?
- Yeah. No, not Pete...
No, you mean Ed.
- Yeah, Big Ed.
Yeah, I'm a little better at faces
than names, I guess.
Yeah, Big Ed.
Shelly, can we get another cup
over here?
Hello, Hank.
- Hi, Harry. Glad to see me?
You looking for a free lunch?
I recommend the meatloaf.
- Well, save it. I'm looking for you.
Harry, I'm innocent.
- What you are is on parole.
You pay your case officer
a visit once a week, Fridays.
You miss a visit, you go to jail.
Got it?
Thanks for the reminder, Sheriff.
Stop in any time.
You think people
really change, Cooper?
I don't.
Oh, afternoon, guys.
Would you like some coffee?
Afternoon, Shelly. Yes.
- We should be on our way.
Harry...
I'm gonna let you in
on a little secret.
Every day, once a day,
give yourself a present.
Don't plan it, don't wait for it,
just let it happen.
Could be a new shirt,
a catnap in your office chair...
or two cups of good,
hot, black coffee.
Like this.
- A present.
Like Christmas?
- Yeah.
Man, that hits the spot.
Nothing like a great cup
of black coffee.
Bye, Audrey.
So did Battis get you a dress?
- Yeah, he did.
Me, too. I'm gonna be hostess.
- Oh, really. Cool.
Get one of these, too?
- What will I do with a horned horse?
Ditto. I bet he's cartons of them.
- He probably does.
God, I did a really dumb thing.
I lost that number he gave me
for Black Rose, do you have it?
Yeah. I got it.
- Great.
Here.
Thanks.
OK, I'll talk to you later.
- OK, see you tomorrow.
I wasn't fooling, Montana.
You show them, Chet.
You show all of them.
Tune in tomorrow for
"Invitation to Love".
Ed.
I'm eating bonbons.
Come on, honey. It's not that bad.
- You don't know how bad it is.
You don't know all the things
I was gonna do for us.
I know.
A new TV. I was gonna do that.
I already looked at a motorboat.
- Sweetheart...
It wasn't just things I was gonna buy.
It was the new life we were gonna lead.
Nadine, there's plenty
of patent attorneys.
We just gotta find one
who understands drape runners.
Rejected.
Rejected, that's what he said.
Nobody will say anything different.
- Don't give up. Don't you dare.
I just got that baby back
from Tim and Tom's Taxidermy.
When I caught him,
he was this big.
I guess by the time they take the
innards out and put the stuffing in...
it loses something
in the translation.
Well, Pete, it's still a fine looking
trophy, no matter what the size.
Yeah, well,
size isn't everything, I guess.
Harry, I didn't expect you
to be here.
I'm late for the mill,
but I'll make time for us.
What's wrong?
What were you doing
at the Timber Falls Motel Tuesday?
Tuesday, I was at the mill.
- Hawk saw you.
I know you were there.
Harry...
You can tell me anything.
Josie, you can tell me anything.
I was there because Ben and Catherine
were there together.
I followed them, and I took pictures.
What's this all about?
You asked me for proof last time...
and I followed them
and I took pictures.
The other night I heard Catherine
talking on the phone.
Something about an accident.
A fire.
A fire at the mill.
A fire at Andrew's mill. My mill.
I'm not gonna let this happen. No.
Neither will I. I won't let it happen.
Well, now.
- Evening, Harry. Ed, you all set?
Is that what you're wearing?
- It's pretty spiffy.
Like to gamble, Ed?
I went to Reno once.
But I never felt too lucky.
Well, you're gonna be lucky tonight.
It's $10,000 of the Bureau's money.
Whenever I gamble, I bring back 10 to 15%.
How much you wanna start with?
How about 300?
And, Ed, the suit is perfect.
Well, Harry'd like to talk with you.
So why don't I see you outside?
Yeah, Harry, what's on your mind?
I'm worried about Josie.
She's been real afraid.
About what?
- Ben Horne and Catherine Martell.
They've seen each other on the side
for years, Josie just found out.
She thinks they're planning to burn
down the mill and get rid of her.
Well, do you believe her?
Ben Horne wants that land
for Ghostwood development,
and Josie won't sell.
Yeah, I believe her.
- How much do you know about her?
Where she's from?
Who she was before?
What are you getting at?
- The truth. That's my job.
I know all I need to know.
I love her, and she's in trouble.
That's good enough for me.
Let's look into it.
Thanks.
Is Hawk ready?
- Yeah, he's outside in the van.
I got that new Cadillac you wanted.
- Good. It's perfect for our cover.
High rollers from the Tri-Cities?
- Oral surgeons, Harry.
Big spenders vacationing
among the firs.
Yeah, has Agent Cooper returned yet?
I need to leave another message.
Tell him that Audrey called again.
Yes, it's still urgent.
Thanks for seeing me, Mrs Martell.
- It's all right.
Normally I never impose this late.
- That's fine. What's this about?
Every agent is instructed,
five signatures...
and, somehow, we missed one.
Refresh my memory. What policy?
- Your new life insurance.
Since the binder takes effect tonight,
I had no choice. It couldn't wait.
Right here, please.
Is everything in order, Mrs Martell?
Yes, it's just...
This was handled without our meeting
each other, and I'd almost forgotten.
To be honest with you, Mrs Martell,
I withheld that last page.
Did you?
- I admit, I thought it unusual.
Life insurance, and the client
is too busy to be involved?
I mean, you did know
about this policy, didn't you?
Are you suggesting that there's
something irregular at work here?
I never got that idea from
Mrs Packard. Or from Mr Horne.
When he offered to collect signatures,
I thought it was fine. Just with...
a new account, I like to be
certain to cross every "t".
Right here, please.
You know, I'm noticing there
are some minor changes
that I asked my attorney to make
that are not included in this draft.
I'd like to go over this
with him in the morning
and initial the changes and get
the documents to you at that time.
If there's anything that I can do
to help you...
with the policy,
or anything at all...
Are you an ambitious man, Mr Neff?
- One likes to think so.
One never knows. There may be
a few "t's" left to cross.
Goodnight.
- Mrs Martell.
I'll see myself out.
Think.
Ed, why don't you open that up?
Wow. Look at all this.
Well, I'm sorry.
There's a curly-haired wig in there.
Ed, it's gonna work like gangbusters.
I'll help you on
with one of those moustaches.
Will it fit? I've got a big head.
- OK, give it a try.
Testing: one, two.
Laura.
What happened?
- Somebody shot Waldo.
Ah, Jesus.
Poor Waldo.
What happened?
- Somebody shot Waldo.
Birdie, birdie, birdie.
Want some orange?
Come on, let's share.
Hello, Waldo.
Laura.
Don't go there.
Hurting me. Hurting me.
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it!
Leo, no! Leo, no!
Casino's probably in the back.
If Jacques is dealing,
he'll be there.
Well, I'll give you the high sign
and clear out.
Here comes something.
- Evening, fellas.
They call me Blackie.
- Glad to know you.
I like your style.
- Most do. First time here?
Yeah, it's our rookie season.
- Tonight is spring training.
With a little luck,
you just might make the team.
You look like a cop.
I'm the cop.
You look like Cary Grant.
Got a name?
Barney and Fred.
Just in from the Tri-Cities.
Well, Fred, what's your line?
- Own a gas station.
I'm an oral surgeon.
I've got a Chevy parked out back
with a serious root canal problem.
Wanna take a look?
I was hoping you needed gum work.
I'd sure like a look under your hood.
Fred's OK.
- Fred's a prince.
So, boys, what's your pleasure?
- Cards. Dice.
For starters.
Casino's that way.
This might just be your lucky night.
Luck has nothing to do with it.
Not bad, Ed. Not bad at all.
Hawk, we have a small casino room
with the usual games of chance.
Bar's at the far end,
and there's stairs to who knows where.
Everybody's having a good time.
No sign of Jacques Renault.
Ed's gonna head to the craps table.
I'm gonna play some blackjack.
Ed, let's gamble.
You simply have got to teach me
some of these incredible songs.
Incredible!
- Incredible.
Jerry? Maybe you'd like to take some
of our guests down to the dining room.
I'll be with you in a half a tick!
You should've seen them
at this tour of the site. The trees!
Jerry.
- They worship them.
I caught a couple of them
hugging pine.
When are they signing
the contracts?
This needs more pecan.
They're ready.
They're poised with their pen
in their hand.
So, what's the catch?
- More fun.
Signing party. They want to finalise
the deal at One-Eyed Jacks.
How'd they find out about Jacks?
I take full responsibility.
Jerry, Jerry.
Get them back on the van.
OK, everybody back in the van.
Road trip! Road trip!
- Going on a road trip! Road trip!
Hello.
- Is she there?
I just came back. She's gone.
We need her at the mill.
- I'll get her there.
Is it set for tonight?
- Yes.
You shouldn't call for a while.
- I know the drill.
You're not a shy one, are you?
- I'm not shy.
Hester Prynne.
Pretty name.
Maple House in Vancouver...
Roy's in Chicago...
Calgary Stampede '87 through '89.
Where'd you work in Calgary?
- Around.
Can you give me a name?
The Lost Dude Ranch.
Big Amos still running things
out there?
Bigger and better.
Big Amos is the name of my dog.
I read "The Scarlet Letter"
in high school, too.
Give me one reason why I shouldn't
airmail you back to civilisation.
Sign here.
Welcome to One-Eyed Jacks, Hester.
21 again. Another winner.
How did you do?
Do I have to pay you back?
- We'll take it out of my winnings.
Care to sit in?
- Blackjack is not my game.
Can you count to 10?
- On a good night.
Then you can win at blackjack.
Gentlemen, place your bets.
Jacques, is it?
- That's me.
Jade, here's to old times.
"Should old acquaintance be forgot?"
Come on, baby. Bottoms up.
One for the road. For old times' sake.
Aloha.
Hey, what's up, Doc?
Feel like I'm gonna dream tonight.
Big bad ones. You know?
The kind you like.
Who is this?
- Who do you think it is, silly?
I want to see you.
You're not Laura.
- OK, Doc.
First thing you have to do is
go to the door.
Go on.
There's something waiting for you.
That's today's paper, Doc.
Now do you believe me?
Meet me at Sparkwood and 21
in 10 minutes.
But wait...
You think he bought it?
I think so.
I think he did.
OK, wait here for us.
Gazebo.
Say goodbye, James.