you
hello Hollywood and welcome to this
morning's Walk of Fame ceremony a
special shout out to our fans watching
the live video stream courtesy of our
media partner variety I'm Lauren Gubler
the retired president CEO of the chamber
which is presenting this ceremony now
today we dedicate the 2,660 fourth star
on the Hollywood Walk of Fame to a man
who is one of the most popular chefs
around in fact he is only the third chef
to get a star on our famous walk a flame
today we honor Guy Fieri so let me tell
you just a little bit about our honoree
and feel free to cheer for anything you
want that's good good practice
Guy Fieri chef restaurateur New York
Times bestselling author and the
award-winning television host and
executive producer all of those
characteristics are of a man who grew up
in the northern california community of
Ferndale
he began his love affair with food at
the age of 10 selling soft pretzels from
a three-wheeled bicycle cart he built
which his father called the awesome
pretzel cart after selling pretzels and
washing dishes for six years guy earned
enough money to pursue his dream of
studying abroad as an exchange student
in Chantilly France there he gained a
profound appreciation for inter
international cuisine that further
strengthened his passion for food he
returned to the US and graduated from
the University of Nevada Las Vegas
somebody must be here from there all
right with a degree in hospitality
management soon after graduation he went
to work for several restaurants right
here in Southern California before
opening his first restaurant up in Santa
Rosa in 2006
guy burst onto the national scene when
he won The Next Food Network Star
competition and since since that time
guy has created a thriving culinary
Empire as the host and producer of
top-rated TV shows including the
long-running five-time Emmy nominated
diners drive-ins and dives
the show airs on the Food Network
Fridays at 9:00 p.m. his show guy's
grocery games airs Wednesdays at 9:00
p.m. now guy earned a Daytime Emmy and a
nomination for Outstanding culinary host
for guys ranch kitchen and other shows
have included guy's big bite ultimate
recipe showdown the best thing I ever
ate and many more a prolific chef he has
opened over 63 restaurants around the
world and it see from the Las Vegas
Strip to the Atlantic City Boardwalk
from South Africa to Dubai and he's also
authored six best-selling cookbooks in
2013 guy fulfilled a personal passion
with the launch of the hunt and ride
winery in Sonoma County named and that
is named for his two sons hunter and
rider
who are here with us he continues to
support numerous charities including his
own cooking with kids the make-a-wish
Foundation and Best Buddies
International
he recently donated his time and efforts
to cooking for the first responders and
displaced residents of the recent
California fires how about that so now
please help me welcome to the stage our
honoree guy you are okay well before we
get to hear from guy we have a couple of
special guests who've asked to say a few
words about him our first speaker today
is chief lifestyle brands officer at
Discovery where she oversees the
management of Food Network HGTV TLC and
too many more to mention she previously
served as president of the six scripts
networks and prior to becoming a network
executive
she spent 12 years as a CBS network news
producer traveling the world to cover
breaking news and events
please welcome Kathleen Finch to the
stage well it is just so incredibly
exciting no you can't it is such an
honor to be here to say a few words
about my dear friend everybody's friend
Guy Fieri whoo and to celebrate this
incredibly exciting occasion of getting
a star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame as
you heard our guys first star came when
he won Food Network Star which is our
annual competition to find celebrity
chef and not the day has gone by that
all of us at Food Network are not so
incredibly grateful for the day that you
want and all that has happened since
then you now have gone on to host
multiple multiple series you have
restaurants all over the world cook
culinary products and my favorite thing
you have many fans who love to dress up
like you on Halloween we probably have a
few out there today but even with all
that success he is still one of the
nicest and most generous people I have
ever known he always takes time to sign
autographs and take pictures and my
favorite thing to do with guy is walk
into a restaurant because when he walks
into a restaurant that staffs go crazy
he is their culinary rockstar and he
will spend as much time with the Busboys
as he will with the head chef he loves
to support the next generation of food
stars on camera and behind the scenes
including through all of his incredible
charities like cooking with kids he's
always thinking about how he can make a
difference whether it's changing lives
by showcasing an unknown restaurant on
one of his shows and trust me being
featured on diners drive-ins and dives
is a game-changer for these small
business owners and I know that we have
some here today or when guide is saving
lives like as you heard when he drops
everything that he's doing to set up
triage kitchens to feed the firefighters
all he does without any fanfare I have
asked him before can we publicize this
and he says no I don't want anything to
get in the way of feeding the
firefighters guy is a unique talent an
incredible chef and just a terrific
person and all of us at Food Network
love having the mayor of flavortown as
part of our family and we are so proud
to share this day with your family with
Lori and hunter and writer and the
entire Fieri family we love you guys
Thank You Kathleen Finch well at 22 our
next speaker is the eldest son of Guy
Fieri's two boys he was at one time
considering a career in Supercross
racing but has since shifted directions
looking to carve out a lane of his own
within the family business
he is currently pursuing a Bachelor of
Science in hospitality management at
UNLV following in his dad's footsteps
and he's excited by what the future has
to offer
please welcome hunter Fieri and rider as
well
you can't cover your ears well thank you
for everyone for being here to celebrate
with my dad and our family this is truly
amazing thank you to the Hollywood
Chamber of Commerce for keeping this
awesome tradition alive dad when I was a
kid and I saw you an expert never star I
was completely blown away by the fact
that you were actually on TV well I
didn't in my perception of you as a
father I knew our family was going to
change positively but I never imagined
come to this point when I first found
out that you're winning the star suits
on the Hollywood Walk of Fame I was in
disbelief no I thought you were lying it
was just more like I couldn't believe it
was happening
this is something that big movie stars
get not my dad to write over me your dad
so you can imagine how we feel about
this moment where your name will forever
sit with the legends of Hollywood you
always tell me throughout my childhood
if it were easy everyone would do it and
you couldn't have been more right how
you managed to work non-stop build your
empire take care of your family and
friends and still find time to be an
amazing father is truly inspiring people
always ask me how does he do it
how does he manage work and family time
what's it like having the mayor of
flavortown as a father it's see the same
person at home as he is on TV that's
quite simple he puts his family first
you make sure we are never hungry he
never gives up on the work that needs to
be done never home and yes what you see
is what you get I believe that's why
you're so good at what you do because he
never changed he's always been that wild
energetic and creative rebel ever since
his early Ferndale days dad the respect
integrity and dedication and love you
have shown to all of us makes me look up
to you in awe it's truly amazing how
this is all transpired like your buddy
Drake would say you start from the
bottom and now you're here
this star is much more than an
impressive souvenir from what a lot
people think would be the best job in
the world but it's also a recognition of
your creativity innovation and passion
for the culinary and television
industries you left your mark and now
it's right on the boulevard people to
see truthfully we all know this is just
the beginning of great things that
you're going to do but really it doesn't
much matter to me and writer and mom and
union champs because you're already our
dad husband son and hero you're my best
friend you're my mentor and my idol and
I cannot be more proud of you thank you
for always being you and for being the
only star we ever need to meet you love
your dad congratulations all right hard
to top that we have a few VIPs here who
I'd like to acknowledge at this time so
if you'd wave to the crowd as I
introduce you we have two celebrated
chefs and judges on Food Network's
chopped series they include Scott Conant
and Mark Murphy please wave to the crowd
back there we also have with us Aarti
Sequeira who is a fellow net Food
Network Star winner I believe in the
sixth season back then and Justin Warner
who was a fellow Food Network Star
winner in the eighth season welcome
we're delighted to have you with us well
it's a time for our last speaker and I
saw I'd have to say last but not least
this Texas native is one of Hollywood's
leading men his career was launched with
his performance in the cult classic
Dazed and Confused since then he has
appeared in over 40 feature films that
have grossed over 1 billion dollars
please welcome Oscar winner and walk a
Famer Matthew McConaughey to the stage
how're we doing
alright alright alright alright when I'm
around guy and I say that it makes me
feel like an 81 z28 and there is one of
those we have been in one of those so 15
or so I don't know years ago I was
living in an Airstream traveling across
America yeah almost a cheer there for
our country I lived on the road and I
came across this show diners drive-ins
and dives
and it quickly became my favorite show
it was a show that when I would pull
into a trailer park I'd always say
listen do you have an open southern sky
I need a spot with an open southern sky
they said why I said because my
satellite dish finds satellite through
in the southern sky and it's the only
way I can tune in get my cable TV and
see Triple D quickly became my favorite
show one day on the road I I get the
number of the host Guy Fieri and I call
him up and I said listen hey Matt we
kind of hairr good yeah man I know yes
listen I'm uh you know I'm gonna be in
Spokane Washington tomorrow night I'm
headed that way
where should I eat oh I gotcha he says
gives me a place a must a must eat
restaurant I go to it it was always
topped so what I started doing is I said
this is this is kind of working I hop
I've got I've got a mobile concierge for
tea we're gonna go eat and I started
sharing with guy all of my roadmap to
where I was gonna be traveling over the
next week or the next two weeks and he
would map out the must go to restaurants
along the way as I drove through the
highways of America and I got to say
thank you because the Subway sandwich is
that although I like them they were
getting a bit old
but it could even those started finding
great little restaurants diners
drive-ins and dives
in America or one day I got back to Los
Angeles where actually was renting an
actual home with an address and got all
the guy and invited him over to house
and this is when I met more than the guy
who was on my favorite TV show this is
when I met a conscientious guy for Yeti
a guy fieri who cared about family who
cared about faith this is when I met a
guy who I could tell right away without
hustle a lot of people who maybe with
equal Talent outwork them this is where
I met a guy who was not a food snob and
I want to give an applause to that
because that can happen thank you for
that this is a guy I met who was curious
he was also dealing with some newfound
fame and wanted to talk about how best
to navigate it we cooked a lot of food
we ate a lot of food we drank a lot of
spirits we talked about life and we
talked about being authentic to who you
are and that's the night that I met you
got Yeti guy came into this business
when food being on TV it wasn't really a
business at all it was a time when food
was going from just being a meal on our
place to being entertainment and must
watch TV yet as he moved up in the ranks
he did just that he always remained
exactly who he was he didn't have to
play a part
he was the character from his days as a
contestant on the Food Network Star
through his major success was over with
over 13 Network shows and multiple Emmy
nominations you really haven't changed
who you are
authenticity we talked about the first
night we met and in a business where you
can be anyone you want to
you've been you the whole time and easy
congratulations and congratulations on
getting your star on the Hollywood Walk
of Fame brother Thank You Matthew
McConaughey so guy the Hollywood Chamber
of Commerce administers the Hollywood
Walk of Fame on behalf of the city of
Los Angeles and they have passed a
special resolution in your honor today
that I've been asked to present to you
so you see this beautiful resolution
here it talks about all of your
achievements it's signed by the
president of the City Council even the
mayor mayor Garcetti and I've been told
if you put this in your car window you
might not get a parking ticket but I
can't vouch for that so on behalf of the
city of Los Angeles it's my pleasure to
present you with this city resolution
so guy it's finally your turn to speak
but let me just say by way of final
introduction that we are very pleased to
name this guy Fatih day in Hollywood
well all right oh it's my favorite thing
I say it all the time and I'm not even
trying to be funny about it first let me
say Hollywood Chamber I don't know what
was going on that evaluation committee
that day but somebody was having a great
day and my buddy Joe I gotta thank all
of you for making this happen you are an
amazing group of people thank you and
Anna Martinez standing right there the
glue the one that really makes it happen
I think you probably come out here and
put the star on the ground yourself and
grind it off in the morning and do the
whole deal I know you do so please for
the lady that made this really all
happen ana martinez please you know to
say that this is an honor and a
highlight of my career would be a would
be a gross understatement this is I
don't know I was on a plane to Miami I
ended up on the moon this I didn't see
coming I thought I had it going I
thought I'd figured it all out and I
will tell you what I'm pretty blown away
I couldn't even do Ryder asked me the
other day on the way to school did you
ever dream of this I said man this this
wasn't even in the dream world so when
it gets to this level I got to tell you
there's a lot of special people making
it happen so thank you thank you all
very much all three of you thank you
when I give out - thank yous the first
two people that get it are my mom and
dad alright those are the first two
penning penny and Jim right here the
redhead over there the redheaded wonder
my mom and dad and then just right there
close second just because they were
first is my wife Laurie my sons hunter
and Ryder without question
this is why it's happening my nephew
Jules my sister Morgan my father-in-law
Bob my brother Johnny why's we miss you
so we also have the knuckle sandwich
crew where are you oh you guys are at
the bar okay
the William Morris Endeavor gang the
Brooks Media Group and of course I get
to play for the best team in television
give it up for the Food Network ladies
and gentlemen I've had a wild ride I
really have my parents always encouraged
me to think outside the box and do
whatever I want to do and be whatever I
want to what I want to be so all of this
you can blame them for but they told me
work hard have direction have vision
love what you do and surround yourself
with great people that's what this is
really about to me as all the great
people I surrounded myself with my I
call them my my angels my advisers my
mentors and my coaches that's really
what's happened I mean that's a lot of
people that all participated and helped
Channel and can direct this this wild
child is under called it now I was a
little bad as a child I was a little bit
of a handful and I know that's hard to
imagine stop imagining I know but some
of my behavior when I was a kid and the
certain I wasn't allowed to go to
certain kids houses and go to the movies
with me and and people thought I might
end up on the streets well not this
street but yeah I grew up in a great
little town called Ferndale well I had a
ton of mentors and advisers and angels
and supporters I had this little pretzel
cart as we were talking about the
awesome pretzel cart and I had some
fantastic teachers that found me two
very young age and said this kids got a
little bit more than seasoned DS this
kids can actually make it that's Fran
Moriarty and Charlie Davidson
great mentors I skipped out of high
school when I was a sophomore when I was
a junior actually went to France as an
exchange student not really through a
program just kind of like bailed town
and went to France
my parents were cool with it I don't
know hippies came back never finished
high school but but actually got my GED
before you start writing about that when
I got my GED I went I took off I went to
Sacramento had a great guy great mentor
again in the restaurant business a guy
named Fernando dela Rosa super supporter
and I got myself to UNLV I'm a running
rebel baby and an ATO brother had a
great time there and again some
fantastic supporters they're showing up
right now hold please
it's actually the flavortown police back
to the regular scheduled program so I'm
in I'm in Vegas and again I'm having a
little bit of that wild child thing
going on unfortunately I had these two
these two advisors or maybe they're
angels I don't know what but to two
great two great guys that really helped
me out
Vinh seed and John Stefanelli and so I
got I got out of college and I came to
here to Los Angeles the Greater Los
Angeles area started doing restaurants
and again someone had to kind of you
know now I know it all because I'm I've
graduated first time but I graduated so
I know it all so of course I get a guy
named Tom Karen that has to kind of
wrangle me and kind of keep me in
direction and he handles me for a few
years and he passes me off this dude
named Robert Kissinger and I used to
drive up and down these streets we had
restaurants here in the area and I used
to drive up and down even then I never
thought man I'll get on this I'll get on
this star one day but that's what it's
really been it's really been a lot of
people it's been it's been an amazing
group of family and friends crazy family
crazy friends always it crazy friends
crazy fit I don't you know II get the
general idea so I took off from here
after doing restaurants went up to
Sonoma County a wonderful place to live
and again a bunch of mentors and
advisers and angels and supporters and
opened up a funky little restaurant
company called Johnny garlic's you guys
six have you been there that's great but
I did Johnny garlic's they did it with
an amazing group of people and those
people I really think where that was
kind of well I was kind of the pinnacle
my career was at its point I was 35
years old an amazing family I wondered
all I wanted to be was a great dad a
great husband a great friend and a great
chef and at 35 years old folks it was
over I did it I was graduated I was
finally with some direction until one
day two buddies again these mentors
angels advisers these two might have
been the devil's a guy named mustard and
a guy named Rob came and said there is a
show on the Food Network called The Next
Food Network Star
and you got to do it I said man I don't
watch any TV especially food TV because
I'm cooking it all day long I don't need
to come home and watch about
said no you got to answer this so I
enter the show for sure I was gonna get
beat I showed up in flip-flops in a
leather jacket and everybody was all
buttoned up in their chef coats oh my
god man this guy Nate Lyons gonna crush
me fortunately because the selection
committee of Bob Bob Tuschman Bobby Flay
and Susie Fogelson we're having a good
day and they voted me in to win the show
that's where you clap for them but
that's where I picked up a whole team I
mean I got like a cavalcade I got an
army of supporters with Kathleen and
Courtney and Alison and Brooke that's
where I met the great mark dissing one
of my favorite producers Brian Lando
Karen grin thaw and and and Danielle
Lauren but one person in particular that
had to go to all the painstaking work to
make this happen
I know they're gonna bring the hook out
and get me off the stage any minute but
I have to say thanks to Erica
Erica you are my rock star where is she
oh she already left and I also got to
meet a great mentor a guy that you know
kind of when I called Matthew or Matthew
and I first talked and he gave me so
much great advice before I had a chance
to meet Matthew I met the great Marc
summers who took a lot of time answered
a lot of phone calls a lot of phone
calls telling me what was going to come
and how to stay genuine be be who you
are says have you ever changed this is
not going to continue on with the
trajectory and that's the same thing
Matthew gave me same great advice I got
to hook up with the William Morris
Endeavor team and I have by the way
ladies and gentlemen I know Matthew or
argue it any of the celebrities here
will argue it but I have the two best
agents in the business Jason hotus and
Jeff Google so up to this point I'd
always been going with this idea of
being lucky I got a big horseshoe tattoo
under my arm I thought man I'm lucky and
I would talk about being lucky and talk
about being lucky and one day this
another mentor a guy named Jack levar
the great lady Jack levar said would you
stop with the lucky thing because it's
not about luck he says it's about what
your mom and dad taught you early on
it's about hard work it's about
dedication it's about vision
it's about loving what you do and it's
about surrounding yourself with great
people and he says you build an army
he says you have an army of great people
and great friends so what does it get me
well now ladies and I think I've got one
of the coolest jobs in the world you
guys ever seen diners drive-ins and
dives
guy's grocery games minute to win it
guys ranch kitchen I mean the list goes
on and on I like how you bumped it up to
13 Matthew I don't know that's the
number but I'm gonna go with it got
amazing people that I work with my team
that I work with all the teams on the
shows painstaking never-ending amazing
people citizen pictures match cut
productions I mean I could go on and on
with all the people that have done it
Francesco Lando triage I can't say
thanks enough they're the ones that
they're the ones that make me a shine on
TV and do great edits and and keep that
camera that filter the right one on me
so we got a little knuckle sandwich
thing going on we got 67 restaurants
across around the world and that's
headed up by two of my favorite people
in the world a guy named Reed Strathearn
and chef Anthony Haiphong he's the tall
guy and do not call him my bodyguard but
I also have a great advisory team again
back to my mentors Burleson James
Burleson Lori Enix and of course my
buddy
the fantastic Ron Wargo so today thank
you I know I'm Way over time I had this
didn't I have this better I just planted
that like five minutes and my ten
minutes yeah Laurie's like I'm gonna
call you offstage at 7:00 I'm only doing
this one so I'm gonna hog all the time I
want I really appreciate you being here
on a Wednesday I don't know why we do
Wednesday but I it's a good kickoff to
the weekend in my opinion I'm surrounded
by all the people that made this happen
you don't get to be understanding behind
the barricades over there I got chefs
and mentors and coaches and best friends
and fraternity brothers and you name it
they're here my dentist is here but most
important the people that are here the
ones that have really made this and this
is I've saved the best for last is I
really want to say thank you to the
residents of flavortown
this ridiculous one-liner that I came up
with on a triple d show Chico I don't
know how many years ago was 10 years ago
these folks these folks he's on a roll
now folks these people have been so
instrumental you want to talk about love
support dedication I mean I'm getting it
from go to this restaurant location to
you know come do this charity gig too we
love what you do here's some inspiration
to keep doing what you do those are the
folks that have really kept this going
so here's what I want to ask you to do
everybody that's here please recognize
it in some way shape or form you had a
part in this star happening for the good
or for the bad now for the good be it
you're my mentor be you're my angel be
you're my supporter be my friend my
family member whatever it is that's our
star okay so I want you to cut now
seriously that's our star I want you to
come visit it I want you to take your
pictures with it I want you to hang out
with your fans and talk about it I don't
want you to share our personal stories
please I don't need any of that out
there and I want you to come and visit
our star and I want to tell you one last
thing I want to thank you for just
taking one day and letting Hollywood
become flavortown
let's unveil that star
please join us at the star
you
yes okay what do you go
just die stand on it yeah we're gonna do
it together
count of three is it one two and on
three come on
one three two
top right
right
commander Burton Center please thank you
forget your personal space very close
together there it is yes well better
thank you
man
and
right into the center
I wouldn't miss much
you're looking Center please look at the
center Center center
and what who's that guy right here to
this camera guys for a moment wonderful
thank you very much
right center everybody you and everybody
just destined all right here everybody
dad there we go dad right here this game
huh
there it is
good
this time right stay right Alex a
brother there we go there we go
and
earlier
yes sir forward we're gonna put a green
lantern shadow on your name Jeff come on
forward it's all good
right drivers power yoga
thank God let's have you do one thing
for it
and for a little bit very good thank you
good job
one side
around the start late
right here this camera gets for a couple
friends right here BAM right here there
we go one more time everybody thank you
you're the only one shades off there we
go we wouldn't recognize you with the
bow there we go there we go family dive
everybody's returned there we go thank
you lady
good
we'll start there everybody in the
middle right here.double friends thank
you guys very much consider right
Wow
thank you
get about
bobwhite
even if you want I need a buck right
here boys
thank you I'm very much
Hey
and let me touch it
thank you very much Richard white
here we got boys my dear yes well thank
you that one for the book return
you