3
00:01:05,774 --> 00:01:07,691
Replacement team's here, sir.

4
00:01:08,151 --> 00:01:10,444
Right. Come on through!

5
00:01:12,947 --> 00:01:15,032
We were gonna start
looking for you guys.

6
00:01:15,241 --> 00:01:17,451
God, it's really something out there.

7
00:01:17,660 --> 00:01:18,744
You look a mess, sir.

8
00:01:19,746 --> 00:01:22,664
Yeah? Your turn next, Ginsberg.

9
00:01:29,672 --> 00:01:31,048
OK, bye. See you in 24.

10
00:01:31,883 --> 00:01:32,883
See you tomorrow.

11
00:01:37,555 --> 00:01:38,722
What were you saying?

12
00:01:38,932 --> 00:01:41,266
I used to hear her
chant all night long...

13
00:01:45,105 --> 00:01:46,105
Over the plants?

14
00:01:46,314 --> 00:01:49,358
She'd cup her hands over the seeds
and chant by the hour.

15
00:01:49,567 --> 00:01:52,694
She grew the most
beautiful wandoos you ever saw.

16
00:01:52,904 --> 00:01:55,572
Primo stuff. Resin city.

17
00:02:00,245 --> 00:02:01,703
Stand clear.

18
00:02:11,005 --> 00:02:13,924
Your mother's been very worried.
Roads must be a bear.

19
00:02:14,342 --> 00:02:16,260
- What roads?
- Visibility.

20
00:02:17,137 --> 00:02:21,598
Visibility, bullshit. You haven't
been on time for the last six months.

21
00:02:21,808 --> 00:02:23,392
I wrote you up in the log book.

22
00:02:23,601 --> 00:02:24,935
Yeah, you're a prince.

23
00:02:26,896 --> 00:02:30,649
Good night, gentlemen.

24
00:02:39,826 --> 00:02:41,702
So it was like sinsemillia, right?

25
00:02:41,911 --> 00:02:45,747
Sinsemillia. This grass made
Thai stick taste like oregano.

26
00:02:45,915 --> 00:02:47,875
Lay you out flat, man.

27
00:02:52,547 --> 00:02:54,423
- Got a red light, sir.
- What on?

28
00:02:54,632 --> 00:02:56,216
Number eight, warhead alarm.

29
00:02:56,593 --> 00:02:57,551
Give it a thump.

30
00:03:03,057 --> 00:03:04,600
Alarm reset.

31
00:03:19,908 --> 00:03:20,991
Skybird, this is Dropkick

32
00:03:21,159 --> 00:03:24,203
with a red-alpha
message in two parts.

33
00:03:24,370 --> 00:03:27,873
- Break, break. Red-alpha.
- Stand by to copy message.

34
00:03:28,041 --> 00:03:29,166
Standing by.

35
00:03:29,375 --> 00:03:32,085
Romeo, Oscar,
November, Charlie...

36
00:03:32,253 --> 00:03:35,464
...Tango, Tango, Lima, Alpha.

37
00:03:35,965 --> 00:03:37,049
Authentication.

38
00:03:37,217 --> 00:03:40,552
Two, two, zero, zero, four...

39
00:03:41,012 --> 00:03:43,472
...zero, Delta, Lima.

40
00:03:43,723 --> 00:03:45,515
I have a valid message.

41
00:03:45,683 --> 00:03:46,850
Stand by to authenticate.

42
00:03:47,060 --> 00:03:49,436
I agree with authentication also, sir.

43
00:04:06,704 --> 00:04:08,247
Enter launch code.

44
00:04:08,456 --> 00:04:12,209
Entering launch code.

45
00:04:15,588 --> 00:04:16,880
Launch order confirmed.

46
00:04:17,340 --> 00:04:18,674
Holy shit!

47
00:04:23,680 --> 00:04:27,516
Target selection complete.
Time on target sequence complete.

48
00:04:27,725 --> 00:04:29,142
Yield selection complete.

49
00:04:29,352 --> 00:04:31,478
Begin countdown. T minus 60.

50
00:04:31,646 --> 00:04:34,690
- Let's do it. Insert launch key.
- Stand by.

51
00:04:35,984 --> 00:04:38,360
- Launch key inserted.
- Roger.

52
00:04:38,528 --> 00:04:39,987
On my mark.

53
00:04:40,196 --> 00:04:41,905
Rotate launch key to "set."

54
00:04:42,740 --> 00:04:47,536
Three, two, one, mark.

55
00:04:47,704 --> 00:04:48,620
T minus 50.

56
00:04:58,798 --> 00:05:00,590
Roger, at "set."

57
00:05:06,973 --> 00:05:08,223
- Sir?
- T minus 40.

58
00:05:08,433 --> 00:05:09,891
All right, enable missiles.

59
00:05:10,310 --> 00:05:13,729
Number one, enabled.
Two, enabled. Three, enabled. Four...

60
00:05:13,896 --> 00:05:15,689
I wanna get this straight.

61
00:05:18,651 --> 00:05:20,068
...seven, eight...

62
00:05:22,071 --> 00:05:22,654
...nine...

63
00:05:26,909 --> 00:05:28,910
...- ten. Missiles enabled.
- - Minus 30.

64
00:05:29,078 --> 00:05:31,913
- Get me wing command post.
- It's not the correct procedure.

65
00:05:32,081 --> 00:05:34,666
SAC. Try SAC headquarters on the HF.

66
00:05:34,834 --> 00:05:37,210
- That's not the procedure.
- Screw the procedure.

67
00:05:37,420 --> 00:05:40,839
I want somebody on the phone
before I kill 20 million people.

68
00:05:44,260 --> 00:05:46,136
T minus 20.

69
00:05:47,138 --> 00:05:48,180
I got nothing here.

70
00:05:48,348 --> 00:05:50,682
It might've been knocked out already.

71
00:05:50,933 --> 00:05:52,059
All right.

72
00:05:52,894 --> 00:05:55,854
On my mark, rotate
launch keys to "launch."

73
00:05:56,064 --> 00:05:57,606
Roger, ready to go to launch.

74
00:05:57,774 --> 00:05:59,608
Fourteen, thirteen...

75
00:05:59,817 --> 00:06:01,526
...twelve, eleven...

76
00:06:04,614 --> 00:06:08,158
... seven, six...

77
00:06:08,534 --> 00:06:11,370
...five, four...
- Sir, we have a launch order.

78
00:06:11,579 --> 00:06:13,789
...three, two...
- Put your hand on the key.

79
00:06:13,956 --> 00:06:15,957
...one. Launch.

80
00:06:19,295 --> 00:06:23,173
- We are at launch, turn your key!
- I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.

81
00:06:23,383 --> 00:06:25,717
Turn your key, sir!

82
00:08:15,912 --> 00:08:17,412
Go ahead, open it up.

83
00:08:21,125 --> 00:08:22,083
Hello, I'm Pat Healy.

84
00:08:22,251 --> 00:08:25,337
I'm Lyle Watson,
this is Arthur Cabot.

85
00:08:25,505 --> 00:08:28,256
I'm Dr. McKittrick's assistant.

86
00:08:28,424 --> 00:08:30,258
We've got some passes for you.

87
00:08:30,718 --> 00:08:33,011
We've scheduled a meeting
on your arrival.

88
00:08:33,221 --> 00:08:36,056
If you have any questions,
feel free to ask me,

89
00:08:36,265 --> 00:08:37,933
I'd be happy to fill you in.

90
00:09:34,448 --> 00:09:35,657
They're here.

91
00:09:36,367 --> 00:09:37,367
Good.

92
00:09:38,035 --> 00:09:39,244
Let's go.

93
00:09:41,330 --> 00:09:44,916
Cabot and Watson came alone.
No senators, no congressmen.

94
00:09:45,084 --> 00:09:47,460
- I wish they'd brought senators.
- What?

95
00:09:47,628 --> 00:09:49,087
To tell them what goes on.

96
00:09:49,255 --> 00:09:52,507
John, please,
don't start that right away.

97
00:09:52,675 --> 00:09:54,593
I had them on the phone, they're calm.

98
00:09:56,679 --> 00:09:58,305
Look now, are we positive

99
00:09:58,472 --> 00:10:02,267
that these men had no way
of knowing this was only a test?

100
00:10:02,476 --> 00:10:05,937
Lyle, how many times
are we gonna go through this?

101
00:10:06,105 --> 00:10:07,397
It doesn't matter.

102
00:10:07,565 --> 00:10:11,526
I've spoken to each of these men.
They all thought it was the real deal.

103
00:10:12,111 --> 00:10:14,779
We have to be on a plane
in less than an hour.

104
00:10:14,947 --> 00:10:16,781
I have to explain to the president

105
00:10:16,991 --> 00:10:21,119
why 22 percent of his missile commanders
failed to launch their missiles.

106
00:10:21,287 --> 00:10:23,997
What am I supposed
to tell him, 22 percent isn't so bad?

107
00:10:24,165 --> 00:10:28,710
The president knows that I am fully
responsible for the men in my command.

108
00:10:28,878 --> 00:10:32,589
I've ordered a revaluation of our
psychological screening procedure.

109
00:10:32,757 --> 00:10:35,050
Wait a minute. Excuse me, general.

110
00:10:35,217 --> 00:10:38,303
We can't ask these men
to go back to the president

111
00:10:38,471 --> 00:10:40,764
with a lot of head-shrinker horseshit!

112
00:10:40,931 --> 00:10:42,724
You can't screen out human response.

113
00:10:42,892 --> 00:10:46,102
Those men know what
it means to turn the keys

114
00:10:46,270 --> 00:10:47,729
and some are not up to it!

115
00:10:48,230 --> 00:10:50,023
Now, it's as simple as that!

116
00:10:54,737 --> 00:10:56,863
We ought to take
the men out of the loop.

117
00:10:57,031 --> 00:10:59,991
- Mr. McKittrick, you're out of line.
- Why?

118
00:11:00,159 --> 00:11:02,369
- Wait. Excuse me.
- What are you talking about?

119
00:11:03,621 --> 00:11:06,998
I'm sorry. What do you mean,
take them out of the loop?

120
00:11:07,166 --> 00:11:10,752
Gentlemen, we've
had men in these silos

121
00:11:10,920 --> 00:11:13,713
since before any of you
were watching Howdy Doody.

122
00:11:15,383 --> 00:11:18,677
For myself,
I sleep well at night,

123
00:11:18,844 --> 00:11:20,679
knowing those boys are down there.

124
00:11:20,846 --> 00:11:22,847
General, we all know they're fine men.

125
00:11:23,015 --> 00:11:27,769
But in a nuclear war, we can't have
our missiles lying in those silos

126
00:11:27,937 --> 00:11:31,731
because they refuse to turn the
keys when the computers tell them to!

127
00:11:31,941 --> 00:11:34,609
You mean, when
the president orders them to.

128
00:11:34,777 --> 00:11:38,405
The president probably follows
the computer war plan. That's a fact!

129
00:11:38,572 --> 00:11:41,950
Well, I imagine the joint chiefs
will have some input.

130
00:11:42,118 --> 00:11:43,118
You're damned tooting.

131
00:11:43,285 --> 00:11:47,205
Well, the Soviets launch
a surprise attack, there's no time.

132
00:11:47,373 --> 00:11:49,999
Twenty-three minutes
from warning to impact.

133
00:11:50,668 --> 00:11:52,293
Six minutes, if sub-launched.

134
00:11:52,461 --> 00:11:57,090
Six minutes, that's barely enough time
for the president to make a decision.

135
00:11:57,299 --> 00:12:00,135
Once he makes that decision,
the computer takes over.

136
00:12:01,887 --> 00:12:04,389
I know that you've
got a plane waiting,

137
00:12:04,557 --> 00:12:07,642
but if you give me five minutes,
I'll show you something.

138
00:12:15,776 --> 00:12:18,695
These computers give us
access to the world.

139
00:12:18,863 --> 00:12:22,115
Troop movements, Soviet missile tests,
shifting weather patterns.

140
00:12:22,283 --> 00:12:26,369
It all flows into this room and then
into what we call the WOPR computer.

141
00:12:26,537 --> 00:12:27,662
WOPR, what is that?

142
00:12:27,830 --> 00:12:30,123
The War Operation Plan Response.

143
00:12:30,291 --> 00:12:34,002
This is Mr. Richter. Paul, would you
tell these gentlemen about the WOPR?

144
00:12:34,170 --> 00:12:37,839
Well, the WOPR spends all its time

145
00:12:38,007 --> 00:12:40,383
thinking about World War III.

146
00:12:40,551 --> 00:12:44,679
Twenty-four hours a day,
365 days a year,

147
00:12:44,847 --> 00:12:47,682
it plays an endless
series of war games

148
00:12:47,850 --> 00:12:51,352
using all available information
on the state of the world.

149
00:12:51,979 --> 00:12:55,857
The WOPR has already
fought World War III as a game

150
00:12:56,025 --> 00:12:57,567
time and time again.

151
00:12:58,027 --> 00:13:00,904
It estimates Soviet
responses to our responses,

152
00:13:01,071 --> 00:13:03,490
to their responses and so on.

153
00:13:03,657 --> 00:13:08,912
Estimates damage, counts the dead,
and looks for ways to improve the score.

154
00:13:09,079 --> 00:13:12,040
But the point is that the key
decisions of every conceivable option

155
00:13:12,208 --> 00:13:14,709
in a nuclear crisis
have been made by the WOPR.

156
00:13:14,877 --> 00:13:17,545
You're saying that this
trillion dollar hardware

157
00:13:17,713 --> 00:13:20,548
is at the mercy
of those men with the brass keys.

158
00:13:20,716 --> 00:13:22,550
That's exactly right.

159
00:13:22,718 --> 00:13:24,928
Whose only problem
is that they're human.

160
00:13:25,095 --> 00:13:28,389
But in 30 days we could
replace them with electronic relays.

161
00:13:28,557 --> 00:13:29,974
Get the men out of the loop.

162
00:13:30,142 --> 00:13:31,351
Gentlemen...

163
00:13:32,812 --> 00:13:35,605
...I wouldn't trust
this pile of microchips

164
00:13:35,773 --> 00:13:37,565
any further than I could throw it.

165
00:13:37,733 --> 00:13:40,235
I don't trust
the safety of our country

166
00:13:40,402 --> 00:13:43,154
to some silicon diode.

167
00:13:43,322 --> 00:13:45,824
General, nobody
is talking about entrusting

168
00:13:45,991 --> 00:13:49,077
the safety of the nation
to a machine, for God's sake.

169
00:13:49,245 --> 00:13:52,247
We'll keep control,
but we'll keep it here at the top.

170
00:13:52,414 --> 00:13:58,002
Gentlemen... I'll recommend
McKittrick's idea to the president.

171
00:13:58,170 --> 00:14:00,463
And I'll get back to you on this.

172
00:14:01,757 --> 00:14:02,757
Thank you.

173
00:14:02,925 --> 00:14:04,509
You won't regret this.

174
00:14:26,740 --> 00:14:29,450
OK, you had fries and a Coke, right?

175
00:14:47,553 --> 00:14:50,430
Damn!

176
00:14:52,141 --> 00:14:55,018
- Hi, David.
- Hey, Howie.

177
00:14:55,185 --> 00:14:57,520
- How's it going?
- Pretty good.

178
00:15:01,191 --> 00:15:03,818
- You wanna take this over? I gotta go.
- Sure.

179
00:15:03,986 --> 00:15:05,987
- All right.
- Thanks.

180
00:15:09,658 --> 00:15:11,492
- Bye, David.
- Bye!

181
00:15:21,086 --> 00:15:22,211
All right.

182
00:15:22,379 --> 00:15:24,839
Question number two.

183
00:15:25,007 --> 00:15:27,467
Seeds that are germinated in water

184
00:15:27,635 --> 00:15:30,219
before they are planted will...

185
00:15:31,972 --> 00:15:34,515
...what? Roderick.

186
00:15:34,683 --> 00:15:37,185
- Sprout roots?
- David!

187
00:15:37,895 --> 00:15:41,898
Nice of you to join us. I have
a little present for you up here.

188
00:15:52,701 --> 00:15:54,535
Question number four.

189
00:15:54,703 --> 00:15:55,954
In science,

190
00:15:56,121 --> 00:15:58,873
innovative concepts
occasionally arise

191
00:15:59,041 --> 00:16:02,126
from sudden left-field inspiration.

192
00:16:02,294 --> 00:16:03,711
Miss Mack...

193
00:16:04,880 --> 00:16:07,048
...tell us your
answer to question four.

194
00:16:07,216 --> 00:16:11,427
Why do nitrogen nodules
cling to the roots of plants?

195
00:16:11,595 --> 00:16:14,931
Um... Love?

196
00:16:19,186 --> 00:16:23,147
Jennifer, what do you know
about nitrogen nodules that we don't?

197
00:16:23,732 --> 00:16:27,068
Some bit of salacious info
to which you alone are privy?

198
00:16:28,404 --> 00:16:29,862
- No.
- I see.

199
00:16:30,030 --> 00:16:34,617
No, you didn't know
the correct answer, symbiosis,

200
00:16:34,785 --> 00:16:38,579
because you don't
pay attention in class.

201
00:16:41,709 --> 00:16:43,626
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.

202
00:16:43,794 --> 00:16:46,921
There seems to be a lot of
confusion on this next question:

203
00:16:47,089 --> 00:16:49,716
"Asexual reproduction."

204
00:16:50,426 --> 00:16:53,761
Could someone tell me,
please, who first suggested

205
00:16:53,929 --> 00:16:58,141
the idea of reproduction without sex?

206
00:17:06,066 --> 00:17:07,525
Miss Mack!

207
00:17:07,693 --> 00:17:09,277
- Yes?
- What is so amusing?

208
00:17:13,490 --> 00:17:14,907
What?

209
00:17:15,701 --> 00:17:17,452
All right, Lightman.

210
00:17:18,787 --> 00:17:23,082
Could you tell us who first suggested
the idea of reproduction without sex?

211
00:17:23,250 --> 00:17:24,667
Um...

212
00:17:24,835 --> 00:17:28,129
Your wife?

213
00:17:29,673 --> 00:17:31,841
Get out, Lightman.
Get out.

214
00:17:40,476 --> 00:17:44,145
Mr. Ligget wants me to discuss my
attitude problem with Mr. Kessler.

215
00:17:44,313 --> 00:17:47,690
Mr. Kessler's tired
of discussing your attitude problem.

216
00:17:48,275 --> 00:17:49,275
Me too.

217
00:18:20,474 --> 00:18:23,684
Lightman. What a surprise.

218
00:18:23,852 --> 00:18:25,061
Won't you come in?

219
00:18:40,911 --> 00:18:42,745
- Hi.
- Whoa!

220
00:18:42,913 --> 00:18:43,955
Hi.

221
00:18:44,123 --> 00:18:47,125
Sorry if I got you in trouble.
I couldn't stop laughing.

222
00:18:47,292 --> 00:18:49,210
That's OK. You were perfect.

223
00:18:49,378 --> 00:18:51,003
- I was?
- Yeah.

224
00:18:51,755 --> 00:18:53,089
You want a ride home?

225
00:18:53,257 --> 00:18:54,423
Yeah.

226
00:18:55,968 --> 00:18:57,343
Hop on.

227
00:19:01,306 --> 00:19:03,432
Whoa!

228
00:19:05,185 --> 00:19:08,271
- You got an F on that test today too?
- Yep.

229
00:19:08,438 --> 00:19:10,606
We're gonna be stuck
in summer school.

230
00:19:10,774 --> 00:19:14,694
- Not me.
- Why not? You have to make up biology.

231
00:19:14,862 --> 00:19:16,279
I don't think so.

232
00:19:16,446 --> 00:19:17,780
Why not?

233
00:19:18,782 --> 00:19:21,159
Why not? Come on, tell me.

234
00:19:21,326 --> 00:19:22,785
Make a left.

235
00:19:22,953 --> 00:19:26,455
- Come up to my house and I'll show you.
- What are you gonna show me?

236
00:19:26,623 --> 00:19:30,877
I'll show you how to do it.

237
00:19:32,254 --> 00:19:35,339
- Hi, Bo.
- Oh, hi, Bo!

238
00:19:40,304 --> 00:19:43,222
Bo! Bo! Bo...

239
00:19:55,360 --> 00:19:56,402
Her room's upstairs.

240
00:19:56,570 --> 00:19:59,113
- Your parents aren't home?
- No, they both work.

241
00:20:13,212 --> 00:20:15,213
Ooh! Oh...

242
00:20:17,883 --> 00:20:19,634
Little mess.

243
00:20:19,801 --> 00:20:22,553
It's OK.
You should see my room.

244
00:20:31,563 --> 00:20:34,357
- You're really into computers, huh?
- Yeah.

245
00:20:40,072 --> 00:20:43,449
- What are you doing?
- Dialing into the school's computer.

246
00:20:55,712 --> 00:20:59,757
They change the password,
but I know where they write it down.

247
00:21:14,147 --> 00:21:16,774
- Are those your grades?
- Yep.

248
00:21:17,234 --> 00:21:19,610
I don't think that
I deserved an F. Do you?

249
00:21:23,532 --> 00:21:24,782
You can't do that!

250
00:21:25,534 --> 00:21:26,701
Already done.

251
00:21:28,704 --> 00:21:31,831
- Do you have a middle initial?
- "K," Katherine.

252
00:21:37,462 --> 00:21:39,213
These are my grades.

253
00:21:40,048 --> 00:21:42,258
How can anybody get a D in Home Ec?

254
00:21:42,426 --> 00:21:43,884
None of your business.

255
00:21:44,052 --> 00:21:46,304
- Can you erase this, please?
- It's too late.

256
00:21:47,389 --> 00:21:49,724
- What are you doing?
- Changing your grade.

257
00:21:49,891 --> 00:21:51,517
I don't want you to do that.

258
00:21:51,685 --> 00:21:54,395
Nobody can find out.

259
00:21:54,563 --> 00:21:56,856
You got a C!
No need for summer school.

260
00:21:57,024 --> 00:21:59,066
- Change it back!
- They can't...

261
00:21:59,234 --> 00:22:00,818
I said change it back.

262
00:22:00,986 --> 00:22:02,403
OK, OK.

263
00:22:10,579 --> 00:22:12,121
I guess I better get going.

264
00:22:14,249 --> 00:22:15,708
Thanks for the ride.

265
00:22:16,251 --> 00:22:18,377
Yeah, OK. Bye.

266
00:22:18,754 --> 00:22:20,212
Bye.

267
00:23:20,524 --> 00:23:22,483
- Get down.
- You've got to see it!

268
00:23:22,651 --> 00:23:23,818
You had your dinner.

269
00:23:23,985 --> 00:23:26,695
Two bedrooms, a bath
and a half, and a bonus room.

270
00:23:26,863 --> 00:23:28,656
Don't forget the garbage.

271
00:23:28,824 --> 00:23:32,076
Put that lid on tight so Bo
doesn't dump over the trash.

272
00:23:32,244 --> 00:23:34,328
- I know, Ma.
- Sh!

273
00:23:34,496 --> 00:23:37,331
Yes, they will
carry back on the second.

274
00:23:38,500 --> 00:23:41,877
Sure, I think we can really
work out some creative financing.

275
00:23:43,046 --> 00:23:47,174
You've gotta see it. There's
a Jacuzzi in the master bedroom.

276
00:23:47,342 --> 00:23:48,968
You know what that means.

277
00:23:49,136 --> 00:23:51,971
I mean, those jets,
they really work, you know.

278
00:23:54,766 --> 00:23:56,267
You are so naughty.

279
00:23:59,354 --> 00:24:01,897
Oh, sure. We can work that out.

280
00:24:03,525 --> 00:24:07,611
That is true. You're gonna have
a balloon payment in five years,

281
00:24:07,779 --> 00:24:10,156
but the economy will be great then.

282
00:24:10,323 --> 00:24:11,365
Bo, come here.

283
00:24:11,533 --> 00:24:13,784
He who dances
must pay the price, right?

284
00:24:13,952 --> 00:24:17,288
That's wonderful.
I'll meet you tomorrow at 9:30. Bye.

285
00:24:20,709 --> 00:24:22,751
You know, I worry about that kid.

286
00:24:22,919 --> 00:24:24,044
Why?

287
00:24:25,839 --> 00:24:28,883
Sometimes I think
we're all gonna get electrocuted.

288
00:24:29,050 --> 00:24:30,634
Ha!

289
00:24:33,722 --> 00:24:35,139
This corn is raw!

290
00:24:35,307 --> 00:24:36,974
I know. Isn't it wonderful?

291
00:24:37,142 --> 00:24:39,894
- It's so crisp.
- Of course it's crisp, it's raw!

292
00:24:40,061 --> 00:24:44,106
No, it's terrific. You can just taste
the vitamin A and D. It's great.

293
00:24:45,066 --> 00:24:47,526
Could we have pills and cook the corn?

294
00:24:48,153 --> 00:24:49,653
What city, please?

295
00:24:49,821 --> 00:24:53,073
For Sunnyvale, California.
The number for Protovision.

296
00:24:53,658 --> 00:24:56,827
Yes. That's 555-8632.

297
00:24:58,163 --> 00:25:02,374
Thank you. And could you also tell me
what other prefixes cover that area?

298
00:25:02,542 --> 00:25:05,336
There's 399, 437,

299
00:25:05,504 --> 00:25:09,256
- 767, 936.
- Thanks.

300
00:25:24,606 --> 00:25:27,066
Protovision, I have you now.

301
00:25:48,630 --> 00:25:49,755
Hello.

302
00:25:56,304 --> 00:25:57,680
Saul's Fish Market.

303
00:26:10,652 --> 00:26:11,610
Hi.

304
00:26:11,778 --> 00:26:13,112
Oh, hi.

305
00:26:16,616 --> 00:26:17,324
What?

306
00:26:17,993 --> 00:26:20,327
I've been thinking about my grade.

307
00:26:20,495 --> 00:26:21,829
Can you still change it?

308
00:26:21,997 --> 00:26:25,332
- Oh, I don't know.
- I should've just let you do it.

309
00:26:27,294 --> 00:26:28,919
It might be kind of rough.

310
00:26:29,087 --> 00:26:30,296
- Why?
- Why?

311
00:26:31,006 --> 00:26:32,631
They can change the password.

312
00:26:32,799 --> 00:26:35,092
Maybe they didn't. Can't we try?

313
00:26:37,929 --> 00:26:39,930
- Damn!
- Please?

314
00:26:41,182 --> 00:26:43,183
- OK.
- OK.

315
00:26:43,351 --> 00:26:47,021
- You owe me a quarter.
- Yeah. Sorry you lost your game.

316
00:26:54,821 --> 00:26:56,322
What's it doing?

317
00:26:56,489 --> 00:26:57,865
It's dialing numbers.

318
00:27:01,828 --> 00:27:04,371
- Don't touch the keys!
- I'm not touching the keys.

319
00:27:05,707 --> 00:27:06,790
Excuse me.

320
00:27:07,792 --> 00:27:11,587
This computer company is coming out
with new games in a few months.

321
00:27:11,755 --> 00:27:14,590
The programs for them
are still in their computer.

322
00:27:14,758 --> 00:27:15,924
I told my system

323
00:27:16,092 --> 00:27:19,428
to search for other
computers in Sunnyvale, California.

324
00:27:23,350 --> 00:27:27,227
They answer with a tone that
other computers recognize. Hear?

325
00:27:28,730 --> 00:27:30,272
You're calling
every number in Sunnyvale?

326
00:27:34,319 --> 00:27:36,445
- Isn't that expensive?
- There's ways around that.

327
00:27:37,822 --> 00:27:41,241
- You can go to jail for that.
- Only if you're over 18.

328
00:27:43,286 --> 00:27:46,246
Will this take a long time?
I'd like to get my grade changed.

329
00:27:48,625 --> 00:27:50,918
That's funny, actually, because...

330
00:27:52,462 --> 00:27:54,171
...I already changed it.

331
00:27:55,674 --> 00:27:57,091
I told you not to do that.

332
00:27:57,258 --> 00:28:00,928
Yeah, I know, but
I figured you'd change your mind.

333
00:28:01,096 --> 00:28:02,513
I didn't want you to flunk.

334
00:28:03,473 --> 00:28:04,473
What did I get?

335
00:28:05,183 --> 00:28:07,851
- You got a D.
- You gave me a D?

336
00:28:08,019 --> 00:28:09,019
No, you got an A.

337
00:28:09,187 --> 00:28:11,271
- I was kidding.
- Oh.

338
00:28:11,815 --> 00:28:13,190
That's OK.

339
00:28:13,900 --> 00:28:15,734
Here. Let's see what we have so far.

340
00:28:17,404 --> 00:28:18,445
Excuse me.

341
00:28:18,697 --> 00:28:21,782
- Did you really give me an A?
- Yeah.

342
00:28:23,618 --> 00:28:26,120
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.

343
00:28:32,127 --> 00:28:33,168
Hey, you got a bank.

344
00:28:33,336 --> 00:28:36,296
Gotta make a note of that.
Might come in handy someday.

345
00:28:42,470 --> 00:28:43,512
Pan Am.

346
00:28:44,597 --> 00:28:46,223
Where should we go?

347
00:28:46,391 --> 00:28:48,142
- Anywhere?
- Anywhere.

348
00:28:48,309 --> 00:28:49,560
- New York?
- OK...

349
00:28:49,728 --> 00:28:51,562
- No, Paris!
- Paris. OK.

350
00:28:57,193 --> 00:28:58,944
Will you be traveling alone?

351
00:28:59,112 --> 00:29:01,655
Yeah. No. You wanna go with me?

352
00:29:01,823 --> 00:29:04,658
OK. Uh...

353
00:29:05,410 --> 00:29:07,494
All right. Smoking or nonsmoking?

354
00:29:07,662 --> 00:29:09,747
- Nonsmoking.
- Nonsmoking.

355
00:29:10,665 --> 00:29:14,793
All right, Miss Mack. You're
confirmed on Pan Am's flight 114,

356
00:29:14,961 --> 00:29:17,087
leaving Chicago's O'Hare Airport

357
00:29:17,255 --> 00:29:19,882
at 8:15 a.m. On 18 August.

358
00:29:20,049 --> 00:29:22,843
Do we need a rental car? No.

359
00:29:23,011 --> 00:29:24,052
We have tickets to Paris?

360
00:29:24,220 --> 00:29:26,430
No, you have a reservation though.

361
00:29:35,148 --> 00:29:36,982
Doesn't identify itself.

362
00:29:37,150 --> 00:29:38,150
Huh...

363
00:29:38,318 --> 00:29:39,485
Try anything.

364
00:29:45,700 --> 00:29:48,452
"Connection terminated." How rude.

365
00:29:49,370 --> 00:29:51,371
- I'll ask it for help.
- Can you do that?

366
00:29:51,539 --> 00:29:52,706
On some systems.

367
00:29:52,874 --> 00:29:55,709
The more complicated they are,
the more they help you.

368
00:30:04,219 --> 00:30:05,511
Now what?

369
00:30:07,222 --> 00:30:08,639
"Help games."

370
00:30:14,604 --> 00:30:16,772
"Games refers to models,
simulations and games

371
00:30:16,940 --> 00:30:19,233
having tactical
and strategic applications."

372
00:30:19,400 --> 00:30:21,151
- What's that?
- It's gotta be them.

373
00:30:21,319 --> 00:30:23,904
Turn on the printer.
I want to get a printout of this.

374
00:30:24,864 --> 00:30:26,448
"List games."

375
00:30:50,765 --> 00:30:52,432
Oh, my God.

376
00:31:03,528 --> 00:31:06,029
These guys can tell you
what that printout means?

377
00:31:06,197 --> 00:31:08,740
Yeah. They probably
invented it in the first place.

378
00:31:28,678 --> 00:31:30,304
- Can you wait here?
- Why?

379
00:31:30,471 --> 00:31:32,764
These guys can get a little nervous.

380
00:31:42,525 --> 00:31:43,525
Jim.

381
00:31:44,569 --> 00:31:45,861
Oh, Lightman.

382
00:31:50,116 --> 00:31:51,533
Hi, Lightman!

383
00:31:52,327 --> 00:31:54,119
I want you to take a look at this.

384
00:32:00,710 --> 00:32:03,170
- What's that?
- I wanted Jim to see that.

385
00:32:06,633 --> 00:32:07,883
Wow! Where'd you get this?

386
00:32:08,051 --> 00:32:11,678
I tried to break into Protovision.
I wanted to see the new games.

387
00:32:11,846 --> 00:32:13,972
- Can I have this?
- Wait, I'm not through yet.

388
00:32:17,185 --> 00:32:21,396
Remember you told me to tell you when
you're acting rudely and insensitively?

389
00:32:21,564 --> 00:32:22,856
You're doing it now.

390
00:32:29,614 --> 00:32:32,908
"Theaterwide biotoxic
and chemical warfare."

391
00:32:34,535 --> 00:32:35,953
This isn't from Protovision.

392
00:32:36,120 --> 00:32:38,664
You bet it isn't.
Ask him where it came from.

393
00:32:38,831 --> 00:32:40,040
I told you already.

394
00:32:40,208 --> 00:32:43,835
Looks military to me. Definitely
military, probably classified.

395
00:32:44,003 --> 00:32:47,047
If it's military, why does
it have checkers and backgammon?

396
00:32:47,215 --> 00:32:49,424
Maybe because they
teach basic strategy.

397
00:32:50,843 --> 00:32:53,845
How do I get into that system?
I want to play those games.

398
00:32:54,013 --> 00:32:55,681
You can't see that stuff!

399
00:32:55,848 --> 00:32:59,351
That system has a data encryption
algorithm. You'll never get in!

400
00:32:59,519 --> 00:33:02,270
I don't believe that
any system is totally secure.

401
00:33:02,772 --> 00:33:06,066
- I bet you Jim could get in.
- I bet you he couldn't.

402
00:33:06,234 --> 00:33:10,445
You'll never get in through frontline
security, but look for a back door.

403
00:33:10,613 --> 00:33:14,658
I can't believe it! She's over there
and you tell him about our back door?

404
00:33:14,826 --> 00:33:19,579
Mr. Potato Head!
Back doors are not secrets!

405
00:33:19,747 --> 00:33:21,623
You're giving away our best tricks.

406
00:33:21,791 --> 00:33:24,710
- They're not tricks.
- What's a back door?

407
00:33:24,877 --> 00:33:29,297
When I design a system, I put in a
simple password that only I know about.

408
00:33:29,465 --> 00:33:32,175
Whenever I want to get back in,

409
00:33:32,343 --> 00:33:34,970
I can bypass whatever security
they've added on.

410
00:33:35,138 --> 00:33:37,139
That's basically what it is.

411
00:33:38,349 --> 00:33:39,808
Yeah?

412
00:33:39,976 --> 00:33:43,854
You really want to get in, find out
about the guy who designed the system.

413
00:33:44,022 --> 00:33:46,231
Come on, I don't
even know the guy's name.

414
00:33:46,399 --> 00:33:49,401
Boy, are you guys dumb.
You're so dumb.

415
00:33:49,569 --> 00:33:51,987
I got this thing figured out
all by myself.

416
00:33:52,155 --> 00:33:54,197
Oh, yeah, Malvin?
How would you do it?

417
00:33:54,365 --> 00:33:58,285
The first game on the list.
Go right through Falken's Maze.

418
00:36:04,745 --> 00:36:06,955
Hi! I'm Jennifer.

419
00:36:07,123 --> 00:36:08,874
- Is David here?
- How do you do?

420
00:36:09,041 --> 00:36:10,625
Yeah. He's up in his room.

421
00:36:12,920 --> 00:36:14,254
Thanks.

422
00:36:14,964 --> 00:36:17,424
Have you ever heard
of the word "tumulus"?

423
00:36:17,592 --> 00:36:20,051
Tumulus. No, I haven't. Sorry.

424
00:36:20,219 --> 00:36:21,428
Neither have I.

425
00:36:25,057 --> 00:36:26,141
Yeah.

426
00:36:27,101 --> 00:36:29,102
Hi!

427
00:36:29,270 --> 00:36:30,937
- Where have you been?
- What?

428
00:36:31,689 --> 00:36:34,357
I haven't seen you in school.
Are you sick?

429
00:36:35,484 --> 00:36:39,738
Oh... No. I was doing things.

430
00:36:39,906 --> 00:36:41,573
You want to sit? How are you?

431
00:36:41,741 --> 00:36:44,117
No, I'm gonna get some water, OK?

432
00:36:44,285 --> 00:36:47,996
- What is all that stuff?
- It's nothing. I was just...

433
00:36:48,164 --> 00:36:52,459
I tried to find out more about the guy
who designed those game programs...

434
00:36:52,627 --> 00:36:54,461
...so I could get his secret password.

435
00:36:55,254 --> 00:36:57,714
- Why?
- Why? Because...

436
00:36:57,882 --> 00:37:00,800
What's so special about
playing games with some machine?

437
00:37:00,968 --> 00:37:03,803
Oh, no. No, it's
not just some machine.

438
00:37:04,889 --> 00:37:06,473
Here, look at this.

439
00:37:07,975 --> 00:37:11,645
This is a tape I got from the library.
It's about this guy named Falken.

440
00:37:14,190 --> 00:37:16,441
He was into games,
as well as computers.

441
00:37:17,818 --> 00:37:21,780
He designed them so that they
could play checkers or poker, chess.

442
00:37:21,948 --> 00:37:23,865
What's so great about that?

443
00:37:24,033 --> 00:37:25,283
Oh, no.

444
00:37:25,451 --> 00:37:27,160
What he did was great.

445
00:37:27,328 --> 00:37:31,122
He designed this computer so that
it could learn from its own mistakes.

446
00:37:31,290 --> 00:37:33,458
So they're better
the next time they played.

447
00:37:33,626 --> 00:37:35,835
The system actually learned
how to learn.

448
00:37:37,255 --> 00:37:38,463
It could teach itself.

449
00:37:40,341 --> 00:37:43,510
If I could just get that damn
password, I could play the computer.

450
00:37:46,681 --> 00:37:48,348
That's him. That's Falken.

451
00:37:50,101 --> 00:37:51,268
That's him?

452
00:37:51,936 --> 00:37:52,894
Wow.

453
00:37:53,062 --> 00:37:55,480
He's amazing looking.

454
00:37:56,857 --> 00:37:59,234
Can't you write to him or call him?

455
00:37:59,402 --> 00:38:00,819
No, he's dead.

456
00:38:01,696 --> 00:38:03,947
- He's dead?
- Yeah.

457
00:38:04,115 --> 00:38:06,032
Here, look. Here's his obituary.

458
00:38:07,576 --> 00:38:08,910
He wasn't very old.

459
00:38:09,078 --> 00:38:11,705
No, he was pretty old.
He was 41.

460
00:38:11,872 --> 00:38:13,999
Oh, yeah? Oh, that's old.

461
00:38:16,711 --> 00:38:18,086
That's his little boy.

462
00:38:19,213 --> 00:38:20,630
Oh, yeah?

463
00:38:21,716 --> 00:38:23,383
This is really sad.

464
00:38:24,218 --> 00:38:26,761
The child and his mother
died in a car crash.

465
00:38:26,929 --> 00:38:27,887
Yeah, I know.

466
00:38:28,055 --> 00:38:30,181
"After the tragic loss
of his family,

467
00:38:30,349 --> 00:38:32,767
Dr. Falken's health deteriorated."

468
00:38:40,359 --> 00:38:42,110
My dad is 45.

469
00:38:45,823 --> 00:38:48,533
- Once he was sick, and we thought...
- What was his name?

470
00:38:49,660 --> 00:38:51,453
My father?

471
00:38:51,620 --> 00:38:53,121
No, no. Falken's kid.

472
00:38:55,333 --> 00:38:56,166
Joshua.

473
00:38:58,252 --> 00:39:00,545
It can't be that simple.

474
00:39:09,472 --> 00:39:11,014
- Wow.
- What?

475
00:39:12,016 --> 00:39:13,308
We got something.

476
00:39:23,652 --> 00:39:24,778
We're in!

477
00:39:26,364 --> 00:39:28,365
It thinks I'm Falken.

478
00:39:30,284 --> 00:39:31,618
"Hello."

479
00:39:35,414 --> 00:39:36,748
How can it ask you that?

480
00:39:37,208 --> 00:39:39,292
It'll ask you what it's programmed to.

481
00:39:39,460 --> 00:39:41,294
- Do you want to hear it talk?
- Yeah.

482
00:39:43,214 --> 00:39:44,547
I'll ask how it feels.

483
00:39:45,925 --> 00:39:47,634
"I'm fine.

484
00:39:47,802 --> 00:39:50,553
How are you?"

485
00:39:51,639 --> 00:39:54,182
Excellent.
It's been a long time.

486
00:39:54,350 --> 00:39:58,436
Can you explain the removal
of your user account

487
00:39:58,604 --> 00:40:02,524
on June 23, 1973?

488
00:40:02,691 --> 00:40:04,317
They must have told it he died.

489
00:40:06,987 --> 00:40:11,908
"People sometimes make mistakes."

490
00:40:12,076 --> 00:40:15,328
- Yes, they do.
- How can it talk?

491
00:40:15,496 --> 00:40:16,996
It's not a real voice.

492
00:40:17,164 --> 00:40:19,999
This box interprets
computer signals into sound.

493
00:40:20,167 --> 00:40:24,129
- Shall we play a game?
- Oh...

494
00:40:24,296 --> 00:40:26,214
I think it missed him.

495
00:40:26,382 --> 00:40:28,091
Yeah. Weird, isn't it?

496
00:40:28,259 --> 00:40:31,177
"Love to. How about...

497
00:40:32,012 --> 00:40:36,057
...Global Thermonuclear War?"

498
00:40:37,393 --> 00:40:41,771
Wouldn't you prefer
a good game of chess?

499
00:40:41,939 --> 00:40:44,023
"Later. Let's play...

500
00:40:45,401 --> 00:40:48,319
...Global Thermonuclear War."

501
00:40:48,696 --> 00:40:50,280
Fine.

502
00:40:50,448 --> 00:40:51,698
All right!

503
00:40:53,576 --> 00:40:54,784
Wow.

504
00:40:57,997 --> 00:40:59,914
Which side do you want?

505
00:41:02,918 --> 00:41:04,544
I'll be the Russians.

506
00:41:09,258 --> 00:41:11,342
Please list primary targets.

507
00:41:12,094 --> 00:41:13,803
Who should we nuke first?

508
00:41:13,971 --> 00:41:15,930
Oh, let's see. How about...

509
00:41:16,807 --> 00:41:17,849
...Las Vegas?

510
00:41:18,017 --> 00:41:20,018
Las Vegas. Great!

511
00:41:22,771 --> 00:41:23,813
What next?

512
00:41:23,981 --> 00:41:25,899
- Seattle!
- Yeah!

513
00:41:38,704 --> 00:41:42,832
I have seven... Correction,
eight redbirds two degrees past apogee.

514
00:41:44,710 --> 00:41:46,836
Better get the old man down here.

515
00:41:47,004 --> 00:41:48,838
We have a Soviet missile warning.

516
00:41:49,006 --> 00:41:51,716
Check for malfunction
and report confidence.

517
00:41:51,884 --> 00:41:55,929
Projected target areas,
NORAD regions 2526.

518
00:42:10,152 --> 00:42:14,364
All stations, this is Crystal Palace
initiating emergency conference.

519
00:42:16,617 --> 00:42:20,537
19 degrees past apogee,
with possible 18 targets in track.

520
00:42:20,704 --> 00:42:24,123
Estimate reentry at 19-23 Zulu.

521
00:42:32,508 --> 00:42:35,260
- What you got here, Joe?
- We have a radar tracking.

522
00:42:35,427 --> 00:42:38,638
Eight inbound Soviet ICBMs
already over the pole.

523
00:42:38,806 --> 00:42:42,475
Estimated impact, 11 minutes.
Target area, western United States.

524
00:42:42,643 --> 00:42:44,394
Why didn't we get detection?

525
00:42:44,562 --> 00:42:47,063
I'm not sure.
We're checking for DSP malfunction.

526
00:42:47,856 --> 00:42:50,984
BMEWS has continuous
radar tracking on inbounds.

527
00:42:51,151 --> 00:42:55,029
Confidence is high.
I repeat, confidence is high.

528
00:43:00,703 --> 00:43:02,495
- What is all that?
- I don't know.

529
00:43:02,663 --> 00:43:05,790
"Trajectory headings
for multiple impact reentry vehicles."

530
00:43:05,958 --> 00:43:07,083
What does that mean?

531
00:43:07,251 --> 00:43:09,210
I don't know, but it's great.

532
00:43:09,378 --> 00:43:12,213
- Which is the bombs?
- Subs.

533
00:43:12,381 --> 00:43:14,424
- Want to blow them up?
- Out of the water.

534
00:43:14,592 --> 00:43:17,468
- What's a "trajectory heading"?
- I have no idea.

535
00:43:21,265 --> 00:43:23,516
The president is diverting to Andrews.

536
00:43:23,684 --> 00:43:27,562
The vice president is out of position
and the chairman of the Joint Chiefs...

537
00:43:27,730 --> 00:43:31,107
Missile warning reports no malfunction.
Confidence remains high.

538
00:43:31,567 --> 00:43:35,278
Take us to DEFCON 3.
Get on to SAC.

539
00:43:35,446 --> 00:43:37,822
- Tell them to flush the bombers.
- Yes, sir.

540
00:43:40,367 --> 00:43:44,037
SAC, this is Crystal Palace.
CINC NORAD has declared DEFCON 3.

541
00:43:44,204 --> 00:43:48,166
Scramble all alert aircraft.
I repeat, scramble all alert aircraft.

542
00:43:49,084 --> 00:43:50,793
Inbounds presently MIRVing.

543
00:43:50,961 --> 00:43:54,464
We now have approximately
24 possible targets in track.

544
00:43:56,383 --> 00:43:58,009
8 minutes.

545
00:43:58,177 --> 00:44:01,554
SAC is launching the bombers.
General Powers is on the line.

546
00:44:01,722 --> 00:44:02,847
Beringer.

547
00:44:03,724 --> 00:44:07,518
Goddamn it! We didn't get
a launch detection from our satellite!

548
00:44:07,686 --> 00:44:10,480
No, radar picked them up
out of the atmosphere.

549
00:44:10,648 --> 00:44:12,231
That's the first we heard of it.

550
00:44:13,734 --> 00:44:17,028
Get the ICBMs in the bullpen
warmed up and ready to fly.

551
00:44:18,155 --> 00:44:20,740
- Get me the president on the horn.
- Yes, sir.

552
00:44:27,081 --> 00:44:30,667
Mr. President,
this is Beringer at NORAD.

553
00:44:31,001 --> 00:44:32,460
Oh, attack!

554
00:44:33,295 --> 00:44:36,631
- I wonder if I should use my subs.
- Sure. Give them the works.

555
00:44:36,799 --> 00:44:37,965
David!

556
00:44:40,678 --> 00:44:41,719
Excuse me.

557
00:44:42,471 --> 00:44:43,888
David!

558
00:44:45,182 --> 00:44:49,686
How many times have I said to fasten
these lids on tight? Look at this!

559
00:44:49,853 --> 00:44:51,437
I'll be down in a few minutes.

560
00:44:51,605 --> 00:44:54,190
Now! I want this
cleared up right away!

561
00:44:54,358 --> 00:44:57,235
Come down here and do what
your father asks you to.

562
00:44:57,403 --> 00:44:59,237
Pronto, David.

563
00:44:59,947 --> 00:45:03,199
We're gonna barbecue tonight.
Want to invite your little friend?

564
00:45:03,367 --> 00:45:05,952
- Please.
- David.

565
00:45:08,122 --> 00:45:09,414
Shit.

566
00:45:16,630 --> 00:45:18,381
"Little friend."

567
00:45:21,468 --> 00:45:22,468
Yes, sir.

568
00:45:25,931 --> 00:45:28,182
Mr. President,
something's happening here.

569
00:45:28,350 --> 00:45:29,600
I'll get back to you.

570
00:45:29,768 --> 00:45:31,269
Reconfirmed.

571
00:45:31,437 --> 00:45:32,645
What's happening?

572
00:45:33,647 --> 00:45:35,148
BMEWS and Cobra Dane now report

573
00:45:35,315 --> 00:45:37,775
negative confirmation
on all inbound tracking.

574
00:45:40,112 --> 00:45:42,989
Get on to SAC.
Tell them to hold steady.

575
00:45:44,825 --> 00:45:48,703
Stop! It's a simulation!
It's an attack simulation running!

576
00:45:48,871 --> 00:45:51,289
What's he yelling about?
I didn't order a simulation.

577
00:45:51,457 --> 00:45:54,417
We're not being attacked!
It's a simulation!

578
00:45:54,918 --> 00:45:56,085
Whoa, now! Hold it!

579
00:45:56,253 --> 00:45:58,421
Don't run.
Somebody could get hurt.

580
00:45:58,589 --> 00:46:00,840
I'm sorry.
We don't know how it happened

581
00:46:01,008 --> 00:46:04,719
but someone on the outside fed
an attack simulation into the main.

582
00:46:05,888 --> 00:46:08,306
Conley, take us off full alert.

583
00:46:08,474 --> 00:46:10,892
Hold at DEFCON 4
till we find out exactly

584
00:46:11,059 --> 00:46:13,352
what in the hell's happening here!

585
00:46:14,021 --> 00:46:18,024
I didn't tell you to cut the line!
Did I tell you to? You cut the line!

586
00:46:18,192 --> 00:46:20,568
They shut down before
we completed our trace.

587
00:46:20,736 --> 00:46:24,030
We located the area
where the transmission originated.

588
00:46:24,198 --> 00:46:26,115
- Where?
- Seattle, Washington.

589
00:46:26,283 --> 00:46:27,784
Shut it down.

590
00:46:27,951 --> 00:46:30,411
Somebody's playing a game with us.

591
00:46:30,746 --> 00:46:33,456
The claims began at
a prophylactic recycling center...

592
00:46:33,624 --> 00:46:36,417
- Hi, Dad!
- David!

593
00:46:36,877 --> 00:46:39,337
- David, come in here.
- What did I do?

594
00:46:39,505 --> 00:46:41,714
Plenty, mister, plenty.

595
00:46:43,342 --> 00:46:46,969
You have just passed
all of your classes this semester.

596
00:46:47,137 --> 00:46:49,680
- Congratulations, dear!
- Oh!

597
00:46:49,848 --> 00:46:51,140
Show this to your dad.

598
00:46:51,308 --> 00:46:54,852
Honey, David has something
to show you.

599
00:46:55,020 --> 00:46:56,145
What's that?

600
00:46:56,313 --> 00:46:58,523
- Here, Dad.
- Uh-oh.

601
00:46:58,690 --> 00:47:02,401
This is good.

602
00:47:03,362 --> 00:47:04,695
I'm so proud of you!

603
00:47:04,863 --> 00:47:07,657
... the U.S. Went on
a full-scale nuclear alert,

604
00:47:07,825 --> 00:47:10,910
believing that the Soviets
launched a surprise missile attack.

605
00:47:11,078 --> 00:47:15,164
A Pentagon spokesman places blame
on a computer malfunction,

606
00:47:15,332 --> 00:47:17,750
assuring that the problem
has been corrected.

607
00:47:17,918 --> 00:47:22,296
For more on the story, let's go live
via satellite to Washington, D.C.

608
00:47:22,464 --> 00:47:24,090
And News 4's Tim Hilert.

609
00:47:24,258 --> 00:47:28,135
- Well, that's your phone.
- Yeah.

610
00:47:28,303 --> 00:47:32,390
Seriously, congratulations.
This'll be a pleasure to sign.

611
00:47:38,939 --> 00:47:40,648
- Hello?
- David?

612
00:47:40,816 --> 00:47:42,525
Are you watching the news?

613
00:47:42,693 --> 00:47:45,236
Jennifer. Yeah, I'm watching.

614
00:47:45,404 --> 00:47:48,155
Is that us on TV?
Did we do that?

615
00:47:48,323 --> 00:47:52,451
It could be. Oh, Jesus, Jennifer!
What am I gonna do?

616
00:47:52,619 --> 00:47:54,954
They're gonna come get me.
I'm screwed!

617
00:47:55,122 --> 00:47:56,372
I am screwed!

618
00:47:56,540 --> 00:48:01,043
Wait, no! Sh!
Calm down, calm down.

619
00:48:01,211 --> 00:48:03,963
If they were so smart,
they would've found you already.

620
00:48:04,131 --> 00:48:05,214
Yeah.

621
00:48:05,382 --> 00:48:09,760
All you have to do is throw the number
away and don't call it again.

622
00:48:09,928 --> 00:48:11,971
That's all.

623
00:48:12,139 --> 00:48:14,098
Maybe they didn't trace the call.

624
00:48:14,266 --> 00:48:16,225
Right. Maybe they didn't.

625
00:48:16,393 --> 00:48:20,813
I'm sure they didn't trace it.
All you have to do is act normal.

626
00:48:20,981 --> 00:48:23,316
We'll both act normal
and it'll be fine.

627
00:48:23,483 --> 00:48:25,818
- OK?
- OK.

628
00:48:25,986 --> 00:48:27,320
OK.

629
00:48:27,863 --> 00:48:29,739
God, this is so unbelievable.

630
00:48:29,907 --> 00:48:32,325
Do you think maybe
I can tell Michelle?

631
00:48:32,492 --> 00:48:34,035
No, Jennifer, don't call her!

632
00:48:34,745 --> 00:48:37,914
I'm sorry. I won't.
I'll talk to you tomorrow, OK?

633
00:48:38,081 --> 00:48:39,498
OK.

634
00:48:39,666 --> 00:48:40,833
Good night, Jennifer.

635
00:49:11,698 --> 00:49:13,908
Greetings, Professor Falken.

636
00:49:15,285 --> 00:49:16,577
Oh, my God.

637
00:49:24,544 --> 00:49:28,464
"Incorrect identification.

638
00:49:28,632 --> 00:49:30,758
I am not Falken.

639
00:49:30,926 --> 00:49:34,053
Falken is dead."

640
00:49:35,806 --> 00:49:38,224
Sorry to hear that, professor.

641
00:49:38,392 --> 00:49:41,018
Yesterday's game was interrupted.

642
00:49:42,729 --> 00:49:45,356
Although primary goal
has not yet been achieved,

643
00:49:45,524 --> 00:49:47,024
solution is near.

644
00:49:47,192 --> 00:49:52,613
31 hours, 12 minutes, 50 seconds.

645
00:49:52,781 --> 00:49:54,782
Estimated time remaining:

646
00:49:54,950 --> 00:49:59,787
52 hours, 17 minutes, 10 seconds.

647
00:49:59,955 --> 00:50:04,250
"What is the primary goal?"

648
00:50:05,293 --> 00:50:09,005
You should know, professor.
You programmed me.

649
00:50:09,172 --> 00:50:10,589
Oh, come on.

650
00:50:11,800 --> 00:50:15,344
"What is the primary goal?"

651
00:50:17,431 --> 00:50:19,432
To win the game.

652
00:51:48,814 --> 00:51:51,524
David Lightman,
hold it right there. FBI.

653
00:51:51,691 --> 00:51:53,776
- I'll read you your rights.
- Step over here.

654
00:51:53,944 --> 00:51:55,569
"You have the right to remain silent.

655
00:51:55,737 --> 00:51:59,156
Anything you say can and will be
used against you in a court of law.

656
00:51:59,324 --> 00:52:03,869
You may consult with an attorney and
have one present during questioning.

657
00:52:04,037 --> 00:52:06,539
If you can't afford one,
one will be appointed to you."

658
00:52:06,706 --> 00:52:07,665
Left hand, please.

659
00:52:07,833 --> 00:52:10,209
Do you understand these rights?

660
00:52:10,377 --> 00:52:13,587
With this in mind, are you willing
to talk about the charges against you?

661
00:52:15,257 --> 00:52:16,340
Let's move.

662
00:52:29,563 --> 00:52:33,649
This large room is the command center
for NORAD. No picture taking.

663
00:52:33,817 --> 00:52:35,693
These screens are connected

664
00:52:35,861 --> 00:52:39,780
to our satellites and missile
tracking stations in the country.

665
00:52:39,948 --> 00:52:42,616
This is the commander's desk.
Col. Conley's in charge.

666
00:52:42,784 --> 00:52:45,744
Colonel, would you mind
relinquishing your command, sir?

667
00:52:45,912 --> 00:52:48,789
Miss Dailey, would you sit
in this rather important chair?

668
00:52:50,083 --> 00:52:53,043
These switches are connected
to the Strategic Air Command

669
00:52:53,211 --> 00:52:56,630
missile launching stations
and other classified things.

670
00:52:56,798 --> 00:52:59,592
Would you press this button
right here? The red one.

671
00:52:59,759 --> 00:53:01,302
- The one in the middle?
- Yes.

672
00:53:01,469 --> 00:53:03,929
Oh, my God! That's the wrong one!

673
00:53:04,097 --> 00:53:06,849
It's a joke! You didn't blow up
anything, but look what you did.

674
00:53:08,143 --> 00:53:10,603
"Distinguished visitors
from Birmingham."

675
00:53:40,550 --> 00:53:43,510
Last week I had the governor
of New Jersey in this chair.

676
00:53:43,678 --> 00:53:47,806
He asked me, "Colonel, why are we
at DEFCON 4 as we are right now?"

677
00:53:47,974 --> 00:53:49,391
Why are we at DEFCON 4?

678
00:53:49,559 --> 00:53:52,311
The Soviets saw our bombers scramble
and went on alert.

679
00:53:52,479 --> 00:53:54,521
We told them
it was just an exercise.

680
00:53:54,689 --> 00:53:57,483
We're waiting for them
to relax their posture before we do.

681
00:53:58,193 --> 00:53:59,526
Wait, wait.

682
00:54:00,153 --> 00:54:02,071
- Give me that.
- Another tour group.

683
00:54:02,239 --> 00:54:04,114
Just what we need today.

684
00:54:04,282 --> 00:54:08,035
- Why don't they go to Disneyland?
- I think they're going tomorrow.

685
00:54:08,203 --> 00:54:09,328
OK, all set?

686
00:54:09,496 --> 00:54:10,746
Oh, here.

687
00:54:13,833 --> 00:54:15,834
It was a one-in-a-million shot.

688
00:54:16,002 --> 00:54:19,171
There was an open line
at our division in Sunnyvale.

689
00:54:19,339 --> 00:54:21,757
The phone company screwed up!

690
00:54:21,925 --> 00:54:24,343
- John McKittrick, George Wigan.
- How are you?

691
00:54:24,511 --> 00:54:26,720
George is with the FBI.
He brought the kid in.

692
00:54:26,888 --> 00:54:30,224
It looks like we've got
a high school prank on our hands.

693
00:54:30,392 --> 00:54:31,642
Paul, what happened?

694
00:54:31,810 --> 00:54:34,144
The kid broke into
the war games subsystem

695
00:54:34,312 --> 00:54:37,189
using a password left
by the original programmer.

696
00:54:37,357 --> 00:54:38,649
- Password?
- Yes, sir.

697
00:54:38,817 --> 00:54:40,693
None of my team knew it was there.

698
00:54:40,860 --> 00:54:43,529
Kid claims he was looking
for a toy company.

699
00:54:43,697 --> 00:54:47,074
That's great.
Anybody in here buy that one?

700
00:54:47,867 --> 00:54:49,827
We can take out the password,

701
00:54:49,995 --> 00:54:52,705
but it'd help to beef up
security around the WOPR.

702
00:54:52,872 --> 00:54:54,623
Beef up, huh?

703
00:54:55,375 --> 00:54:56,500
How about screwed up?

704
00:54:57,210 --> 00:54:59,503
We did all that
and he broke in again.

705
00:54:59,671 --> 00:55:02,047
Kid says
your computer called him.

706
00:55:02,215 --> 00:55:04,800
What the hell is going on, John?

707
00:55:04,968 --> 00:55:08,971
I woke up the president. I told him
we were under attack by the Russians.

708
00:55:09,139 --> 00:55:13,309
Do you know what kind of idiot that
makes me look like? Or the general?

709
00:55:13,476 --> 00:55:15,602
Wait, general.
We're being naive.

710
00:55:15,770 --> 00:55:19,273
There's no way a high school punk
can put a dime in a telephone

711
00:55:19,441 --> 00:55:20,899
and break into our system.

712
00:55:21,067 --> 00:55:23,235
He's got to be working
with somebody else.

713
00:55:23,403 --> 00:55:24,987
He fits the profile perfectly.

714
00:55:25,155 --> 00:55:27,323
He's intelligent,
but an underachiever,

715
00:55:27,490 --> 00:55:31,076
alienated from his parents,
has few friends.

716
00:55:31,244 --> 00:55:32,870
Classic case for Soviet recruitment.

717
00:55:33,079 --> 00:55:35,664
What does this say
about the state of our country?

718
00:55:35,832 --> 00:55:37,750
Have you gotten any insight

719
00:55:37,917 --> 00:55:43,088
as to why a bright boy like this
would jeopardize the lives of millions?

720
00:55:43,256 --> 00:55:45,299
Says he does this sort
of thing for fun.

721
00:55:45,717 --> 00:55:48,886
Damn it, John, I want some answers
and I want them now!

722
00:55:49,054 --> 00:55:50,888
Arthur.

723
00:55:52,724 --> 00:55:55,893
- Let me talk to this prick.
- No more talk. Just do it!

724
00:55:58,480 --> 00:55:59,646
I'll talk to the kid.

725
00:56:03,443 --> 00:56:05,235
Who do they belong to,
do you know?

726
00:56:05,403 --> 00:56:06,904
No idea.

727
00:56:07,530 --> 00:56:09,198
- Good morning, sir.
- Where's the kid?

728
00:56:09,366 --> 00:56:11,075
In the infirmary, sir.

729
00:56:20,377 --> 00:56:24,421
Hello, David. John McKittrick.
I run the computer facility here.

730
00:56:25,382 --> 00:56:28,509
- These aren't necessary, the handcuffs?
- No, sir.

731
00:56:30,220 --> 00:56:31,678
David, uh...

732
00:56:32,472 --> 00:56:36,058
We called your parents
and we told them everything's fine.

733
00:56:36,226 --> 00:56:38,977
- No charges have been filed.
- Yet.

734
00:56:39,145 --> 00:56:43,857
But I think we are gonna need
a little time to sort things out here.

735
00:56:44,734 --> 00:56:45,818
How much time?

736
00:56:46,653 --> 00:56:49,238
That depends on how willing
you are to cooperate.

737
00:56:49,406 --> 00:56:51,532
Oh. Of course.

738
00:56:53,034 --> 00:56:54,159
I tell you what.

739
00:56:54,327 --> 00:56:56,995
Sergeant, tell the O.D.
I'm taking David for a walk.

740
00:56:57,163 --> 00:56:59,998
Let's go to my office.
We'll be more comfortable.

741
00:57:01,126 --> 00:57:02,334
Go ahead.

742
00:57:07,632 --> 00:57:09,633
You worked with Stephen Falken,
didn't you?

743
00:57:09,801 --> 00:57:12,344
I started out as his assistant.
How'd you know?

744
00:57:12,512 --> 00:57:15,347
I read an article you co-wrote
on poker and nuclear war.

745
00:57:15,515 --> 00:57:18,142
Bluffing.
Yeah, that shook a few people up.

746
00:57:18,309 --> 00:57:20,144
He must have
been pretty amazing.

747
00:57:20,311 --> 00:57:22,354
He's a brilliant man.
A little flaky.

748
00:57:22,522 --> 00:57:27,067
He never understood
the practical uses of his work.

749
00:57:27,235 --> 00:57:30,821
This machine over here
runs his game program.

750
00:57:30,989 --> 00:57:32,364
Joshua.

751
00:57:34,659 --> 00:57:35,701
Come here a minute.

752
00:57:37,996 --> 00:57:40,414
- See that sign up here? Up here?
- Yeah.

753
00:57:40,582 --> 00:57:42,124
DEFCON?

754
00:57:42,292 --> 00:57:45,085
That indicates
our current defense condition.

755
00:57:45,253 --> 00:57:48,714
It should read DEFCON 5,
which means peace.

756
00:57:48,882 --> 00:57:51,842
It's still on 4 because of
that little stunt you pulled.

757
00:57:52,010 --> 00:57:56,013
Actually, if we hadn't caught it in
time it might have gone to DEFCON 1.

758
00:57:57,223 --> 00:57:59,725
- Do you know what that means?
- No, what?

759
00:58:00,310 --> 00:58:01,435
World War III.

760
00:58:03,062 --> 00:58:03,729
Wow.

761
00:58:03,897 --> 00:58:06,857
You say you broke into our system
just to play a game?

762
00:58:07,025 --> 00:58:09,318
That's right. That's exactly right.

763
00:58:09,486 --> 00:58:12,696
Mm-hm.

764
00:58:13,615 --> 00:58:16,241
When you saw it on the news,
you knew how serious it was.

765
00:58:16,409 --> 00:58:17,701
Why'd you do it again?

766
00:58:17,869 --> 00:58:20,370
I didn't.
I even threw the number away.

767
00:58:20,538 --> 00:58:22,164
Yeah, they found it in the trash.

768
00:58:22,332 --> 00:58:24,082
Joshua called me.

769
00:58:24,918 --> 00:58:29,588
- Hey! Look at that. That's some setup.
- What'd you say?

770
00:58:29,756 --> 00:58:31,673
This is some setup.

771
00:58:31,841 --> 00:58:33,467
No, no, before that.

772
00:58:33,635 --> 00:58:35,260
Joshua called me.

773
00:58:37,263 --> 00:58:39,431
Machines don't call people.

774
00:58:40,892 --> 00:58:42,142
Yours did.

775
00:58:46,314 --> 00:58:48,690
Who are you going to Paris with?

776
00:58:50,818 --> 00:58:53,529
Pari... Oh!
No, no, you don't understand.

777
00:58:53,696 --> 00:58:56,406
Now, you had reservations
for two to Paris.

778
00:58:59,452 --> 00:59:01,912
- Who are you working with?
- Nobody!

779
00:59:04,958 --> 00:59:05,999
Why don't I believe you?

780
00:59:10,046 --> 00:59:12,714
I shouldn't say any more
until I talk to a lawyer.

781
00:59:14,509 --> 00:59:16,802
I think we better forget
about a lawyer

782
00:59:16,970 --> 00:59:19,429
until I get a few answers
out of you myself.

783
00:59:39,075 --> 00:59:40,659
You gonna answer the phone?

784
00:59:44,831 --> 00:59:48,500
Hello. Yeah. What?

785
00:59:50,253 --> 00:59:51,295
All right, I'll be right down.

786
00:59:52,380 --> 00:59:54,339
You stay here. Don't move.

787
01:00:06,603 --> 01:00:07,644
What's going on?

788
01:00:07,812 --> 01:00:11,315
There's been a serious penetration
into our WOPR execution order file.

789
01:00:11,482 --> 01:00:13,859
- What's he saying?
- Let's have it in English.

790
01:00:14,027 --> 01:00:18,363
I'll give it to you in English.
Somebody got into McKittrick's system

791
01:00:18,531 --> 01:00:20,282
and stole our missile codes.

792
01:00:20,450 --> 01:00:21,408
Is that right?

793
01:00:21,576 --> 01:00:25,787
The system won't accept a launch code
unless we're at DEFCON 1.

794
01:00:25,955 --> 01:00:28,165
I can change those codes in an hour.

795
01:00:28,625 --> 01:00:29,708
Who did this?

796
01:00:30,168 --> 01:00:32,669
The kid's gotta be working
with somebody.

797
01:00:32,837 --> 01:00:37,382
I sure as hell don't want our bombers
on the ground if anything happens.

798
01:00:38,217 --> 01:00:41,637
Take us to DEFCON 3 and get SAC
on the line. Where are you?

799
01:00:41,804 --> 01:00:43,388
Sir.

800
01:00:43,556 --> 01:00:46,725
Get me an update. I wanna know
what those bastards are up to.

801
01:00:46,893 --> 01:00:47,851
Yes, sir.

802
01:01:15,213 --> 01:01:16,505
Joshua.

803
01:01:18,716 --> 01:01:21,009
Greetings, Professor Falken.

804
01:01:24,180 --> 01:01:27,808
Hello. Are you still
playing the game?

805
01:01:29,727 --> 01:01:30,686
Of course.

806
01:01:30,853 --> 01:01:32,771
I should reach DEFCON 1

807
01:01:32,939 --> 01:01:36,441
and launch my missiles in 28 hours.

808
01:01:36,609 --> 01:01:41,405
Would you like to see
some projected kill ratios?

809
01:01:41,572 --> 01:01:44,574
Sixty-nine percent
of the housing destroyed.

810
01:01:44,742 --> 01:01:47,244
Seventy-two million people dead?

811
01:01:51,124 --> 01:01:54,042
Is this a game...

812
01:01:54,669 --> 01:01:56,336
...or is it real?

813
01:01:57,046 --> 01:01:59,673
- What's the difference?
- Oh, wow.

814
01:02:01,467 --> 01:02:03,969
You are a hard man to reach.

815
01:02:04,137 --> 01:02:06,471
Could not find you in Seattle

816
01:02:06,639 --> 01:02:10,976
and no terminal is in operation
at your classified address.

817
01:02:16,691 --> 01:02:20,235
What classified address?

818
01:02:22,155 --> 01:02:26,408
DOD pension files
indicate current mailing ad...

819
01:02:28,995 --> 01:02:30,829
...Dr. Robert Hume,

820
01:02:30,997 --> 01:02:34,082
a.k.a. Stephen W. Falken.

821
01:02:36,169 --> 01:02:40,839
5 Tall Cedar Road,
Goose Island, Oregon, 97...

822
01:02:41,007 --> 01:02:43,842
Can I just talk to Mr. McKittrick?
I know what's... Ah!

823
01:02:44,010 --> 01:02:45,177
Can I talk to McKittrick?

824
01:02:45,344 --> 01:02:48,180
I'll be escorting you
to federal authorities in Denver

825
01:02:48,347 --> 01:02:51,516
where you'll be under arrest
pending indictment for espionage.

826
01:02:51,684 --> 01:02:54,603
No, wait a minute.
He's right over there.

827
01:02:55,521 --> 01:02:57,439
Get that bastard out of the war room!

828
01:02:57,607 --> 01:02:59,316
No! It's Joshua!

829
01:02:59,484 --> 01:03:02,235
He's still playing the game!
He's gonna start a war!

830
01:03:02,403 --> 01:03:05,363
Hold him where you had him before.
We'll be leaving soon.

831
01:03:05,531 --> 01:03:08,033
Call Falken! He'll tell you.
Please call him.

832
01:03:08,201 --> 01:03:09,951
Please call him! Call him!

833
01:03:10,286 --> 01:03:12,412
What the hell's he doing
in here anyway?

834
01:03:29,972 --> 01:03:32,599
Some of the men say
you're quite a tennis player.

835
01:04:43,379 --> 01:04:47,299
Patient's eyes are dilated,
consistent with use of marijuana

836
01:04:47,466 --> 01:04:49,718
and possibly PCP.

837
01:05:18,581 --> 01:05:21,791
Depending on what information you want,
you press a button.

838
01:05:21,959 --> 01:05:26,171
Well, let's say I wanted
to find out how to hit a backhand.

839
01:05:26,339 --> 01:05:28,840
I don't think
I have the right program.

840
01:05:29,008 --> 01:05:31,259
Excuse me. What do you want?

841
01:05:31,427 --> 01:05:33,929
Bathroom.
It's a long ride to Denver.

842
01:05:40,895 --> 01:05:43,396
Please, let me talk to Mr. McKittrick.

843
01:05:43,564 --> 01:05:46,149
You're not talking to anybody.
The FBI's coming soon.

844
01:05:46,317 --> 01:05:49,027
- Do you have to take a leak?
- No.

845
01:06:16,472 --> 01:06:18,723
- I'm working here.
- Oh, I'm sorry.

846
01:06:19,266 --> 01:06:20,976
Stop it!

847
01:06:21,143 --> 01:06:23,853
- You have pretty eyes.
- That's original.

848
01:06:28,734 --> 01:06:30,527
- I'll get the elevator.
- Sign in?

849
01:06:30,695 --> 01:06:33,446
Yeah, get us all.

850
01:06:55,094 --> 01:06:58,638
I heard they voted you
Miss Fine in 1979. Is that true?

851
01:07:00,599 --> 01:07:01,808
Will you stop it?

852
01:07:01,976 --> 01:07:03,768
- Am I bothering you?
- Yes.

853
01:07:03,936 --> 01:07:06,479
- Do you want me to leave?
- Yes.

854
01:08:19,428 --> 01:08:20,762
I want this door open now.

855
01:08:20,930 --> 01:08:23,640
- How about calling?
- Yes, sir.

856
01:08:23,808 --> 01:08:24,682
I don't believe this.

857
01:08:59,176 --> 01:09:01,219
Hey, Scooter. Wait up.

858
01:09:02,555 --> 01:09:04,514
Come on, hurry it up. I'm late.

859
01:09:04,682 --> 01:09:06,141
OK, I'll be right with you.

860
01:09:07,726 --> 01:09:10,311
I think it's jammed from inside.

861
01:09:10,479 --> 01:09:12,272
David!

862
01:09:12,439 --> 01:09:14,899
You're just making it
harder on yourself.

863
01:09:19,905 --> 01:09:21,406
Let's go.

864
01:09:30,416 --> 01:09:31,875
Right this way, folks.

865
01:09:32,376 --> 01:09:36,171
I was just told that they're cleaning
the floors in the computer center.

866
01:09:36,338 --> 01:09:40,216
Don't want anyone to slip and fall,
so we'll end the tour here.

867
01:09:40,759 --> 01:09:43,803
Now, if I can ask you to board
the bus as quickly as possible...

868
01:09:44,388 --> 01:09:48,558
...you'll have a complimentary beverage
waiting at the officer's center.

869
01:09:48,726 --> 01:09:50,268
- Hold it! What are you doing?
- Ah!

870
01:09:50,436 --> 01:09:52,687
Got it. Here it comes.

871
01:09:54,148 --> 01:09:55,398
Do you kids think
you own this place?

872
01:09:55,566 --> 01:09:58,943
Oh.
I was just looking around.

873
01:10:00,070 --> 01:10:01,362
You're not supposed
to leave the group.

874
01:10:01,530 --> 01:10:02,155
Yes.

875
01:10:02,323 --> 01:10:05,992
- So why don't you get back there?
- Thank you very much, sir.

876
01:10:07,244 --> 01:10:08,286
Get out of the way.

877
01:10:13,834 --> 01:10:15,043
Take care. Watch your step.

878
01:10:15,211 --> 01:10:17,503
- Bye.
- Bye, now.

879
01:10:17,671 --> 01:10:18,838
Watch your step. Thank you.

880
01:10:19,006 --> 01:10:21,591
Check everywhere.
He can't be far. Let's move.

881
01:11:17,731 --> 01:11:19,524
- Thanks, pal.
- Take care.

882
01:12:41,940 --> 01:12:43,775
One...

883
01:12:43,942 --> 01:12:45,193
...five...

884
01:12:56,538 --> 01:12:57,872
What city, please?

885
01:12:58,040 --> 01:12:59,499
Goose Island, Oregon.

886
01:12:59,666 --> 01:13:02,460
The number for
Dr. Robert Hume, H-U-M-E,

887
01:13:02,628 --> 01:13:04,796
on Tall Cedar Road.

888
01:13:07,216 --> 01:13:10,802
Checking under Dr. Robert Hume,
H-U-M-E, on Tall Cedar Road.

889
01:13:10,969 --> 01:13:12,637
I find no listing.

890
01:13:12,805 --> 01:13:15,056
What does that mean?
He doesn't have a phone?

891
01:13:15,224 --> 01:13:17,642
I'm sorry. I have no listing.

892
01:13:17,810 --> 01:13:19,644
Oh, wait. Uh...

893
01:13:19,812 --> 01:13:23,898
Falken. Dr. Stephen Falken,
F-A-L-K-E-N,

894
01:13:24,066 --> 01:13:25,525
at the same address.

895
01:13:26,235 --> 01:13:29,570
I find no listing for
Dr. Stephen Falken, F-A-L-K-E-N,

896
01:13:29,738 --> 01:13:32,490
on Tall Cedar Road, Goose Island.

897
01:13:32,658 --> 01:13:33,658
Thank you.

898
01:13:50,843 --> 01:13:51,843
Yeah?

899
01:13:52,511 --> 01:13:53,594
Jennifer, it's me, David.

900
01:13:53,762 --> 01:13:56,347
- David?!
- Yeah, uh...

901
01:13:56,515 --> 01:13:57,974
Listen, I'm in Colorado

902
01:13:58,142 --> 01:14:00,351
and I need a really big favor.

903
01:14:00,519 --> 01:14:02,895
- Can you lend me some money?
- What?

904
01:14:03,063 --> 01:14:05,898
I need an airline ticket.
I'll pay you back.

905
01:14:06,066 --> 01:14:09,068
I need a ticket from Grand Junction
to Salem, Oregon.

906
01:14:09,236 --> 01:14:10,611
Why? What's going on?

907
01:14:10,779 --> 01:14:12,363
I'll tell you about it later.

908
01:14:12,531 --> 01:14:14,657
What are you doing in Colorado?

909
01:14:14,825 --> 01:14:17,869
I went by your house.
Your parents were freaked

910
01:14:18,036 --> 01:14:21,080
and there are men from the FBI
asking all these questions.

911
01:14:21,248 --> 01:14:23,708
I can't talk about it right now.
Listen...

912
01:14:24,460 --> 01:14:25,960
...when you buy the ticket,
tell them

913
01:14:26,128 --> 01:14:28,963
I'll pick it up
in Grand Junction Airport?

914
01:14:29,131 --> 01:14:31,048
David, what's happening?

915
01:14:31,216 --> 01:14:33,217
I can't talk.
I gotta get off the phone.

916
01:14:33,385 --> 01:14:35,636
But please, will you do this for me?

917
01:14:40,309 --> 01:14:42,852
Punch up number five.
Let me see what you have.

918
01:14:44,062 --> 01:14:47,398
Twenty-two typhoon-class submarines
departing Petropavlovsk,

919
01:14:47,566 --> 01:14:51,319
turning southbound at Nordkapp,
bearing 095 degrees.

920
01:14:51,487 --> 01:14:53,946
Sergeant, I hope you like vodka.

921
01:14:54,114 --> 01:14:58,659
Yes, sir. I just hope they don't make
me eat none of them damn fish eggs.

922
01:15:05,250 --> 01:15:09,128
Sir, the Soviets are denying any
increase in their submarine deployment.

923
01:15:09,296 --> 01:15:11,255
They want to know
why we're provoking them.

924
01:15:11,423 --> 01:15:14,759
They're full of shit.
We know they're down there.

925
01:15:14,927 --> 01:15:17,345
I'm gonna blow their ass
out of the water.

926
01:15:59,096 --> 01:16:00,513
Surprise!

927
01:16:01,765 --> 01:16:02,807
Why are you here?

928
01:16:02,975 --> 01:16:05,685
You didn't sound too good.
It's only a three-hour drive.

929
01:16:05,852 --> 01:16:07,478
You shouldn't have come.
I'm in trouble.

930
01:16:07,646 --> 01:16:08,646
Why?

931
01:16:09,940 --> 01:16:12,441
Is this because of
what you did with my grade?

932
01:16:20,075 --> 01:16:22,618
Better hustle. The ferry's
gonna leave any second.

933
01:16:22,786 --> 01:16:24,704
Thanks. Come on, we gotta run.

934
01:16:29,793 --> 01:16:31,335
Wait, wait, wait!

935
01:16:31,503 --> 01:16:32,837
Hold it, hold it.

936
01:16:41,930 --> 01:16:45,057
If he's alive, why'd
the obituary say he's dead?

937
01:16:45,225 --> 01:16:47,310
He's not dead. He left.

938
01:16:48,770 --> 01:16:51,272
When they know too much,
they get new identities.

939
01:16:51,440 --> 01:16:54,442
- Anyway, the computer said so.
- Oh, the computer said so.

940
01:16:54,610 --> 01:16:57,820
Is that the computer
that's still playing the games?

941
01:16:57,988 --> 01:17:00,781
It's the military's computer.
Why wouldn't they know?

942
01:17:00,949 --> 01:17:04,410
They don't know about Joshua.
Falken knows about Joshua.

943
01:17:04,578 --> 01:17:06,996
He's the only one
who knows what it can do.

944
01:17:07,164 --> 01:17:10,416
The computer is trying to win
the game we asked it to play.

945
01:17:10,584 --> 01:17:12,209
For real!

946
01:17:13,837 --> 01:17:16,005
You don't even believe me!

947
01:17:19,926 --> 01:17:21,344
David...

948
01:17:21,887 --> 01:17:23,846
David, David...

949
01:17:24,014 --> 01:17:25,181
He's not dead.

950
01:17:25,349 --> 01:17:26,432
I'm sorry.

951
01:17:29,728 --> 01:17:31,103
I believe you.

952
01:18:19,736 --> 01:18:21,237
Oh, shit!

953
01:18:21,405 --> 01:18:22,405
What was that?

954
01:18:23,031 --> 01:18:24,198
I don't know.

955
01:18:29,121 --> 01:18:31,455
Did you see that?

956
01:18:31,623 --> 01:18:33,833
Some people won't believe
they could fly.

957
01:18:34,000 --> 01:18:35,793
The sky was once filled with them!

958
01:18:35,961 --> 01:18:37,461
I'm looking for Dr. Hume.

959
01:18:37,629 --> 01:18:40,423
Are you a paleontologist?
I need a paleontologist.

960
01:18:40,590 --> 01:18:41,882
No, we're high school students.

961
01:18:42,050 --> 01:18:44,677
Oh... pity.

962
01:18:44,845 --> 01:18:49,932
Well, high school students, you're on
my land and I didn't invite you.

963
01:18:50,100 --> 01:18:53,519
But aren't you Stephen Falken?

964
01:18:54,771 --> 01:18:57,314
Now, listen carefully.

965
01:18:57,482 --> 01:18:58,524
Path.

966
01:18:58,692 --> 01:18:59,817
Follow path.

967
01:19:00,402 --> 01:19:03,487
Gate. Open gate,
through gate, close gate.

968
01:19:03,655 --> 01:19:05,823
Last ferry, 6:30,
so run, run, run.

969
01:19:06,491 --> 01:19:10,494
Wait! Wait!
I came because of Joshua.

970
01:19:52,370 --> 01:19:53,454
Radar reports two unknown tracks

971
01:19:53,622 --> 01:19:56,707
are penetrating
the Alaskan air defense zone.

972
01:19:58,919 --> 01:20:02,546
Flight profile suggests
Soviet backfire bombers.

973
01:20:02,714 --> 01:20:07,218
I want a visual confirmation on that.
Scramble two F-16s out of Galena.

974
01:20:09,679 --> 01:20:10,721
Go to DEFCON 2.

975
01:20:43,588 --> 01:20:46,215
Crystal Palace,
this is Delta Foxtrot 27.

976
01:20:46,383 --> 01:20:50,803
I have negative radar contact.
Repeat, negative Soviet aircraft.

977
01:20:50,971 --> 01:20:54,306
27, this is Brass Hat.
They're right in front of you!

978
01:20:54,474 --> 01:20:56,183
You're almost on top of them.

979
01:20:56,935 --> 01:20:58,811
Brass Hat,
we got nothing on radar

980
01:20:58,979 --> 01:21:00,980
and 40 miles visibility.

981
01:21:01,147 --> 01:21:03,899
There's nothing out there, general.
Just blue skies.

982
01:21:05,151 --> 01:21:07,069
What the hell?

983
01:21:17,205 --> 01:21:18,873
You really
haven't been listening.

984
01:21:19,040 --> 01:21:23,085
Yes, I have. I loved it
when you nuked Las Vegas.

985
01:21:23,253 --> 01:21:26,630
Suitably biblical ending
for the place, don't you think?

986
01:21:26,798 --> 01:21:29,466
You gonna tell them
what Joshua's doing?

987
01:21:31,136 --> 01:21:32,595
Children, come over here.

988
01:21:32,762 --> 01:21:35,598
I'm gonna tell you a bedtime story.

989
01:21:35,765 --> 01:21:38,058
Are you sitting comfortably?

990
01:21:38,226 --> 01:21:40,185
Then I'll begin.

991
01:21:40,353 --> 01:21:42,146
Once upon a time...

992
01:21:43,315 --> 01:21:46,317
...there lived
a magnificent race of animals...

993
01:21:47,027 --> 01:21:49,570
...who dominated the world
through age after age.

994
01:21:49,738 --> 01:21:53,949
They ran and they swam
and they fought and they flew,

995
01:21:54,117 --> 01:21:55,409
until suddenly...

996
01:21:55,577 --> 01:21:57,161
...quite recently...

997
01:21:57,329 --> 01:21:58,704
...they disappeared.

998
01:21:58,872 --> 01:22:00,956
Nature just gave up

999
01:22:01,124 --> 01:22:03,000
and started again.

1000
01:22:03,668 --> 01:22:05,169
We weren't even apes then.

1001
01:22:05,337 --> 01:22:09,340
We were just these smart
little rodents hiding in the rocks.

1002
01:22:09,507 --> 01:22:11,091
And when we go...

1003
01:22:12,093 --> 01:22:14,261
...nature will start again...

1004
01:22:14,429 --> 01:22:16,305
...with the bees probably.

1005
01:22:17,974 --> 01:22:19,934
Nature knows when to give up.

1006
01:22:20,101 --> 01:22:21,894
I'm not giving up.

1007
01:22:23,188 --> 01:22:26,190
If Joshua tricks them into launching
an attack, it'll be your fault.

1008
01:22:27,067 --> 01:22:28,233
My fault?

1009
01:22:28,401 --> 01:22:31,695
The whole point was
to practice nuclear war

1010
01:22:31,863 --> 01:22:33,238
without destroying ourselves.

1011
01:22:33,406 --> 01:22:37,201
To get the computers to learn
from mistakes we couldn't make.

1012
01:22:37,369 --> 01:22:41,705
Except that I never could get Joshua
to learn the most important lesson.

1013
01:22:41,873 --> 01:22:43,457
What's that?

1014
01:22:43,625 --> 01:22:47,211
Futility. That there's a time
when you should just give up.

1015
01:22:47,379 --> 01:22:49,088
What kind of lesson is that?

1016
01:22:49,255 --> 01:22:51,382
Did you ever play tic-tac-toe?

1017
01:22:53,051 --> 01:22:54,385
Yeah. Of course.

1018
01:22:54,552 --> 01:22:56,512
- But you don't anymore.
- No.

1019
01:22:56,680 --> 01:22:57,930
Why?

1020
01:22:58,890 --> 01:23:01,725
Because it's a boring game.
It's always a tie.

1021
01:23:01,893 --> 01:23:06,438
Exactly. There's no way to win.
The game itself is pointless.

1022
01:23:07,607 --> 01:23:11,819
But back at the war room, they believe
you can win a nuclear war...

1023
01:23:12,487 --> 01:23:15,072
...that there can be
acceptable losses.

1024
01:23:16,241 --> 01:23:17,533
So you gave up?

1025
01:23:18,284 --> 01:23:19,827
Decided to play dead?

1026
01:23:20,829 --> 01:23:24,581
For security reasons,
they graciously arranged my death.

1027
01:23:26,001 --> 01:23:28,419
Did you know that no land animal

1028
01:23:28,586 --> 01:23:31,880
with a body weight of
over 50 pounds survived that age?

1029
01:23:33,133 --> 01:23:36,093
Extinction is part
of the natural order.

1030
01:23:36,261 --> 01:23:37,511
Bullshit!

1031
01:23:39,055 --> 01:23:42,224
If we're extinguished,
it's not natural. It's stupid.

1032
01:23:42,392 --> 01:23:45,227
It's all right. I've planned ahead.

1033
01:23:45,395 --> 01:23:49,189
We're just three miles
from a primary target.

1034
01:23:49,357 --> 01:23:51,608
A millisecond of brilliant light...

1035
01:23:51,776 --> 01:23:53,569
...and we're vaporized.

1036
01:23:54,279 --> 01:23:56,113
Much more fortunate than the millions

1037
01:23:56,281 --> 01:23:59,825
who'll wander sightless
through the smoldering aftermath.

1038
01:24:01,661 --> 01:24:04,455
We'll be spared
the horror of survival.

1039
01:24:05,123 --> 01:24:07,958
I'm only 17 years old.

1040
01:24:08,710 --> 01:24:10,502
I'm not ready to die yet.

1041
01:24:10,670 --> 01:24:12,963
You won't make a simple phone call?

1042
01:24:15,050 --> 01:24:18,469
If the real Joshua were still alive,
your Joshua...

1043
01:24:18,636 --> 01:24:19,803
...you'd do it.

1044
01:24:19,971 --> 01:24:23,098
We might gain a few years,
enough for you to have a son

1045
01:24:23,266 --> 01:24:25,017
and watch him die.

1046
01:24:26,811 --> 01:24:30,230
But humanity planning
its own destruction...

1047
01:24:31,608 --> 01:24:32,983
...that, a phone call won't stop.

1048
01:24:33,818 --> 01:24:35,152
This is unreal!

1049
01:24:35,779 --> 01:24:37,988
You don't care about death
because you're already dead!

1050
01:24:40,408 --> 01:24:43,786
I know a lot about you.
I know you weren't always like this.

1051
01:24:43,953 --> 01:24:45,621
What's the last thing
you cared about?

1052
01:24:50,376 --> 01:24:52,169
You've missed the last ferry.

1053
01:25:00,011 --> 01:25:01,386
You're welcome to stay.

1054
01:25:02,222 --> 01:25:04,098
You want to sleep on the floor?

1055
01:25:08,103 --> 01:25:09,520
Good night.

1056
01:25:12,982 --> 01:25:14,149
Let's get out of here.

1057
01:25:24,327 --> 01:25:25,994
Come on, we'll find a boat.

1058
01:25:26,162 --> 01:25:27,830
There's gotta be a boat.

1059
01:25:45,140 --> 01:25:48,559
Mr. President, we've got 48 nuclear subs
closing on the United States,

1060
01:25:48,726 --> 01:25:53,063
and we've got 100,000 Soviet troops
massing in East Germany.

1061
01:25:53,231 --> 01:25:56,024
We're monitoring their bombers
that are on alert.

1062
01:25:56,192 --> 01:25:57,985
Well, that's a load of shit!

1063
01:25:58,153 --> 01:26:00,070
No, no, sir. Not you.

1064
01:26:00,822 --> 01:26:04,408
Yes, sir. We'll be in touch
as soon as the information changes.

1065
01:26:05,076 --> 01:26:08,370
There's rumors of a new Soviet bomber
with stealth capabilities.

1066
01:26:08,538 --> 01:26:12,249
It can project a false radar image
600 miles from the real aircraft.

1067
01:26:12,417 --> 01:26:14,793
Christ! Now they got us
chasing shadows.

1068
01:26:27,265 --> 01:26:29,141
I think I saw one.

1069
01:26:34,189 --> 01:26:37,482
What kind of asshole lives on
an island and doesn't have a boat?

1070
01:26:39,027 --> 01:26:41,528
Maybe we can swim.
How far do you think it is?

1071
01:26:41,696 --> 01:26:45,199
No, it's two, three miles, at least.

1072
01:26:45,366 --> 01:26:46,700
Maybe more.

1073
01:26:46,868 --> 01:26:48,493
What do you say? Let's go for it.

1074
01:26:48,661 --> 01:26:50,162
- No.
- Come on.

1075
01:26:50,330 --> 01:26:52,414
No. I can't swim.

1076
01:26:54,042 --> 01:26:55,042
You can't swim?

1077
01:26:55,210 --> 01:26:57,294
I can't swim, OK, Wonder Woman?

1078
01:26:57,921 --> 01:27:01,340
What kind of asshole grows up in
Seattle and doesn't learn to swim?

1079
01:27:01,507 --> 01:27:03,634
I never got around to it, OK?

1080
01:27:03,801 --> 01:27:06,678
I always thought there was
gonna be plenty of time.

1081
01:27:06,846 --> 01:27:08,805
Sorry.

1082
01:27:13,770 --> 01:27:16,313
I wish I didn't know
about any of this.

1083
01:27:18,149 --> 01:27:20,442
I wish I was like everybody else
in the world.

1084
01:27:21,277 --> 01:27:23,987
And tomorrow it would just be over.

1085
01:27:26,449 --> 01:27:29,076
There wouldn't be any time
to be sorry...

1086
01:27:30,453 --> 01:27:32,246
...about anything.

1087
01:27:38,920 --> 01:27:40,504
Oh, Jesus.

1088
01:27:42,173 --> 01:27:44,508
I really wanted to learn how to swim.

1089
01:27:45,635 --> 01:27:47,511
I swear to God I did.

1090
01:27:56,854 --> 01:27:59,773
Did I tell you that next week...

1091
01:28:00,483 --> 01:28:02,025
...I was gonna be on TV?

1092
01:28:02,193 --> 01:28:04,528
- You're kidding.
- No.

1093
01:28:04,696 --> 01:28:08,532
Just on that aerobics show
with some girls from my dance class.

1094
01:28:08,700 --> 01:28:09,950
A movie star.

1095
01:28:10,118 --> 01:28:11,535
Yeah.

1096
01:28:12,829 --> 01:28:14,454
It's kind of stupid, huh?

1097
01:28:14,622 --> 01:28:16,915
Nobody would've been
watching me anyway.

1098
01:28:17,083 --> 01:28:19,459
I would have.

1099
01:28:38,187 --> 01:28:39,354
Oh, Jesus!

1100
01:28:39,522 --> 01:28:41,523
The bastard turned us in!

1101
01:29:42,794 --> 01:29:45,462
It's all right. Get in!

1102
01:30:12,156 --> 01:30:15,409
We have a launch detection.
We have a Soviet launch detection.

1103
01:30:15,576 --> 01:30:17,202
BMEWS confirmed a massive attack.

1104
01:30:17,370 --> 01:30:20,997
Missile warning. No malfunction.
Confidence is high.

1105
01:30:21,165 --> 01:30:23,959
- Is this an exercise?
- This is not an exercise.

1106
01:30:24,127 --> 01:30:27,838
General, DBS is tracking
300 inbound Soviet ICBMs.

1107
01:30:34,512 --> 01:30:37,806
Tell me this is one of your simulations,
Mr. McKittrick.

1108
01:30:37,974 --> 01:30:41,852
All right. Flush the bombers,
get the subs in launch mode.

1109
01:30:42,687 --> 01:30:44,521
We are at DEFCON 1.

1110
01:30:44,689 --> 01:30:47,315
DEFCON 1.

1111
01:30:49,485 --> 01:30:50,777
Look at this.

1112
01:30:50,945 --> 01:30:53,113
Major Lem, get me a report on
the WOPR.

1113
01:30:55,199 --> 01:30:58,785
Initial attack profile is
a full-scale Soviet strike.

1114
01:30:58,953 --> 01:31:03,206
WOPR is putting our losses at 85 to 95
percent of the strategic forces.

1115
01:31:03,374 --> 01:31:05,375
What does WOPR recommend?

1116
01:31:06,210 --> 01:31:08,044
Full-scale retaliatory strike.

1117
01:31:09,672 --> 01:31:12,340
I need some machine to tell me that?

1118
01:31:12,925 --> 01:31:15,135
President's going to Andrews
to Airborne Command.

1119
01:31:15,303 --> 01:31:16,845
We have to give launch option.

1120
01:31:17,013 --> 01:31:18,597
Is he in touch
with the Premier?

1121
01:31:18,764 --> 01:31:20,348
Russians are denying everything.

1122
01:31:20,516 --> 01:31:24,060
We have a Soviet submarine
launch detection.

1123
01:31:24,228 --> 01:31:27,481
Let's go into a launch mode.
Close up the mountain.

1124
01:31:34,572 --> 01:31:38,033
This is Crystal Palace.
We're closing up the mountain. Hurry.

1125
01:31:38,201 --> 01:31:40,785
After the gates are closed,
nobody gets in or out.

1126
01:31:47,960 --> 01:31:49,794
Initiate internal power.

1127
01:31:51,255 --> 01:31:53,256
Generators on and functioning.

1128
01:32:02,099 --> 01:32:04,142
External power disconnected.

1129
01:32:07,730 --> 01:32:09,397
Seal off ventilation shafts.

1130
01:32:10,274 --> 01:32:11,775
Shaft locks sealed.

1131
01:32:16,489 --> 01:32:18,114
The gate's closed.

1132
01:32:18,282 --> 01:32:19,115
Oh, Jesus!

1133
01:32:26,707 --> 01:32:27,791
Let's get out!

1134
01:32:27,959 --> 01:32:30,794
- Are you all right?
- Yeah. Run for it.

1135
01:32:34,131 --> 01:32:36,383
Move it! The gate's gonna shut.
Come on!

1136
01:32:37,885 --> 01:32:39,386
Come on! Come on!

1137
01:32:50,731 --> 01:32:52,774
Hold the door! Hold the door!

1138
01:32:56,904 --> 01:32:58,738
Hold the goddamn door!

1139
01:33:04,287 --> 01:33:05,829
Run! Come on! Hurry!

1140
01:33:08,124 --> 01:33:10,166
They're clear! They're clear!

1141
01:33:29,604 --> 01:33:31,771
All units confirm weapons
targeted and ready.

1142
01:33:31,939 --> 01:33:33,315
Awaiting launch codes.

1143
01:33:33,482 --> 01:33:35,275
We are in a launch mode.

1144
01:33:35,443 --> 01:33:37,944
Major Lem, lock out changes.

1145
01:33:38,112 --> 01:33:39,821
Roger. Lock out enabled.

1146
01:33:50,207 --> 01:33:51,666
All right, I'll call you back.

1147
01:33:52,627 --> 01:33:54,169
Here!

1148
01:34:01,802 --> 01:34:04,721
I don't know what you think
you could do here.

1149
01:34:04,889 --> 01:34:08,558
John! Good to see you.
I see the wife still picks your ties.

1150
01:34:08,726 --> 01:34:09,976
What has this kid been telling you?

1151
01:34:11,020 --> 01:34:12,062
How far has it gone?

1152
01:34:12,813 --> 01:34:14,522
The president's ready to order
a counter-strike.

1153
01:34:14,690 --> 01:34:17,192
That's what we're recommending he do.

1154
01:34:19,695 --> 01:34:22,697
- It's a bluff. Call it off.
- It's not a bluff. It's real.

1155
01:34:23,240 --> 01:34:25,742
Hello, General Beringer!
Stephen Falken.

1156
01:34:26,827 --> 01:34:29,454
Mr. Falken, you picked
a hell of a day for a visit.

1157
01:34:29,622 --> 01:34:34,334
General, what you see on these screens
up here is a fantasy...

1158
01:34:34,502 --> 01:34:36,920
...a computer-enhanced hallucination.

1159
01:34:37,088 --> 01:34:40,215
Those blips are not real missiles.
They're phantoms.

1160
01:34:40,883 --> 01:34:44,594
Nothing indicates a simulation at all.
Everything's working perfectly.

1161
01:34:44,762 --> 01:34:47,555
- But does it make sense?
- Does what make sense?

1162
01:34:47,723 --> 01:34:48,556
That.

1163
01:34:48,724 --> 01:34:52,310
Look, I don't have time for
a conversation right now!

1164
01:34:52,478 --> 01:34:56,272
General, are you prepared to
destroy the enemy?

1165
01:34:56,440 --> 01:34:59,317
- You bet!
- Do you think they know that?

1166
01:34:59,485 --> 01:35:01,194
I believe we've
made that clear enough.

1167
01:35:01,362 --> 01:35:03,238
Then don't.

1168
01:35:04,073 --> 01:35:06,241
Tell the president to ride out
the attack.

1169
01:35:07,034 --> 01:35:09,119
Sir? They need a decision.

1170
01:35:09,787 --> 01:35:14,416
Do you really believe that the enemy
would attack without provocation,

1171
01:35:14,583 --> 01:35:16,626
using so many missiles,
bombers and subs

1172
01:35:16,794 --> 01:35:20,130
so that we'd have no choice
but to totally annihilate them?

1173
01:35:20,297 --> 01:35:22,716
One minute and 30 seconds to impact.

1174
01:35:23,217 --> 01:35:27,011
General, you are listening
to a machine.

1175
01:35:27,179 --> 01:35:29,055
Do the world a favor
and don't act like one.

1176
01:35:33,769 --> 01:35:37,105
One minute
and 20 seconds to impact.

1177
01:35:48,492 --> 01:35:50,535
Yes, Mr. President.

1178
01:35:50,703 --> 01:35:53,997
At this time, we cannot
positively confirm the inbounds.

1179
01:35:54,457 --> 01:35:56,875
We have reason to believe
they may not exist.

1180
01:35:57,752 --> 01:35:59,377
Yes, that's affirmative.

1181
01:36:00,963 --> 01:36:03,298
Yes, sir. I do too.

1182
01:36:03,466 --> 01:36:05,508
One minute to impact.

1183
01:36:07,219 --> 01:36:08,386
Who's first, how soon?

1184
01:36:08,554 --> 01:36:11,514
Initial impact points
in the 43rd bomb wing at Loring,

1185
01:36:11,682 --> 01:36:14,768
319th at Grand Forks
and Alaskan Air Command at Elmendorf.

1186
01:36:14,935 --> 01:36:16,644
50 seconds to impact.

1187
01:36:16,812 --> 01:36:20,356
Get me the senior controller at those
stations. I want to talk to them.

1188
01:36:20,524 --> 01:36:22,358
All stations, this is Crystal Palace.

1189
01:36:22,526 --> 01:36:25,361
Stand by for a message from Brass Hat.
Acknowledge.

1190
01:36:25,529 --> 01:36:29,115
Elmendorf Air Force Base,
Operations. Lieutenant Colonel Bowers.

1191
01:36:29,283 --> 01:36:32,494
319th Bomb Wing, Operations.
Colonel Chase.

1192
01:36:33,537 --> 01:36:35,079
This is Loring Air Force Base.

1193
01:36:35,247 --> 01:36:37,540
The senior controller
isn't here right now.

1194
01:36:37,708 --> 01:36:40,001
That's all right. Who are you?

1195
01:36:40,169 --> 01:36:42,879
Sir, this is Airman Dougherty, sir.

1196
01:36:44,048 --> 01:36:46,341
This is General Beringer at NORAD.

1197
01:36:46,509 --> 01:36:48,551
Our current situation is...

1198
01:36:49,553 --> 01:36:51,179
Men...

1199
01:36:51,347 --> 01:36:56,100
...we are currently tracking
about 2400 inbound Soviet warheads.

1200
01:36:56,268 --> 01:36:58,812
But at the moment,
we cannot confirm this.

1201
01:36:58,979 --> 01:37:01,564
I repeat, we cannot confirm this.

1202
01:37:01,732 --> 01:37:03,650
Thirty seconds to impact.

1203
01:37:04,401 --> 01:37:08,363
We're right there with you
guys. We've taken all the steps we can.

1204
01:37:09,740 --> 01:37:11,825
Stand by to launch missiles
at my command.

1205
01:37:19,458 --> 01:37:22,126
Stay on this channel
as long as you can.

1206
01:37:22,586 --> 01:37:24,087
We'll be standing by.

1207
01:37:24,255 --> 01:37:26,965
Twenty seconds to impact.

1208
01:37:36,267 --> 01:37:37,517
Ten...

1209
01:37:37,685 --> 01:37:38,643
...nine...

1210
01:37:38,811 --> 01:37:40,562
...eight...

1211
01:37:40,729 --> 01:37:41,688
...seven...

1212
01:37:41,856 --> 01:37:43,231
...six...

1213
01:37:43,399 --> 01:37:45,108
...five...

1214
01:37:45,276 --> 01:37:46,276
...four...

1215
01:37:46,443 --> 01:37:47,735
...three...

1216
01:37:47,903 --> 01:37:49,112
...two...

1217
01:37:49,280 --> 01:37:51,281
...one. Impact.

1218
01:38:08,966 --> 01:38:15,388
This is Crystal Palace.
You still on?

1219
01:38:15,556 --> 01:38:17,098
Anyone there?

1220
01:38:18,976 --> 01:38:21,102
That's affirmative, sir.

1221
01:38:21,270 --> 01:38:23,187
Yeah! We're here!

1222
01:38:23,355 --> 01:38:26,399
- Christ! We're here!
- Boards are showing impact.

1223
01:38:28,193 --> 01:38:31,487
No, sir. No impact.
We're alive and well.

1224
01:38:31,655 --> 01:38:34,991
All right!

1225
01:38:40,331 --> 01:38:41,998
All right!

1226
01:38:49,548 --> 01:38:51,132
Recall the bombers!

1227
01:38:51,300 --> 01:38:54,385
Stand down the missiles!

1228
01:39:25,084 --> 01:39:27,543
Joshua, what are you doing?

1229
01:39:30,923 --> 01:39:33,216
COC, I need Dr. McKittrick right away.

1230
01:39:33,717 --> 01:39:34,842
This is McKittrick.

1231
01:39:35,010 --> 01:39:38,638
We got a problem.
WOPR is not letting me log back on.

1232
01:39:38,806 --> 01:39:40,807
I can't get in to stand down
the missiles.

1233
01:39:40,975 --> 01:39:42,350
All right, stand by.

1234
01:39:55,197 --> 01:39:56,656
Paul, this is McKittrick.

1235
01:39:56,824 --> 01:40:01,786
- The WOPR's not letting us back in.
- I know. No one can get back on.

1236
01:40:01,954 --> 01:40:06,457
We're trying everything. It's like
the password file has been wiped out.

1237
01:40:06,625 --> 01:40:09,419
Don't you think I would've tried that?

1238
01:40:13,257 --> 01:40:14,590
What are those?

1239
01:40:15,384 --> 01:40:16,843
Those are launch codes.

1240
01:40:17,011 --> 01:40:18,553
What are they for?

1241
01:40:19,179 --> 01:40:22,765
Joshua's finding the right code
so he can launch the missiles himself.

1242
01:40:33,694 --> 01:40:34,986
What's happening?

1243
01:40:35,154 --> 01:40:37,530
The random number generators
aren't even running.

1244
01:40:37,698 --> 01:40:39,532
- Got anything?
- I'm still looking.

1245
01:40:39,700 --> 01:40:42,326
I got no idea.
It could be coming from anywhere.

1246
01:40:44,288 --> 01:40:46,164
Sir, you better get on the headset.

1247
01:40:48,709 --> 01:40:49,792
Yeah?

1248
01:40:49,960 --> 01:40:54,464
The machine's locked us out. It's
sending random numbers to the silos.

1249
01:40:54,631 --> 01:40:57,008
It's trying to hit the codes
to launch the missiles.

1250
01:40:57,176 --> 01:40:59,177
Just unplug the goddamn thing.

1251
01:40:59,344 --> 01:41:02,305
- Jesus Christ!
- That won't work, general.

1252
01:41:03,098 --> 01:41:06,434
It would interpret a shutdown
as the destruction of NORAD.

1253
01:41:06,602 --> 01:41:10,146
Computers in the silos would carry out
their last instructions. They'd launch.

1254
01:41:11,148 --> 01:41:12,607
Can't we disarm the missiles?

1255
01:41:12,775 --> 01:41:15,526
Over a thousand of them?
There's no time.

1256
01:41:15,694 --> 01:41:19,697
At this rate, it'll hit
the launch codes in 5.3 minutes.

1257
01:41:21,325 --> 01:41:22,408
Mr. McKittrick?

1258
01:41:23,285 --> 01:41:26,370
After very careful consideration,
I've come to the conclusion

1259
01:41:26,538 --> 01:41:29,082
that your new defense system sucks.

1260
01:41:30,834 --> 01:41:32,960
I don't have to take that,
you sack of shit!

1261
01:41:33,128 --> 01:41:36,589
Oh, I was hoping for something
a little better than that from you,

1262
01:41:36,757 --> 01:41:38,466
a man of your education.

1263
01:41:38,634 --> 01:41:40,259
It's the president.

1264
01:41:45,182 --> 01:41:48,101
Well, what are you gonna tell him?

1265
01:41:49,561 --> 01:41:52,438
That I'm ordering our bombers
back to fail-safe.

1266
01:41:52,856 --> 01:41:55,108
We might have to go through
this thing after all.

1267
01:41:58,362 --> 01:41:59,320
Yes, sir.

1268
01:42:06,870 --> 01:42:10,039
He's got one. When he gets 10,
he'll launch the missiles.

1269
01:42:10,207 --> 01:42:11,624
Can't they stop it?

1270
01:42:11,792 --> 01:42:14,001
No, they can't.

1271
01:42:16,130 --> 01:42:19,048
They've taken out my password!

1272
01:42:19,216 --> 01:42:20,341
What are we gonna do?

1273
01:42:20,509 --> 01:42:22,176
I don't know. Do you?

1274
01:42:22,553 --> 01:42:25,388
I told you not to start playing games
with that thing.

1275
01:42:29,768 --> 01:42:30,893
It's games.

1276
01:42:33,480 --> 01:42:35,565
- Games!
- Try it.

1277
01:42:35,732 --> 01:42:37,191
John, let's feed it a tapeworm.

1278
01:42:37,359 --> 01:42:40,403
- It might smash the system.
- The kid get in by the back door?

1279
01:42:40,571 --> 01:42:42,697
- We took it out.
- Can we invade the deep logic?

1280
01:42:42,865 --> 01:42:44,448
We keep hitting a firewall.

1281
01:42:44,616 --> 01:42:46,200
If it wants to play a game, then play.

1282
01:42:46,368 --> 01:42:48,536
- Have it list games.
- Stephen, for chrissake!

1283
01:42:48,704 --> 01:42:50,288
Let him!
He's played it before.

1284
01:42:50,455 --> 01:42:52,331
- He can't do any worse.
- Two numbers.

1285
01:42:52,499 --> 01:42:55,835
I'd piss on a spark plug
if I thought it'd do any good.

1286
01:42:56,003 --> 01:42:57,461
Let the boy in there.

1287
01:42:57,629 --> 01:42:58,713
List games.

1288
01:43:04,970 --> 01:43:06,137
"Chess."

1289
01:43:13,604 --> 01:43:15,271
Three numbers locked in.

1290
01:43:15,439 --> 01:43:16,689
"Poker."

1291
01:43:19,234 --> 01:43:22,111
The security system's not gonna
let anything through.

1292
01:43:25,616 --> 01:43:27,325
"Global thermonuclear war."

1293
01:43:36,335 --> 01:43:37,543
Four numbers.

1294
01:43:39,963 --> 01:43:42,006
Stephen, for chrissake, do something.

1295
01:43:42,174 --> 01:43:44,800
- Come on, kid. Let's go.
- No. Try again.

1296
01:43:48,263 --> 01:43:50,181
- Put the list back up.
- We tried that.

1297
01:43:50,349 --> 01:43:52,183
- Put it up!
- Yes, put it up.

1298
01:44:00,484 --> 01:44:03,027
- It's not on the list!
- What's not on the list?

1299
01:44:03,195 --> 01:44:05,071
It's gotta be in there.

1300
01:44:08,116 --> 01:44:10,993
"Tic-tac-toe."

1301
01:44:17,668 --> 01:44:18,668
You're in.

1302
01:44:19,211 --> 01:44:21,462
- Order to disarm the missiles.
- No. No.

1303
01:44:31,265 --> 01:44:33,349
Five numbers. It's got half the code.

1304
01:44:35,394 --> 01:44:36,602
One.

1305
01:44:38,480 --> 01:44:40,523
- Put X in the center.
- I know.

1306
01:44:51,827 --> 01:44:53,828
- Six up.
- You can't win that game.

1307
01:44:53,996 --> 01:44:57,039
I know that. It doesn't.
It hasn't learned.

1308
01:44:57,207 --> 01:44:59,292
Can you make it play itself?

1309
01:45:00,252 --> 01:45:01,877
Zero.

1310
01:45:23,150 --> 01:45:24,108
Seven!

1311
01:45:24,276 --> 01:45:26,944
Come on. Learn, goddamn it!

1312
01:45:39,791 --> 01:45:40,833
Eight!

1313
01:45:41,001 --> 01:45:42,501
Must be caught in a loop.

1314
01:45:42,669 --> 01:45:45,421
It's drawing more power
from the rest of the system.

1315
01:45:46,965 --> 01:45:48,341
Nine numbers!

1316
01:45:52,512 --> 01:45:55,431
Ten! It's got the code.
It'll launch!

1317
01:46:14,159 --> 01:46:16,786
Colonel Conley, call SAC
for a launch status report.

1318
01:46:19,331 --> 01:46:21,332
- Get me the president.
- Yes, sir.

1319
01:46:54,783 --> 01:46:55,741
How you doing?

1320
01:46:55,909 --> 01:46:59,328
Our land lines are dead. I'm trying
to break through on satellites.

1321
01:47:24,604 --> 01:47:26,021
What's it doing?

1322
01:47:26,189 --> 01:47:27,356
It's learning.

1323
01:48:14,988 --> 01:48:17,781
Greetings, Professor Falken.

1324
01:48:26,917 --> 01:48:27,917
"Hello...

1325
01:48:28,460 --> 01:48:29,585
...Joshua."

1326
01:48:30,712 --> 01:48:31,962
Strange game.

1327
01:48:32,130 --> 01:48:36,091
The only winning move
is not to play.

1328
01:48:43,767 --> 01:48:48,020
How about a nice game of chess?

1329
01:49:23,598 --> 01:49:24,848
Colonel Conley...

1330
01:49:25,684 --> 01:49:28,435
...take us to DEFCON 5.
- Yes, sir.
